<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="forums">
  <title>openSUSE Forums</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/forums/english/other-forums/news-announcements/announcements/454608-opensuse-11-4-release-party-post-yours-here.html">
	openSUSE 11.4 Release Party? Post yours here !!
	</ulink></title>
    <para>
      Thirteen days and counting down to the 10th of March: the release of openSUSE 11.4. Here in the Netherlands we're trying to have a release party, date and place will be announced here in this thread. If you're attending a release party, organizing one yourself, having a private one at home, here's a chance to let others know, to see if there's one in your neighbourhood (or at least close enough to get there in time.
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/applications/454603-searching-understand-some-system-modifications.html">
      Searching to understand some system modifications
      </ulink></title>
    <para>
      Where do you start when you suspect an intruder? Here's a thread from a user that wants to make sure no one has made his way in on his computer. Read ahead to see what you can do.
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/applications/454337-can-i-use-debian-package.html">
      Can I use a Debian package?
      </ulink></title>
    <para>
      On linux systems, there are mainly two types of packages: Debian and RPM (Redhat Package Management). Sometimes it happens that an application is available in just one format, where the user runs a distro using the other one. Read to see what can be done, when you want to use a Debian package to install software on openSUSE, which is rpm-based.
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>This week's subforum: <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/laptop/">
      Laptop
      </ulink></title>
    <para>
      Even though a laptop is no more than a computer in a compact format, it's still a different kind of machine, with all it's built in hardware. Manufacturers do no always provide the right info on the hardware used, let alone give good linux support. Hence, a subforum for laptop users was created long ago. 
      </para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 23.2.11 gl $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
