<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="forums">
  <title>openSUSE Forums</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/pre-release-beta/463068-opensuse-12-1-milestone-3-available-download.html">openSUSE 12.1 Milestone 3 available for download</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>
      It was brought to my attention that there was no mentioning this event in the previous openSUSE Weekly News. Well, here it is. Like with the Milestones for the previous releases, we see growing activity in the forums with each new milestone release. Members test, try, use them, they report bugs, all to make openSUSE 12.1 better than any openSUSE before. Read the thread, read about issues, features, follow what's going on on the road to openSUSE 12.1, to be released in November 2011.
    </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
    <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/pre-release-beta/463408-kde-4-7-out.html">KDE 4.7 is out</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>
      A big hand to the KDE developpers for delivering KDE 4.7. Not just some small maintenance update, but lots of new features, furhter integration of applications in the desktop, better interaction between applications. As usual a quite a lot of KDE users want to see what it would mean for them, so they look for updates. The thread provides links to a new KDE:Release:47 repo. At the moment KDE 4.7 has not yet landed in the Tumbleweed repos, the advice to Tumbleweed users is to wait a bit.
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
    <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/install-boot-login/463525-upgraded-32-bit-64-bit-opensuse-11-4-missing-kde-desktop.html">upgraded from 32-bit to 64-bit openSUSE 11.4--missing KDE desktop</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>
      At first glance I would say, that it's normal to run into trouble when doing what this member did: perform a 32bit install from DVD first, then perform a 64bit install on the same root partition afterwards, where, as far as I understood, the 32bit install was not erased, but overwritten. Well, the story has a happy ending, though not easily reached. Like always, attempts to repair have one major requirement: backup anything you want to keep, before even starting to attempt.
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      openSUSE Language specific subforums:
    </title>
    <para>We now host the following language specific subforums under the umbrella of the openSUSE Forums:
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/">Main forums, english</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/ae-ae-chinese/">中文(Chinese)</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/nederlands-dutch/">Nederlands (Dutch)</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/frana-ais-french/">Français (French)</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/deutsch-german/">Deutsch (German)</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/greek/">Ελληνικό (Greek)</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/magyar-hungarian/">Magyar (Hungarian)</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/japanese/">日本語 (Japanese)</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/portuguese/">Portuguese</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/p-russian/">Pусский (Russian)</ulink>
      </para>
<!-- ($ ld: 03.08.2011 gl $) -->  </blockquote>
</sect1>
