<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="updates">
  <title>New/Updated Applications @ openSUSE</title>
  <!--* Gnome
* KDE
* XYZ 

Version should be available at packman or software.opensuse.org/search max. 4 posts. -->
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.wafaa.eu/entry/the-board---packaged-for-your-pleasure-1-50.html">Javier Llorente: Oxygenise your Apache</ulink></title>
    <para>I have updated <ulink url="http://bit.ly/f2eLPJ">apache2-icons-oxygen</ulink> with icons
      from KDE 4.6 RC2. Thanks Nuno &amp; Co! Now Apache’s directory listings look a bit better
      ;-)</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/screenshot-300x205.png"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>See it in action <ulink url="http://www.javierllorente.com/tmp/">here</ulink>. If you want
      to download the tarball/rpm, go to the <ulink url="http://bit.ly/f2eLPJ">Build
      Service</ulink>.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 24.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://packman.links2linux.org/package/vlc/203011">Packman: vlc
        1.1.6-1.pm</ulink></title>
    <para><quote>VLC media player is a highly portable multimedia player for various audio and video
        formats (MPEG-1, MPEG-2, MPEG-4, DivX, mp3, ogg, ...) as well as DVDs, VCDs, and various
        streaming protocols. It can also be used as a server to stream in unicast or multicast in
        IPv4 or IPv6 on a high-bandwidth network.</quote></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 26.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://saigkill.wordpress.com/2011/01/25/newupdated-applications/">Sascha
        Manns: New/Updated Applications</ulink></title>
    <para>The last days i’ve updated or added new Packages:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://shutter-project.org/">shutter</ulink>: new added. Available in:
              <ulink url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/openSUSE:/Factory:/Contrib/openSUSE_11.3/">openSUSE:Factory:Contrib</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://www.calibre-ebook.com/">calibre</ulink>: updated. Available in:
              <ulink url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/home:/thomas-schraitle:/calibre/">home:thomas-schraitle:calibre</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="">bleachbit</ulink>: updated. Available in: <ulink url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/openSUSE:/Factory:/Contrib/openSUSE_11.3/">openSUSE:Factory:Contrib</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>Have a lot of fun with it :-)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 26.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.gnome.org/~michael/blog/2011-01-25-libreoffice-release.html">Michael Meeks: LibreOffice - our first release</ulink></title>
    <para>Today we <ulink url="http://blog.documentfoundation.org/2011/01/25/the-document-foundation-launches-libreoffice-3-3/">released</ulink> our first stable release of LibreOffice. That is really rather exciting !
      and a major milestone. Of course, if you have a GNU/Linux or Unix distribution, most likely
      your packagers already knew our release timetable, and have distribution packages ready for
      you to use. If you can use those, do - they are likely to be better integrated with the
      system, and somewhat faster. </para>
    <para>If you are a Windows or Mac user though, it is a great time to try out LibreOffice,
      directly from our <ulink url="http://www.libreoffice.org/download/">download</ulink> site. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Why LibreOffice ?</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>Apart from all the obvious reasons - of loving Freedom, Free Software, and fun, open,
      community development. LibreOffice is just better, much better, check out our (still
      expanding) <ulink url="http://www.libreoffice.org/download/new-features-and-fixes/">New
        Features</ulink> page - showing off what people can expect to enjoy in LibreOffice. As I get
      time, I'll add some highlights of my own appended here. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">What next ?</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>As we work in a much more conventional Free Software project mold, we are releasing a
        <emphasis role="italic">point-zero</emphasis> release. This will not be perfect, but is any
      software ? what we will be doing is rapidly iterating it, via many minor point releases,
      towards perfection. We've published our <ulink url="http://wiki.documentfoundation.org/ReleasePlan">timeline</ulink> for that. Something
      you don't like ? some hideous translation or crasher bug ? we can include that fix soon, so do
      get stuck in and help out. </para>
    <para>Perhaps the more interesting piece is the commitment to move to a six month release cycle,
      that is well aligned with existing Free Software community and distribution release cycles. We
      hope this will help get the latest, and best LibreOffice into users' hands as quickly as
      possible. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">How do I get involved ? </emphasis></para>
    <para>LibreOffice is a project, almost uniquely suited to scaling to hundreds of people working
      on it - there are problems, missing features and bugs everywhere. There are millions of
      malnourished lines-of-code, awaiting your loving ownership, and remedial care - can you help
      them ? If so, please head to our <ulink url="http://www.libreoffice.org/get-involved/developers/">developer instructions</ulink>
      grab the code from freedesktop's git repository, and get stuck in, we'd love to work with you.
      We have many <ulink url="http://wiki.documentfoundation.org/Development/Easy_Hacks">Easy
        Hacks</ulink> designed for beginners to get involved - ranging from zero programming skill
      required, to some heavier lifting for the elite. As you do that, please do say hello on IRC:
        <emphasis role="italic">#libreoffice</emphasis> on irc.freenode.net, where much of the team
      hangs out. </para>
    <para>Of course, if you want to mirror our binaries - and we are only 11Gb small (compared to
      70Gb+ for OO.o), then drop a mail to <email>mirrors@documentfoundation.org</email>, we use Peter's excellent
        <ulink url="http://mirrorbrain.org/">mirrorbrain</ulink> - we have good coverage, but it can
      always improve. If you just like web banners that point to us there is just such a <ulink url="http://wiki.documentfoundation.org/File:LibreOffice_banner_728x90_L.png">image</ulink>. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Who did this thing ? </emphasis></para>
    <para>Well, in fact many people, far more than I can write down in one place - there are
      extensive credits <ulink url="http://www.libreoffice.org/credits.html">here</ulink> for all of
      the many individuals that have struck their blow for freedom with us; I am incredibly grateful
      for their support and friendship. </para>
    <para>However, of course, some people have put more than the usual effort into this release -
      and here is where I forget people and offend at least someone. For various reasons: new
      packaging, and split help - the Windows build sucked a lot of mental energy this cycle, with
      Fridrich and Tor bearing the brunt of the pain. Similarly, Kendy battled the split help
      indomitably at great length, while managing the Novell team too. Then of course, the Steering
      Committee have put in lots of time with my personal favorite of Italo - creating and massaging
      press text and briefing many. The poor translation team, worked incredibly well under very
      tight deadline pressure to make up for the late strings that routinely needed shoving in, with
      Andras doing fantastic work getting their changes merged. Then finally, the website, its
      infrastructure, mirroring, scripting, design, artwork, and volume of text, polish, translation
      and beauty, as always - done on the very cusp of release swallowed much sweat and tears
      particularly from David, Christian, Florian, Thorsten and Sophie. My profound thanks to all of
      these, and more who worked so hard to get the release out - oh, and especially to the many
      un-sung hackers who got really stuck into triple reviewing, and fixing nasty blocker bugs
      before final code freeze.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 26.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
