<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
<!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! --><!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://labs.qt.nokia.com/2011/10/21/the-qt-project-is-live/">The Qt Project is live!</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>I’m happy to announce that the Qt Project officially went live today. Starting today, development of Qt will be governed as a true open source project.</para>
      <para>We now have <ulink url="http://qt-project.org/">qt-project.org</ulink> – a website where all development of Qt will be centered, providing the same infrastructure and processes for everybody that wants to contribute to Qt. (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> --><!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.socallinuxexpo.org/blog/design-logo-scale-10x-win-trip-la">Design a logo for SCALE 10X, win a trip to LA!</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Want a free trip to SCALE 10X in Los Angeles this January?</emphasis></para>
      <para>In marking 10 years of the Southern California Linux Expo (SCALE) and 20 years of Linux, the SCALE team wants to incorporate an open-source approach to this year’s expo logo designs for publications and for swag. 

With this in mind, the SCALE team announces a contest to select the artwork for use on this year&apos;s t-shirts, attendee bags, and other conference materials.</para>
      <para>The designer of the winning submission will win a free pass to <ulink url="http://www.socallinuxexpo.org/scale10x/">SCALE 10x</ulink>, including airfare within the continental United States, as well as a three-night stay at the <ulink url="http://www.hilton.com/en/hi/groups/personalized/L/LAXAHHH-LNX-20120116/index.jhtml?WT.mc_id=POG%20target=">Hilton Los Angeles Airport</ulink>. (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=MTAxMjI">Phoronix/Michael Larabel: GNOME Shell Works Without GPU Driver Support</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>As reported on Thursday, <ulink url="http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=MTAxMTI">GNOME Shell / Mutter no longer requires OpenGL-accelerated hardware drivers</ulink>. It&apos;s possible to run this GNOME3 desktop with a software back-end via Gallium3D&apos;s <ulink url="http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=search&amp;q=LLVMpipe">LLVMpipe</ulink>.</para>
      <para>Reaching this milestone can be attributed to Red Hat, Google&apos;s Chrome/Chromium OS developers, and others working on the Mesa / Gallium3D software stack. Just recently <ulink url="http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=MTAwNTg">LLVMpipe gained support for GLX_EXT_texture_from_pixmap</ulink>, the GLX extension that&apos;s required by many Linux compositing window managers. These improvements allow the desktop effects to all be done on the CPU without any dependence on any GPU hardware driver. GNOME Shell on the VESA driver or within a KVM/QEMU guest is fair game. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 11.11.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.datamation.com/security/firefox-8-locks-down-plug-ins.html">Datamation/Sean Michael Kerner: Firefox 8 Locks Down Plug-ins</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Mozilla&apos;s rapid release train has pulled into the station on time, with the fifth major Firefox browser release of 2011. Firefox 8 is being released today, providing developers with new capabilities and offering users more security via a new add-ons policy.</para>
      <para>&quot;We&apos;re proud of the way Firefox continues to move the web forward in this release,&quot; Gavin Sharp, Firefox engineer and the Firefox module owner told <emphasis role="italic">InternetNews.com</emphasis>. &quot;Our support for Cross-Origin Resource Sharing (CORS) in WebGL lets developers build incredible 3D experiences on the Web in a secure way.&quot;</para>
      <para>Sharp noted that Firefox 8 also introduces a simpler way for HTML5 applications to provide a right-click menu, to provide a more complete experience. He explained that this release of Firefox introduces better support for Web applications, allowing them to provide context menu options without requiring complicated custom code. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 11.11.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/perlow/exclusive-adobe-ceases-development-on-mobile-browser-flash-refocuses-efforts-on-html5-updated/19226">ZDNet/Jason Perlow: Exclusive: Adobe ceases development on mobile browser Flash, refocuses efforts on HTML5 (UPDATED</ulink>)</title>
      <para>Sources close to Adobe that have been briefed on the company’s future development plans have revealed this forthcoming announcement to ZDNet:</para>
      <para>Our future work with Flash on mobile devices will be focused on enabling Flash developers to package native apps with Adobe AIR for all the major app stores. We will no longer adapt Flash Player for mobile devices to new browser, OS version or device configurations. Some of our source code licensees may opt to continue working on and releasing their own implementations. We will continue to support the current Android and PlayBook configurations with critical bug fixes and security updates.</para>
      <para>Additionally, the e-mail briefing to Adobe’s partners has been summed up as follows:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Adobe is <emphasis role="bold">Stopping development on Flash Player for browsers on mobile</emphasis>.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>(...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 11.11.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.itworld.com/software/221653/4-strange-places-find-open-source">ITworld/Carla Schroder: 4 strange places to find open source</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Open source is about more than code: it&apos;s about unlocking all possibilities. Here are four unusual projects made possible by open source.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Prosthetics</emphasis></para>
      <para>Years ago I hung out with a friend who had a prosthetic hand. It was a stiff plastic hand, like a store mannequin hand, that could open and close in a simple grip. It didn&apos;t have much functionality, but it had a bit of fun factor -- my friend liked to remove it to scratch his back. In public, of course, with a freaked-out audience. Americans seem to have a hard time looking at these sorts of things. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 11.11.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.techdirt.com/articles/20111104/08151716637/free-as-freedom-whose-freedom.shtml">Techdirt/Glyn Moody: Free As In Freedom: But <emphasis role="italic">Whose</emphasis> Freedom?</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>It would be hard to overstate the contribution of <ulink url="http://www.stallman.org/">Richard Stallman</ulink> to the digital world. The founding of the <ulink url="http://www.gnu.org/">GNU project</ulink> and the creation of the <ulink url="http://www.gnu.org/copyleft/gpl.html">GNU General Public License</ulink> laid the foundations for a wide range of free software that permeates computing from smartphones to supercomputers. Free software has also directly inspired like-minded movements based around sharing, such as open access and open content (Wikipedia, notably).</para>
      <para>At the heart of everything Stallman does lies a desire to promote freedom, specifically the freedom of the software user, by constraining the freedom of the developer in the way the code is distributed. That&apos;s in contrast to <ulink url="http://www.linfo.org/bsdlicense.html">BSD-style licenses</ulink>, say, where the developer is free to place additional restrictions on the code, thus reducing the freedom of the user. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 11.11.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="https://www.linux.com/learn/tutorials/507223-what-employers-want-from-linux-job-seekers">Linux.com/Rikki Endsley: What Employers Want from Linux Job Seekers</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Job seekers with Linux smarts have the upper hand in the Linux job market right now, but the right combination of technical and people skills are still required.</para>
      <para>&quot;When we look to hire Linux system administrators, there are a few key aspects that get our attention,&quot; says Peter Baer Galvin, Chief Technologist for Corporate Technologies. &quot;Natural curiosity is one. Is the candidate interested in technology, finding solutions to problems, inventing new solutions, and experimenting? We find those attributes to be a good indicator of whether the admin will be able to improvise, learn, and determine the best course of action.&quot;</para>
      <para>Obviously, no Linux admin can have all the skills every employer will want. But as Galvin says, natural curiosity can help make you stand out as a job candidate. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 11.11.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
<!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.digitaltrends.com/web/spammers-create-and-launch-url-shortening-services-to-hide-links/">Digital Trends/Mike Flacy: Spammers create and launch URL shortening services to hide links</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">While spam continues to be a major problem for email providers and consumers, spammers have come up with a new way to hide links and slip through the spam filters.</emphasis></para>
      <para>According to new information from researchers at Symantec, a group of spammers have created a group of 87 spam-friendly, public URL shortening services and are actively using them to circumvent spam filters on popular sites. Using URL shortening scripts that are free and open source, the spammers are churning spam through the service and the public is also free to create links through the URL shorteners, perhaps an attempt to pass off the links as legitimate. All the URL shorteners are using the .info domain and are being operated through contacts in Moscow as well as a hosting company in the United Kingdom. (...)</para>
   </blockquote>
  </sect2<
  <sect2>
    <title>LOL</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://like-a-boss.org/2011/09/30/hacking-the-imperial-death-march/">like-a-boss.org: hacking the imperial death march</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>One of the great things about the original Star Wars trilogy, was the “lived in”, junky, hacked together aesthetic of the Star Wars universe. Everything was a bit trashed, as if real people actually lived there. Thankfully, that’s one of the things that George Lucas hasn’t tinkered with in his endless quest to ruin the childhood memories of a generation. So it’s heartening to see this tradition carried on with the playing of the imperial death march on miscellaneous hacked together hardware. Enjoy … (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> --></sect1>
