<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
<!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.gnome.org/press/2011/06/karen-sandler-named-new-executive-director-of-the-gnome-foundation/">Karen Sandler Named New Executive Director of the GNOME Foundation</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>June 21, 2011: The GNOME Foundation today announced that it has appointed Karen Sandler as Executive Director. Sandler’s dedication to software freedom, her non-profits experience and her involvement in a wide range of free and open source software communities distinguish her as the logical choice for GNOME. “I’m very excited that Karen is joining the GNOME Foundation as Executive Director!”, says Stormy Peters, former Executive Director who has recently joined the GNOME Board as a new Director, “Karen brings a wealth of experience in free software projects and nonprofits as well as a passion for free software. That experience will be invaluable as GNOME continues to expand its reach with GNOME 3.0 and GNOME technologies.” (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 24.6.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://dot.kde.org/2011/06/20/call-participation-workshops-bofs-desktop-summit-2011">Call for Participation - Workshops &amp; BoFs for the Desktop Summit 2011</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The <ulink url="http://desktopsummit.org/">Desktop Summit 2011</ulink> is a joint conference organized by the GNOME and KDE communities in Berlin, Germany from the 6th August 2011 to the 12th August 2011.</para>
      <para>The organizing team is now inviting applications to hold workshop and Birds of a Feather (BoF) sessions at the Desktop Summit. Read on for more details and how to make a proposal. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 24.6.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/networking/firefox-5-new-but-improved/1196">ZDNet/Steven J. Vaughan-Nichols: Firefox 5: New, but improved?</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>I’ve liked <ulink url="http://www.mozilla.com/en-US/firefox/new">Firefox</ulink> since
        it first showed up. But, this new <ulink url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/hardware/firefox-50-is-live/13398">Firefox 5</ulink>
        concerns me. Oh, it’s a fine browser. But, it’s not a major new release. At most, I’d call
        it Firefox 4.1, but really it’s little more than Firefox 4.02.</para>
      <para>The Mozilla Foundation, following in the footsteps of <ulink url="http://www.google.com/chrome/">Google’s Chrome Web browser</ulink>, seems to believe
        that if they keep popping out new “major” releases every six weeks, they’ll convince people
        they’re better than the competition. That seemed like a dumb idea to me when Microsoft went
        from Word for Windows 2.0 to Word for Windows 6.0 back in 1993. The idea hasn’t improved any
        with age. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 22.6.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxjournal.com/content/xen-enters-mainline-kernel">Linux Journal/Michael Reed: Xen Enters Mainline Kernel</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Future versions of the Linux Kernel (such as 3.0) will include support for the <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Xen">Xen</ulink> hypervisor. This means that Linux distributions will typically offer out of the box support for both hosting Xen and running as a guest operating system under Xen. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 24.6.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.datamation.com/open-source/50-must-have-open-source-apps-for-your-home-office-1.html">Datamation/Cynthia Harvey: 50 Must-Have Open Source Apps for Your Home Office</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>These days, more and more people work at home at least part of the time. According to
        the U.S. Small Business Administration, more than half of the 29.6 million small businesses
        in the country are home-based.</para>
      <para>If you add to those figures the number of people who telecommute to their jobs part of
        the time, the Telework Research Network estimates that between 20 to 30 million people work
        from home at least once a week. And WorldatWork claims that approximately 44 million
        Americans work at home at least one day a year.</para>
      <para>Whether they work for themselves, a small business or a large multinational corporation,
        all of these workers need good software for their home offices. And many of these people who
        work at home don&apos;t have a lot of money to spend on that software -- especially if they work
        for themselves.</para>
      <para>With those workers in mind, we&apos;ve created a list of open source applications that are
        the most helpful for home offices. Unlike many of our other Datamation lists, we&apos;ve kept the
        number of applications in each category small—usually just the one or two top apps in each
        category. Nearly all of this software will run on Windows, and these are some of the most
        mature and user-friendly open source applications available. If you&apos;re reasonably
        tech-savvy, you should be able to set up and use any of these apps.</para>
      <para>Also, recognizing that home office computers get used for more than just work, we&apos;ve
        included a mix of business software, utilities, and &quot;fun&quot; apps for those times when you need
        a break.</para>
      <para>As always, if you&apos;d like to recommend another open source app that we&apos;ve missed, feel
        free to add a comment below. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 22.6.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://fossforce.com/2011/06/libreoffice-vs-openoffice-when-the-ball-bounces-your-way/">FossForce/Christine Hall: LibreOffice vs OpenOffice: When the Ball Bounces Your Way</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Probably the most boring open source story recently has also been the one getting the
        most ink. The problem with with the Apache/OpenOffice saga is that the real story already
        happened, it’s history.</para>
      <para>Oracle’s “gift” of OpenOffice.org to Apache, and the change of license from copyleft to
        permissive, is merely an epilogue referring back to a prologue: Oracle’s sudden ownership of
        the open source office suite as a mere byproduct of their acquisition of Sun. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 22.6.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.theregister.co.uk/2011/06/22/open_source_is_hard/">The Register/Matt Asay: The real reason most source is closed? Open is hard</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Open...and Shut</emphasis> As much as 95 percent of the world&apos;s software is written for internal, enterprise use, rather than by vendors for sale, a point famously<ulink url="http://oreilly.com/catalog/cathbazpaper/chapter/ch05.html"> made by Eric Raymond</ulink> in <emphasis role="italic">The Cathedral and the Bazaar</emphasis>. Much of this software, in turn, has no proprietary value for the enterprises that develop it. So why isn&apos;t the world deluged with enterprise-written open-source software? Why do so many CIOs gladly use open source but <ulink url="http://www.theregister.co.uk/2010/08/13/open_source_numbers/">not contribute to it</ulink>?</para>
      <para>Because open source is hard. Really, really hard. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 24.6.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linux.com/learn/tutorials/460661-the-2011-linux-distro-scorecard">Linux.com/Joe &apos;Zonker&apos; Brockmeier: The 2011 Linux Distro Scorecard</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Picking a Linux distribution isn&apos;t always easy. It&apos;s one of the most common hurdles for new and aspiring Linux users, deciding which distribution is going to be right for them. With so many to choose from, how do you pick the right one? Let&apos;s start with an overview of the major Linux distros, and you&apos;ll be ready to jump in right away.</para>
      <para>You can find <emphasis role="italic">hundreds</emphasis> of Linux distributions, depending on what your needs are. For this scorecard, we&apos;re focusing on desktop distributions that are fairly popular, well-supported, and have a reliable release history, and strong community. In <ulink url="http://www.linux.com/news/enterprise/biz-enterprise/313053-the-spring-2010-linux-distro-scorecard">last year&apos;s scorecard</ulink>, we started with seven distros — this year, we&apos;ve narrowed the field to six distributions:

    </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Debian</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fedora</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Linux Mint</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>openSUSE</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Slackware</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Ubuntu (...)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
<!-- ($ ld: 24.6.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://linuxisit.com/doku.php/blog/2011/06/21/which_free_documentation_license_is_right_for_you">linuxisit.com: Which Free Documentation License is Right for You?</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>When writing documentation for GNU/Linux or any other FOSS project it makes sense to license it under some sort of Free license. Doing so will allow others to redistribute and build on it. But with the plethora of Free Documentation licenses available it can be confusing to choose the right one for you. This article will explain the differences among some of the most common licenses so that you can make the best choice.</para>
      <para>The licenses discussed here can, and often are, used for a variety of different forms of expression, but for the purpose of this article we will only focus on how they apply to the written word. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 24.6.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
<!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://omgsuse.com/content/yet-another-flash-player-security-update">OMG!SUSE! team: Yet another Flash Player security update</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Security Team member <ulink url="http://www.suse.de/~thomas/">Thomas Biege</ulink>
        published an advisory this morning more critical security updates in..you guessed it:
        <emphasis role="bold">flash-player</emphasis>.</para>
      <para>According to the security announcement this package update affects openSUSE 11.3, 11.4
        as well as SUSE Enterprise Linux Desktop 10 SP4 and 11 SP1. This announcement also mentions
        that this is a <emphasis role="bold">remote code execution</emphasis> vulnerability, which
        means not updating to the latest flash-player package will leave you open to attackers
        running programs and exploits on your machine!</para>
      <para>Adobe has posted more <ulink url="http://www.adobe.com/support/security/bulletins/apsb11-12.html">details on this bulletin on their site</ulink> if you&apos;re <emphasis role="italic">that</emphasis>
        interested in the different issues this fix addresses.</para>
      <para>For most users, you&apos;ll just need to follow these steps:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Open up <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/YaST2-GTK">Yast2</ulink><emphasis role="bold">or</emphasis> click on the &quot;Online Update&quot; applet running in your GNOME or
            KDE panels</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Select the flash-player update and install it</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Make sure you restart <emphasis role="bold">
            <emphasis role="italic">all</emphasis>
          </emphasis> of your browsers, this will ensure that no program is
            running the older vulnerable flash-player package</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Relax with a Long Island Ice Tea</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
          </blockquote>
  </sect2> --><!--<sect2>
  <title>LOL</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://xkcd.com/874/">XKCD: Time Management</ulink>
    </title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/time_management.png" width="50%"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.5/">CC-BY-NC</ulink></para>
  </blockquote>
</sect2>--></sect1>
