<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/06/20/1-2-3-cloud/">Robert Schweikert: 1-2-3
        Cloud</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>Towards the end of last year there was an article in openSUSE news “announcing” the cloud
      efforts in the openSUSE project and on OBS. Well, cloud is still all the rage (see Jos’
      contribution to openSUSE News issue 180) and people just cannot stop talking about cloud
      computing.</para>
    <para>Using openSUSE as a host for your cloud infrastructure is also making great progress. We
      have 3 cloud projects in OBS and hopefully these cover your favorite cloud infrastructure
      code, Virtualization:Cloud:Eucalyptus, Virtualization:Cloud:OpenNebula, and
      Virtualization:Cloud:OpenStack. The projects provide repositories for Eucalyptus, OpenNebula,
      and OpenStack, respectively.</para>
    <para>We attempt to make it relatively easy to get a cloud up and running. In this process
      OpenNebula and OpenStack have progressed the most. Eucalyptus is working, but due to an issue
      with Eucalyptus and openSSL 1.0 and later (the version in openSUSE) automation has to wait
      until these issues are resolved.</para>
    <para>For OpenNebula we now have a <ulink url="http://kiwi.berlios.de">KIWI</ulink><ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/SDB:KIWI_Cookbook_ONebula_Cloud">example</ulink> that shows how
      one can get a cloud setup from scratch in less than 2 hours, including the image build. The
      example contains a firstboot workflow for the head node, and self configuration of cloud
      nodes.</para>
    <para>For OpenStack <ulink url="http://susegallery.com/browse">SUSE Gallery</ulink> images are
      in the works and will be published in the near future.</para>
    <para>All repositories provide packages you can install on running openSUSE systems. If you are
      interested in using openSUSE as the underlying OS for your cloud or if you want to contribute
      to the cloud projects, subscribe to the cloud mailing list <ulink
        url="mailto:opensuse-cloud@opensuse.org">opensuse-cloud@opensuse.org</ulink></para>
<!--($ ld: 21.6.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://obsforandroid.wordpress.com/2011/06/21/opensuse-buildservice-101/"
        >Justine Leng: openSUSE buildservice 101</ulink></title>
    <para>One of the reasons that Novell created this community-based openSUSE project was to invite
      contributions from independent developers. It also unveiled a new online service that
      automatically builds binary packages from source code. The openSUSE buildservice initially
      focused on building packages for the SUSE variants — openSUSE, SLES, and SLED — but the tool
      was later extended to support packages for other major distributions, such as Red Hat, Fedora,
      Mandriva, Debian, and Ubuntu. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 22.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
