<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="status-updates">
  <title>Status Updates</title>

  <!--
  <sect2 role="board">
    <title>Board</title>
    <blockquote>
      <para>...</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->

  <sect2 role="distribution">
    <title>Distribution</title>

<!--* interesting topics relating factory (opensuse-factory) (mostly status) * topics from yast/zypp teams (mostly status) * topics from kde/gnome teams (mostly status) As needed. -->

    <blockquote>
      <title></title>
      <para></para>
    </blockquote>
    <!--
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink 
        url="http://www.suse.de/~coolo/opensuse_11.4/"
        >Schedules for the next week</ulink></title>
      <para>...</para>
    </blockquote> -->

    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Important Links</title>

      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://tinyurl.com/392jnb">Detailed Bugzilla
        Report</ulink></para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Submitting_bug_reports">Submitting
        Bug Reports</ulink></para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Bug_reporting_FAQ">Bug Reporting
        FAQ</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>

  <!--
  <sect2 role="susestudio">
    <title>SUSE Studio</title>

    <blockquote>
      <title>Interesting article</title>

      <para>blah laber</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->

  <sect2>
    <title>Team Report</title>

    <sect3 role="artteam">
      <title></title>
      <blockquote>
        <title></title>
        <para></para>
      </blockquote>
    </sect3>

    <!--
    <sect3 role="boosters">
      <title>Boosters Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3> -->

    <sect3 role="buildserviceteam">
      <title>Build Service Team</title>

     <!-- News related to Build Service (mostly status) * meeting minutes As needed. -->

      <blockquote>
        <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/12/06/osc-0-130/">Marcus Hüwe: osc
            0.130</ulink></title>
        <para>We just released a new osc version: 0.130. The main changes/features are:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>– new “revert” command to restore the original working copy file (without
              downloading it)</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>- rewrote “diff” logic</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>- added new “–http-full-debug” option, “–http-debug” filters the “Authentication”
              and “Set-Cookie” header</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>- added new “–disabled-cpio-bulk-download” option: disable downloading packages as
              cpio archive from api</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>- added new “repairwc” command which tries to repair an inconsistent working
              copy</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>- workaround for broken urllib2 in python 2.6.5: wrong credentials lead to an
              infinite recursion</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>- support –interactive-review option when running “osc rq list
              &lt;project>”</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>- improved “osc rq show &lt;id> –interactive-review”</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>- do_config: added new options –stdin, –prompt, –no-echo:<itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>–stdin: read value from stdin</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>–prompt: prompt for a value</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>–no-echo: prompt for a value but don’t echo entered characters (for instance
                    to enter a passwd)</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist></para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>- added template support for a submitrequest accept/decline message</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>- lots of internal rewrites (new working copy handling etc.)</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>- support added for osc search ‘perl(Foo::Bar)’</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>- New “service” command to run source services locally or trigger a re-run on the
              server.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>- setlinkrev is setting now the revision to xsrcmd5 by default to avoid later
              breakage on indirect links by default.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Features which requires OBS 2.1: support reliable diff for an accepted
              request</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>Due to the rewrite of the working copy handling osc might fail with the following
          error: <emphasis role="italic">Your working copy ‘.’ is in an inconsistent state. Please
            run ‘osc repairwc .’ (Note this might _remove_ files from the .osc/ dir). Please check
            the state of the working copy afterwards (via ‘osc status .’)</emphasis></para>
        <para>Simply run “osc repairwc” which might fetch files from the api or delete some files
          from the storedir (.osc/). It won’t touch locally modified files. For more information see
          section “WORKING COPY INCONSISTENT” in the README.</para>
        <para>The new packages should be available soon in the <ulink
            url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/openSUSE:/Tools/">openSUSE:Tools
            repo</ulink>.</para>
        <para>Thanks to everyone who contributed to osc! ($ ld: 10.12.10 sm $)</para>   
      </blockquote>

      <formalpara>
        <title>Build Service Statistics</title>

        <para>Statistics can found at <ulink url="http://build.opensuse.org"
          >Buildservice</ulink></para>
      </formalpara>
    </sect3>

    <!--
    <sect3 role="education">
      <title>Education Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3>

    <sect3 role="forums">
      <title>Forums Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3> -->

    <sect3 role="gnometeam">
      <title>GNOME Team</title>

      <blockquote>
        <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/12/07/indicator-me-has-landed/">Nelson
          Marques: Indicator ME has landed!</ulink></title>
        <para>The first package I pushed to openSUSE was Notify OSD (Canonicals Notification
          Agent/Bubble) with a small patch for extended features (skinning/theming) maintained by Roman
          Sukochev. This patch is popular and wasn’t merged with Notify OSD because it ‘breaks’ the spec
          of Notify OSD that states it shouldn’t be skinnable/themable on Ubuntu. </para>
        <para>Now I’ve packaged a lot of dependencies… cracked and patched GTK with a patch taken from
          Ubuntu, spended hours of mind crushing frustration…. but finally it has landed! The first
          ‘Indicator’ has landed… Often known as “Ubuntu Me Menu”, under openSUSE it will be known as
          ‘indicator-me’.</para>
        <figure id="fig.indicator">
          <title>Indicator ME Screenshot 1</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/Screenshot-1.png" width="75%"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>This screenshot was taken on openSUSE Factory 11.4 Milestone 4. It’s a clean install with
          Sonar and the only tweak is the Faenza-Dark icon theme, which I also packaged and pushed to
          openSUSE:Contrib. <xref linkend="fig.indicator"/></para>
        <para>Top right corner… Indicator ME on openSUSE. It works… I won’t backport it and will only
          maintain it from 11.4 forward. I’m doing this for personal reasons, mainly to become an
          alternative on a localized openSUSE Spin that will be named ‘openSUSE IBERIA’, which was
          already taken into openSUSE-Project by Javier Llorente. </para>
        <para>The main reason to bring this to openSUSE and into IBERIA is tightly related to the fact
          that most people on the Iberian Peninsula use Ubuntu, so we find the best approach possible to
          offer something as close as Ubuntu and hopefully even a better offer when it comes to
          localization. We don’t want to make of openSUSE a ‘clone’ of Ubuntu, instead we want to make
          the openSUSE experience more close to what people already use. </para>
        <para>I’m also going to post a small pic of the same software, this time with Canonical’s
          Radiance Theme, which introduces a small ‘tab’ like visual on the bar. This theme is awesome…
          regardless of what people think of Ubuntu and Canonical… This is the kind of polishing that
          makes Canonical successful, not just the ‘marketing’ many point and even despise.</para>
        <figure id="fig.indicator1">
          <title>Indicator ME Screenshot 2</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/Screenshot-2.png" width="75%"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>Indicator ME as landed… soon others will follow… My plans are to submit this pieces of
          software to GNOME:Apps, and not to push as default, but instead offer them at the distance of
          a ‘zypper in package’ to the openSUSE users out there. And at the same time, since the
          libraries behind it are also packaged… be more attractive to developers who might want to use
          them. I see no loss neither an identity crisis on openSUSE by providing more packages and
          alternative software to improve users Desktop experience… <xref linkend="fig.indicator1"/></para>
        <para>Future work (after indicators):<itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Synapse Launcher;</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Unity (depending on some wild dependencies and some progress in understanding
              cmake).</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
      </blockquote>
      <blockquote>
        <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/12/09/indicator-sessionnetwork/">Nelson
            Marques: indicator-{session,network}</ulink></title>

        <para>I’ve manage to hammer in 2 more indicators. Indicator-session provides a quick and
          easy method to manage your GNOME session. The options are pretty intuitive and it works ok
          so far. A simple screenshot. </para>
        <figure id="fig.gnometeam">
          <title>Screenshot</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/Screenshot.png" width="50%"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
          </figure>
          <para>Then we have also indicator-network which was a bit more problematic to build and required a couple of very ugly quick fixes. Though I’ve built a package for it and it’s dependencies (including The Connection Manager). My concerns about it: <xref linkend="fig.gnometeam"/></para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem><para>It’s a piece of software under heavy development;</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>The user configuration interface is very fuzzy and provides cool clear text passwords for LAN;</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>nm-applet is far superior;</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>Requires ‘connection manager’ – Connection Manager is a pretty cool application, and it’s compat mode with Network Manager makes it’s integration pretty easy… Though ‘connection manager’ seemed to be an outstanding piece of software, I’m not going through all the trouble to package and integrate it in openSUSE (integration should be pretty fast, just a init script, since it allows compat mode with Network Manager).</para></listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
        <para>I personally don’t like this network indicator… Though I’ve packaged it,  I’ve decided not to share it because of 4 points above. I really don’t see anything positive about having it for openSUSE users, it would most likely turn their GNOME experience into something a bit fuzzy.</para>
        <para>Either way… that’s how it looks…</para>
        <figure id="fig.gnometeam2">
          <title>Screenshot 2</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/Screenshot-41.png" width="50%"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para><xref linkend="fig.gnometeam2"/>
        </para>
      </blockquote>
      <blockquote>
        <title><ulink
            url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/12/10/new-indicators-the-saga-continues/">Nelson
            Marques: New Indicators… the saga continues…</ulink></title>
        <para>As the indicator saga continues… some new indicators were built… Indicator-messages is
          a small indicator that pics up messages and stuff from applications to display them on a
          nice all-around indicator. It works fine with evolution (plugin also built and doesn’t
          require patching for what I’ve seen). </para>
        <para>This indicator support more applications, though they require some patching. As being
          discussed on the opensuse-GNOME mailing list as as proposed by Vincent Untz, this
          indicators are moving to GNOME:Apps and there _might_ an effort to support some features
          in applications like empathy. Keep in mind this is not a priority, but if it’s possible to
          support some more feature, it might happen.</para>
        <figure id="fig.gnomeindicator">
          <title>Screenshot</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/Screenshot-21.png" width="50%"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>Additionally<xref linkend="fig.gnomeindicator"/>, I’ve also tried some other indicators… indicator-application for what I
          can tell is an indicator that removes the menu’s from the GTK applications and places them
          on the panel (MAC style). I’ve built this indicator, but I have no means to test yet
          because further patching is required at least in GTK and eventually on glib. I don’t think
          there’s actually any need to have this indicator, specially when it will bring additional
          efforts on GTK maintenance, and this feature is somehow supported by software like
          gnome-globalmenu (which I’ve also packaged for myself and works dearly with supported
          apps). </para>
        <para>I’ve done some hammering on indicator-sound as well… Ubuntu’s sound widget… I’m stuck
          with some error and I have 2 possibilities… downgrade to the last version of the previous
          branch which should built, or work the current branch (more dependency demanding). I’m
          working on it… it will happen one way or another during the next days. I guess this one is
          actually one of the most wanted :) </para>
        <para>There are few other indicators… for time and date, calendar and so on… Those will be
          last ones. After indicator-sound is done, I’m starting to clean up the packaging and make
          sure it’s compliant to the GNOME team methodology and submit them to GNOME:Apps and the
          support libraries that are required as dependencies forwarded to projects where they might
          be useful (need to check out with the people which ones those will be). </para>
        <para>A special thanks to Ken Vandine from Canonical for some guidance with libindicate. </para>
        <para>I’ve seen around some ‘hate’ waves towards Canonical, and I would like to say that so
          far in the few times I’ve interacted with them, either on bug submission or asking help,
          they have been awesome and caring. It’s really something I would like to point… they are
          pretty cool, and their devs are very helpful (but hey… so are our devs ;) ). Also a very
          special thanks to Vincent Untz, Dimstar and mrdocs which have been a great help and from
          whom I’ve learned already a lot.</para>
        <para>So picking up the useful stuff… and placing it up together in a single Indicator:</para>
        <figure id="fig.gnomeindicator2">
          <title>Screenshot 2</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/Screenshot-11.png" width="50%"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para><xref linkend="fig.gnomeindicator2"/> ($ ld: 10.12.10 sm $)</para>
      </blockquote>     
    </sect3>

    <sect3 role="kdeteam">
      <title>KDE Team</title>

      <blockquote>
        <title></title>

        <para></para>
      </blockquote>
    </sect3>

    <!--
    <sect3 role="marketingteam">
      <title>Marketing Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3>

    <sect3 role="medical">
      <title>Medical Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3>

    <sect3 role="monoteam">
      <title>Mono Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3> -->

    <sect3 role="openfateteam">
      <title>openFATE Team</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem><para><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310883">#310883: File Integrity GUI/Nautilus/GOME/Right click</ulink></para></listitem>
        <listitem><para><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310885">#310885: Use flash-player square for x64 instead of 10.1</ulink></para></listitem>
        <listitem><para><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310887">#310887: buil gimp in openoffice</ulink></para></listitem>
        <listitem><para><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310889">#310889: YaST UI Two modes for the control center panels</ulink></para></listitem>
        <listitem><para><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310891">#310891: ease amazing presentation</ulink></para></listitem>
        <listitem><para><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310896">#310896: Consistent Network device naming-Name network interfaces to
          match chassis labels</ulink></para></listitem>
        <listitem><para><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310899">#310899: Bring back yast2-repair (or alternative)</ulink></para></listitem>
        <listitem><para><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310904">#310904: Include Mesa 7.10</ulink></para></listitem>
        <listitem><para><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310905">#310905: Make Konqueror Default File Manager</ulink></para></listitem>
        <listitem><para><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310909">#310909: Bibliography management system</ulink></para></listitem>
        <listitem><para><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310911">#310911: Use RPM 5 for opensuse 11.4</ulink></para></listitem>
        <listitem><para><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310912">#310912: Please, include Kile</ulink></para></listitem>
        <listitem><para><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310913">#310913: Add YAST module to set up multiseat installations</ulink></para></listitem>
        <listitem><para><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310920">#310920: The ~200 Line Linux Kernel Patch That Does Wonders for opensuse
          11.4</ulink></para></listitem>
        <listitem><para><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310922">#310922: central system user registry</ulink></para></listitem>
        <listitem><para><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310923">#310923: Update tv-card list in Yast Module</ulink></para></listitem>
        <listitem><para><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310929">#310929: include blender 2.5 in opensuse 11.4</ulink></para></listitem>
        <listitem><para><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310930">#310930: Split samba-server.desktop into two desktop files</ulink></para></listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Feature Statistics</emphasis></para>

        <listitem>
          <para>Statistics for openSUSE 11.4 <ulink
          url="https://features.opensuse.org/statistic/product/22236">in
          openFATE</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </sect3>
    
    <!--
    <sect3 role="oooteam">
      <title>OpenOffice Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3>

    <sect3 role="testing">
      <title>Testing Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3> -->

    <sect3 role="translationteam">
      <title>Translation Team</title>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Daily updated translation statistics are available on the
          <ulink url="http://i18n.opensuse.org/">openSUSE Localization
          Portal</ulink>.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><ulink
          url="http://i18n.opensuse.org/stats/trunk/toplist.php">Trunk
          Top-List</ulink> – <ulink
          url="http://en.opensuse.org/OpenSUSE_Localization_Guide">Localization
          Guide</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </sect3>
    
    <!--
    <sect3 role="wiki">
      <title>Wiki Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3>

    <sect3 role="yast">
      <title>YaST Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3> -->
  </sect2>
</sect1>
