<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://mschlander.wordpress.com/2011/03/12/opensuse-11-4-has-been-released/"
        >OMG! SUSE!/rtyler: On release day, it is like a big dump truck</ulink></title>
    <para>Shortly after the initial release of openSUSE 11.4, I posted some <ulink
        url="http://omgsuse.com/content/rapidly-downloading-opensuse-114-bittorrent">giant
        BitTorrent links</ulink> to speed up your downloading of openSUSE. Now that the initial
      flood of downloads has come and gone, I wanted to report back with some statistics shared by
      openSUSE Contributor <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2008/03/01/people-of-opensuse-marcus-rueckert/">Marcus
        Rueckert</ulink>.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Note</emphasis></emphasis>: These numbers
      are for BitTorrent downloads only.</para>
    <para>As of last Thursday (March 17th), the numbers broke down as follows:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Full DVD images downloaded: <emphasis role="bold">8228</emphasis></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Live CD images downloaded: <emphasis role="bold">4009</emphasis></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>If you're not terrifically familiar with the way that BitTorrent works, all users are
      constantly sharing data with one another but users fall into two buckets:
        <quote>leechers</quote> and <quote>seeders</quote>. The <quote>leechers</quote> are users
      who don't <emphasis role="italic">yet</emphasis> have the complete file, while the
        <quote>seeders</quote> have fully completed their download and are <emphasis role="bold"
        >only</emphasis> uploading to the other users. In short, having a lot of seeders means you
      have a good healthy torrent and downloads for new folks will be <emphasis role="italic"
        >fast</emphasis>.</para>
    <para>As of last Thursday, both the 32-bit and the 64-bit DVD images had over <emphasis
        role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">one thousand seeders</emphasis></emphasis>, 20% more
      seeders than leechers too! That is incredibly awesome!</para>
    <para>Marcus went on to say:</para>
    <para><quote>I tested on friday morning and peaked at 11.2MB/s download speed for torrent which
        is almost max speed of my line.</quote></para>
    <para>This means if you download the DVD image <emphasis role="italic">right now</emphasis>, you
      are likely going download openSUSE as fast as technically possible!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">CC-BY-SA</ulink></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 21.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/03/13/opensuse-11-4-how-it-goes-in-portugal/">Nelson Marques: openSUSE 11.4 :: How it goes in Portugal ?!</ulink></title>
    <para>I’ve been following the biggest general technology forum in Portugal with a close eye for
      openSUSE 11.4 comments and reviews… 10 years ago SuSE Linux was one of the predominant Linux
      distributions fighting for first place with Red Hat and followed closely by Debian. The fourth
      place belonged to Slackware.</para>
    <para>10 years after… Slackware mainly disappeared, the Red Hat/Fedora community somehow
      vanished (judging by LUG member strength), and fate hasn’t been nicer for openSUSE. From most
      of what I read, Ubuntu became the major power, followed by Arch Linux and Debian… there’s a
      few pockets of resistance by Mandriva… It’s also interesting to see that new users are mainly
      confused between choosing Fedora and openSUSE… this relation is also getting strong with drop
      outs from Ubuntu. The timing is good for intervention…</para>
    <para>From what I could see in the reports of openSUSE reviews I’ve seen:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Installer – Users expected something new, but they didn’t disclaimed what they
            expected. They say that openSUSE installer is pretty much offering the same features as
            other distributions. I really don’t know what can be innovated here….</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Updates – This is one of the points that is most commented in the reviews. Though
            there’s no real claims on what could be improved or what is missing, everyone points to
            a simple conclusion: people seem to like updates and the faster they are done, the
            better. Update timings seem important.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Tumbleweed – There are a lot of expectations towards rolling releases and
            Tumbleweed. This feature seems to captivate a lot of veterans changing from other
            distributions and also new comers. This is without doubt one of the points to invest in
            the future for the local community…</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Time of Installation – Some harsh critics on the installation time. People believe
            that 30 minutes is too much of installation time. I kinda disagree as it seems pretty
            much normal for a DVD install. Installing openSUSE LiveCD’s on real hardware (no
            virtualization) through USB2 and USB3 sticks, is pretty much bellow 10 minutes. Should
            we focus on USB sticks installations and work the methodology? Sounds good as a
            differentiation point.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>USB Sticks – Some harsh critics with people using imagewritter and unetbootin. For
            what I was able to determine, this problems seem to be related with the partitions not
            being flagged as ‘active’. Something we can improve here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>KDE – All the reports seem to place openSUSE as the best KDE offer. Nothing was
            expected besides this.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>OpenSUSE and other distros – Not much has been written, except some comments
            considering that Mandriva Spring was the only distribution that is more attractive than
            openSUSE 11.4. Only 2 comments place emphasis on this… Something we can improve on this
            field ?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Support – Support on those forums is rudimentary… Something we can improve and
            that’s being worked on. Soon Portuguese will become available on the official openSUSE
            Forums and a Portuguese Team as been assembled for this. Additionally Jim Henderson is
            contacting Carlos Ribeiro to explore the possibility of having also Brazilian
            contributors and community to help on this Forums. They will become Portuguese (language
            wise) following the work by the Wiki and IRC.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>The feedback is very positive, and there’s an abnormal dropouts from Ubuntu and many
      confused people…. The timing is perfect for taking action… and that will happen soon! </para>
    <para><emphasis role="italic">License: GFDL V1.2</emphasis></para>
    <!--($ ld: 14.3.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://blog.cornelius-schumacher.de/2011/03/its-not-address-book.html">Cornelius Schumacher: It's not an address book</ulink></title>
    <para>It began about <ulink url="http://markmail.org/message/7ef64iba64mjoy4a">ten years
        ago</ulink>, when I <ulink url="http://markmail.org/message/cyt6drrtjjem2xti">rewrote the
        KDE address book library</ulink>. I implemented a nice API, vCard parsing, and a
      representation of something I called an Addressee back then, a contact, the data belonging to
      a person or any other entity, closely modelled after the fields of vCard, which is a fine
      standard for storing and exchanging address book data.</para>
    <para>We wrote <ulink url="http://userbase.kde.org/KAddressBook_4.3">KAddressBook</ulink> as an
      application to manage contact data on top of the address book library, and while it's a nice
      and useful application, in some ways it still follows to some degree the technical thinking
      coming from the structure of the underlying implementation. This shows in the user interface,
      and makes it less useful, attractive, and intuitive as it could be.</para>
    <para>So I thought it would be a good idea to experiment a bit and approach the task of handling
      people data from the other direction. Ignoring technical aspects of the implementation, or
      constraints of underlying technology, but thinking from a user's point of view, thinking about
      what's a natural way how to deal with this kind of data. I started to think and code a bit,
      and during <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Hackweek">Hackweek 6</ulink> I went on
      and got the application I started to a level where I think it's time now to share it and
      gather some more feedback.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://en.opensuse.org/images/8/8e/Hackweek6Logo.png" width="20%"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>But before I come to the application itself, here is some of the motives and concepts
      behind it.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Mental model of people</emphasis></para>
    <para>The first thing I did was trying to come up with an idea of what the mental model is how
      people think about people. The way address books usually present this data is practical in
      some ways, but when you think about other people, do you have an alphabetically ordered list
      of names in your mind? Probably not. So I collected a list of concepts, which better address
      the mental model of people.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Groups</emphasis>. People usually belong to some groups. There are
      colleagues, friends, familiy, the weird group of hackers you hang around with on IRC. These
      groups are often used to classify people, and provide a pretty solid way to structure how you
      organize people, the KDE guy you met at last year's Akademy, the colleague who used to study
      with you at university. People often belong to multiple groups, and sometimes there is no
      clear mapping.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Pictures</emphasis>. When thinking of people you usually have some
      kind of picture in mind. You would recognize most persons you know on a photo without effort.
      Pictures are widely used to identify people, and pictures of people, especially of people you
      have a closer relation with are easily available from various sources now.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Fuzzy information</emphasis>. In many cases the information you have
      about other people is somewhat fuzzy. You might not know the exact address, just a city. You
      might only know a nickname, or the date of the birthday, but not the year, or you might have
      trouble assigning the parts of a foreign name to the fields of a technical address book. Is it
      a middle name or is it part of the given name? Is this the surname, or maybe a suffix? While
      it's nice from a technical view, to have this exact classification of fields of a record, in
      practice and from a human point of view, it often just is neither possible nor important.
      Humans deal with fuzzy information pretty well, especially when dealing with other people. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Time</emphasis>. An important factor to classify information is
      time. You remember that you met a person at a certain time. When having multiple phone numbers
      available, the time, when you got them, will give an important hint about which one is more
      likely to work. In general, knowing when something changes, helps a lot with navigating
      information.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Space</emphasis>. Another important factor is space. You think of
      people being close to each other, either physical, as in neighbors, or in a logical way, as in
      family. A family tree is a great example how space is used to organize and structure people.
      There are also numerous other ways how to relate people in a spacial configuration. How they
      appear on a photo, a seating order for a celebration, and many more.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">It's not paper</emphasis></para>
    <para>In addition to coming up with a way how to meet the mental model of how people think about
      people, I also wanted to take benefit of having available the power of managing the data on a
      computer. There are many address book applications which resemble paper address books, going
      as far as mimicking the texture of the leather cover. But being able to manage the data
      electronically without the restrictions of paper, leather, and spiral binders, gives some
      unique freedom and potential in a couple of areas.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Ubiquity</emphasis>. As it's so easy to store, transmit, and
      distribute data electronically, data can be ubiquitous, it can be available at work as well as
      at home, or when being on the road, on your laptop, phone, tablet. It can live in the cloud,
      easily accessible from everywhere.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">History</emphasis>. Without the restrictions of paper, there is no
      reason to ever delete data. You can keep an unlimited history, which gives you the safety to
      always being able to go back, if you have changed something you later realize you didn't want
      to change, or if a need to access old data arises. This all can be done in a way, which hides
      old data from the current view, to not clutter the most recent view you normally use.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Low-cost editing</emphasis>. With electronic data, the cost of
      editing, rearranging, duplicating, and deleting data is very low. You can easily duplicate a
      set of entries about people to do some rearrangements, and then delete it again after a few
      minutes without loosing anything. No striked through entries, no wasted pieces of paper, no
      mess of failed attempts to get something done. This provides the opportunity for ad-hoc
      editing, especially if combined with some kind of history.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Connect to the cloud</emphasis>. A ton of personal data lives in the
      cloud, on various web sites, in structured and not so structured ways. With Facebook, Google,
      Linkedin, your corporate directory server, the data on your private mail account and much
      more, you have access to a lot of data from the people you usually deal with. By putting an
      application at the right place, you can connect all this to represent your personal social
      network.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Unconstrained user interface</emphasis></para>
    <para>Finally I wanted to go beyond the standard user interface of current address book
      applications. There is much value in standardized interfaces, taking into account style
      guides, using standard components, and all the other good stuff of working in a nicely
      defined, consistent, and integrated environment. But I wanted to experiment with leaving this
      behind and trying some non-standard concepts.</para>
    <para>So I decided to not care much about standard widgets, to get rid of everything, which was
      non-essential to the actual application, to use animations gratiously to make the interface
      dynamic and support the user in understanding transitions. I also decided to try a new kind of
      menu, which isn't seen much on desktop applications, but could give more direct access to the
      actions the user needs. Finally I also decided to create a UI, which is not limited to a
      specific form factor, but can deal with a variety of devices, not only classical desktops, but
      also stuff like tablets, or maybe even phones.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Polka</emphasis></para>
    <para>Now that you know where I came from let me introduce you to my experiment. I call it
      Polka. It's an application for dealing with people data based on the concepts I described,
      thinking from a user's point of view, matching the mental model of how we think about people,
      and not caring too much about the current status quo in terms of address book applications. I
      summarized that in the FATE entry for my hackweek project, where I called it the <ulink
        url="https://features.opensuse.org/311143">humane address book for the cloud</ulink>. The
      title came from the idea to approach an address book not from the technical point of view, but
      from what is relevant for human users, and to tie it to all the data and functionality which
      is available in the cloud.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-xeFtKuDablU/TX15k4HbdcI/AAAAAAAAAKU/7lus4acD60g/s320/polka_start.png"
          width="30%"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>I started to think about this quite some time ago, and did write some code here and there,
      but during last hackweek I made the effort to actually put it all together and polish it so
      that it hopefully adequately illustrates the concepts I wanted to experiment with.</para>
    <para>Let me explain some of the main elements of Polka.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Group view </emphasis></para>
    <para>The central part of Polka is the group view. It shows a group of people and possibly some
      sub groups. The display is based on people's pictures and makes use of the view as a kind of
      canvas, where the members of the groups can freely be arranged. Names are shown for entries
      where no picture is set, and they are shown for all entries, when hovering over with the mouse
      pointer, so it's easy to identify people.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-Eqc4BFJcCII/TX15gWlVtUI/AAAAAAAAAKE/D51MxeWvnw4/s320/polka_group.png"
        />
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>By default all people are shown in a compact regular arrangement, but you can simply move
      all entries around to create a different arrangement. The next screenshot shows an example.
      It's the group of people, who attended the <ulink
        url="http://community.kde.org/KDE_PIM/Meetings/Osnabrueck_8">Osnabrück 8 meeting</ulink>.
      The arrangement reflects where people were on the <ulink
        url="http://community.kde.org/File:KDEPIM_Meetings_Osnabrueck8_group.jpg">group
        photo</ulink>. </para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-jPlKm7h6dew/TX15iHRxVLI/AAAAAAAAAKI/Xfh7gyKzxJM/s320/polka_group_menu.png"
        />
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>That's just one application for arranging people freely. You could also reflect breakout
      groups, seating orders, a family tree, or any other relations between people. The basic idea
      is that you use space to naturally reflect how you are thinking of people. People can be added
      to as many groups as needed, and any group can contain other groups with the same or different
      people. The arrangement of people is specific to the view of the group, but the entries of
      people are always the same, they are just links, so a person can appear in multiple groups,
      but the data is only there once.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Menus</emphasis></para>
    <para>For menus and getting access to actions in general I wanted to experiment with something
      different than the classical menu bars and context menus, and see if I could find a way to
      make it more natural and direct to work with the elements shown in the user interface. So I
      got rid of all traditional menus, no menu bar, no status bar, no right clicks.</para>
    <para>In the previous screen shot you can see how you get access to actions for a person. If you
      hover over a person, there is shown a fan-like menu, where you can select some person-related
      options. For general options there is the "main" menu disk at the top right, which also shows
      actions on hover. You can also click on the canvas to get options which are related to a
      certain location like adding a label.</para>
    <para>This all is pretty simple, and you don't even have to be very exact, when hitting a menu,
      so it probably would also work with a touch screen, although I didn't try it, so take this
      with a grain of salt.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Person view</emphasis></para>
    <para>When you click on the "show" menu item, a detailed view of the person is shown. It
      includes all the data you store about this person. This is the usual contact information, but
      most of it is stored in a relatively free form. You don't have to identify components of the
      name or the address for example. They are just text fields. You can also easily add free form
      text by adding comments to every field of the person's data. The speech bubble indicates where
      a comment is there, and you can add general comments to the person's entry. All this helps
      dealing with the fuzziness which data about people often has.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-1ahv7j2sCqs/TX15kUMo4PI/AAAAAAAAAKQ/Lr4GH9CfxSE/s320/polka_person.png"
        />
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>When you hover over a data field, some editor controls are shown to comment, edit or
      remove the field, and the information is shown when the fields was modified the last time.
      This way you can judge, which fields are relevant, and which ones might be outdated, and it
      also can help with putting the entry in the perspective of time, they might be related to
      something which happened at a certain time you remember.</para>
    <para>An important element are the pictures of the person. Polka collects pictures from
      different sources on the web, e.g. from your Twitter profile, and you can easily add more
      pictures by using a built in screenshot function. So if you see a picture of a person on a web
      site, in your mail client or any other place, you can just capture it directly from the
      display without having to deal with saving image files or getting URLs.</para>
    <para>What the screenshots don't show is how the views transition. It's all done dynamically
      with animations converting between views of different groups or when the details of a person
      are shown. This makes it easier to keep track of what belongs where, and also is fun, because
      it looks and feels nice and smooth.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">History</emphasis></para>
    <para>Polka takes care of saving data in the background. The user doesn't need to know or think
      of that at all. All changes are saved and the complete history of changes is preserved, so
      data is never lost, and there is no need for confirmation dialogs or anything like
      that.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-Nw0nP12fSiY/TX15jK8xDeI/AAAAAAAAAKM/pZrOvHpuDGY/s320/polka_history.png"
        />
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>The data can also be shared via a server, including the full history. So all your people's
      data is always available and shown in the same way, no matter where you are.</para>
    <para>Storing the history also makes it possible to have unlimited undo, even across different
      computers. But I haven't implemented any user interface for that yet.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Technology</emphasis></para>
    <para>So much about what Polka does and how the user interface looks and behaves. Although the
      implementation is not that important, it is working code, so some technical details might
      still be interesting.</para>
    <para>The data is stored in an application-specific XML format, including all the meta data like
      comments, when something changed, the position of objects in the views. So everything is in
      one place and can easily be versioned and shared. The interface to the XML is generated via
        <ulink url="https://github.com/cornelius/kode/tree/master/kxml_compiler"
        >kxml_compiler</ulink> from an example XML file. So there is a native API to access the data
      without having to maintain the code to read and write the XML and represent it in C++
      objects.</para>
    <para>To store history and for sharing the data across machines, everything is stored in a git
      repository. Every change is recorded, so the full history is available in the git history. Git
      is amazing as a storage backend. As it's so fast, it's not really noticable that storing data
      is more than just writing a file, and by using git's distributed nature, sharing the data and
      its history with a server and across different machines comes almost for free.</para>
    <para>The UI is implement with QGraphicsView and the Qt animation framework. I thought about
      using QML, but as C++ is my native language, using QGraphicsView directly seemed like the more
      straight-forward way to me. The implementation separates models handling the data and the
      views reasonable well, though, so adding a QML based view should be possible without too much
      hassle.</para>
    <para>For the person's view I use Webkit. The data is rendered as HTML and CSS and shown in
      Webkit. This gives some more flexibility and power than a widgets or QGraphicsView based view,
      and also opens a path towards the web. I tried again to write a small library to make it
      convenient to generate HTML and CSS. It's better than some of Spaghetti code I wrote in the
      past for this purpose, but it still doesn't match the elegange of for example some of the Ruby
      based solutions for this. It's a pretty tough problem in C++.</para>
    <para>Other than that it's a pretty much standard KDE application. It doesn't make too much use
      of the platform, though, as I consciously didn't use many of the standard UI elements. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Code</emphasis></para>
    <para>The code for Polka is available at <ulink
        url="http://quickgit.kde.org/?p=scratch/cschumac/polka.git"
        >git://anongit.kde.org/scratch/cschumac/polka.git</ulink>. It's still experimental, so use
      with care, although by the use of git as a storage backend your data is pretty safe. </para>
    <para>I don't have specific plans for making a release or making it a more official part of KDE
      right now, but will continue to use it as a playground for trying out concepts and maybe
      provide some inspiration for other projects.</para>
    <para>I am interested in feedback and comments. So don't hesitate to <ulink
        url="mailto:schumacher@kde.org">contact me</ulink>, if you have questions, ideas, comments,
      or suggestions.</para>
    <para>So I'm at the end with this blog post, and while it is a very long post, there is still a
      lot to tell. For now I'll let the code speak, and maybe I'll blog again later to discuss some
      more details about specific aspects of Polka. </para>
    <!--($ ld: 14.3.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://omgsuse.com/content/sharing-opensuse-world-mirrorbrain">OMG! SUSE!/rtyler: Sharing openSUSE with the world, via MirrorBrain</ulink></title>
    <para>Some of our readers might not know this, but the release of openSUSE 11.4 is actually the
        <emphasis role="bold">second</emphasis> release that OMG! SUSE! has had the opportunity to
      cover, the first one being <ulink url="http://omgsuse.com/content/meet-opensuse-113">openSUSE
        11.3</ulink>. </para>
    <para>Shortly after the 11.3 release, I reached out to some of the folks responsible for
      coordinating the distribution of <emphasis role="bold">terabytes</emphasis> of openSUSE on
      release day. I managed to interview <ulink url="http://poeml.de/">Peter Pöml</ulink> one of
      the creators of MirrorBrain, the brain (weak-pun intended) behind distributing some of the
      biggest projects on the internet, including <ulink url="http://opensuse.org/"
      >openSUSE</ulink>.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://pixelpressicons.com/MinersHelmet.jpg" align="right" width="10%"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>At a high level, MirrorBrain allows a central server such as <ulink
        url="http://download.opensuse.org/">download.opensuse.org</ulink> utilize a vast network of
      "mirrors" for distributing enormous amounts of data in such a way that users are downloading
      from a mirror that's "close" to them. For example, if you're in the UK, MirrorBrain will try
      to bounce you to a UK mirror, failing that a european mirror, and so on.</para>
    <para>Enough with the formalities, put on your Miner's cap and let's dig into the
      interview.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="bold">OMG! SUSE!</emphasis>: The openSUSE project
        uses a tool called MirrorBrain, which (correct me if I'm wrong) tries to automatically
        redirect users to their closest mirror based on a geographic lookup of their IP address.
        When did openSUSE start using MirrorBrain and what motivated the switch?</emphasis></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Peter</emphasis>: By the end of 2006, a new openSUSE release (10.0
      maybe?) was just being issued. There were serious problems with stability of the download
      server during the "peak". At the time, I joined a new team to work on the openSUSE Build
      Service. That team used the same download server to publish their work, so I came into contact
      with this part of the infrastructure. As Apache guru, the server crashes were seriously
      irritating me and it was clear to me that something should be done about them. Thus, I started
      working on a solution and made it my obsession for the next three years. The Build Service
      team kind of had to do without me. However, the Build Service benefitted most from my work,
      more than anything else. See below :-)</para>
    <para>You probably realize, as I did at the time, the utter importance of the download system,
      because a working download is the life blood of openSUSE; its aorta, so to speak. (Users take
      this for granted, of course.) </para>
    <para>If you think about delivering openSUSE, you might first thing about CD and DVD images.
      However, that's only a part. And it is the part that's not difficult to deal with. The images
      account for about 3 requests per second (peak), which is easily to deal with with a simple
      Perl script that you can hack up in half an hour. That's what other projects do successfully.
      openSUSE also had such a script, but it had some performance issues. </para>
    <para>The real challenge was that we redirect more than ISO images. We have to handle requests on:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>updates</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>network installs</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>packages built by the build service</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>When the build service was presented, it quickly became popular, and we soon realized that
      we need a powerful content delivery for all those things. </para>
    <para>Therefore, we are talking about 300-500 requests per second to be handled and redirected.
      That made a good design necessary. In the beginning, a handful of people at SUSE gathered to
      think about the needed feature and the design, but with one early exception I'm the only one
      who ever worked on it. </para>
    <para>If it weren't for the build service, it would have been easy to do the following:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>redirect requests for ISO images via a little Perl script</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>distribute updates by giving the clients lists of mirror URLs and let them pick a
            mirror, just like Fedora does with yum.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>The build service however could not be handled by either of this methods. Since it pushes
      out new packages at an extremely high pace (more than <emphasis role="bold">once a
        minute</emphasis>). There is simply no time for mirrors to synchronize and for the mirror
      system to stabilize. They'll always lag and be out-of-date by definition.</para>
    <para>That's the reason for the design of MirrorBrain. It runs all client requests through a
      single system (also because we wanted to be able to be in a position to count things), and it
      keeps track of the mirrors contents and does that for ISO images, updates and buildservice
      packages alike. </para>
    <para>The openSUSE build service would impossibly have succeeded without MirrorBrain. It can't
      work without it.</para>
    <para>But the DVD and CD images' distribution is a bagatelle, from the perspective of
      MirrorBrain. Those 3 req/s don't surface in the graph of a server that constantly gets 300
      req/s. They certainly don't cause any noticeable load. And finally, all the hard work is done
      by the mirrors! Their bandwidth, hardware and manpower which they contribute is what makes
      openSUSE whir. </para>
    <para>You'd have to look very, very hard at <ulink
        url="http://download.opensuse.org/apachestats/">openSUSE's apache stats</ulink> to see any
      effect of the recent release on openSUSE's infrastructure.</para>
    <para>For the mirrors however, the release causes a very noticeable peak, since the files are
      huge (while the request is tiny, which is all that MirrorBrain has to handle). I worked hard
      to collect as many mirrors as possible, over three years, so that openSUSE enjoys the help of
      about 150 mirrors at this time. This number seems to do the demand justice, and there hasn't
      been a shortness of bandwidth since a long time - the US being an exception, where we had only
      a few mirrors sometimes and openSUSE wasn't popular enough to find more. </para>
    <para>Finding mirrors and keeping them working correctly means to communicate with mirror admins
      and to carefully listen to users. One has to have "big ears" to get hold of problems that
      surface for users. Of all the problems that occur, only a very tiny fraction is reported in
      public forums, or even directly to us. Thus, if one happens to hear about some problem it
      usually affects many people, and has to be taken very seriously. </para>
    <para>Another design goal of MirrorBrain was reusability and modularity, because an in-house
      solution didn't seem to have the chance to grow enough. So MirrorBrain is open source and
      freely available to other projects, and attempts to suit them as well. OpenOffice.org and the
      Free Software Foundation use MirrorBrain, and Sourceforge uses components of it. The users
      that I know of are <ulink url="http://mirrorbrain.org/users/">collected here</ulink>.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="bold">OMG! SUSE!</emphasis>: Does MirrorBrain
        incorporate any "health" or speed metrics to try to determine if a mirror is slowing down?
        Could you tell us a bit about how MirrorBrain determines what the "best" mirror for me
        is?</emphasis></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Peter</emphasis>: Every mirror is checked once a minute with a
      simple request that it has to answer within 20s. The time seems generous, but has to take into
      account that many mirrors are far away, on the other end of the world so to speak, it can take
      that long to talk to them.</para>
    <para>In addition, when assessing mirrors content we do some trickery to make sure that the
      mirror is 100% capable of delivering large files (>2G, >4G) correctly and supporting partial
      transfers (to complete a previously aborted transfer). </para>
    <para>Since mirrors often are older systems, there are still about 30% among them that don't do
      this correctly. </para>
    <para>Further health metrics havn't proven necessary. We had a lot of ideas initially, but
      either they were to difficult to put into practice or not so much needed in reality, as
      real-world experience showed. </para>
    <para>For the distribution of ISO images, it would be quite useful to survey mirrors more
      closely and monitor their "performance", because:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>A user is directly involved and sitting in front of his computer.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Web browsers don't do error checking on downloads</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Due to the size of the files, a drop in performance can easily catapult the download
            time from an hour to 3 days.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>This is where torrents come into play, because (at least for some savvy users) they
      improve on this. Even though distribution via torrents is not known for the good speed that
      you can reach when downloading from fast mirrors. </para>
    <para>There's a lot that could be done in regard to monitoring, and I'd love to see
      contributions. </para>
    <para>Regarding other files (not ISOs), we have pursued a different approach. We have large
      control over the download client that is used to download packages and updates, and we have
      made the client robust to deal with slow or broken mirrors. MirrorBrain is not only a
      redirector, but also a Metalink generator. Metalinks contain all the information that is
      needed to find packages on mirrors and make sure they are 100% intact. MirrorBrain serves
      Metalinks to zypper and YaST, so they can download packages in parallel from multiple mirrors
      at the same time, do error correction and automatically deal with most mirror problems that
      way. </para>
    <para>This method could also used for ISO images (see: <ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2008/12/16/best-way-to-download-opensuse/">Best way to
        download openSUSE</ulink>) and it would be ideal if web browsers would natively support this
      technology. For now, this isn't the case though. I have been working hard on a standard for
      the Metalink Download Description format for more than a year, because protocol
      standardization would probably lower the barrier of such implementations, and the standard has
      been <ulink url="http://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc5854">published</ulink> in March this year. </para>
    <para>Regarding mirror selection, the client is geolocated by GeoIP and the network prefix and
      its autonomous system is looked at. The process is <ulink
        url="http://www.poeml.de/~poeml/talks/free_software_CDN_vision.pdf">illustrated
      here</ulink>. Mirrors from the same country (or same continent) are preferred, or in the case
      of some countries there's a special configuration that makes sure that a useful choice is
      made. For instance, it could be a nearby country that works best (New Zealand -> Australia),
      or it could be a country far away that works much better than a neighbouring country
      (Mozambique -> Germany instead of South Africa). This <ulink
        url="http://mirrorbrain.org/static/talks/mirrorbrain_fosdem_2010.pdf">presentation from
        FOSDEM</ulink> contains such an example, which shows that a simple proximity- or
      geolocation-based choice is not enough.</para>
    <para>From all mirrors that are eligible for a request, a weighted randomized choice is made, so
      that powerful mirrors can get a larger amount of requests than small ones. It is also possible
      (and necessary) to restrict some mirrors to their country, autonomous system, or network. For
      many mirrors, international bandwidth is scarce and needs to be protected.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="bold">OMG! SUSE!</emphasis>: For openSUSE 11.4 and
        subsequent major releases, how could MirrorBrain or the openSUSE distribution infrastructure
        improve to make the release process smoother and faster?</emphasis></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Peter</emphasis>: Did the 11.3 release leave something to desire in
      this regard? From what I heard, it went smoothly. There is always a little discussion whether
      the use of Akamai during the first day makes things faster or slower, but apart from that I
      didn't hear complaints. However, I'm mostly not involved anymore and miss most of the
      communication going on.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="bold">OMG! SUSE!</emphasis>: How does the openSUSE
        project ensure that all mirrors that users are being redirected to have the absolute correct
        files at the time of a release?</emphasis></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Peter</emphasis>: Registered mirrors pull the images before they are
      released. They are first synchronized in a directory that is not readable to the public (and
      the team makes sure that the mirrors replicate these permissions, so the new stuff doesn't
      "leak"). The release team then waits and checks mirrors periodically, to see when enough
      mirrors have the files. Then a time is agreed on when the permissions are "flipped" to open
      the directory, a procedure often called "bitflip release" which is also employed by other
      Linux distributors. </para>
    <para>The reason behind this is that it takes time to spread the files to the mirrors (it could
      take 3-5 days), and it works best if the files become publicly available within a short
      timeframe on all mirrors at once. If files become available only on one or a few mirrors,
      they'll soon be swamped completely by downloading users, which doesn't please the mirror
      operators (and neither the openSUSE project).</para>
    <para><emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="bold">OMG! SUSE!</emphasis>: Many existing
        openSUSE users, myself included, use Zypper to upgrade from previous releases. The packages
        are all downloaded from download.opensuse.org, just like ISO images are. Do you have any
        numbers to give us a rough idea of how much traffic upgrades produce?</emphasis></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Peter</emphasis>: An upgrade generally consumes less bandwidth than
      a DVD download, because unnecessary stuff isn't downloaded in the first place. It causes more
      requests on download.opensuse.org (let's say, a thousand requests) instead of the single
      request for the image. All that runs through MirrorBrain of course.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="bold">OMG! SUSE!</emphasis>: Releases typically
        "go live" around mid-day in Europe and early morning in the United States. Do you have an
        idea when traffic "peaks" after a release?</emphasis></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Peter</emphasis>: Usually, after 6-10 hours. All traffic that <ulink
        url="http://download.opensuse.org/">download.opensuse.org</ulink> receives follows a clearly
      visible circadian rhythm. The release peak also follows this and overlays it.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="bold">OMG! SUSE!</emphasis>: This has all been
        incredibly informative, as it stands right now, are there any other major hurdles or
        challenges faced when distributing openSUSE?</emphasis></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Peter</emphasis>: I would like to point out that contributions to
      MirrorBrain would be important, to keep the project alive and improve it further. It is
      important to make it more attractive for more users, to strengthen its user base. A
      contribution could be development (a web frontend is needed, e.g., and IPv6 geolocation),
      sponsoring of the development of a new feature and fixing of bugs, testing, packaging,
      documentation, testing the documentation, or lastly (but not least) a donation. Donations can
      ensure all of the above. We have a <ulink url="http://mirrorbrain.org/donations/">donations
        link</ulink> on the site and feel free to spread the word.</para>
    <para>I'd like to take this opportunity to publicly thank Peter for taking time out of his busy
      schedule to share so much information with us about distibuting a major operating system like
      openSUSE. You can learn more about MirrorBrain at <ulink url="http://mirrorbrain.org/"
        >mirrorbrain.org</ulink>.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">CC-BY-SA</ulink></para>
    <!--($ ld: 15.3.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://opensuse.terrorpup.net/?p=246">Chuck Payne: Time to start writing again</ulink></title>
    <para>I know since the elections it’s been very quite here. I been on the openSUSE Wave that’s
      calming down a bit, which is sad, because it been a wonderful ride. It fact lately I feel I am
      on the downward ebb of Karma. </para>
    <para>The wave started getting ready for Hackfest/SCALE which took place in L.A. I got to work
      with a great group of people. Very long hard days, but we made a very big splash at SCALE.
      Where I got to do a bit of training openSUSE Day, and thanks to Alan Clark, got to help give a
      talk at SCALE. </para>
    <para>Coming back from that week, I got sick but couldn’t slow down because of the release of
      openSUSE 11.4 and working on a Poster, I assume for Linux Magazine in UK. Both were very
      import. The poster looks great because of Carlos awesome background and the release when
      great. (...)</para>
    <para><!--($ ld: 15.3.11 sm $)--></para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://e-tote-kala.blogspot.com/2011/03/attachmate-supportive-friend-of.html">Kostas Koudaras: Attachmate - A supportive friend of the openSUSE Project</ulink></title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-RHd1mQJWS0s/TX5b1sDf6pI/AAAAAAAAA8Q/D4kH-fD9cWo/s1600/cip_attachmate-sold.gif"
          align="center"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Today, Jeff Hawn the Chairman and CEO of <ulink url="http://www.attachmate.com/"
        >Attachmate</ulink> made an announcement <ulink
        url="http://www.attachmate.com/Press/PressReleases/congratulations-openSUSE-project.htm"
        >congratulating the openSUSE community on the release of openSUSE 11.4</ulink>. It is the
      second press release of <ulink url="http://www.attachmate.com/">Attachmate</ulink> after the
        '<ulink url="http://www.attachmate.com/Press/PressReleases/nov-22-2010-SUSE.htm">Attachmate
        Corporation Statement on openSUSE project</ulink>' and it shows the intentions of
      Attachmate's people to support the openSUSE project and community and all together to achieve
      great things in the Future. -- Kostas Koudaras</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">CC-BY-SA </ulink></para>
    <!--($ ld: 15.3.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://nowwhatthe.blogspot.com/2011/03/be-proud-of-yourself-geekos.html">Jos Poortvliet: Be proud of yourself, Geekos!</ulink></title>
    <para>Right now I'm enjoying the post-release stress. Going back and catching up with what was
      delayed due to the release being priority and all... And enjoying huge discussions on
      Identi.ca like <ulink url="http://identi.ca/conversation/65860477#notice-66972122">this
        one</ulink> ;-)</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-5cGzCcRPd18/TX7ZH6urREI/AAAAAAAABbc/5dbpQYZiR0A/s200/11.4_NET_installer-boot.png"
          align="right"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Me proud of the Geeko!</emphasis></para>
    <para>The article which went out on Friday made me very proud - <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/12/opensuse-11-4-made-a-splash/">openSUSE 11.4 made a
        splash</ulink>. The title is really correct - we're gathering info on reviews etc on <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/In_the_press">this page</ulink> but it is extremely incomplete -
      there are so many reviews, articles, <ulink url="http://twitter.com/#!/search/opensuse"
        >tweets</ulink>, <ulink url="http://bit.ly/e3IAHc">dents</ulink>, <ulink
        url="http://www.facebook.com/#!/pages/openSUSE/45393742283">facebook</ulink> comments,
        <ulink url="http://bit.ly/fPsJaZ">video's on youtube</ulink> - it is really great! And well
      over <emphasis role="bold">100.000 downloads in 24 hours</emphasis>, almost twice what we did
      for 11.3 - awesome. openSUSE has its momentum back, that's clear. We already wrote that <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/01/03/opensuse-finished-2010-big/">in this "end of 2010"
        article</ulink>, and the subsequent Bretzn and Appstore sprints, the marketing sprint and
      all the cool stuff that is going on makes me quite certain about this: the openSUSE conference
      2010 was a real turning point for openSUSE. The Geeko's back in the game!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Did we leave?</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>The question that might come up is - did the Geeko ever leave? I had a look at <ulink
        url="http://opensuse.org/statistics">some statistics</ulink> on our user base.<emphasis
        role="bold"> openSUSE has 7-8 million users</emphasis>, that's significant! And,
      interestingly enough, between 30-50% more than Fedora. Ubuntu has no statistics online but
      once made some noise about numbers - talking somewhere between 6 and 8.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">So be a proud Geeko! </emphasis></para>
    <para>Now all these numbers have some uncertainty associated with them, nothing is sure. Yet the
      numbers of Fedora and openSUSE at least are measured in the same way, so likely you can at
      least compare them roughly. And I bet Ubuntu has similar statisics on which they based their
      number - with the usual exaggeration. So even though the numbers aren't entirely clear, it is
      interesting to see openSUSE ain't exactly insignificant as many seem to believe... Not only do
      we have amazing technology like <ulink url="http://build.opensuse.org/">OBS</ulink> and <ulink
        url="http://susestudio.com/">Studio</ulink> but we also have a HUGE user base whom we serve
      with <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/10/opensuse-11-4/">a pretty awesome
        distro</ulink>! So, Geeko's, in the communication and marketing department - maybe openSUSE
      is not well known for that. But we're a leading distro when it comes to what matters - users
      and technology. Be proud!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">CC-BY-SA</ulink>
    </para>
    <!--($ ld: 15.3.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/03/16/first-survey-on-opensuse-version-naming-is-open-now/">Andreas Jaeger: First Survey on openSUSE Version naming is open now</ulink></title>
    <para>Following my last blog post on “<ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/03/11/how-to-name-the-distribution-releases/">how to
        name the distribution release</ulink>“, I’ve opened up a public <ulink
        url="http://www.surveymonkey.com/s/ZYC5PYZ">survey</ulink> and look forward to your votes.
      There is also a good discussion going on on the <ulink
        url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-project/2011-03/msg00262.html">opensuse-project
        mailing list</ulink>. </para>
    <para>This is the first iteration. Coolo and myself discussed to use a second survey with the
      group of winners on <ulink url="http://connect.opensuse.org"
      >connect.opensuse.org</ulink>.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 16.3.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/03/17/opensuse-and-kraft-on-clt/">Klaas Freitag: openSUSE and Kraft on CLT</ulink></title>
    <para>First some news about my KDE project <ulink url="http://volle-kraft-voraus.de/"
        >Kraft</ulink>: </para>
    <para>A review was posted on <ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/03/17/opensuse-and-kraft-on-clt/Technewsworld.com"
        >Technewsworld.com</ulink> with title <ulink url="http://bit.ly/f40Pux">Kraft: A No-Nonsense
        Office Assistant That Gets Straight to Work</ulink>. Nice title, and also the bottomline of
      the whole article. Good to read, however I am wondering why the author tested Kraft version
      0.32 instead the current one 0.40 which is out already for ten month. Are there *still* 0.32
      packages around in the Ubuntu-World? On the <ulink
        url="http://volle-kraft-voraus.de/Main/Download">download page</ulink> on Kraft’s website,
      there are good Ubuntu packages linked thanks to Rohan Garg. </para>
    <para>The only remark in the review was that the list of document types should be editable. It
      is since 0.40 :-) Anyway, thanks for considering Kraft for a review. </para>
    <para>On next weekend I will be in Chemnitz on the <ulink
        url="http://chemnitzer.linux-tage.de/2011/">Chemnitzer Linux Tage</ulink>. I will give a
      talk titled <ulink url="http://chemnitzer.linux-tage.de/2011/vortraege/800">Linux im Büro von
        Kleinunternehmen</ulink> (Linux in the small enterprise). Beside other interesting things I
      will present Kraft of course. It will be a talk for people who are new to Linux but try to get
      their work done with Linux. I am looking forward as I enjoy these solution focused topics. If
      you are interested, show up and we talk about Kraft. And, yes, a new release of Kraft is also
      on the way, it can’t take too long any more. </para>
    <para>The <ulink url="http://www.opensuse.org/">openSUSE Project</ulink> will have a booth as
      well and I probably will be around there for the rest of the time together with friends from
      the project. We will tell you about our cool project, explain how you can participate and show
      the brand new <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/10/opensuse-11-4/">openSUSE 11.4
        release</ulink>. It is a nice one. and we think you will like it. I hope to see you there
      :-) </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">FDL 1.2</ulink>
    </para>
    <!--($ ld: 17.3.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.linuxuser.co.uk/reviews/opensuse-11-4-review-kde-4-6-and-tumbleweed-shine/">Linux User &amp; Developer/Koen Vervloesem: openSUSE 11.4 review – KDE 4.6 and Tumbleweed shine</ulink></title>
    <para>Do you want to run the newest software like KDE 4.6 and LibreOffice 3.3? OpenSUSE 11.4 has
      it all on offer, and if you’re really impatient there’s even a rolling updates repository in
      the form of Tumbleweed. Koen Vervloesem investigates… (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 18.3.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.digitalflow.de/blog/2011/03/opensuse-11-4/">Thomas Schmidt: openSUSE 11.4</ulink></title>
    <para>After 8 months of work openSUSE 11.4 has been <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/10/opensuse-11-4/">released</ulink> last week! This
      has been celebrated with <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/10/opensuse-11-4/"
        >release parties</ulink> all around the world. As usual, the new release comes with the
      latest <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/10/opensuse-11-4/">kernel</ulink>, <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/07/opensuse-11-4-will-be-first-to-roll-out-with-libreoffice/"
        >LibreOffice</ulink>, <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/03/gnome-on-opensuse-11-4/">Gnome</ulink> and <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/02/opensuse-11-4-and-kde-2/">KDE</ulink>
      packages.</para>
    <para>In Nuremberg, we celebrated the release with a party at the Artefakt bar, and had the
      fabulous <ulink url="http://on.fb.me/g2Ux2X">Ukulele Insanity</ulink> playing live.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5259/5532944943_f725cf95d3_m.jpg"
          width="20%" align="right"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Althogh the release is considered a very good one by many <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/In_the_press">press and user reviews</ulink>, I had some small
      problems after upgrading to it and want to share with you how I solved those: (...)</para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://anditosan.blogspot.com/2011/03/opensuse-release-party-provo-ut.html">Andres Silva: openSUSE Release Party - Provo, UT</ulink></title>
    <para>The openSUSE release party was a lot of fun and I was very happy to be there one more
      time. The Novell facility in Provo, UT is pretty big and had plenty of room to accommodate the
      few of us that attended. I met a few personalities as well, most of them participants of the
      SLED version of openSUSE sponsored by Novell. I also had the chance to talk to some of the
      guys there about what they did as part of the project and felt like my contributions to the
      project seem to be so much smaller than theirs. People working for XEN, the package manager,
      Yast and others have put a lot of effort into making openSUSE a great distribution. </para>
    <para>I am happy for their achievement and their contribution as well. openSUSE would not be my
      favorite distribution if it wasn't for much of the work that these people do. So a big THANK
      YOU to all of them. They also had pizza, a few goodies and 2 big screens. That did it for me.
      I was happy to see openSUSE handling big screens like that. Although with gnome 3 and the
      resolution, there were some glitches. </para>
    <para>Anyway, I promised some pics and here they are. They are not the greatest quality, I used
      my Palm Pre to take the shots and the lighting was not that great for this tiny phone.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">CC-BY-SA</ulink></para>
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
