<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/05/16/opensuse-conference-2011-to-be-creative-and-open/"
        >openSUSE Conference 2011 to be creative and open!</ulink></title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Time to get ready for the openSUSE Conference 2011</emphasis></para>
    <para>On Sunday the 11th of September it will be that time again: <ulink
        url="http://conference.opensuse.org">the openSUSE Conference</ulink> starts. And of course
      we want an exciting program. Today, the proposal submission time starts and you have until
      July 11th to let us know what you want to discuss at the conference!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">The openSUSE Conference</emphasis></para>
    <para>The openSUSE conference is where Free Software people meet. And a meeting of so many
      developers, artists, translators, documentation writers and others leads to great things! The
      latest Free Software technologies will be showcased, cool projects initiated and great ideas
      discussed. Last year, <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/10/28/opensuse-conference-big-success/">the conference
        was awesome</ulink> and resulted in many new projects and collaborative efforts. This year,
      the conference will be combined with the SUSE Labs conference to bring even more brilliant
      minds together! The SUSE Labs conference has traditionally been about advancing low-level
      technology like the kernel and surrounding infrastructure as well as server related,
      deployment and management tools. </para>
    <para>The openSUSE Conference 2011 will happen from <emphasis role="bold">Sunday 11th to
        Wednesday 14th of September</emphasis> in Nuremberg, Germany. This date shouldn’t conflict
      with too many other conferences. We’ll be open for registration and a pre-party on <emphasis
        role="bold">Saturday night</emphasis>! The website on <ulink
        url="http://conference.opensuse.org">conference.opensuse.org</ulink> is being updated still
      and we’ll let you know once you can register.</para>
    <para>We expect about 500 visitors this year and hence had to find a new location. A perfect
      spot was found in <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Conference_Location_Zentrifuge"
        >a previous industrial complex from AEG named ‘<emphasis role="italic"
        >Zentrifuge</emphasis>‘</ulink>. This cultural center might not be the ‘usual’ space for an
      IT conference but offers a very creative and open space, currently used for art and music.
      Exactly right for the openSUSE Free Software gathering! (...)</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GFDL 1.2</ulink></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 14.5.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>  
</sect1>
