<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 id="gsoc">
  <title>Google Summer of Code</title>
  <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
      <imagedata fileref="http://michal.hrusecky.net/wp-content/uploads/GSoC2011_300x200.png"
        width="20%" align="center"/>
    </imageobject>
  </mediaobject>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.vuntz.net/journal/post/2011/03/07/Google-Summer-of-Code-2011-for-GNOME-openSUSE">Vincent Untz: Google Summer of Code 2011 for GNOME</ulink></title>
    <note><para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is licensed under the <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/fr/legalcode">Creatice Commons Attribution 2.0 France (CC-BY 2.0)</ulink></emphasis>.</para>
    </note>
    <para>Every once in a while, I fall into a trap that causes me to care about a specific topic. Last week, this happened for the <ulink url="http://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/program/home/google/gsoc2011">Google Summer of Code 2011</ulink>.</para>
    <para>Twice.</para>
    <para>I'm apparently going to be a GSoC co-admin for both GNOME and openSUSE, assuming the two organizations get accepted. But I'm not unhappy about that, since GSoC is one really amazing opportunity for free software projects to get useful contributions, but more importantly, to introduce new people to the projects. People who will stay as contributors later on, if we do a good job at making them feel welcome.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">GNOME</emphasis></para>
    <para>GNOME has participated to all GSoC, and that's something we're very proud of. The best part is that past students have become highly involved in GSoC in later years, with some of them being the main admins for GNOME. We usually have a team of several admins (at least four), and everybody has experience of GSoC, so organizing our participation is probably easier than for many projects. We've put all of our <ulink url="http://live.gnome.org/SummerOfCode2011">GSoC documentation</ulink> online, and that's really the place to visit if you want to be a mentor or student for GSoC on a GNOME-related project.</para>
    <para>We've just started collecting <ulink url="http://live.gnome.org/SummerOfCode2011/Ideas">project ideas</ulink>. If you work on something GNOME-related (or a cross-desktop technology), don't hesitate to add your project ideas there. The admin team will triage the list of ideas later on, so don't worry if your idea seems to be lost in a big list of ideas :-) <ulink url="http://cfergeau.blogspot.com/">Christophe</ulink> will send a proper request for ideas in the next few days (if he hasn't already, I haven't read all my mails).</para>
    <para>With <ulink url="http://www.gnome3.org/">GNOME 3</ulink> just around the corner, there is without a doubt a good opportunity to attract students: those are exciting times for GNOME where a student could make a big difference for 3.2/3.4 with a single project, and become a core actor of the GNOME 3 development, and therefore of the GNOME community!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">openSUSE</emphasis></para>
    <para>For openSUSE, things are different: we participated three times (2006, 2008 and 2009), and our application was unfortunately rejected last year. So a few people worked hard in the past few weeks to increase our chances to participate this year (special thanks to <ulink url="http://sysbytes.wordpress.com/">Manu</ulink> who did a good part of the job).</para>
    <para>We gathered all the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:GSOC_2011">relevant information</ulink> on the wiki and our community already offered many different <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:GSOC_2011_Ideas">project ideas</ulink> (roughly 40, as of right now). What's exciting is with openSUSE, we offer topics ranging from low-level C code to Ruby on Rails, from infrastructure tools to end-user features, from openSUSE-specific topics to cross-distribution ones, etc. Our list of ideas is extremely broad, and we believe the technologies we cover are exciting for students. Thanks to this preliminary work, we've already got several students contacting us about the projects. Isn't that cool?</para>
    <para>As the openSUSE Foundation might not be setup in time to receive GSoC money, we're considering various options as to what to do with the money. The two main contenders are leaving the money to Google for future similar initiatives (GSoC or <ulink url="http://code.google.com/gci">Code-In</ulink>, for example), and giving the money to another non-profit organization that we believe is important. We welcome feedback on this, so raise your voice if you have an opinion :-)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 7.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
