<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
<!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://kde.org/announcements/plasma-active-one/">Plasma Active One Arrives!</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>On the 9th of October, 2011 (9.10.11), the first release of the Plasma Active tablet user experience was made publicly available. Plasma Active One’s touchscreen interface is more than just an application launcher. As soon as the device is turned on, rather than the traditional grid of applications, you see the Activities view showing your current project, task or idea. With Activities, you can collect all of the documents, people, web sites, media and widgets related to a topic in one place, building personalized and interactive views of your life.</para>
      <para>With Plasma Active, the possibilities are unlimited. You can add as many things to an Activity as you wish with its “infinite scroll” feature. You can create as many Activities as you like and move between them using the touch-friendly Activity Switcher. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 14.10.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.socallinuxexpo.org/blog/design-logo-scale-10x-win-trip-la">Design a logo for SCALE 10X, win a trip to LA!</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Want a free trip to SCALE 10X in Los Angeles this January?</emphasis></para>
      <para>In marking 10 years of the Southern California Linux Expo (SCALE) and 20 years of Linux, the SCALE team wants to incorporate an open-source approach to this year’s expo logo designs for publications and for swag. 

With this in mind, the SCALE team announces a contest to select the artwork for use on this year&apos;s t-shirts, attendee bags, and other conference materials.</para>
      <para>The designer of the winning submission will win a free pass to <ulink url="http://www.socallinuxexpo.org/scale10x/">SCALE 10x</ulink>, including airfare within the continental United States, as well as a three-night stay at the <ulink url="http://www.hilton.com/en/hi/groups/personalized/L/LAXAHHH-LNX-20120116/index.jhtml?WT.mc_id=POG%20target=">Hilton Los Angeles Airport</ulink>. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 14.10.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxuser.co.uk/opinion/whats-next-for-meego-join-opensuse-says-jos-poortvliet/"> What’s next for MeeGo? “Join openSUSE”, says Jos Poortvliet </ulink>
      </title>
      <para>openSUSE community manager, Jos Poortvliet, shares his thoughts on the recent creation
        of Tizen and offers a new home for the MeeGo project… </para>
      <para>A while ago Intel and Samsung announced a new initiative under the Linux Foundation
        umbrella: Tizen. Tizen is a Linux OS for embedded use building on HTML5 and CSS. Cool? Well,
        maybe. If you’ve been involved with MeeGo, the Linux Foundation’s previous embedded Linux
        OS, you’re probably not too happy right now. Yes, MeeGo will have to go. For them, as
        Richard Dale wrote, it’s ‘Tizen or Tizen’t’. The MeeGo community had no say in the merger of
        Moblin and Maemo to MeeGo, nor did they in the birth of Tizen. Surprised? (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 13.10.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.h-online.com/security/news/item/Anti-virus-software-fails-to-deal-with-government-trojan-1360015.html"
          >h-online: Anti-virus software fails to deal with government trojan</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Since last Monday at the latest, all virus scanners will issue an alert when an attempt
        is made to load the <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/news/item/CCC-cracks-government-trojan-1357755.html">trojan</ulink> that was exposed by the <ulink url="http://www.ccc.de/en/">Chaos Computer Club</ulink> (CCC) onto a computer. However, to think that one is therefore protected from
        the government-procured spyware would be a serious mistake. Anti-virus software hardly
        stands a chance against such malware; some of the alerts have even turned out to be proper
        dummies.</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 13.10.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/open/news/item/openQA-emerges-from-openSUSE-Update-1359661.html">h-online: openQA emerges from openSUSE - Update</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>An open source automated testing framework, <ulink url="http://openqa.opensuse.org/">openQA 1.0</ulink>, has been released by openSUSE to make it easier to test Linux
        distributions and other operating systems. The GPLv2 licensed framework is already running
        within the openSUSE process to <ulink url="http://openqa.opensuse.org/">test openSUSE Factory</ulink> distributions, including the upcoming openSUSE 12.1, due mid-November. </para>
      <para><inlinegraphic fileref="http://www.h-online.com/imgs/43/7/2/3/4/6/2/973eaa058f505522.png"/></para>
<!-- ($ Id: 13.10.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/open/news/item/ownCloud-web-based-storage-app-hits-version-2-0-1359068.html">h-online: ownCloud web-based storage app hits version 2.0</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The <ulink url="http://kde.org/">KDE</ulink> project has <ulink url="http://dot.kde.org/2011/10/11/owncloud-2-released">announced</ulink> the release of
        version 2.0 of <ulink url="http://owncloud.org/">ownCloud</ulink>, an open, web-based
        storage application which is designed to be run on a user&apos;s personal server. The major
        stable update includes a new user interface and several new features, such as support for
        calendar and address book syncing.</para>
<!--($ Id: 13.10.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="https://desktopsummit.org/news/desktop-summit-survey-report">Desktop Summit Survey Report</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Thanks to the people who completed the survey for the Desktop Summit 2011!</para>
      <para>To improve Desktop Summits in the future, the Desktop Summit organizing team collected feedback from attendees through this survey, which 192 people answered. The survey asked for brief background information, a general evaluation of the Desktop Summit and various elements of it, and feedback on the social events.</para>
      <para>The overall feedback was positive. People enjoyed Desktop Summit 2011 Berlin and the forum it provided for exchanging technology and ideas among different free software communities. In addition, there were suggestions for improvements to upcoming Desktop Summits.</para>
      <para>Details can be read <ulink url="https://desktopsummit.org/sites/www.desktopsummit.org/files/Survey%20Report%20DS%202011-public.pdf">in the report</ulink> if you&apos;re interested.</para>
      <para>We appreciate you taking time to give us feedback and look forward to seeing you again at the next Desktop Summit!</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 14.10.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/security/the-greatest-security-vulnerability-you/9612">ZDNet/Ken Hess: The greatest security vulnerability: You</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Believe it or not, the greatest threat to your personal or corporate computing environment is you. You put your personal and collective corporate security at risk every day by just being you. It’s not a particular personality flaw with you as an individual but rather it is your innate human response to other humans. You want to be open, helpful and kind but those attributes are also your security Achilles’ heel. The quote, “A little kindness goes a long way,” is no less true when speaking of computer security. That wee bit of kindness that you show a stranger could put your personal and corporate security at significant risk and could result in very high remedial costs. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 14.10.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
<!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.theregister.co.uk/2011/08/13/oscommerce_infection_threatens_web/">The Register/Dan Goodin: Attack on open-source web app keeps growing</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>An attack targeting sites running unpatched versions of the osCommerce web application kept growing virally this week, more than three weeks after a security firm warned it was being used to install malware on the computers of unsuspecting users.</para>
      <para>When researchers from Armorize first spotted the exploit on July 24, they estimated it had injected malicious links into about 91,000 webpages. By early last week, The Reg reported it had <ulink url="http://www.theregister.co.uk/2011/08/02/mass_injection_attack_goes_viral/">taken hold of almost 5 million pages</ulink>. At time of writing, Google searches <ulink url="https://encrypted.google.com/#num=100&amp;hl=en&amp;safe=off&amp;q=%22http:%2F%2Fwillysy.com%2Fimages%2Fbanners%2F%22&amp;oq=%22http:%2F%2Fwillysy.com%2Fimages%2Fbanners%2F%22&amp;aq=f&amp;aqi=&amp;aql=&amp;gs_sm=e&amp;gs_upl=3751l5401l10l6328l9l7l0l0l0l2l168l883l2.5l7l0&amp;fp=1&amp;biw=1365&amp;bih=913&amp;bav=on.2,or.r_gc.r_pw.&amp;cad=b">here</ulink> and <ulink url="https://encrypted.google.com/#hl=en&amp;source=hp&amp;q=%22http:%2F%2Fexero.eu%2Fcatalog%2Fjquery.js%22&amp;oq=%22http:%2F%2Fexero.eu%2Fcatalog%2Fjquery.js%22&amp;aq=f&amp;aqi=&amp;aql=&amp;gs_sm=e&amp;gs_upl=13178l40428l0l40708l35l35l0l34l0l0l105l105l0.1l1l0&amp;fp=1&amp;biw=1365&amp;bih=913&amp;bav=on.2,or.r_gc.r_pw.&amp;cad=b">here</ulink> suggested that the number exceeded 8.3 million. (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->  <sect2>
    <title>LOL</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://like-a-boss.org/2011/09/30/hacking-the-imperial-death-march/">like-a-boss.org: hacking the imperial death march</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>One of the great things about the original Star Wars trilogy, was the “lived in”, junky, hacked together aesthetic of the Star Wars universe. Everything was a bit trashed, as if real people actually lived there. Thankfully, that’s one of the things that George Lucas hasn’t tinkered with in his endless quest to ruin the childhood memories of a generation. So it’s heartening to see this tradition carried on with the playing of the imperial death march on miscellaneous hacked together hardware. Enjoy … (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 8.10.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
