<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="https://jfehlig.wordpress.com/2011/10/25/updated-libvirt-for-opensuse12-1-rc1/">Jim
        Fehlig: Updated libvirt for openSUSE12.1 RC1</ulink></title>
    <para>Last week I updated the libvirt package for openSUSE12.1 RC1 / Factory to version 0.9.6.
      The package was also submitted for SLE11 SP2 Beta8. Changes since last update include
      backporting of AHCI controller patch for qemu driver. With this patch it is possible to use
      SATA drives with qemu instances. The following controller device XML is used to specify an
      AHCI controller
      <programlisting>&lt;controller type='sata' index='0'&gt;
  &lt;address type='pci' domain='0x0000' bus='0x00' slot='0x05' function='0x0'/&gt;
&lt;/controller</programlisting>The
      libvirt qemu driver supports many AHCI controllers, each with one bus and 6 units. To attach a
      SATA disk to a unit on an AHCI controller, use the following disk device XML
      <programlisting> &lt;disk type='file' device='disk'>
  &lt;driver name='qemu' type='raw'/>
  &lt;source file='/var/lib/libvirt/images/test/disk0.raw'/>
  &lt;target dev='sda' bus='sata'/>
  &lt;address type='drive' controller='0' bus='0' unit='0'/>
&lt;/disk </programlisting></para>
    <para>Also new to this libvirt update is opt-in for Apparmor confinement of qemu instances.
      /etc/libvirt/qemu.conf has been patched to explicitly set the security driver to ‘none’. If
      Apparmor is enabled on the host, libvirtd is generously confined since it needs access to many
      utilities and libraries, but users must opt-in to also have qemu instances launched by
      libvirtd confined. Simply edit /etc/libvirt/qemu.conf and change security_driver to
      ‘apparmor’. Of course, selinux is also available if users prefer it over Apparmor.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 26.10.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://blog.cornelius-schumacher.de/2011/10/introducing-inqlude-qt-library-archive.html"
        >Cornelius Schumacher: Introducing Inqlude, the Qt library archive</ulink></title>
    <para>Today I would like to introduce you to <ulink url="http://inqlude.org/">Inqlude</ulink>,
      the Qt library archive. The goal of this project is to provide a comprehensive listing of all
      existing libraries for developers of Qt applications. So if you are creating applications
      using the <ulink url="http://qt-project.org/">Qt toolkit</ulink>, and are looking for
      libraries, components or modules to use, Inqlude is meant to be the place where you find all
      information and pointers to get started.</para>
    <para><inlinegraphic
        fileref="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-OlDauS1xh-o/TqlYqnvZHRI/AAAAAAAAAT0/W9OY3LLS3o0/s1600/inqlude-home.png"
        width="20%"/></para>
    <!--($ ld: 28.10.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
