<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1>
  <title>openSUSE Conference 2010</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://nmarques.digitalwhores.net/2010/10/16/to-nuremberg/"
        >Nelson Marques: To Nuremberg!</ulink></title>
    <para>Next thursday I’m flying to Nuremberg for the openSUSE
      Conference. I’m arriving somewhere between 14:00 and 15:00
      considering that nothing strange happens (ex: like a snow
      storm).</para>
    <para>For me it’s the first time I attend to FOSS event from such
      caliber. I’m having my own expectations about it, and it will for
      sure help me in the work I’ve been doing. I’m also looking forward
      to meet ‘the’ people to which I have interacted with during the
      last times online. (...)</para>
  </blockquote>

  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://karl-tux-stadt.de/ktuxs/?p=2817">Sirko
        Kemter: May I introduce you …</ulink></title>
    <para>Marya Morevna, she is one of the attendees of openSUSE
      Conference. She helps me with my presentation on wednesday
      evening. She comes from Russia, she likes free software because
      she earned her live from a tool which is free software -
      SynfigStudio. (...)</para>
  </blockquote>

  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/10/18/the-third-opensuse-conference-keynote/"
        >The third openSUSE Conference Keynote</ulink></title>
    <para>This Wednesday the 2nd openSUSE Conference 2010 opens its
      doors and we are very happy to announce the third keynote
      today.</para>
    <para>The Desktop and the Cloud – Thoughts about Freedom on Thursday
      morning at 9:30 am. How relevant is the desktop in a world where
      computing is happening in the cloud?</para>
    <para>The motto for our conference is one of the basic ideas of
      openSUSE: Collaboration across borders. This is why we are
      especially proud to have this subject addressed in a keynote by
      two key people from the free desktop world: Cornelius Schumacher,
      president of KDE e.V., and Vincent Untz, former president of the
      GNOME Foundation. (...)</para>
  </blockquote>
  <!-- More entries here... -->
</sect1>
