<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="community">
  <title>In the Community</title>
<!--Put here things relevant to the openSUSE community maybe from * People of openSUSE or elections, votings 1 - 2 posts-->  
  <sect2>
    <title>Postings from the Community</title>
    <figure id="fig.cebit">
      <title>Picture from cebit</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="http://karl-tux-stadt.de/graph/cebit/cebit.png" width="25%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://karl-tux-stadt.de/ktuxs/?p=2933">Sirko Kemter: Event review 2010</ulink></title>
      <para>2010 is nearly over now, time to look backwards what I did this year.The year begun for me with one of the greatest events arround IT the Cebit. I wasnt the whole week in Hanover, I missed the first day because I had an appointment on this day. The next day, I missed my train then but I arrived right at the point. I had a invitation to a press conference so had only enough time for changing the shirt. Btw there was deliciuos apples served at the conference ;) The rest of the week we had a lot of interviews and press conferences, most of them not so interesting for the people. But with the openPandora project our stage was really filled up.<xref linkend="fig.cebit"/> (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://suseware.com/blog/2010/12/16/day-1-fossin/">Manu Gupta: Day 1 at
          FOSS.in</ulink></title>
      <para>My first ever open source conference was just awesome. First of all, thanks a lot to
          the<ulink url="http://suseware.com/blog/category/opensuse/"> openSUSE</ulink> community
        which arranged my stay. Thanks a lot guys, you rock. As it was my first open source
        conference so there was a lot to learn. </para>
      <para>As soon as I entered the NIMHANS Convention Centre, the venue I saw some of the stalls.
        I met some of the guys at <ulink url="http://suseware.com/blog/tag/foss-in/">FOSS.in</ulink>
        from NIT Trichy. These guys along with their seniors had worked upon a CMS known as Pragyan.
        They have been working on it for over 3 years and looking at the CMS was just awesome. It
        was a php based CMS and was made without using any of the existing frameworks. You can find
        the source code at <ulink url="http://www.pragyan.sourceforge.net/"
          >http://www.pragyan.sourceforge.net</ulink>
      </para>
      <para>The next thing I did was to attend a keynote by Danese Cooper from the wikipedia
        foundation, I heard a lot about server based softwares like varnish, powerdns etc and also a
        lot of info on semantic mediawiki. One of the keyfeatures which mediawiki foundation would
        like to have is realtime editing just like etherpad. The talk was awesome and I hope to
        attend tomorow’s mediawiki workshop. It was lunch time and I met some guys from <ulink
          url="http://suseware.com/blog/tag/opensuse/">openSUSE</ulink> like Akhil Ladha and Bharath
        Acharya. Bharath Acharya kept on saying “Oh! You are the SUSE blog guy rite”. Both of them
        are very nice fellows but could not be with them for a lot, I hope to meet them tomorrow.
        (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 16.12.10 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/17/educational-track-at-opensuse-conference-2010-big-success/">Educational track at openSUSE conference 2010 big success</ulink></title>
      <figure id="fig.edu">
        <title>Heinz with Skolelinux</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/heinz-skolelinux.jpg" width="25%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>      
      <para>At the openSUSE conference almost two months ago a special Educational track on Saturday
        featured talks about the progress on openSUSE Edu-L.i.f.e, the applications it ships and
        many other educational topics. The goal of the openSUSE Edu team is to cater for students,
        educators as well as parents and the software they develop, package and ship has everything
        required to make computers productive for either home or school usage. </para>
      <para>At the conference over 30 people discussed topics including X2go and thin client
        computing in general, several openSUSE based educational distributions, opsi, a Client
        Management System for Windows clients based on Linux servers, groupware (including
        openXchange), PyKota printing accounting software, the KIOSK tool and more.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">X2go</emphasis> is based on FreeNX, a remote display server
        technology providing very good application responsiveness over high latency, low bandwidth
        links like the Internet. X2go upstream developer Heinz M. Graesing gave a talk about
        Skolelinux and also gave some insights of his work on X2go. He attended also other sessions,
        including one by openSUSE’s Michael Kromer about X2go installation, configuration and best
        practices on openSUSE and SLES. openSUSE is very close to upstream X2go and Heinz came away
        impressed, asking for the code behind one of the demoed features!</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Several demonstrations</emphasis> and talks about linux in schools
        were given. Besides Skolelinux and Arktur, the Extis GmbH (who also sponsored the Education
        Flyers sent to the schools in the town and some speakers) showed a business school server
        (based on SLES11-SP1). And the Desktop4Education project from Austria showed a desktop and
        server solution based on openSUSE. The talk from Helmut Hullen, working on Arktur, the
        oldest Linux school server project (since 1992!) in Germany, shows the enthusiasm of users
        and developers behind such projects. Arktur is a Slackware based system with a huge
        community of users. Unfortunately the team developing it has been shrinking and is now down
        to mostly one person, but they work together with Heise, a German magazine, to distribute
        copies and information about Arktur. (..)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <!--  
  <sect2>
    <title>People of openSUSE</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>This Week: xyz</title>
      <para>Good Guy. Glows in the night.</para>
    </blockquote>
    </sect2> -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Welcome new openSUSE Members</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/Izabelvalverde">New Member: Izabel Valverde
          (Izabelvalverde)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>He is involved in some Ambassadoring Projects in Project.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 16.12.10 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/teegee-tg">New Member: Thomas Gross
          (teegee-tg)</ulink></title>
      <para>He works in the Wiki, Bugzilla and OBS.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 16.12.10 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Events &amp; Meetings</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Past</title>
      <listitem>
<para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/02/ambassador-support-review/">December 06, 2010 : Marketing Collaboration Day - Ambassador Support Review</ulink></para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/05/30/german-wiki-team-meeting-2/">December 08, 2010 : German Wiki Team Meeting</ulink></para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/05/13/%ef%bb%bfopensuse-kde-team-meeting/">December 09, 2010 : ﻿openSUSE KDE Team meeting</ulink></para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/02/marketing-materials-review/">December 13, 2010 : Marketing Collaboration Day - Marketing Materials Review</ulink></para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/10/05/opensuse-marketing-team-meeting-8/">December 14, 2010 : openSUSE Marketing Team Meeting</ulink></para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/03/24/opensuse-board-meeting/">December 15, 2010 : openSUSE Board Meeting</ulink></para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/03/24/opensuse-board-meeting/">December 15, 2010 : openSUSE Board Meeting</ulink></para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/11/24/opensuse-gnome-meeting-11/">December 16, 2010 : openSUSE GNOME Meeting </ulink></para>
</listitem>

    </itemizedlist>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Upcoming</title>
      <listitem>
<para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/02/pr-social-media-review/">December 21, 2010 : Marketing Collaboration Day - PR and Social Media Review</ulink></para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/05/30/german-wiki-team-meeting-2/">December 22, 2010 : German Wiki Team Meeting</ulink></para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/05/13/%ef%bb%bfopensuse-kde-team-meeting/">December 23, 2010 : ﻿openSUSE KDE Team meeting</ulink></para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/13/opensuse-testing-core-team-irc-meeting-2/">December 27, 2010 : openSUSE Testing Core Team IRC Meeting</ulink></para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/03/24/opensuse-board-meeting/">December 29, 2010 : openSUSE Board Meeting</ulink></para>
</listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <!-- ($ ld: 15.12.10 ts $) -->
    <para>You can find more informations on other events at: <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/category/events/">openSUSE News/Events</ulink>. - <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Ambassadors_events">Local Events</ulink></para>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>openSUSE for your Ears</title>
    <para>The openSUSE Weekly News are available as livestream or podcast in German. You can hear it
      or download it on <ulink url="http://blog.radiotux.de/podcast">Radiotux</ulink>. </para>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>From Ambassadors</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/12/12/outcome-of-the-christmas-dinner/">Nelson
          Marques: Outcome of the Christmas dinner…</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Nelson Marques gives us a good summary about the Christmas Dinner in Portugal.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>  
    <title><ulink url="http://e-tote-kala.blogspot.com/2010/12/me-and-stathisdiamondgr-once-again-i.html">Kostas Koudaras: Community Works</ulink></title>
      <figure id="fig.greek">
        <title>Me and Stathis(diamond_gr)</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://diamond.comlu.com/suse/events/xariseto_12_12_10/2.jpg" width="25%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>Yesterday once again I felt very proud about the work I have done so far with Stathis
        (diamond_gr) in the formation of the Greek community from Scratch. We were having that event
        at a school for xariseto.gr where people were giving away stuff they no longer used for free
        to other people and we were there to inform people about FOSS. The last time I went to such
        an event I was alone and I had difficulties on talking to everybody since there were a lot
        of people that were really got interesting in openSUSE. This time Stathis would come with me
        and we asked other people to come to help if they could. The response was immediate from 2
        members that came and helped us for more than 7 hours.<xref linkend="fig.greek"/></para>
      <figure id="fig.greek2">
        <title>Our member Ipparion giving instructions about openSUSE</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://diamond.comlu.com/suse/events/xariseto_12_12_10/5.jpg" width="25%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>When we people started coming asking questions I felt very proud about those people. The
        reason was the passion that people show about serving the Greek openSUSE community, three
        months ago we were 2 people trying to make a stand and now we have a bunch of very skilled
        people making all short of things for openSUSE community. The Greek openSUSE community seem
        to bloom and it is great to know that you have a great part. Yesterday we showed our
        superiority since we went to the event like a team,we worked as a team and we managed to do
        all the right things a community should do. Older communities from openSUSE community were
        present but not even close to our level of organization. And although the great amount of
        work we made, still we had a lot of fun. <xref linkend="fig.greek2"/></para>
      </blockquote>
      <!-- ($ ld: 15.12.10 sm $) -->
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Communication</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/">The Mailinglists</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org">The openSUSE Forums</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Contributors</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://users.opensuse.org">The User Directory</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
