<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://vizzzion.org/blog/2011/01/open-slx-end-user-platform-announced/">Sebastian
        Kügler: open-slx end-user platform announced</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>A couple of months ago at open-slx, when we (like so many times before and after) talked
      about how we can make the lives of Linux users easier, an idea was sparked. While there’s huge
      amounts of content out there, it struck us that there’s still a large number of people not
      being too well served when searching Google to get answers to your questions. This poses some
      problems though: First of all, most of the information is not in English. This poses an extra
      barrier for some, who might not be as fluent in English as we developers usually are. Then,
      the content is hard to verify: How do I *know* that the information given there makes sense?
      Maybe it will just delete all my erotic movies? ;) So the problem is that there’s little
      content for the German end-user audience, which is hard to verify. So a team consisting of
      openSUSE community members and open-slx employees led by my colleague Rupert Horstkötter has
      set out to fix this problem. They looked into existing solutions to these problem, and found
      that what is currently running as ubuntuusers.de comes closest to the solution we have in
      mind. We got in contact with the team at ubuntuusers.de, and they were enthusiastic about the
      idea and willing to make it happen. A good start. </para>
    <para>Then comes the real work of course. We’ve worked out a concept that allows us to provide a
      modern support tool for our users, which builds on two pillars: information and interaction.
      The concept we come up with puts this into three different tools: a wiki as knowledgebase, a
      forum to discuss articles, questions and to get in contact with other people, and a blog
      aggregation (Planet) which collects news about developments in openSUSE and howtos for
      specific topics. In order to accomplish this gargantuan task, we’ve asked for help in the
      openSUSE community. People were immediately enthusiastic about the idea, and started chipping
      in, helping to review and improve lots of articles. </para>
    <para>Over the past few months, we have reviewed about 2000 articles from the existing
      ubuntuusers.de <ulink url="http://wiki.open-slx.de">knowledgebase</ulink>, prioritizing 500 of
      them, and adapted the articles to modern standards and that they apply to openSUSE. These 500
      articles form the foundation for the knowledgebase we created for the open-slx community
      platform. We’ve also set up a <ulink url="http://community.open-slx.de">webforum</ulink> users
      can use to communicate and ask further questions, and we’ve put up a <ulink
        url="http://planet.open-slx.de">blog aggregator</ulink>. </para>
    <para>So, if you’re a German-speaking user (or future user :)) of openSUSE, hop over to
      community.open-slx.de and see for yourself whether this new platform fits your needs (and if
      it doesn’t, let us know what we can improve). You can find the official announcement <ulink
        url="http://news.open-slx.de/2011/01/17/herzlich-willkommen-bei-community-open-slx-de/"
        >here</ulink>.</para>
    <para>(...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 18.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/01/17/a-brief-update/">Nelson Marques: A
        brief update…</ulink></title>
    <para>In the last days I’ve been leaving my full attention to Compiz and the famous glib main
      loop. I’ve made a small perl script to compare my local builds with the ones available on
      launchpad… nothing too fancy, but it seems to work. During the last days Canonical updated a
      lot of software. </para>
    <para>I’ve decided to start updating the on my test repository to the newer versions. A couple
      of new packages are required as dependencies (the most impressive one is utouch-evemu, which
      is a part of Canonical’s Multitouch uTouch stack). </para>
    <para>The number of updates is quite impressive, the number of patches (even on some new
      updates) is equally impressive… I’ve just realized that GTK+-2.0 has been subjected of a
      couple of fun patches and gobject-introspection is becoming mind crushing… Either way, the
      work continues, and unfortunately for me I was planning to do a small open beta phase for
      Factory users soon… but all this changes will require much more work and a lot of packages
      will have dependency lists updated. </para>
    <para>The next days free time will be spent around this massive update, I am sure it will pay
      off. If anyone is using my test repository on my home project, expect some turbulence during
      the next days. Since I’m on this, I’m already starting to enable GTK3 wherever I can do it in
      a safe way, nevertheless, it’s just to speed work for the time being, as much things are
      changing.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 18.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://www.vuntz.net/journal/post/2011/01/18/Cross-distribution-meeting-on-application-installer"
        >Vincent Untz: Cross-distribution meeting on application installer</ulink></title>
    <para>Back in October, at the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Conference">openSUSE
        Conference</ulink>, many people were interested in the whole app store/market place/software
      center topic for openSUSE: we had a session about that, and several hallway discussion. There
      is no big surprise here, since it's a hot topic for various <ulink
        url="http://www.apple.com/mac/app-store/">OS</ulink>
      <ulink
        url="http://www.neowin.net/news/microsoft-planning-039windows-store039-app-store-for-windows-8"
        >distributors</ulink>, and not just our free distributions. Of course, being lazy people, we
      discussed what we could re-use to minimize our work; the <ulink
        url="https://wiki.ubuntu.com/SoftwareCenter">software center</ulink> used in Ubuntu and the
        <ulink url="http://blogs.gnome.org/hughsie/2010/09/07/linux-and-application-installing/"
        >app-install</ulink> work that <ulink url="http://blogs.gnome.org/hughsie">Richard</ulink>
      did a while ago came to our minds. </para>
    <para>And then we thought: Hrm, why do this in our corner? Everybody is doing this in a corner.
      Let's see if we can work together! </para>
    <para>Obvious idea, right? But on the other hand, everybody is generally all for collaboration,
      but when it comes to do the work, it's easier to hack in a corner. So we didn't exactly know
      what to expect: is this something that can really happen, or is this just a blue-sky dream? I
      decided to give it a try. </para>
    <para>In the past couple of months, I chatted with people from various distributions to organize
      a cross-distribution meeting. I first talked to <ulink url="http://mvogt.wordpress.com/"
        >Michael</ulink> (Ubuntu), and <ulink url="http://blogs.gnome.org/hughsie">Richard</ulink>
      (Fedora) who were both enthusiastic about the idea. I met <ulink
        url="http://upsilon.cc/~zack/blog/">Stefano</ulink> (Debian) at an <ulink
        url="http://www.toulibre.org/ubuntuparty">event in Toulouse</ulink>, and we had a great chat
      about many topics; that lead me to ask him if we could help find some Debian people interested
      in this. I discussed with <ulink url="https://blog.misc.ephaone.org/">Michael </ulink>(Mageia)
      to find out the relevant people in Mageia, and a few people were interested in the topic. And
      of course, I knew the right openSUSE people ;-) So after a few weeks, it turned out there was
      great interest from Debian, Fedora, Mageia, openSUSE and Ubuntu, with people willing to attend
      such a meeting. I then sent out a mail to <ulink
        url="http://lists.freedesktop.org/archives/distributions/2010-December/000408.html"
        >distributions@fd.o</ulink>, to open this up to other distributions. </para>
    <para>Fast-forward a bit, and here we are today: I'm flying to Nuremberg in a few hours to
      attend this <ulink url="http://distributions.freedesktop.org/wiki/Meetings/AppInstaller2011"
        >cross-distro meeting on application installer</ulink>, that will occur in the next three
      days with a group of 14 people. The goals are to see where and how we can work together on the
      end-user experience as well as on the application metadata that we want to provide. It might
      all sound easy, but the fact is that with all distributions building its own packages, on its
      own infrastructure, with different metadata and different users who could create more
      metadata, we're currently not set to share anything, which is a shame. This meeting will help
      us decide where we can mutualize our efforts to provide the best end-user experience possible
      for everyone. </para>
    <para>Three days is a short time for a topic like this, and we obviously won't do everything
      we'd love to. But I'm optimistic about the result :-) </para>
    <para>Thanks to Novell for hosting and sponsoring a few attendees, to Canonical and Red Hat for
      sending people on their own budget, to Debian for helping sponsoring a last-minute attendee,
      and also to some attendees who didn't need sponsorship at all!</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 18.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://nowwhatthe.blogspot.com/2011/01/meetings-stuff.html">Jos Poortvliet:
        Meetings</ulink></title>
    <para>I just heard from Vincent that the <ulink
        url="http://distributions.freedesktop.org/wiki/Meetings/AppInstaller2011">Cross-distro app
        installer</ulink> meeting organized by openSUSE is in full swing. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Cross distribution Appstore Sprint </emphasis></para>
    <para>As Vincent wrote <ulink
        url="http://www.vuntz.net/journal/post/2011/01/18/Cross-distribution-meeting-on-application-installer"
        >in his blog</ulink>, the idea came up at the openSUSE conference. We should work on getting
      distributions on the same page when it comes to a Linux Appstore technology. Appstore API's
      have been in development for ages on linux so we have a strong base. The as the <ulink
        url="http://freedesktop.org/wiki/Specifications/open-collaboration-services">Open
        Collaboration Services</ulink> we currently have on freedesktop.org are inspired by the
      GetHotNewStuff technology which was developed by Josef Spillner many years ago - KDE and GNOME
      have used this to deliver wallpapers and scripts to their users. After GHNS, two possible
      successors were developed - OCS, started by Frank Karlitschek, seems the de-facto standard
      now. It was adopted by Maemo and now by MeeGo for their appstore, openoffice.org supports it
      and of course the family of <ulink url="http://opendesktop.org">opendesktop.org</ulink> series
      of sites including the popular gtk-apps.org, qt-apps.org, GNOME- and KDE-look.org are all
      accessible from this API. </para>
    <para>At the <ulink url="http://distributions.freedesktop.org/wiki/Meetings/AppInstaller2011"
        >cross-distro appinstaller meeting</ulink> which started this morning people from several
      distributions including Red Hat, Mandriva and Debian are discussing together how Linux should
      tackle this. Can we agree on a common technology shared between distributions and Desktops?
      Hopefully we can bring together the work on <ulink
        url="http://blogs.gnome.org/hughsie/2010/09/07/linux-and-application-installing/">app
        install</ulink> by <ulink url="http://blogs.gnome.org/hughsie">Richard</ulink>, the <ulink
        url="https://wiki.ubuntu.com/SoftwareCenter">Software Center</ulink> tech from Ubuntu and
      FD.o's <ulink url="http://freedesktop.org/wiki/Specifications/open-collaboration-services"
        >Open Collaboration Services</ulink> in a way that benefits all. </para>
    <para>I had a quick phone call with Frank who told me the meeting is very constructive and he
      hopes that the major distributions can agree on some kind of standard by the end of this week.
      That would be pretty awesome! The appstore sprint aims to bring people on the same page and
      will be followed by a Bretzn sprint for openSUSE. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Bretzn Sprint </emphasis></para>
    <para>At the Bretzn sprint (also sponsored by openSUSE) the goal is to get something done: work
      on appstore integration in openSUSE, as well as smoothen the process of building and
      distributing an application for developers. Bretzn, <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/10/26/from-the-developer-to-the-user-and-back-announcing-project-bretzn/"
        >first announced at the openSUSE conference in October</ulink>, is almost ready for its
      first release. At the sprint, Pavol Rusnak, who developed a web based openSUSE Games store,
      will also be present - I hope he can make sure we also have a web-accessible store for
      openSUSE! </para>
    <para>While it is unsure if the work on Bretzn and the openSUSE appstore will make it into
      openSUSE 11.4, it is clear that openSUSE is pushing innovation and standardization in the
      Linux market. Not going all alone, but thinking and caring about the larger ecosystem - I
      think that is what separates a real community effort from a company pushing a corporate
      agenda. Bringing the right people with the right skills and the right ideas together is what
      these sprints are all about - I'm happy to have helped make it possible. And less happy that I
      couldn't be there myself, there is little in the world of Free Software that gives me more
      energy than being at a developer sprint! </para>
    <para>I'd like to thank Frank and Vincent for organizing, as well as all the attendees for
      attending and I look forward to their blogs and <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org"
        >news.o.o</ulink> article ;-) </para>
    <para>Good luck and Rock the Boat!</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 18.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://blog.hennevogel.de/why-we-are-here/">Henne Vogelsang: Why we are
        here.</ulink></title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://blog.hennevogel.de/files/2011/01/12694840_204ab9cba6_o.jpg"
          width="25%" align="center"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>I’m chewing on something for a couple of weeks now and I think I need to tell you before
      my jaw turns into dust. It’s about the <ulink url="http://www.opensuse.org">openSUSE
        Project</ulink> and what’s happening with it. I’m heavily involved in the project. Since
      over 10 years I get paid by my employer to work in that project and I spend a lot of my spare
      time on it. It’s a huge part of my life, both personal and professional and I love it! I love
      the people, I love how the project is set up and I love all the cool results we produce
      together. But since a couple of weeks, I couldn’t really pin down if there was a single cause,
      what it was or when, I was in misery about it. It’s only yesterday that while talking to a
      fellow <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board">openSUSE Board</ulink> member that I
      realized what really causes my grief. All of the sudden this project went from “<emphasis
        role="bold">Hey dude, let’s do cool things together</emphasis>” to “<emphasis role="bold">I
        have this and that opinion and I’m going to stick it to you!</emphasis>”. The whole project
      went from collaboration to politics in a blink. Now I’m sure all of you tin foil hat wearing
      people out there will start to spin this as result of some single event, whatever fits your
      agenda best, but I assure you it’s not. Sometime in the last couple of weeks this tipped over
      and we started to have discussions about all aspects of the theory of politics, we argue about
      human rights or quotes from Mahatma Gandhi, people put up motions for the powers that be, the
      structure and people are questioned to the last extent, alliances are forged, opportunities
      are seized to get even and a lot of distrust is spreading around. </para>
    <para>And there are two answers so far I have heard. One is that people say that this is normal.
      Because we as open source project always ask for equal rights, democracy and all these other
      crazy liberal ideas and that now <emphasis role="bold">we reap what we sow:
        politics</emphasis>. So however you are involved in this, like me for instance that stood up
      and took responsibility for nasty things nobody else wants to do, you have asked for this and
      now got what was coming to you. <emphasis role="bold">Don’t be a crybaby now, bitch!
      </emphasis></para>
    <para>The other answer I see to this from the members of our project is to be passive. <emphasis
        role="bold">YAWN politics</emphasis>… I want to code, draw, write, fix, test. Politics are
      not of my interest and I don’t want to get involved. You idiots can fight this out, I just
      work on my stuff while you’re doing that. So however you are involved in this, like me for
      instance that stood up and took responsibility for nasty things nobody else wants to do, you
      have asked for this and now got what was coming to you. <emphasis role="bold">Don’t look at
        me, not interested!</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>Both are equally destructive and neglect the reason all of us are here. We are here for
      one thing: <emphasis role="bold">FUN</emphasis>! Yes, remember please why you have came to the
      openSUSE Project. Because it’s fun to use the software for any purpose you want. Because it’s
      great to study how the software works, and change it to make it do what you wish. Because it’s
      cool to redistribute copies so you can help your neighbor. Because it’s a great feeling to
      give the whole community a chance to benefit from your work. You know what’s wrong with us? We
      have forgot to Have a lot of fun! </para>
    <para>Can all of you who love openSUSE please go to a console, open an xterm, gnome-terminal or
      a konsole, do a <emphasis role="italic">cat /etc/motd</emphasis> and think about the output
      for a while? </para>
    <para>Then pull yourself together and stop doing what is robbing ALL OF US of the reason we are
      here! If you want to push through your agenda, don’t! If you want to stick it to the man,
      don’t! If you want to insist on all of your given rights, don’t! If you want to be pigheaded,
      don’t. If you want to be serious, don’t! </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Instead, remember to Have a lot of fun!</emphasis></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 20.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
