<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://dominique.leuenberger.net/blog/2011/12/enhanced-typelib-based-dep-generation/"
        >Dominique Leuenberger: Enhanced typelib based dep generation</ulink></title>
    <para>A long time ago I <ulink
        url="http://dominique.leuenberger.net/blog/2011/06/gobject-introspection-based-typelib-provides-and-requires/"
        >posted</ulink> about our inclusion of an automatic dependency generator for typelib() style
      provides and requires. The main goal there was to have the various seed and python based
      programs depending on gobject-introspection based bindings properly require the bindings,
      which also dragged in the libraries needed.</para>
    <para>For the openSUSE 12.2 release cycle we have to push this a little further: As the typelib
      namespace and version does not grow linear together with the shared library name, we have to
      split the *.typelib files out of the shared library package.</para>
    <para>An example why the typelib files need to be split out from the libraries:</para>
    <para> Clutter: the library was renamed from libclutter-glx-1.0.so.0 to libclutter-1.0.so.0, the
      typelib remained Clutter-1.0.typelib. The upgrade process is slightly ‘messy’ in this case and
      a bunch of problems could be avoided by splitting the typelib files out. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 10.12.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/12/07/cooking-with-docbook/">Thomas
        Schraitle: Cooking with DocBook</ulink></title>
    <para>Hi DocBook lovers, browsed through a book, used your favorite search engine, or posted on
      LinkedIn, Xing, or the DocBook mailinglist to hunt for answers to your problems?</para>
    <para>As an additional alternative, I’m happy to announce my latest project:</para>
    <para><quote><ulink url="http://doccookbook.sf.net">The DoCookBook Project</ulink> (released
        under Creative Commons License)</quote></para>
    <para>The tongue-twisting name is a word play and picks up the two central topic about DocBook
      and cookbook. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 10.12.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://vavai.net/2011/12/how-to-check-test-validate-dkim-records-setting-for-mail-server/"
        >Masim Sugianto: How to Check, Test and Validate DKIM Records in DNS is Correct and
        Valid</ulink></title>
    <para>As I’ve wrote in the article: “<ulink
        url="http://vavai.net/2011/12/2011/11/10-tips-for-auditing-improving-mail-server-performance/"
        >10 Tips for Auditing &amp; Improving Mail Server Performance</ulink>“, Dkim or Domainkeys
      is one feature that can be used to increase the acceptance rate (eligibility) of email on the
      destination mail server.</para>
    <para>DomainKeys or DKIM signature basically allowing good senders to “sign” a message to prove
      that it really did come from them. This process is obtained by signing the outgoing mail with
      a specific code corresponding domain name and identity of the mail server so it is considered
      valid and convincing as an authorized sender.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 10.12.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/12/08/the-exo-typeface-family/">Thomas
        Schraitle: The Exo Typeface Family</ulink></title>
    <para>Some week ago, I’ve stumbled upon a very promising font project. It’s called the <ulink
        url="http://kck.st/tivQep">Exo Typeface Family</ulink> and I think this could be a valuable
      addition to our distribution:</para>
    <para>The sans serif font is beautifully crafted and contains 9(!) different width as you can
      see in the following graphic: (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 10.12.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://blog.jospoortvliet.com/2011/12/calligra.html">Jos Poortvliet:
        Calligra...</ulink></title>
    <para>While <ulink url="http://www.calligra.org/">Calligra 2.4</ulink> did not make it as part
      of openSUSE 12.1, its <ulink
        url="http://www.calligra.org/news/announcements/calligra-2-4-beta-4/">latest beta</ulink> is
      available in the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/KDE_repositories#Updated_applications_only"
        >KDE:UpdatedApps</ulink> repository and I hope Tumbleweed will pick it up too. I'm quite
      excited about this release and I'd like to share why!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Little intro</emphasis></para>
    <para>As you might or might not know, Calligra is the result of a split of the KWord maintainer
      with the rest of the KOffice team. The ODF based Suite has a wide range of applications. From
      Krita, the most versatile and usable sketching and painting application on Linux (click for an
      experts opinion), and Kexi, the most powerful and complete database tool available as Free
      Software - to Words, Karbon and Stage. These last, as well as all the other applications in
      Calligra, are far less mature than Krita and Kexi. The team has been limiting their scope,
      focusing on getting them stable and usable while skipping on features.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 10.12.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
