<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 id="gsoc" role="gsoc">
  <title>Google Summer of Code</title>
  <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
      <imagedata fileref="http://michal.hrusecky.net/wp-content/uploads/GSoC2011_300x200.png"
        width="20%" align="center"/>
    </imageobject>
  </mediaobject>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://nbprashanth.wordpress.com/2011/06/11/gsoc-report-2/">N.B.Prashanth:
        GsoC Report – 2</ulink></title>
    <para>Hi. The last week was full of changes for libYUI. To start off, the packages are no longer
      being built locally and the build process is now handled by OBS. This makes libYUI available
      on a wide range of operating systems and architectures. Currently, the build at OBS is being
      done for Fedora 14/15 as well as Ubuntu 10.10/11.04 for both x86 and x86_64 architectures.
      Interested people can find the OBS repository at <ulink
        url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/home:/nbprashanth/"
        >http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/home:/nbprashanth/</ulink>. This means that the
      binaries will no longer be availalbe at the gitorious repository(<ulink
        url="http://gitorious.org/libyui">gitorious.org/libyui</ulink>).</para>
    <para>Secondly, the initial documentation for the library is hosted at <ulink
        url="http://doc.opensuse.org/projects/libyui/HEAD/"
        >http://doc.opensuse.org/projects/libyui/HEAD/</ulink>. This documentation is subjected to
      frequent updates and will change regularly (weekly updates planned). Again, to avoid
      duplications, the gitorious repository will not contain the documentation anymore.</para>
    <para>People who test the new packages are requested to submit bug reports (here or at OBS) in
      order to help improve libYUI.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 12.6.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://redache.wordpress.com/2011/06/10/entomologist-ui-changes-weekly-report-3/"
        >David Williams: Entomologist UI changes Weekly Report 3</ulink></title>
    <para>This week I’ve been working on tidying up the tab changes and it has been going a lot
      slower than I’d like. It feels like I’m only now getting really used to the code and my speed
      is picking up as I work through it. The biggest problem I’ve had is QtDesigner and trying to
      drag and drop widgets into layouts and have them continue to resize correctly. Very much a
      banging head against a wall process.</para>
    <para>Apart from that I’ve improved the tabs themselves as before they were populated by tab
      index in relation to a list index for each tab widget which would then select from the bugs
      database based on that id (If I add my bug tracker first then that will probably have an ID of
      one) but this would not facilitate easy delete as the relation between tracker id and tab id
      would break. I’ve replaced it with a more sensible SQL query that bases it on the name of the
      tracker (The actual query is something like WHERE bug.tracker_id IN (SELECT tracker.id FROM
      trackers WHERE tracker.name = var)). I spent a while trying to see if there were ways to make
      it even more succinct but my knowledge of SQL isn’t that great and most of my googling
      returned solutions similar to the one I had come up with. </para>
    <para>I’ve also added favicons to the tabs to make them look nicer and it also lets you see the
    tracker type at a glance. You can see an image below:</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://redache.files.wordpress.com/2011/06/screen-shot-2011-06-08-at-20-07-17.png"
          width="30%"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Over the next week (hopefully I’ll get it done before monday) I want to get the tabs
      finished and the stats/tracker lists finished so I can move on to the new comments dialog. I
      don’t want to spend forever on these simple things as I want to move on to the TODO stuff as
      soon as I can get there.</para>
    <para>I’d also like feedback on what you think the TODO list should integrate with. I’ve seen a
      request for Remember the Milk integration and Google Calendar/iCal will be supported too. If
      there are any services that you’d like to see used either comment on this post or e-mail
      me/file a feature request on the <ulink url="http://trac.entomologist-project.org"
        >Entomologist Bug Tracker</ulink> and I will take it into consideration (which means I’ll
      try my best to integrate it before the end of summer <inlinemediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="http://s1.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif?m=1306912051g"/>
        </imageobject>
      </inlinemediaobject> ). </para>
    <para>There’s still work to do on the tabs as filtering doesn’t work yet and neither do the
      context menus for the bugs lists. This is why I added buffer weeks into my timeline, for the
      times where issues would arise and I didn’t have time to fix things in time. So next week is
      more of the same but with an end point <inlinemediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="http://s1.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif?m=1306912051g"/>
        </imageobject>
      </inlinemediaobject> .</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 12.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://cbounta.wordpress.com/2011/06/10/a-utility-for-merging-configuration-sysconfig-files-week-3-report/"
        >Christos Bountalis: A utility for merging configuration / sysconfig files – Week 3
        Report</ulink></title>
    <para>This my regular weekly post on my GSoC project. Even though this week I had to give my
      last exams for my bachelor degree and some days of the week I had to spent them on reading, I
      did some progress on the actual project. First of all, I created my first patch for Augeas,
      yes this is my first patch not for this particular project, but in general. Every week I found
      my self, reading learning and carrying out new things, this is the coolest and most exciting
      thing in the GSoC experience until now.</para>
    <para>Back to the actual patch, below you can see the description of the patch:<blockquote>
        <para>Subject: [PATCH] Added aug_find_lense function to find and return used for loading a
          specific file</para>
        <para>Aug_find_lense is a function that accepts a path of a file, and tries to find the
          lense that was used to load this file in Augeas. Returns either a string representing the
          lense if it is located succesfully either null if the lense could not be found, or the
          file is not loaded in augeas.</para>
      </blockquote></para>
    <para>As i had told you before, i am working on a merge method for augtool as well. This command
      works like this,</para>
    <para>merge destination merging-parameters files-to-be-merged</para>
    <para>example:</para>
    <para>merge /etc/hosts/ (merging-parameters) /tmp/myfile1 /tmp/myfile2 ….. /tmp/myfile3</para>
    <para>Until now I am able to use the aug_find lense to locate the lense used for the destination
      file. Then i have implemented an extra function that can use the name of the lense to load the
      files-to-merged to augeas. This permits me to have all these files in tree form used by
      Augeas. The plan now is to finish the code with aug_process_tree function[1] that will try to
      match the destination with the files-to-be-merged, and will then call the right function
      according to merging-parameters if a match is found.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">What is next? </emphasis></para>
    <para>By having a merge command in augtool, that can load files in the way I mentioned above, i
      now have a test basis that will permit me to implement and test the merging functions. This
      must be done in the next two weeks, so i can be in the initial schedule. I am quite
      optimistic, things will go as planned. This week among with the coding there has been quite a
      lot of research on tree pattern matching algoriths, I am grateful that there are always nice
      people in open source communities that provide help and tips. I am back to coding… <inlinemediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif?m=1307715965g"/>
        </imageobject>
      </inlinemediaobject></para>
    <para>Kind Regards,</para>
    <para>Christos</para>
    <para>[1] Work in Progress – The aug_process_tree function will be like: int
      aug_process_trees(struct augeas *aug, const char *dest, void (*process)(struct augeas *aug,
      const char *first, const char *second, void* data), void* data,const char *sources,…);</para>
    <!--($ ld: 12.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://blog.jospoortvliet.com/2011/06/gsoc-mentoring.html">Jos Poortvliet:
        GSOC mentoring</ulink></title>
    <para>Dave Neary has written an <ulink
        url="http://blogs.gnome.org/bolsh/2011/05/31/effective-mentoring-programs/">interesting
        blogpost on 'effective mentoring'</ulink>.</para>
    <para>If you don't feel like reading the whole thing (it's big, yes) I can give you some
      highlights on common issues that make mentoring less effective:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>communication. Apprentices often expect their mentor to check in, the mentor expects
            apprentices to ask questions if they have any. This means it is a wise thing to contact
            your apprentice and:<itemizedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>ask how it is going, if they need any help</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>tell them they have to be pro-active: ask questions and give you reports. Just
                  to correct their perception if they expected YOU to ask them! Make clear it has to
                  be pull from their side, it won't be push from yours. Their GSOC project is their
                  responsibility.</para>
              </listitem>
            </itemizedlist></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Mentoring doesn't stop in August: realize YOU are the friendly face to the project
            for the student/apprentice. Please be prepared to keep talking to the students and help
            them, even (especially!) if GSOC is over! And tell them so.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Regular meeting are really important. Have a weekly IRC chat and just talk. Both
            about personal things (get to know each other!) and about the project.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>And please tell the students to help each other and others. That is both a learning
            experience for them, AND they understand others who are new better than anyone!</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>If you have questions, please ask on the mentor mailinglist, not only on IRC. Others can
      learn from the answers. Others here includes me, btw, I love to know what issues you bump
      into!</para>
    <para>Good luck mentoring and remember, we want the students to STAY, not just fire some code at
      us and go again ;-)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 6.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://obsforandroid.wordpress.com/2011/06/10/obs-mobile-package-page-makeover/"
        >Justine Leng: [Seeking Feedback] OBS mobile: project / package page
      makeover</ulink></title>
    <para>In this post, I would like to discuss some ideas I’ve had on improving the project /
      package view pages in the OBS mobile client, and seek users’ feedback. (Please also <ulink
        url="http://obsforandroid.wordpress.com/2011/06/09/obs-mobile-request-page-makeover/">take a
        look</ulink> at my proposal on the request page makeover.)</para>
    <para>On the OBS mobile client’s homepage, the “List of All Projects” displays as
    follows:</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://obsforandroid.files.wordpress.com/2011/06/package1.png"
          width="20%"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <!--($ ld: 11.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://alex.eftimie.ro/2011/06/10/packagekit-backend-for-software-center-week-2-report/"
        >Alex Eftimie: PackageKit backend for Software Center: week 2 report</ulink></title>
    <para>A week of fail and win has almost ended.</para>
    <para>On the fail part, I had a hard time building pygobject, gobject-introspection and glib
      from git.gnome.org. At first I’ve trying pulling from git, configuring and building, without
      luck. Then I switched to jhbuild, which after a few sanitychecks, bootstraps and
      configuration, worked; a day after I found that I’m on the stable branch (-2-28/gnome-3) which
      wasn’t good enough for my aim at patching master, and have switched branches to master, trying
      build -n. Of course it didn’t work until I hacked PKG_CONFIG_PATH to include paths such as
      /usr/share/pkgconfig, /usr/lib/pkgconfig and /usr/lib/i386-linux-gnu/pkgconfig – with help
      from walters on #introspection. This week my hard drive was about to die – because of a <ulink
        url="https://bugs.launchpad.net/ubuntu/+source/linux/+bug/397096">bug in the kernel driver
        for ata</ulink>, it was reset every 30 seconds, causing everything to freeze. Different
      liveCDs have failed, the symptoms were ambigous and hard to reproduce – almost an entire day
      of fun.</para>
    <para>On the win side, I figured out the hdd problem, and locked the kernel version to 2.6.38-9
      for now. Hacked pygobject, posted patch in bugzilla B-), I’m one <ulink
        url="https://mail.gnome.org/archives/python-hackers-list/2011-June/msg00005.html"
        >step</ulink> further into making packagekit python bindings work; also I used the remaining
      time to push forward some <ulink
        url="https://code.launchpad.net/~alexeftimie/software-center/backend-refactor">more</ulink>
      preparation refactor on software-center.</para>
    <para>I have also updated the GSoC <ulink
        url="http://swarm.cs.pub.ro/%7Ealexef/gsoc/gsoc-calendar.html">timeline</ulink> – I’ll try
      to keep it up to date.</para>
    <para>For the next week, same objectives remain.</para>
    <para>PS: If you’re a python hacker and feel like helping out <inlinemediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://alex.eftimie.ro/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif"/>
        </imageobject>
      </inlinemediaobject> , please check this <ulink
        url="http://swarm.cs.pub.ro/~alexef/gsoc/gsoc-calendar.html">bug</ulink> report out.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 11.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://cbounta.wordpress.com/2011/06/10/a-utility-for-merging-configuration-sysconfig-files-week-3-report/"
        >Christos Bountalis: A utility for merging configuration / sysconfig files – Week 3
        Report</ulink></title>
    <para>This my regular weekly post on my GSoC project. Even though this week I had to give my
      last exams for my bachelor degree and some days of the week I had to spent them on reading, I
      did some progress on the actual project. First of all, I created my first patch for Augeas,
      yes this is my first patch not for this particular project, but in general. Every week I found
      my self, reading learning and carrying out new things, this is the coolest and most exciting
      thing in the GSoC experience until now. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 11.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/06/10/gsoc-summary-of-week-3/">Marcus Hüwe:
        [gsoc] summary of week 3</ulink></title>
    <para>here’s a small summary of the 3rd (coding) week. This week I spent most of my time with
      developing the remote model classes. The goal  was to put most of the code into a base class
      from which all remote models will be derived (if you’re interested how it works have a look at
      it). So far we have classes for:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>a remote project (RemoteProject – manages project metadata)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>a remote package (RemotePackage – manages package metadata)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>a request (Request)</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>TODO for this week:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>add exception handling to the httprequest.py module</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>add a RemoteFile class which can be used to access a remote file</para>
        <para> like a buildlog, prjconf or a source file</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>add a BuildResult class:</para>
        <para> - get the build results for a project or package</para>
        <para> - get the buildlog of a package</para>
        <para> - get the binary/binaries from the api</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <!--($ ld: 11.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
