<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://omgsuse.com/content/ten-days-opensuse-day-one-kernel">OMG! SUSE!/rtyler: Ten Days of openSUSE, Day One: The Kernel</ulink>
    </title>
    <note>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is licensed under the <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">Creatice Commons
        Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License</ulink></emphasis>.</para>
    </note>
    <para>In the lead up to the upcoming openSUSE release 11.4, I figured we could highlight some major new developments that are coming in this release.</para>
    <para>At the core of every Linux distribution lies the Linux Kernel, the heart of it all. The kernel the most fundamental part of the operating system, allowing programs to 
    interact with your processor, hard disks, keyboard, etc. The kernel coming in 11.4 contains quite a number of great improvements.</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>"Kernel activity patch," which we had previously talked about makes the openSUSE desktop feel faster and more responsive than ever.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para><ulink url="http://kernelnewbies.org/Linux_2_6_37-DriversArch#head-c3d9fded6c4cb322c878028ff6af0bd9b491d86a">Hoardes of new drivers</ulink> adding better 
      hardware support than ever, including a number of new input devices (including some new Wacom hardware, which I'm particularly pleased about).</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Multi-processor support for Ext4, the default filesystem openSUSE uses. If you have a dual-core notebook or desktop, openSUSE 11.4 will give you faster 
      data access than before</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Plenty more that I cannot properly enumerate.</para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>For all the gritty technical details, the folks over at <ulink url="http://kernelnewbies.org/">kernelnewbies.org</ulink> put up <ulink 
      url="http://kernelnewbies.org/LinuxChanges">this handy summary</ulink> of changes.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 1.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://omgsuse.com/content/ten-days-opensuse-day-two-libreoffice">OMG! SUSE!/rtyler: Ten Days of openSUSE, Day Two: LibreOffice</ulink></title>
    <note>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is licensed under the <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">Creatice Commons
        Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License</ulink></emphasis>.</para>
    </note>
    <para>With 8 days to go until the release of openSUSE 11.4, why not highlight: <emphasis role="bold">LibreOffice</emphasis>! (since <ulink url="http://identi.ca/jospoortvliet"
      >Jos</ulink> already <ulink url="http://nowwhatthe.blogspot.com/2011/03/libreoffice-and-opensuse-114.html">spilled the beans</ulink>)</para>
    <para>As far as I know, openSUSE 11.4 will be <emphasis role="italic">the first</emphasis> major distribution to bundle LibreOffice with a release, something the folks in the 
    underground SUSE ice cave seem pretty happy about.</para>
    <para>What's the big deal about LibreOffice? Remember OpenOffice and how it was pretty good but occasionally had some annoying quirks that seemed to take forever to get 
    fixed. Lots of things have changed for the better with LibreOffice.</para>
    <para>For starters LibreOffice is developed under the umbrella of <ulink url="http://www.documentfoundation.org/">The Document Foundation</ulink> which strives to foster 
    development and partipation in the LibreOffice community.</para>
    <para>This focus on open development and a merit-based leadership means end-users like us get to see <emphasis role="bold">more bug fixes</emphasis> and <emphasis role="bold"
      >newer features</emphasis> faster! Already the LibreOffice guys have incorporated a number of outstanding improvements that were not yet incorporated into OpenOffice (such 
      as the <ulink url="http://go-oo.org/">go-oo.org</ulink> changes)).</para>
    <para>The version of LibreOffice shipping with openSUSE 11.4 is faster, less buggy and will continue to improve at an incredible pace compared to the old OpenOffice, this is 
      a <emphasis role="bold">good thing</emphasis>!</para>
    <para>If you're upgrading to, or installing openSUSE 11.4 on March 10th, you should get the latest LibreOffice but if you can't wait until then, click the shiny button and 
    grab LibreOffice for 11.3!</para>
    <para><ulink url="http://bit.ly/hML0Pd">Install LibreOffice 3.3.1 for 11.3</ulink></para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://nowwhatthe.blogspot.com/2011/03/libreoffice-and-opensuse-114.html">Jos Poortvliet: LibreOffice and openSUSE 11.4</ulink></title>
    <note>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is licensed under the <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">Creatice Commons
        Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License</ulink></emphasis>.</para>
    </note>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-zsh13s7cR7s/TW2Nw8AhS7I/AAAAAAAABQ0/w1dRRxtlsJE/s200/LibreOffice-logo.jpg"/>
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Happy to see LibreOffice going strong... <ulink url="http://www.linuxjournal.com/content/who-contributes-most-libreoffice">This article</ulink> analyzes the 
      contributions to LibreOffice. Some impressive numbers - 133 new contributors already!!! Even Canonical has send in a patch to fix something... Meanwhile Michael Meeks' team 
      (Novell) is leading the 'corporate contributors' pack. And yes, openSUSE will be the first major linux distribution to ship LibreOffice - and it'll be good, thanks to that 
      involvement in LibreOffice development.</para>
    <para>Sean Michael Kerner mentions this fact and our upcoming release in his <ulink url="http://blog.internetnews.com/skerner/2011/02/novell-opensuse-114-nears-comp.html"
      >blog on internetnews.com</ulink> where he also quotes our AJ on several infrastructural improvements. We do need to educate him and explain openSUSE isn't exclusively a 
      Novell product - with so many volunteers involved and the work going on to set up a Foundation you simply can't claim that anymore... We're leading the pack in that area as 
      well and we need to be vocal about that!</para>
    <para>PS will blog on the Marketing Meeting we had last week soonish, need to catch up to some urgent things first... Especially sleep!</para>
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
