<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
  <!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
  %myentities;
]>
<sect1>
  <title>openSUSE Board Election 2010</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://nmarques.digitalwhores.net/2010/10/16/to-nuremberg/">Sebastian 'sebas'
        Kügler: Running for the openSUSE Board.</ulink></title>
    <para>Following up on the call for candidates, I’d like to let you know that I’m intending to
      run for the openSUSE Board. </para>
    <para>In my dayjob, I am responsible for user experience at open-slx, and will be able to invest
      time on a regular basis into participating in the openSUSE board. I have a degree in business
      science, which gives me some formal insight into organisational processes, this has helped my
      work for the KDE e.V. in the past, and it will surely be benefitial for openSUSE. I am 34
      years old, and live in Nijmegen, in the east of the Netherlands. </para>
    <para>I have more than 4 years of experience in administering a Free software project (I’m
      member of the KDE e.V. board since 2006), and during this period have helped turning the KDE
      e.V. into an effective community representation and supporting organisation, which in many
      ways acts as a role model to other, similar organisations. The Geeko in me is about 9 years
      old, it started with openSUSE 7.2, which got me hooked on Linux. After a period of trying all
      kinds of Linuxen, I’m firmly back to openSUSE for about two years now. </para>
    <para>openSUSE represents to me a technically excellent product with a friendly, helpful and
      skilled community around it that is failing to realise its potential, and in many ways is
      searching for orientation and a clear mission. Aside from organisational topics, this process
      I’d like to facilitate. </para>
    <para>My platform for the elections is to help set up the openSUSE e.V. (or rather a legal
      representation of the community, as outlined in the current plans), and to help the community
      through the process of becoming more independent from Novell, which in my opinion is important
      for the growth and sustainability of openSUSE as product and community. I’m a Free software
      dude by heart, and the principle and ethics of the Free software community will be what drives
      my decisions as executive. My experience as "cat-herder" will be beneficial in the same
      way.</para>
    <para>I do realise that my involvement in the openSUSE community has been fairly transparant,
      following things from the sideline, stepping in actively here and there, and certainly far
      from taking on any role as rock-star. I am planning to further ramp up my profile, since that
      a) will make the members’ decision during the elections a lot easier, and b) it improves
      accessibility and visibility of the TOTRoS (The Organisation That Represents openSUSE). </para>
    <para>This email is just to let you know in advance that I’m intending to run for the board. As
      I /also/ intend to go on vacation on Friday, I might appear unresponsive until ~christmas.
      Still, I opted for letting everybody know early on that I’m intending to run (rather than
      sending my note of intent to run after christmas), as planning will likely make the work of
      the election committee a bit easier. Surely, if you’ve questions already, feel free to ask. I
      will, after returning from vacation be more outgoing about my involvement with openSUSE and my
      ideas and plans for the openSUSE board. Thanks for your attention, and your support.
      (EDITMARK)</para>
  </blockquote>

  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://karl-tux-stadt.de/ktuxs/?p=2817">Sirko
        Kemter: May I introduce you …</ulink></title>
    <para>Marya Morevna, she is one of the attendees of openSUSE
      Conference. She helps me with my presentation on wednesday
      evening. She comes from Russia, she likes free software because
      she earned her live from a tool which is free software -
      SynfigStudio. (...)</para>
  </blockquote>

  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/10/18/the-third-opensuse-conference-keynote/"
        >The third openSUSE Conference Keynote</ulink></title>
    <para>This Wednesday the 2nd openSUSE Conference 2010 opens its
      doors and we are very happy to announce the third keynote
      today.</para>
    <para>The Desktop and the Cloud – Thoughts about Freedom on Thursday
      morning at 9:30 am. How relevant is the desktop in a world where
      computing is happening in the cloud?</para>
    <para>The motto for our conference is one of the basic ideas of
      openSUSE: Collaboration across borders. This is why we are
      especially proud to have this subject addressed in a keynote by
      two key people from the free desktop world: Cornelius Schumacher,
      president of KDE e.V., and Vincent Untz, former president of the
      GNOME Foundation. (...)</para>
  </blockquote>
  <!-- More entries here... -->
</sect1>
