<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
  <!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://dot.kde.org/2011/01/05/46-rc2-available-last-chance-test">KDE
          News/Sebastian Kügler: 4.6 RC2 Available, Last Chance to Test</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><quote>KDE's release team has rolled another set of 4.6 tarballs for us all to test and
          report problems: 4.6 RC2 This is the last test release leading up to 4.6.0, which is
          planned for 26th January.</quote></para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 6.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://dot.kde.org/2010/12/28/confkdein-first-kde-conference-india">conf.KDE.in:
          First KDE Conference in India</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The Indian KDE community will organize its first conference at Bengaluru in March 2011.
        The 5 day event will bring together KDE contributors, Qt developers, users and FOSS
        enthusiasts.</para>
      <para>We realise that there are not many KDE/Qt related events that are accessible to Indians.
        FOSS conferences or meetings are an excellent way to show people the technology first hand
        and ways to contribute to it. We not only dazzle them with the world of KDE, but show them
        first hand how simple it is to get involved and make a difference. This is our motivation
        for conducting this event. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 31.12.10 sat $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.calligra-suite.org/news/koffice-2-3-0-released/">KOffice 2.3.0
          Released</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The KOffice team is happy to announce the 2.3 release of KOffice. This release brings
        many small improvements to all the KOffice applications, but not as many large new features.
        Among the most important new features are:</para>
      <para>* Krita is now ready for professional artist use. This is thanks to the very focused
        effort by the Krita team after a meeting which resulted in a clear vision and well defined
        goals. More details are available in <ulink
          url="http://www.calligra-suite.org/news/koffice-2-3-0-released/">Krita 2.3.0
          announcement</ulink>
      </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>A new slide sorter view in KPresenter, which has been greatly missed by some users.
            There is also a new shape animations feature for KPresenter.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Improvements of the core engine and plugins in the support of the OpenDocument
            Format. Especially text rendering has seen much work.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Even more improved support for reading Microsoft file formats (doc, xls, ppt, docx,
            xlsx, pptx).</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>A new report engine used in KPlato and Kexi. (...)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <!-- ($ ld: 01.01.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://qt-apps.org/news/?id=340">QT Apps: Win 10.000,- EUR at the <quote>Qtest Mobile App Port</quote></ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Welcome to the Qtest Mobile App Port! As developers of applications using Qt, you
        already know how great it is to work with - but how about on mobile platforms, such as
        Symbian and MeeGo? How would you like to take that step you have been wanting to take, but
        not been able to justify: Take your application from the desktop and bring it into the
        hand-held world via the Ovi store. Let this contest be the justification, with the
        possibility of a new phone or even 10,000 euros waiting at the end. </para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Dates</emphasis>: The contest starts on 20th of December, 2010,
        and runs till 28th of February. The 31st of December is important for you if you wish to
        take part in the Early Bird competition. If you do no win, you will still take part in the
        main competition, and will be allowed to continue your work and submit new versions to the
        Ovi Store. The 28th of February is the deadline for taking part in the main
        competition.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Developer Sprint</emphasis>: There will be a sponsored developer
        sprint organized together with the KDE e.V. during the competition. The travel and stay can
        be paid for if you do not have the budget yourself. Further details will be made public at a
        later time, and all participants will be notified of this information via email. </para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Judging and prizes</emphasis>: The Qtest Mobile App Port is
        evaluated by a panel of judges which will be announced in the next few days. The jury will
        pic 5 winners at 31th of December as the early bird winners. Every winner gets a free N900
        phone. The main competition first prize is EUR 10,000, which will be awarded to the
        application which the judges find to be the best ported application. The second to sixth
        price will be another 5 N900 phones.</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata width="25%" fileref="http://qt-apps.org/CONTENT/news-pics/340-pic4.jpg"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>And, finally: Everybody who takes part in the competition will be awarded a gift bag,
        with a T-shirt and other merchandise.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Eligibility</emphasis>: To be able to take part in the contest,
        the ported application must be submitted for Ovi Store signing by one of the two deadlines:
        - Early bird entries must be submitted by December 31st - Standard entries must be submitted
        by February 28th.</para>
      <para>You also have to submit your application to the &quot;Mobile Contest&quot; category on
        Qt-Apps.org or MeeGo-Central.org </para>
      <para>You can submit your application to the Ovi Store as many times as you wish during the
        competition. This allows you to get feedback from the public on your software. It´s possible
        to submit new or existing KDE/Qt applications.</para>
      <para>So have fun and good luck everybody!</para>    
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://apachelog.wordpress.com/2011/01/05/phonon-loves-codecs/">Harald Sitter:
          Phonon Loves Codecs</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>As the Phonon team is hard at work to prepare for the release of Phonon 4.4.4, the
        GStreamer backend has seen some awesome improvements these past few days.</para>
      <para>Not only will it be the second backend to support the experimental video capturing
        features introduced with Phonon 4.4.3 but has also seen tremendous improvements with regards
        to stability. But most importantly of all it got improved codec installation support.</para>
      <para>If you ever found yourself looking for a way to play that mov video a friend sent you,
        then you will love Phonon GStreamer 4.4.4. Whenever it can not play a file because a media
        plugin is missing, it will now try to get it semi-automatically. Check out the
        screencast:</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <videoobject>
          <videodata width="40%" fileref="http://blip.tv/file/4592850" align="center"/>
        </videoobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>This gives user experience quite a boost, so I am most certain that Linux distributions
        will pick this up and integrate it nicely with their package management systems.</para>
      <para>In the video KPackageKit is handling the plugin lookup and installation, so both Fedora
        and Kubuntu should have this awesome feature in their next releases.</para>
      <para>Have fun...</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 5.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://ostatic.com/blog/results-are-in-opensuses-community-survey">ostatic/Susan
          Linton: Results are in: openSUSE&apos;s Community Survey</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Back in February openSUSE held a survey to find more out about its community. Who are
        they? What OS do they normally run? What do they want? How can openSUSE improve? Well, the
        results are in and quite interesting to openSUSE users and the community at large.</para>
      <para>Most questions received approximately 8,500 responses. Generally it was found that young
        male adult students with moderate to high technical knowledge and prefer stability, hardware
        support, and security, many of which dual boot with some version of Windows for work, who
        install openSUSE for personal use and are not involved with openSUSE development or
        promotion for email, chat, and surfing the Internet think openSUSE has a good amount of
        software and is easy to install. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 31.12.10 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://www.networkworld.com/community/osi-chimes-in-on-novell-sale"
          >NetworkWorld/Joe Brockmeier:Open Source Initiative chimes in on Novell
        sale</ulink></title>
      <para>The Open Source Initiative (OSI) is stepping into the Novell sale. The organization is
          <ulink url="http://www.opensource.org/statements/CPTN">asking the German Federal Cartel
          Office</ulink> to investigate the sale of Novell's patents to the Microsoft-led
        CPTN.</para>
      <para>OSI is primarily known for being the keeper of the flame for the <ulink
          url="http://opensource.org/docs/osd">Open Source Definition (OSD)</ulink> and approving
        licenses that <ulink url="http://opensource.org/licenses/index.html">meet the
          definition</ulink>. But members of the self-appointed OSI board, in particular Simon
        Phipps, have said they <ulink
          url="http://www.itworld.com/open-source/100432/osi-board-addition-may-bring-needed-change"
          >wish to nudge OSI into becoming a more active organization</ulink> with an <ulink
          url="http://blogs.computerworlduk.com/simon-says/2010/06/your-chance-to-change-osi/index.htm"
          >actual representative membership structure</ulink>. So far, little has happened, but this
        is at least a minor step in that direction.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 1.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/networking/browser-wars-internet-explorer-loses-and-firefox-wins-in-europe/499"
          >ZDNET/Steven J. Vaughan-Nichols: Browser Wars - Internet Explorer loses and Firefox wins
          in Europe</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>It wasn’t that long ago that your choice of Web browsers were Internet Explorer (IE)
        and, ah, uh, a sadly out of date <ulink url="http://practical-tech.com/network/rip-netscape"
          >Netscape Navigator</ulink> or the then obscure <ulink url="http://www.opera.com/"
          >Opera</ulink>. IE was the Web browser, but then along came Firefox in 2004, and
        everything changed. Today, IE may finally be on its way to losing its market-share
        leadership position to <ulink url="http://www.mozilla.com/en-US/firefox/">Firefox</ulink>. </para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata width="50%" fileref="http://i.zdnet.com/blogs/web-browsers-2011.jpg"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>According to a pair of research firms, <ulink url="http://gs.statcounter.com/"
          >StatCounter</ulink> and <ulink url="http://www.netmarketshare.com/?source=NASite">Net
          Application</ulink>, IE is sinking fast, while <ulink url="http://www.google.com/chrome"
          >Google’s Chrome</ulink> is gaining rapidly at IE’s expense. </para>
      <para>By <ulink url="http://www.netmarketshare.com/browser-market-share.aspx?qprid=1">Net
          Application’s Web browser reckoning</ulink>, IE’s market-share has dropped to 57.1%, an
        all-time low. Chrome’s market-share, in the meantime, has climbed above 10% for the first
        time. Apple’s Safari is also showing strong gains by reaching the 5.9% mark. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 5.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://everydaylht.com/2011/01/01/kde-sc-4-6-rc1-another-look/">Everyday Linux
          How2s: KDE SC 4.6 RC1 – Another Look</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>A few weeks ago, I put up a <ulink
          url="http://everydaylht.com/2010/11/26/kde-4-6-beta-1-a-first-look/">post</ulink> about
        the first beta release of <ulink url="http://kde.org/announcements/announce-4.6-rc1.php">KDE
          SC 4.6</ulink>. Unfortunately, due to a number of bugs, I’ve had to revert back to 4.5 on
        a couple of machines. One because there seemed to be a regression in graphics performance on
        the Intel based chipset I had on one machine. The other, because I decided to move from
        openSuse back to Kubuntu, which I might say was a pleasant surprise in terms of polish and
        stability. Anyway, back to the story at hand … Having now installed KDE SC 4.6 RC1 on my
        main desktop machine, running Kubuntu, it seems to be playing quite nicely. Here are my
        impressions of this latest pre-release of KDE SC 4.6.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">kdepim and akonadi</emphasis></para>
      <para>As I have stated in my previous post, the only really earth shattering thing in this
        release is (was) the porting of the KDEPIM suite of applications to Akonadi. This was left
        out of the 4.5 release due to too many bugs. Well, it seems that it will be left out of the
        4.6 release as well, due to migration issues with large data sets. This is interesting, as I
        had a number of issues with Kmail 2.0 when testing the beta release. I’d checked on
        bugs.kde.org to see if others had experienced these issues and filed a bug in relation to
        the main issue I was having. I don’t know if my email store of a few thousand emails on my
        IMAP server would fall into the category of a <quote>large dataset</quote> and if the bugs I
        was experiencing were the same bugs that have held back the release. However, I’m glad
        they’ve delayed again until these bugs are finally sorted out. However, this does
        potentially move this release from <quote>unspectacular</quote> to <quote>borderline
          uninteresting</quote>. I just can’t see any new features that I can really get excited
        about. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 3.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/The-H-Year-2010-s-Wins-Fails-and-Mehs-1159394.html"
          >h-online/Dj Walker-Morgan: The H Year: 2010's Wins, Fails and Mehs</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Welcome to The H's look back at 2010. We've broken down the events of the year by what
        The H thinks was <ulink url="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Full+of+win"
          >full of win</ulink>, who was getting on the <ulink
          url="http://failblog.org/2008/04/17/failboat-down-to-business/">failboat</ulink> and what
        made us just say <quote><ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Meh">Meh</ulink></quote>.
        From the corporate giants and how they handled open source and the community to the battle
        to be the best browser, and from the best new open source to the worst mis-steps in the
        community.</para>
      <para>(...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 3.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://fsfe.org/about/overview2010.en.html">fsfe.org: FSFE's year 2010 - a
          letter from the President</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="italic">We have had an eventful year, and a good one. In the following
          text you will find background links to our various activities. Please take this
          opportunity to get a much more complete picture of our present and future work for Free
          Software</emphasis></para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Awards and recognition for FSFE's work</emphasis></para>
      <para>We celebrated not one, but two awards this year. In May, <ulink
          url="http://fsfe.org/news/2010/news-20100126-01.en.html">FSFE received the Theodor Heuss
          Medal</ulink>. During a grand ceremony with numerous German political luminaries in
        Stuttgart in May, Ludwig Heuss, Director of the Theodor Heuss Foundation, praised FSFE's
        work for freedom in the information society: </para>
      <para><quote>Free Software Foundation Europe receives the Theodor Heuss Medal 2010 because it
          competently contributes to creating new rules for social, political and legal conditions
          for digital freedom through Free Software.</quote></para>
      <para>A week earlier, on the 28th of April, FSFE's founding President <ulink
          url="http://fsfe.org/news/2010/news-20100428-01.en.html">Georg Greve was awarded the
          German Federal Cross of Merit</ulink> (Bundesverdienstkreuz) in recognition of his great
        achievements in promoting Free Software with FSFE. To our knowledge, this is the first time
        that any country in the world bestows such an honour on any Free Software activist. This is
        a well-deserved reward for many years of hard work. Congratulations, Georg! (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 3.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.groklaw.net/article.php?story=http://itmanagement.earthweb.com/osrc/article.php/3919321/Switching-to-Linux-For-the-Right-Reasons.htm"
          >internet.com/Matt Hartley: Switching to Linux (For the Right Reasons)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Why are you using Linux on your desktop? </para>
      <para>Before answering this question, consider the advantages and disadvantages and then come
        back full circle to your own motivation for using Linux. Nearly every week, I find my news
        feeds filled with the usual generic articles describing rather vanilla reasons for using
        Linux on the desktop. </para>
      <para>Why do I have a problem with this? Perhaps because the reasons often being shared are
        just echoes of other opinions that clearly aren't that of the author. Instead, we are
        reading the thoughts and ideas of many articles since past. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 5.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://www.consortiuminfo.org/standardsblog/article.php?story=20110105174405322"
          >Consortiuminfo/Andy Updegrove: Attachmate and the SUSE Linux Project: What's
          Next?</ulink></title>
      <para>Over the last few months, I've frequently pointed out the vulnerability of important
        open source projects that are supported and controlled by corporate sponsors, rather than
        hosted by independent foundations funded by corporate sponsors. One of the examples I've
        given is SUSE Linux, which has been hosted and primarily supported by Novell since that
        company acquired SuSE Linux AG in 2003. Novell, as you know, is expected to be acquired by a
        company called Attachmate a few weeks from now, assuming approval of the transaction by the
        Novell stockholders and by German competition regulators. </para>
      <para>Recently, the future of the SUSE Linux Project (as compared to the Novell commercial
        Linux distribution based on the work of that project) has become rather murky, as reported
        by Pamela Jones, <ulink url="http://www.groklaw.net/article.php?story=20101227144336645">at
          Groklaw</ulink>. Apparently, Novell is facilitating some sort of spin out of the Project,
        which is good but peculiar news. </para>
      <para>Why peculiar? Because when a company is subject to an agreement of sale, one of the
        requirements the buyer imposes during the sale-pending period is that the seller cannot
        engage in any transactions outside of the ordinary course of business without the consent of
        the acquiror. This makes sense, because once the buyer has committed to a price, it doesn't
        want the value of any of the assets it is purchasing to fall. That means that one would
        expect that Novell would at minimum be abstaining from taking any action in connection with
        any effort to move the project out and into an independent entity. (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/security/news/item/Phrack-hole-closed-in-ProFTPD-1156782.html">h-online: Phrack hole closed in ProFTPD </ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The development team behind <ulink url="http://www.proftpd.org/">ProFTPD</ulink> has
        released version <ulink url="http://www.proftpd.org/docs/RELEASE_NOTES-1.3.3d">1.3.3d</ulink>, which closes a critical security hole in the SQL module of all previous
        versions. The flaw was <ulink url="http://www.phrack.org/issues.html">reported</ulink>
        roughly a month ago in Phrack, the hacker magazine. A buffer overflow in the function
        sql_prepare_where() allows attackers to remotely execute arbitrary code on the server. The
        developers themselves suffered when this vulnerability was exploited by still unknown
        parties, who entered the project server and <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/news/item/Back-door-in-ProFTPD-FTP-server-1146592.html">installed</ulink> a back door in the source code.</para>
      <para>The new version also fixes a number of additional <ulink url="http://www.proftpd.org/docs/NEWS-1.3.3d">bugs</ulink>; as a result, the GPL-licensed
        server is reportedly now more stable. At the same time, the developers have also published
        the first release candidate for version <ulink url="http://www.proftpd.org/docs/RELEASE_NOTES-1.3.4rc1">1.3.4</ulink>. (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
  <sect2>
    <title>LOL</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://e-tote-kala.blogspot.com/2011/01/first-joke-of-year-if-operating-systems.html">Kostas Koudaras: First Joke of the year: If Operating Systems Ran The Airlines</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The first joke of the year :-)
      </para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.pcworld.com/article/214710/15_crazy_japanese_tech_gizmos.html">PCWorld/Jeff Bertolucci: 15 Crazy Japanese Tech Gizmos</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The Japanese have proven their techie prowess over the decades. Where would we be
        without the transistor radio, the camcorder, or the Sony Walkman? But sometimes they jump
        the technological shark with whimsical and weird gear, some of which is downright loopy.
        Here are our favorite examples of oddball tech that could be made only in Japan.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 7.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
