<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
  %myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="kernel">
  <title>Kernel Review</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/Kernel-Log-Coming-in-2-6-38-Part-1-Graphics-1176900.html"
        >h-online/Thorsten Lemmhuis: Kernel Log: Coming in 2.6.38 (Part 1) – Graphics</ulink>
    </title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Kernel version 2.6.38 supports AMD's new Fusion CPUs and offers 2D
        and 3D acceleration with many current GeForce and Radeon graphics cards. Power economy for
        the graphics cores in Intel processors and chip-sets has been improved; new page flipping
        features aim to eradicate image flickering, tearing and incomplete rendering issues.
      </emphasis></para>
    <para>Less than five days after <ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/news/item/Main-development-phase-of-Linux-kernel-2-6-38-completed-1171565.html"
        >closing the 2.6.38 merge window</ulink>, Linus Torvalds has already <ulink
        url="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.kernel/1090573">issued</ulink> the second release
      candidate of Linux 2.6.38. Last Saturday's fast follow-up wasn't due to a major flaw in
      2.6.38-rc1; it had more mundane reasons. On Sunday, Torvalds travelled to this year's <ulink
        url="http://lca2011.linux.org.au/">Linux.conf.au</ulink> (LCA), which, despite the flooding,
      is being held in Brisbane this week. Before travelling, Torvalds wanted to test whether he had
      installed all the kernel development and release components he needed on the computer he
      intended to take. </para>
    <para>In his release email, Torvalds indicated that he will now be stricter and disallow
      anything that doesn't explicitly promote stability; any further major changes will have to
      wait until release .39. The current development state of 2.6.38 is, therefore, unlikely to
      differ much from the final release expected in late March or early April. </para>
    <para>The Kernel Log is therefore already in a position to provide a comprehensive overview of
      the most important new features of release .38. As usual, we will split the information into
      several articles which will eventually cover the various functional areas of the kernel. The
      first part of the "Coming in 2.6.38" mini series describes the changes to the kernel's
      graphics hardware support; over the coming weeks, further articles will cover advances in
      terms of network support, storage hardware, file systems, drivers, architecture code, and
      kernel infrastructure. (...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 26.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
