<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="forums">
  <title>openSUSE Forums</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/other-forums/news-announcements/tech-news/457543-gnome-3-0-here.htmlhttp://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/install-boot-login/458607-windows-opensuse-11-4-dual-boot-problem.html">Windows and openSuse 11.4 dual boot problem</ulink></title>
    <para>
      Dual booting is still very popular. It allows you to use different operating systems for different tasks. Most of the times this works out of the box. However, there are situations, where users cannot access both operating systems, or can access only one of them. In the thread from the title a user cannot manage to get a working situation for his Win7 and openSUSE 11.4, read ahead to see what possible solutions are available.
    </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/install-boot-login/456493-opensuse-11-4-install-hard-drive-like-usb.html">Opensuse 11.4 install from Hard Drive Like usb</ulink></title>
    <para>
      The last couple of years we've seen an increase of devices that do not have a CD/DVD drive, so installing from traditional media is not possible. This issue was met by using technology that allows copying the install media images to USB devices, which can be used to install on CD/DVD driveless machines. Here we have a user that wants to use an extra internal hard disk to install from. Is this possible? The answer is yes, read the thread to find out how it's done.
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/applications/458529-gnome-3-11-4-known-issues-workarounds.html">Gnome 3 and 11.4 Known Issues and Workarounds</ulink></title>
    <para>
      Now that GNOME 3 is here, and packages for openSUSE 11.4 have been officially released and approved, we see that some users have issues / problems after upgrading. One of our members started a thread to gather these issues / problems and collect workarounds / solutions for those. Although it's far from complete, the thread is giving a good impression of what one can expect when upgrading to GNOME 3. The time does not seem to be ready yet for KDE users that have GNOME installed as well to perform an upgrade yet. We'll follow the developments and let you know.
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/install-boot-login/458706-upgrade-suse-linux-9-2-opensuse-11-4-a.html">Upgrade SUSE Linux 9.2 to OpenSUSE 11.4?</ulink></title>
    <para>
      This title describes a returning question: Can I upgrade version X to version Y. In general, one could say, that this is possible, if versions are not too far apart. In this case: No. Development in linux has made giant leaps forward in such a way, that doing what's suggested in the title would and will only lead to massive trouble. Read the thread to see why.
      </para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 28.04.2011 gl $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
