<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="tipsandtricks">
  <title>Tips and Tricks</title>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Desktop Users</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://www.techrepublic.com/blog/opensource/how-to-use-calibre-to-access-your-ebook-collection-online/2275">techrepublic.com/Jack Wallen: How to use Calibre to access your ebook collection online</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Takeaway</emphasis>: Calibre is one of the most powerful ebook managers available. But did you know that Calibre has a built in server that 
      allows you to access your library from a web browser? In this how-to, Jack Wallen shows you how to set up Calibre to serve up your book library.</para>
      <para>I have been in near-saturation mode with ebooks lately, due to the publishing of my own works of fiction (find them on <ulink url="http://amzn.to/hmXIQN">Amazon</ulink>, 
        <ulink url="http://bit.ly/e8coZL">Barnes &amp; Noble</ulink>, and <ulink url="http://bit.ly/e553VF">Smashwords</ulink>). For many indie writers/publishers and readers of 
        ebooks the challenge of managing a vast collection of works can be a bit overwhelming (thanks to the ereaders’ insufficient built-in book management tools). Thankfully there 
        are tools available for the PC to help you manage those collections.</para>
      <para>Naturally Linux is not left out of this mix. The <ulink url="http://calibre-ebook.com/">Calibre</ulink> ebook manager is one of the best tools of the trade I have 
        found for managing ebooks. And for administrators looking for ways to convert and add books, PDFs, howtos, etc. to an ereader for portable reading, Calibre is exactly 
        the tool you need. Let’s take a look at this tool and how you can benefit from using it. (...)</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Copyright</emphasis>: <link linkend="extcopyright">1</link></para>
      <tip><para>The Calibre Package can downloaded in the <ulink url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/Documentation:/Tools/">Documentation:Tools Repository</ulink>. 
        Because the Developer uses brand new Libs it is just available for >= 11.4</para></tip>
      <!-- ($ Id: 01.3.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Commandline/Script Newbies</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://bashshell.net/utilities/exercise-6-set-variables-in-scripts/">BashShell.net/Mike: Exercise #6: Set Variables in Scripts</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>When you need to set variables, you can do that in the BEGIN section of an awk script. Here the variable firstuser is set to 1000. The BEGIN section sets that 
      variable and it is then used later in the script. (...)</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Copyright:</emphasis><link linkend="extcopyright">3</link></para>
      <!-- ($ Id: 01.3.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://bashshell.net/script-of-the-week/log-parser/">BashShell.net/Mike: LogParser</ulink></title>
      <para>The idea behind a log parser is to create a loop that will check all of your required logs to return information about specific needs that you may have as an 
        administrator. For example, with this script you may want to search a specific log for one or two text strings that are very important to the function of your 
        system.(...)</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Copyright:</emphasis><link linkend="extcopyright">3</link></para>
      <!-- ($ Id: 01.3.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Developers and Programmers</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://python4kids.wordpress.com/2011/02/24/a-big-jar-of-pickles/">python4kids/Brandan Scott: A Big Jar of Pickle</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>In the last tutorial we learned how to pickle our objects.  Pickling is a way of storing the object (on the computer’s file system) so that it can be used later. 
        This means that if we want to re use an object we can simply save it and load it when we need it, rather than re-creating it each time we want to use it.  This is very 
        useful when our object is a list of questions for our trivia game.  We really only want to type the questions in once and then reload them later.</para>
      <para>Now we need to settle on a way to structure our data.  We saw in our earlier tutorial that each question was a list, and that the list itself had a certain 
        structure.  We also need to think about how a number of questions will be stored.  We will use a list to do that as well!  In this case we will have a list of questions. 
        Each of the elements in the list will itself be a list. Let’s build one. First we make an empty list to store all the questions: (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ Id: 1.3.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For System Administrators</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/02/19/atiamd-fglrx-catalyst-for-opensuse/"
          >Bruno Friedmann: ATI/AMD fglrx 8.821 Catalyst 11.2 available for openSUSE 11.2, 11.3,
          11.4</ulink>
      </title>
      <note>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is licensed under the <ulink
              url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/fdl.txt">GNU Free Documentation
            License.</ulink></emphasis></para>
      </note>
      <para>"<emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="underline">Preambule : free
          software</emphasis></emphasis>
      </para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Warning</emphasis>
        </emphasis></para>
      <para>I would notice everybody which will install these software : you will install
        proprietary softwares on your computer. Nobody will be able to debug them, nor help you to
        resolve what can be happen. That must be said !</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">The free future </emphasis></para>
      <para>The real future is already in place : it’s called radeon (or free-radeon), it’s fully
        integrated in kernel &amp; xorg. Actually ( for openSUSE 11.4, or openSUSE 11.3 with <ulink
          url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/Kernel:/stable/openSUSE_11.3/"
          >kernel-stable</ulink> + <ulink
          url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/X11:/XOrg/openSUSE_11.3/">X11 obs
          repo</ulink> ). Support for many chipset is in real progress even for the 6xxx series.
        Give it a try before using the proprietary software, report any bugs you find with it. Only
        your contributions can help and will make a real differences. Thanks for doing that !</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Unofficial but working repository </emphasis></para>
      <para>I offer for those of you that for any reasons can’t use successfully the free-radeon
        drivers a repository where you will find the latest fglrx/catalyst drivers following the
        packaging policy made avalaible by AMD. Thanks to Sebastian Siebert ( check his blog ) to
        work in coordination with ati/amd and follow the catalyst packaging. His work allow us to
        have that driver available for openSUSE.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">The quick how-to</emphasis>
        </emphasis></para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="underline">Adding the
          repository</emphasis></emphasis>
      </para>
      <para/>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">For openSUSE
      11.4</emphasis><screen>zypper ar -c -f -n "ATI/AMD fglrx non-official" \\
        http://linux.ioda.net/mirror/ati/openSUSE_11.4/ "ATI/AMD FGLRX"
</screen></para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">For openSUSE
      11.3</emphasis><screen>zypper ar -c -f -n "ATI/AMD fglrx non-official" \\
        http://linux.ioda.net/mirror/ati/openSUSE_11.3/ "ATI/AMD FGLRX"</screen></para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">For openSUSE
      11.2</emphasis><screen>zypper ar -c -f -n "ATI/AMD fglrx non-official" \\
        http://linux.ioda.net/mirror/ati/openSUSE_11.2/ "ATI/AMD FGLRX"
</screen></para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="underline">Installing the
          driver</emphasis></emphasis></para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Nota previous version</emphasis></para>
      <para>Due to change in ati/amd way of life, it’s recommanded to completely remove any version
        of fglrx previously installed with a zypper rm </para>
      <para>I can only recommand to also (as root)
        <screen># Remove old conf &amp; stuff
rm -fr /etc/ati
# Remove any old fglrx inside kernel modules
find /lib/modules -type f -iname "flgrx.ko" -exec rm -fv {} \;</screen></para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">New installation</emphasis>
      </para>
      <para>Once the repo has been added, you will certainly have to reboot to get ride off free
        radeon module. At boot on the grub line
        add<screen>nomodeset blacklist=radeon 3</screen></para>
      <para>Don’t panic you will be land to a console, open it with root account to install fglrx.
        Search the software you want for example under openSUSE 11.4
        <screen>zypper se -s fglrx
Loading repository data...
Reading installed packages...

S | Name                  | Type    | Version | Arch   | Repository
--+-----------------------+---------+---------+--------+-----------
  | fglrx64_7_6_0_SUSE114 | package | 8.812-1 | x86_64 | ATI/AMD fglrx non-official
i | fglrx64_xpic_SUSE114  | package | 8.821-1 | x86_64 | ATI/AMD fglrx non-official
  | fglrx_7_6_0_SUSE114   | package | 8.812-1 | i586   | ATI/AMD fglrx non-official
  | fglrx_xpic_SUSE114    | package | 8.821-1 | i586   | ATI/AMD fglrx non-official</screen></para>
      <para>Starting with 8.821 (Catalyst 11.2) ATI use now xpic (full explanation) So use that
        one.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">For a 64bits
        version</emphasis><screen>zypper in fglrx64_xpic_SUSE114</screen></para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">For a 32bits
        version</emphasis><screen>zypper in fglrx_xpic_SUSE114</screen></para>
      <para>During the installation process, all the dependencies will be added, which mostly are
        needed to build the kernel modules. Expect around 200MB to dowload. </para>
      <para>Then the installer will build the module for your installed kernel. And if there’s a
        kernel update, the script will automagically detect that, and will rebuild the module for
        the new kernel installed. (So if you find that your workstation is slow on reboot just press
        the esc key to see the details … )</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Preparing xorg to use fglrx </emphasis></para>
      <para>Once the module is build and installed, you should have a file fglrx.conf or
        50-fglrx.conf in
        /etc/modprobe.d<screen>cat /etc/modprobe.d/50-fglrx.conf
blacklist radeon</screen></para>
      <para>Next ati recommend to use ati –initial-config but that break the auto-detect stack of
        xorg. So I recommend changing one line in file /etc/X11/xorg.conf.d/50-device.conf </para>
      <para>just change driver line to driver “fglrx” </para>
      <para>All the rest of the setup (double screen etc) will be made lately with the ati catalyst
        control center (command is amdcccle). </para>
      <para>For those of you which want to have an xorg.conf file just have a look at aticonfig
        –help command.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Start X</emphasis>
      </para>
      <para>If you are inside the console we start to use before just run “init 5″ to start xorg,
        and normally you will find your normal xorg login screen (kdm, gdm, ldm, xdm). Hit
        ctrl+alt+f1 to return to the console and type exit or logout or ctrl+d to close it. then
        ctrl+alt+f7 to return to the xorg session.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Updates </emphasis></para>
      <para>ati/amd catalyst are release on a month basis, but this vary from 3 weeks to 8 weeks.<itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para> Catalyst 11.2 – fglx 8.821 : 14 February 2011 </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">References </emphasis><itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink
                url="http://www.sebastian-siebert.de/2011/02/15/opensuse-11-3-proprietaeren-grafik-treiber-ati-catalyst-11-2-als-rpm-installieren/"
                >Sebastian Siebert blog ( German )</ulink> with nice howto and problem
              resolution.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/?p=4673">My previous post on the
                subject</ulink> "</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 20.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://ironman.darthgibus.net/?p=113">Fred Blaise: Alfresco 3.4d ldap
          sync</ulink></title>
      <para>While upgrading from 3.3g to 3.4d, my ldap sync wouldn’t work anymore. </para>
      <para>I had to add in my ldap-ad-authentication.properties the following
        line:<screen>ldap.synchronization.java.naming.security.authentication=simple</screen></para>
      <para>While there is a similar line for authentication, it doesn’t do it for sync’ing
        up.<screen>ldap.authentication.java.naming.security.authentication=simple</screen></para>
      <!--($ ld: 22.2.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.howtoforge.com/how-to-install-railo-3.2-under-opensuse-11.3-running-apache2-tomcat6-virtual-host"
          >HowtoForge/wintel2006: How To Install Railo 3.2 Under OpenSUSE 11.3 Running Apache2
          Tomcat 6 Virtual Host</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>&quot;Railo Server 3.2 Final. (3.2.1.000) has been released. As you know Railo is an
        Open Source ColdFusion Markup Language (CFML) engine. It is free and pretty fast. </para>
      <para>For the new 3.2 version railo stop running resin, but tomcat as the default web server. </para>
      <para>Instead of compile apache2 with tomcat 6 by yourself, the railo team had created the
        default installation script which help you setup railo on tomcat6 and using apache2 to
        connect to tomcat via mod_jk. Instead of using tomcat default webapps directory, we will
        modify the server.xml file and DocumentRoot will point back to default apache DocumentRoot
        directory defined under the virtual host configuration file. </para>
      <para>The server is running OpenSUSE 11.3 (i386) on vmware player, and we need apache2 and
        Java installed before you run tomcat/railo service. (...)&quot;</para>
      <!-- ($ Id: 26.2.11 sat $)-->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
