<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="community">
  <title>In the Community</title>
  <!--Put here things relevant to the openSUSE community maybe from * People of openSUSE or elections, votings 1 - 2 posts-->
  <sect2>
    <title>Postings from the Community</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blog.karlitschek.de/2011/01/2-amazing-meetings-to-change-world.html"
          >Frank Karlitschek: 2 amazing meetings to change the world</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Last week I attended two very interesting developer sprints at the SUSE office in
        Nürnberg. </para>
      <para>More and more people in the Linux world realize that a nice application installer
        (Application Store) is needed to make the Linux platform more attractive for normal users
        and third party developers. The current package managers expose way to much complexity to
        the end users. The normal users doesn´t care about dependencies, libraries and other
        internals. But the user cares about things like screenshots, description texts, ratings.
        tags, comments, recommendation from friends and other features which current package
        managers don´t provide. So the idea grow to build a better tool for finding and installing
        applications which sits on top of the current package management. </para>
      <para>It´s part of the Bretzn project to build something like this. The first sprint last week
        brought people from all major Linux distributions on one table to discuss ways to work
        together to build a common application installer API and infrastructure. Developers from
        RedHat, Fedora, Debian, Ubuntu, openSUSE, Mandriva and Mageia met and discussed ways to make
        this happen. After 2 and a half days we all agreed on an architecture and we will work in
        the next few month to bring this to all majors distributions. I´m happy that OCS was chosen
        as the standard API to access App Store Servers. </para>
      <para>The second sprint was the Bretzn sprint which took place directly afterwards and was all
        about coding. </para>
      <para>Several people from openSUSE and KDE met to build a proof of concept implementation of
        an Application Store for openSUSE and KDE. </para>
      <para>This second sprint was also super productive so after another weekend we have a basic
        App Store client together with a server running. </para>
      <para>All the basic features are in place and it just needs a bit more polishing. </para>
      <para>There is a news story coming up with some more information and screenshots. So stay
        tuned if you are looking for more information. :-)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 24.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://nowwhatthe.blogspot.com/2011/01/opensuse-in-netherlands.html">Jos
          Poortvliet: openSUSE in the Netherlands</ulink></title>
      <para>In May, the dutch "HCC" computerclub will organize a Linux day. They have asked me if
        I'd be willing to give a talk there - cool, I can do that. And if I could also set up and
        staff a booth. Slightly harder to do that on my own - so I hereby would like to ask any
        dutch openSUSE users who are willing to help out to contact me! </para>
      <para>Maybe we can do more than only that booth, there are plenty of events in the Netherlands
        and of course we should organize a openSUSE 11.4 release event to get to know each other! </para>
      <para>Talking about local openSUSE, <ulink
          url="http://gihyo.jp/magazine/SD/archive/2011/201102">look at this site</ulink> and find
        the openSUSE article by HeliosRed :D</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 26.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://nowwhatthe.blogspot.com/2011/01/lca-on-friday.html">Jos Poortvliet:
          LCA on Friday</ulink></title>
      <para>Still at Linux Conf Australia. Have new pictures, see below. A few notes:<itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>I spoke with some local Novell/SUSE people - and we made a deal that we'll work
              more together to <emphasis role="bold">promote openSUSE in Down Under</emphasis>.
              Sorely needed, our technology can contribute a lot to the work people here are doing.
              And I bet we can learn a thing or two too... </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Yesterday I attended talks about <emphasis role="bold">Koji (Red Hat build system)
                and Fedora</emphasis>. Koji - let's just say we need to communicate <ulink
                url="http://build.opensuse.org">OBS</ulink> a lot better. Will make the lives of
              many sysadmins quite a bit easier. Seriously, Koji is nice but: command line only (web
              interface just monitors and can restart tasks); runs on local hardware and thus only
              builds for your own architecture; doesn't really support building for other distro's -
              surely not Ubuntu and Debian like OBS can do; you can't just point it to a SVN or Git
              repository - no, first have to create source RPM's by hand. And there's more - just
              showing how awesome OBS really is. I do think OBS needs a name change - to something
              like Open Build Service. To make clear it ain't just <emphasis role="bold">openSUSE
                specific!</emphasis></para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>The Fedora talk was also interested and the Fedora Project Lead is a cool dude. I
              spend some time with him during the Penguin Dinner and he invited me to a cross-distro
              discussion panel at FOSDEM together with the Debian project lead. We seem to be very
              much on the same page and I look greatly forward to that!</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>The Friday keynote by <ulink url="http://markpesce.com/">Mark Pesce</ulink> was
              awesome, be sure to to check the video's on <ulink
                url="http://blip.tv/search?q=lca2011">blip</ulink>! There is an upload/network
              issue, so they won't be there anytime soon, unfortunately. He spoke about <emphasis
                role="bold">freedom, mesh networking, facebook and more</emphasis>. Oh and it's 18+
              rated - including juicy quotes on <emphasis role="bold">Steve Jobs</emphasis> you
              don't want to miss! </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
      <para>All in all - great day which isn't over yet. I'll be giving a <emphasis role="bold">90
          sec lightning talk</emphasis> at the closing ceremony, showing off the <emphasis
          role="bold">awesomeness of SUSE Studio</emphasis>. Mostly due to that being the only thing
        I could whip together into a PDF quick enough - ImageMagick's "convert" tool to the rescue!
        But it will give a taste to people, show them (open)SUSE is more than relevant: you really
        need to some SUSE knowledge on your CV if you want to be a good sysadmin ;-) </para>
      <para>Of course the result will end up on the openSUSE marketing resources page <ulink
          url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Presentations#SUSE_Studio">here</ulink> - I just need
        darix to upload it as the PDF is more than the 2 MB limit.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 27.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>People of openSUSE</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>This Week: xyz</title>
      <para>Good Guy. Glows in the night.</para>
    </blockquote>
    </sect2> -->
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Welcome new openSUSE Members</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/fcrozat">Frederic Crozat (fcrozat)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Very active in the openSUSE GNOME Team and Bugzilla.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/helen-au">Helen South
        (helen-au)</ulink></title>
      <para>Helen works inside Marketing and the Editor Team of news.opensuse.org.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/dominian">Matt Hayes
        (dominian)</ulink></title>
      <para>Active in Bugzilla, Wiki and Mailinglists.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/tsotsos">Angelos Tzotsos
        (tsotsos)</ulink></title>
      <para>Active inside the Greek Community and Marketing.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/bekun">Kai-Uwe Behrmann
        (bekun)</ulink></title>
      <para>Kai-Uwe serves as Speaker, Boothman and Developer for the openSUSE Project.</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Events &amp; Meetings</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Past</title>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/01/11/opensuse-gnome-team-meeting-22/"
            >January 20, 2011 : openSUSE GNOME Team meeting</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Upcoming</title>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/01/19/hackweek-vi-2/">January 24, 2011 :
            Hackweek VI</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/05/13/%ef%bb%bfopensuse-kde-team-meeting/"
            >January 27, 2011 : ﻿openSUSE KDE Team meeting</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink
            url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/01/20/21st-opensuse-testing-core-team-irc-meeting/"
            >January 31, 2011 : 21st openSUSE Testing Core Team IRC Meeting</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <!-- ($ ld: 21.01.10 th $) -->
    <para>You can find more informations on other events at: <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/category/events/">openSUSE News/Events</ulink>. - <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Ambassadors_events">Local Events</ulink></para>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>openSUSE for your Ears</title>
    <para>The openSUSE Weekly News are available as livestream or podcast in German. You can hear it
      or download it on <ulink url="http://blog.radiotux.de/podcast">Radiotux</ulink>. </para>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>From Ambassadors</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://stick.gk2.sk/blog/2011/01/gnome-python-hackfest-appinstaller-meeting-and-bretzn-hackfest/"
          >Pavol Rusnak: GNOME Python Hackfest, AppInstaller Meeting and Bretzn Hackfest</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>What a cool and productive week! But let me start from the beginning … </para>
      <para>A couple of months ago we decided to start a <ulink
          url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hackerspace">hackerspace</ulink> in Prague called <ulink
          url="http://brmlab.cz/">brmlab</ulink>. Most of the members deal with hardware, but there
        are also couple of software guys like me. At the end of November we were contacted by <ulink
          url="http://blog.tomeuvizoso.net/">Tomeu</ulink> and he asked if they can organize <ulink
          url="http://live.gnome.org/Hackfests/Python2011">GNOME Python Hackfest</ulink> in our
        hackerspace. I was more than delighted about the idea, so we agreed and started to plan
        things. In the end we had 9 FOSS hackers working on GNOME and Python and I think they
        enjoyed their time in Prague. Hackerspace is a great concept, because these folks didn’t
        have to spend extra money on renting some place and our members had opportunity to meet
        foreign FOSS developers and try exotic hardware like <ulink
          url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OLPC_XO-1">OLPC XO-1</ulink>.</para>
      <figure id="fig.blogpost">
        <title>Blogposts from <ulink
            url="http://blog.tomeuvizoso.net/2010/12/python-gnome-hackfest-2011.html">Tomeu</ulink>
          and <ulink url="http://www.j5live.com/2011/01/19/pygi-in-prague/">J5</ulink> about the
          event</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://stick.gk2.sk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/gnome-python-1.jpg"
              width="25%" align="center"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>I had to leave the guys on Tuesday evening, because I spent the rest of the week in SUSE
        office in Nuernberg. The first three days were dedicated to <ulink
          url="http://distributions.freedesktop.org/wiki/Meetings/AppInstaller2011"
          >Cross-distribution meeting</ulink> about application installer organized by <ulink
          url="http://www.vuntz.net/journal/">Vincent</ulink>. It went more than well, we discussed
        and agreed on many things, which is great and in the end we were able to give a <ulink
          url="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BHeP2ZBwS_U">presentation</ulink> + we also created a
          <ulink url="http://distributions.freedesktop.org/wiki/AppStream">nice AppStream
          wikipage</ulink> as a starting point for any future work.</para>
      <figure id="fig.summary">
        <title>Vincent wrote a nice summary for <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/">openSUSE
            News</ulink>. (It is not yet there, but should appear soon.)</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://stick.gk2.sk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/appstream_meeting.jpg"
              width="25%" align="center"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>This meeting was immediately followed by <ulink
          url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:2011_Bretzn_Meeting">Bretzn hackfest</ulink>
        organized by <ulink url="http://blog.karlitschek.de/">Frank</ulink>. The main focus of it
        was implementing some of the things we agreed on previous meeting from the KDE/Qt
        perspective and porting MeeGo Garage to openSUSE. During it I was mainly dealing with
        appdata.xml format we described in the AppStream meeting – I created an XML schema so we can
        validate it and also developed a proof-of-concept generator of this piece of metadata in
        Python. (<ulink url="http://gitorious.org/appstream">git repo</ulink>) Hope we can get it in
        createrepo and dpkg-scan* utilities soon.</para>
      <figure id="fig.planetsuse">
        <title>Frank’s summary about the hackfest will appear on <ulink
            url="http://planet.opensuse.org/">Planet openSUSE</ulink> soon</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="http://stick.gk2.sk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/DSC_1674.jpg"
              width="25%" align="center"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>I would like to thank GNOME Foundation and Collabora for sponsoring the GNOME Python
        Hackfest, Novell for sponsoring the Bretzn Hackfest and Canonical, Debian, Mageia, Novell
        and Red Hat for sending their people to AppInstaller Meeting! It’s really nice and
        encouraging to see folks from various companies working on one common goal.</para>
      <para>And yeah,</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://stick.gk2.sk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/going-to.png"
            width="10%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>so see you there!</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 24.01.10 th $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://opensuseambassadors.blogspot.com/2011/01/greek-customs-new-years-pie.html"
          >Greek openSUSE Ambassadors: Greek Customs (New Year's Pie)</ulink></title>
      <para>Here in Greece we celebrate the new year except from gifts but also by cutting a New
        Year's Pie where inside there is a coin hidden. Whoever finds it wins a special gift and is
        meant to be lucky the new year. A local Linux User Group located in Volos called Volug and
        LinuxTeam Teilar in Larisa which both teams consist of colleagues had two small parties for
        cutting the New Year's Pie. I was there to celebrate with those people and inform them about
        openSUSE and openSUSE community. They were all interested about openSUSE distribution. I
        answered many questions about Tumbleweed and Evergreen and informed them about our new 11.4
        and OBS as many of them where interested about the work that is done by openSUSE community
        and by the Greek Community. I had some cds/dvds and posters with me which i gave them. In
        the future we will make some events together. Unfortunately we did not took any pictures. I
        would slightly have won the hidden coin at the first party but the next person got it. </para>
      <para>Photo of the New Year's Pie</para>
      <figure id="fig.pie">
        <title>Happy New Year All!!!!</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_jdKLYe7Jeds/TT2yTD-TOII/AAAAAAAAADc/mjbWhEdAlxo/s1600/5360749563_455c17fa19.jpg"
              width="25%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para><ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/User:Etern4L">George Bratsos aka
        Etern4L</ulink></para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 24.01.10 th $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Communication</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/">The Mailinglists</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org">The openSUSE Forums</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Contributors</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://users.opensuse.org">The User Directory</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
