<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://ungethym.blogspot.com/2011/02/google-code-in-my-summary.html">Thomas Thym:
        Google Code In – My Summary</ulink>
    </title>
    <figure id="fig.mensch">
      <title>(C) by Wade Olsen</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_uRmToxm-PAQ/TU6wEtbe6YI/AAAAAAAAACs/YPv8edxeXZ0/s1600/560184_16070576_large.png"/>
        </imageobject>        
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>    
    <para>It was my first time I mentored a couple of students <xref linkend="fig.mensch"/>during a Google sponsored project. It
      was possible to submit non-coding tasks as well. So I focused on promo stuff. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Results </emphasis></para>
    <para>Over all I submitted ten tasks (nine could be closed). </para>
    <para>The first block of tasks (solved by Todor Stoyanov and Paul) was about the creation of a
        <ulink url="http://community.kde.org/Promo/Material/OpenContent">free/open content
        collection</ulink> that could be shown during demos and presentations or could be integrated
      into live CD/DVDs. </para>
    <para>The second block of task was covering KDE and FLOSS in the area of education (solved by
      TheOne and Giannis Konstantinidis). It started with a <ulink
        url="http://community.kde.org/Promo/SchoolSurvey">survey of needs of students</ulink>,
        <ulink url="http://community.kde.org/Promo/SchoolSurveyResult">doing the survey</ulink>,
        <ulink url="http://community.kde.org/Promo/Schools/StudentTasks">analyzing student
        tasks</ulink> and ended with a <ulink url="http://community.kde.org/Promo/Schools">concept
        for students</ulink> how to promote KDE and FLOSS at their school (incl. <ulink
        url="http://dl.dropbox.com/u/6538846/KDE_marketing_material.zip">promo material</ulink> e.g.
        <ulink url="http://dl.dropbox.com/u/6538846/KDE_poster.tar.gz">a poster</ulink>, <ulink
        url="http://www.google-melange.com/gci/work_submission/download_blob?key=AMIfv94cKKVFpAA8e706_2J1ACCc8MoqCqhBAWjiABsEpIzGtTuq9VwmxwFuwODmAadK2XMV1RKEjIGCAH2i87BN6z29AhGH_4i-SRjme1fHwknxKtrN1OZo1TQjvp7XZlYmeZyQZtDJexAQsHkRVScJdEvIjXQ7Ew"
        >presentation</ulink>, <ulink url="http://community.kde.org/Promo/Schools/TalkingPoints"
        >talking points</ulink> for students etc.). One of the students is going to test it within
      his school. Isn't that rocking? </para>
    <para>I truly believe that KDE and FLOSS (esp. KDE EDU and the openSUSE based Desktop4Education
      and Server4Education projects) have so much to offer for schools and students. We should do
      even more in this area. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Challenges </emphasis></para>
    <para>For me it was very difficult to set the level and the time needed to fulfill the task when
      I was submitting it. It depends so much on the skills and the age of the student. The task to
      find free music and test it with Amarok (support for CD cover, lyrics and Wikipedia
      information) would be easy for a student with installed KDE and with some experiences with
      free and open stuff. A student new to the open source world will need days to work out that
      (for him) difficult task. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Summary</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>All in all it was much more work than I expected, on the other side it was a wonderful
      experience to see how the students developed themselves over time (and how fast the tasks were
      taken). It was a great success and I am looking forward to the next time. </para>
    <para>@my students: Thanks for your contribution. It was a great pleasure to work with you.
      Let's keep in touch. Let's keep on rocking the world!</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 7.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
