<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 id="gsoc" role="gsoc">
  <title>Google Summer of Code</title>
  <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
      <imagedata fileref="http://michal.hrusecky.net/wp-content/uploads/GSoC2011_300x200.png"
        width="20%" align="center"/>
    </imageobject>
  </mediaobject>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://rxvl.in/post/6688635893">Ratan Sebastian: GSOC 2011: ssc - Week
        4</ulink></title>
    <para>The DirectoryManager module has been polished and it now handles duplicate entries in the
      software and repositories files. The app now handles errors better and crashes more gracefully
      with meaningful error messages. As for functionality, I’ve added package banning and
      unbanning. Also package importing has been included in the current release.</para>
    <para>I’ve started work on the file handling of the app. Currently it works similar to the
      packages or repositories with the difference that the file in question is copied over to
      &lt;appliance_directory&gt;/files. Adding and removing these files will be simple enough
      within the current framework. And with some work time-stamp information can be incorporated to
      do more efficient syncs. I hope to have that done by next week and follow up with a basic
      implementation of the commit command in the week after that so that we can have a first usable
      version of the client.</para>
    <para>If you want to check out the application now, you can take it for a spin using <ulink
        url="http://dl.dropbox.com/u/546252/ssc_releases/ssc-0.1.0.gem">the gem</ulink>. Use with
      caution, and all that. It shouldn’t do anything catastrophic, but, I wouldn’t use it with
      anything other than a test appliance at this point. Download it from <ulink
        url="http://dl.dropbox.com/u/546252/ssc_releases/ssc-0.1.0.gem">here</ulink>. Install it
      with <ulink url="http://rubygems.org">rubygems</ulink> (gem install ssc-0.1.0.gem) and run ssc
      help to see the usage instructions.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 20.6.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://rxvl.in/post/6481353758/gsoc-2011-ssc-week-3">Marcus Hüwe: [gsoc] osc code
        cleanup – summary of week 4</ulink></title>
    <para>here’s a small summary of the 4th (coding) week. I spent most of the time with writing the
      RemoteFile classes and the BuildResult class (+ testcases of course:) ).</para>
    <para>TODO for this week:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>improve RemoteFile classes</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>add APIInfo class:</para>
        <para> - resolve url-like parameters (api://foo/bar repo/arch)</para>
        <para> - raise an exception if required parameters are missing</para>
        <para> - initialize optional parameters with the config default</para>
        <para> - encapsulate “context-sensitivity” logic (sometimes parameters should be read from
          the working copy (like apiurl, project or package))</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <!-- ($ ld: 20.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://fridrich.blogspot.com/2011/06/libreoffice-visio-import-filter-shaping.html"
        >Fridrich Strba: LibreOffice Visio import filter - shaping up the baby</ulink></title>
    <para>Maybe you were asking yourself what happened in the Google Summer of Code Visio Import
      filter project since <ulink
        url="http://fridrich.blogspot.com/2011/06/libreoffice-visio-import-filter-first.html">last
        week</ulink>. But even if you did not ask yourself this necessary question, here is some
      update about the baby:</para>
    <para>The focus this week was mainly on shaping the baby up. <ulink
        url="http://www.derivativezero.com/blog/">Eilidh</ulink> added to her blog a photo and an
      "About" line and then she got exhausted and decided to rest by coding. And it is like this
      that she implemented polylines, ellipses and circular arcs.</para>
    <para>And since the images speak louder then any words, enjoy the look: (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 18.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://cbounta.wordpress.com/2011/06/17/a-utility-for-merging-configuration-sysconfig-files-week-4-report/"
        >Christos Bountalis: A utility for merging configuration / sysconfig files – Week 4
        Report</ulink></title>
    <para>This is the 4rth week report, a lot of coding this week, you can see some code on my
      project github under branch working. Yes the code there is still not stable, but I am
      improving it constantly. Till this moment, i didn’t have any feedback except from my mentor,
      so if you check it out and have some suggestion or something, please feel free to contact me. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">What is new in few words?</emphasis></para>
    <para>There have been improvements in many of the functions i did, several new functions have
      been added in my augeas branch repo, i try to split things up as much as possible, to help me
      debug things. </para>
    <para>Functions Changed/Added:</para>
    <para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para> aug_find_lense</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para> aug_load_file</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para> tree_child_sort_label</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para> aug_process_tree</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para> int label_compare</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>merge command in augtool was changed a bit too.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">What is next?</emphasis></para>
    <para>The basic steps for tree matching have already been implemented, the goal now is to finish
      it and actually include the merging functions too. The tree matching is the most complex part
      as far i have understood in this project. By completing it, the other steps in the initial
      schedule will be implemented easier.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 18.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://obsforandroid.wordpress.com/2011/06/17/6-17-2011-weekly-report/"
        >Justine Leng: 6.17.2011 Weekly Report</ulink></title>
    <para>This week, I primarily focused on accumulating community feedback on my <ulink
        url="http://obsforandroid.wordpress.com/2011/06/09/obs-mobile-request-page-makeover/"
        >request page makeover suggestions</ulink>, and refining the features accordingly.</para>
    <para>So based on the limited but helpful user feedback I received, I’ve made the following
      changes: (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 18.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
