<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="forums">
  <title>openSUSE Forums</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/applications/458722-gnome3-configuration.htmll">GNOME 3 configuration</ulink></title>
    <para>
      Well, talking about "different", one could say a lot about GNOME 3, at least one of the things should that it's different. Different compared to GNOME 2, compared to the other linux desktops as well. It needs some maturing, but it's funcional, and on my laptop it's stable for what I use it for: browsing, mail, work. Then, when we have all that, we want to apply some changes to the look and feel etc. This thread is about how to do this. Our member malcolmlewis is running his feet off to provide GNOME 3 users with advice, support and suggestions on how to configure GNOME 3. I suggest GNOME 3 users to join the forums, and read his contributions in various threads. It brought me a nice and comfortable GNOME 3 experience.
    </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/install-boot-login/458636-can-no-longer-boot-into-opensuse-11-4-after-updating-nvidia-drivers.html">Can no longer boot into OpenSuse 11.4 after updating NVIDIA Drivers </ulink></title>
    <para>
      This thread is a good example of what can happen if users follow instructions for older versions to get video card drivers installed. Configuration files are being generated for the Xorg display server, where these files have become obsolete from openSUSE 11.2 on. A bit of advice before reading the thread: in cases like this, first thing one should do is find the most recent information on the forums.
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/install-boot-login/455350-opensuse-11-4-startup-problems.html">openSUSE 11.4 startup problems</ulink></title>
    <para>
      An ongoing thread with quite a mix of startup troubles using openSUSE 11.4. Probably the title invites people to jump in with their own openSUSE startup problem. Yet a very interesting read, not only if you meet trouble installing openSUSE, but also if you're interested in seeing the community help posters to get things working like they should. Prepare, it's a long read.
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/hardware/458939-cant-mount-my-ext-ntfs-hdd.html">Can't mount my EXT NTFS HDD</ulink></title>
    <para>
<!--       This is one of the threads on this subject. Caused by the latest kernel update, which needs something to be added to a config file. Read the thread and find the solution -->
      </para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 04.05.2011 gl $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
