<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://saigkill.homelinux.net/entry/2011/11/12/plasma-activities-in-balsam-professional"
        >Sascha Manns: Plasma Activities in Balsam Professional</ulink></title>
    <para><inlinegraphic fileref="http://saigkill.homelinux.net/images/preferences-activities.png"/>
      Maybe you&apos;ve noticed this Icon in your Taskbar? But what should you do with this? This i would
      like to tell you in this Blog. </para>
    <para>The Name of this Icon is &quot;Activity Manager&quot; and its job is to organize a &quot;Activity&quot;. But
      whats that? We have this Tool per default in KDE 4.7. But sadly some of us not knowing exactly
      what to to with this. </para>
    <para>The first time who uses a Project this Activities in a constant way, this was the Plasma
      Active Project. </para>
    <para>The Idea is to collect Programs, Documents, Contacts, Pictures, Movies and
      Internet-Bookmarks in a human understandable way. In the real life we&apos;re collecting similar
      things in similar &quot;Mind-Boxes&quot;. The Activities using the same Scheme. </para>
    <para>Let&apos;s guessing we are organizing a Birthday-Party for our Grandma. We need for that Task
      some special Contacts, maybe some Websites with Party-Accesoires, maybe some nice little
      Movies from Grandmas golden times and a Textwriter Program who you can prepare Invitements for
      the Party. </para>
    <para>The Activities can help you know. Creating an new Activity presents a blank Screen. If
      you&apos;re starting an Application like the Writer you can use the share-like-connect Combo to
      make the App available in the present Activity. You can use it to many interesting things.
      (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 15.11.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://jaegerandi.blogspot.com/2011/11/just-three-more-days-until-release-of.html">Andreas Jaeger: What has changed since RC2 in openSUSE 12.1?</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>Just three more days until the release of openSUSE 12.1. Last Friday, 11th of November,
      Coolo declared 12.1 as golden and the openSUSE community is now busy pushing out everything to
      the mirros and reworking the openSUSE web pages for the launch. If you like more information
      about openSUSE 12.1, check the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:12.1">openSUSE 12.1 Portal</ulink>.</para>
    <para>Since the release of RC2 quite a number of bugs have been fixed. During the
      RC phase and especially after the last RC, Coolo pushes for bugs that cannot be fixed with an
      online update, thus bugs that break initial installation, installed defaults and the update
      applets. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 15.11.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://suseserver.de/?p=56">Jörg Stephan: The Packman Repo (cause of sox)</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>This post does not target any server specific issue. But aims on showing you another repo
      wich is not already placed in the official OpenSuse repository.</para>
    <para>This is called Packman <ulink url="http://packman.links2linux.de/">http://packman.links2linux.de/</ulink></para>
    <para>In this repo you
      can find many software pakets which you maybe need. I found the repo while trying to convert
      some of my .ogg files to .mp3. A forum just told me that i could do it just with</para>
    <para>sox file.ogg
      file.mp3 (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 15.11.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://fridrich.blogspot.com/2011/11/it-has-been-long-time-since-i-last-time.html">Fridrich Strba: LibreOffice Visio Import filter: the goodness soon on your desktop</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>It has been a long time since I last time blogged about the LibreOffice Visio import
      filter. My silence did not prevent a pretty cool code from falling gradually into our <ulink url="http://cgit.freedesktop.org/libreoffice/contrib/libvisio/">git repository</ulink>. To the point where now we are working on the last 5% of features that normally
      take the 95% of development time. But, let us see what happened since my <ulink url="http://fridrich.blogspot.com/2011/07/libreoffice-visio-import-filter-round.html">July blog</ulink>:</para>
    <para>First of
      all, <ulink url="http://www.derivativezero.com/blog/">Eilidh</ulink> was busy as a bee and, in the second half of the Google Summer of Code,
      implemented support of stylesheets, stencils and basic text. She also debugged and fixed quite
      a number of imperfections that <ulink url="http://bugware.livejournal.com/">Valek</ulink> found. Frankly speaking, this Google Summer of Code was
      by far the best from my point of view. We managed to achieve a very good fidelity of import
      only in about 3 and half months. Impressive. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 15.11.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://www.oyranos.org/2011/11/scarse-profile-library-warning/">Oyranos: Scarse Profile Library Warning</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>Scarse is a project for profiling scanners under GPL based on Argyll code. It started in
      the old century and became pretty silent, with <ulink url="http://www.oyranos.org/2005/11/scarse-0-4-alpha-released/">the last news dating from 2005</ulink>. The project provides a nice collection of ICC profiles in the <ulink url="http://www.scarse.org/goodies/profiles/">Scarse Profile Library</ulink>, which is now
      used by some open source graphics packages. ICC profiles referring to standards are used to
      describe the exact colorimetry of a colour space. The ICC profiles are used to convert to and
      from other colour spaces in order to exchange with applications, services and customers. It is
      therefore crucial to meet these standards otherwise results will be incorrect right from the
      beginning and might render further colour work damaged. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 17.11.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
</sect1>
