<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
<!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.attachmate.com/Press/PressReleases/attachmate-group-completes-aquisition-of-novell.htm">The Attachmate Group Completes Acquisition of Novell</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">HOUSTON – April 27, 2011</emphasis> – <ulink url="http://www.attachmategroup.com/">The Attachmate Group</ulink> today announced the completion of the acquisition of Novell, Inc., a leader in intelligent workload management, under the terms of the definitive agreement <ulink url="http://www.attachmategroup.com/news/attachmate-corporation-to-acquire-novell-inc.html">disclosed</ulink> on November 22, 2010. Novell will now operate as two separate business units under the Novell® and SUSE® brand names and join Attachmate® and NetIQ® as holdings of The Attachmate Group.

</para>
      <para>The addition of Novell furthers the mission of The Attachmate Group and its ability to support customers’ strategic and tactical business requirements through innovative solutions, quality products, and exceptional service. The Attachmate Group product families now include complementary solutions that range across IT operations management; open source; end user computing and collaboration; host connectivity and legacy modernization; security, identity and compliance management; virtualization and cloud computing; and more. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 30.4.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://futureofopensource.drupalgardens.com/2011-future-open-source-survey">5th Annual North Bridge Future of Open Source Survey 2011</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Who are the top 3 up-and-coming commercial open source software companies?

</para>
      <para>Take 5 minutes to take the survey, make your vote count, answer question 15.

</para>
      <para>Complete the survey &amp; you can register for OSBC with a 20% discount! (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 30.4.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/attachmate-reveals-novell-suse-linux-plans/8771">ZDNet/Steven J. Vaughan-Nichols: Attachmate reveals Novell, SUSE, &amp; Linux Plans</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Now that <ulink url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/novell-deals-done/8755">Attachmate owns Novell</ulink>, what does the formerly obscure company plan to do with its $2.2-billion operating system and networking prize? I interviewed <ulink url="http://www.attachmate.com/">Attachmate</ulink> via e-mail CEO Jeff Hawn and this is what he told me.

</para>
      <para>Before launching into the interview, I’ll note that most of Novell’s senior executive staff won’t be hanging around. Ron Hovsepian; President and CEO; Dana Russell, CFO; John Dragoon,  CMO; and Markus Rex, SVP and General Manager of open platforms and long time SUSE leader have all left. So it is that Attachmate is starting with a clean management slate.</para>
      <para>(...)</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">SJVN</emphasis>: What plans does Attachmate for Novell/SUSE’s open-source offerings? E.g. <ulink url="http://www.opensuse.org/en/">openSUSE</ulink> and <ulink url="http://www.mono-project.com/Main_Page">Mono</ulink>.

</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">JH</emphasis>: SUSE sponsorship and participation in key open-source projects is a fundamental element of the business. This commitment is driven by a desire to contribute to and collaborate with the community in a way that fosters the success of open source technologies overall and creates the greatest value for our customers. The openSUSE project is a great example of vibrant and healthy collaboration. SUSE sponsorship and participation in projects like openSUSE creates great value for the community and also for SUSE customers who benefit from the innovations and advancements we create together. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 30.4.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/Open-source-gaming-or-things-I-do-when-I-should-be-working-1230013.html">h-online/Richard Hillesley: Open source gaming – or things I do when I should be working</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="italic">&quot;What I was proud of was that I used very few parts to build a computer that could actually speak words on a screen and type words on a keyboard and run a programming language that could play games. And I did all this myself&quot;</emphasis>–Steve
        Wozniak</para>
      <para>For some users computer games are little more than <quote>the things I do when I should be working</quote>, a soothing distraction or a waste of time and space. For others games
        are a matter of life and death, the bane of partners, the be all and end all of computing,
        and the reason why we bother. So the addicts are pleased to go out and buy an XBox, a
        Nintendo or a PlayStation 3 rather than a full-blown computer, and are happy to play the
        night away.</para>
      <para>The best games are a learning experience, an exercise in strategic thinking, memory
        retention, what-if scenarios and problem solving – not unlike programming itself. Each piece
        in a game like chess has a limited number of moves, yet the game itself is a world of
        possibilities, and like a chess player, a programmer has to think ahead, so it isn&apos;t really
        surprising that many coders approach programming as if it was a game of chess, and are also
        gamers. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 25.4.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.dedoimedo.com/computers/trinity-kde.html">Unixmen/Anuradha Shukla: When will Linux games become more mainstream?</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Developers are quite often gamers at heart. Until they get to core structure, there is
        no respite. Delving deep into popular games and rebuilding them are quite often the reason
        developers go on to develop the next generation of games. Linux has had quite a challenging
        history of games and their development. These are notably due to technical and practical
        reasons. While sometimes the philosophy of Open source have been the hurdle for successful
        games development.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Linux and lack of technical framework</emphasis></para>
      <para>Technically the lack of GPU drivers for Linux-based graphic cards, like in
        high-performing as proprietary software and the never resolving patents do put a large
        hurdle-infested road map for Linux games. Experts believe the continued failure to include
          <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/S3_Texture_Compression">S3TC</ulink> for open
        source OpenGL drivers as most are patent pending is creating a pseudo-scenario where distros
        are being released on the assumption that the drivers are already available. Distros without
        supporting graphic card drivers are as improper to have as a web browser without
        .jpg.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Linux and lack of revenue generation from games</emphasis></para>
      <para>The main belief for laxity in Linux games is that open source gaming sponsors find there
        is a lack of revenue generation as most is free software and most believe in
        doing-it-yourself philosophy. The limitation in specialized proprietary game-ware available
        currently, is that they become so niche in their genre that gamers are finding it difficult
        to port games across platforms.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Linux overworked by licenses?</emphasis></para>
      <para>Linux Gamers have a choice between choosing limited digitally licensed games that allow
        games to be installed on several systems and open source fee games. But again, the buck
        stops why are they not as powerful or as overwhelming as MMORG games and their ilk, given
        that Linux offers such fantastic scope for similar gaming ecosystems. Grapple is one of the
        free software projects, which is bundled with the Linux Game Publishing. It offers
        multiplayer opportunities and applications development.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Trend towards Linux game change </emphasis></para>
      <para>Analysts are now pinning down on new trends of platform confining proprietary games.
        Purist gamers believe cross-platform gaming and Linux with its high degree of cross platform
        compatibility are beginning to look towards Linux for better gaming solutions.</para>
      <para>The dichotomy in Linux games seems to have been bridged somewhat by the availability of
          <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Humble_Indie_Bundle">Humble Indie Bundles</ulink>
        a non-dependent video gaming line by <ulink url="http://www.wolfire.com/">Wolfire Games</ulink>, which are multi-platform, non-DRM and compatible with Windows, OS X as well
        as Linux. The first bundle released in the second quarter of May 2010, saw the likes of
        World of Goo, Lugaru, Penumbra, Gish and Samorost 2 as an afterthought. As the developers
        committed to offer these under open source if sales went beyond $1 million, the 1.25 million
        sales led to these games being available under the GPL license. Revenge of the Titans was
        released post better sales in Dec 2010.</para>
      <para>Despite <ulink url="http://www.worldofgoo.com/">World of Goo’s</ulink> success, open
        source yet remains a high-risk option for games owners. Humble Indie Bundle has proved a
        successful model and will hopefully be the harbinger of greater, more enjoyable games on the
        open source platform.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/nl/">CC-BY-NC-ND</ulink></para>
<!-- ($ ld: 29.4.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxaria.com/article/10-easter-eggs-in-linux?lang=en">Linuxaria: 10 Easter Eggs in Linux</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Happy easter to all, what’s better than celebrate this holiday taking a look at what have hidden the programmers in our software ?
A virtual Easter egg is an intentional hidden message, in-joke or feature in a work such as a computer program, web page, video game, movie, book or crossword. The term was coined—according to Warren Robinett—by Atari after they were pointed to the secret message left by Robinett in the game Adventure. (...)</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Editors Note</emphasis>: If you are an openSUSE user, try &apos;zypper moo&apos; on your console. ;-)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 30.4.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://linuxlibrary.org/index.php/distributions/opensuse-11-4-gnome-review/">Linux Library/thinkinhurtz: OpenSUSE 11.4 Gnome Review</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Here is another great all purpose Linux distribution with lots of the newest software only a few clicks away. Although things don’t appear to have changed much in recent years there are still some great improvements under the hood. OpenSUSE is known as a reliable distribution with a diverse selection of options making it another great choice for desktops and servers alike. Lighter desktop editions of OpenSUSE might be a better for choice for laptops however. I have already covered OpenSUSE 11.4 KDE for those who are interested, here I will focus on the OpenSUSE Gnome desktop. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 30.4.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
<!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.petur.eu/blog/?p=349">Petur.eu: Linux can be hacked with an USB device</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>I have to admit, over the years I haven’t given openSUSE enough love or credit for being
        the outstanding Linux distribution is it. With that said, I wanted to give some attention to
        the latest release coming out of the openSUSE project. And, since the default desktop for
        openSUSE 11.4 is KDE, I will be giving a little extra attention to the KDE desktop. Since
        both might well gain some serious ground, when Ubuntu 11.04 is released, it will be nice for
        users to not only know of its existence, but to also know that openSUSE 11.4 is, in fact, a
        solid distribution worth giving a look. (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> --><!--<sect2>
  <title>LOL</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://xkcd.com/874/">XKCD: Time Management</ulink>
    </title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/time_management.png" width="50%"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.5/">CC-BY-NC</ulink></para>
  </blockquote>
</sect2>--></sect1>
