<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
<!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://blog.karlitschek.de/2011/01/contest-deadline-extended.html">Frank Karlitscheck: Contest deadline extended</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Several developers approached me and asked for more time to port their applications. So
        we extend the deadline of the contest to 31. of march. Everybody has one more month to port
        a KDE or Qt application to Symbian or MeeGo. Remember that you can win 10.000,- so please
        consider to make your KDE or Qt application ready for mobile. </para>
      <para>You find more informatiuon in the original contest announcement: <ulink url="http://blog.karlitschek.de/2010/12/qtest-mobile-app-port-contest-launched.html">http://blog.karlitschek.de/2010/12/qtest-mobile-app-port-contest-launched.html</ulink>
      </para>
      <para>Please make sure that you also provide binaries for you applications. This makes is a
        lot easier for the jury to test you application. Have fun and good luck.</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 30.1.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://sourceforge.net/blog/sourceforge-net-attack/">Sourceforge: Sourceforge.net attack</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Yesterday our vigilant operations guys detected a targeted attack against some of our
        developer infrastructure. The attack resulted in an exploit of several SourceForge.net
        servers, and we have proactively shut down a handful of developer centric services to
        safeguard data and protect the majority of our services. </para>
      <para>Our immediate priorities are to prevent further exposure and ensure data integrity.
        We’ve had all hands on deck working on identifying the exploit vector or vectors,
        eliminating them, and are now focusing on verifying data integrity and restoring the
        impacted services. </para>
      <para>The problem was initially discovered on the servers that host CVS but our analysis
        indicates that several other machines were involved, and while we believe we’ve determined
        the extent of the attack, we are verifying all of our other services and data. </para>
      <para>As a short term response, we’ve taken down the following services to prevent any
        possible escalation:<itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>CVS Hosting</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>ViewVC (web based code browsing)</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>New Release upload capability</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Interactive Shell services</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
      <para>Once the immediate response to this attack is over, we will be providing a much more
        detailed account of what’s happened, and what specific actions we are taking to prevent
        further exploits.</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 31.1.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.samba.xp.de/index.php?id=14">SambaXP 2011</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The Samba eXPerience 2011 in Göttingen, Germany is the 10th(!) international <ulink url="http://samba.org/">Samba</ulink> conference for users and developers. Meet the Samba
        Team and discuss requirements, new features and get an update on current developments! The
        conference is organized by <ulink url="http://www.sernet.de/">SerNet</ulink>.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">May 9th - 11th, 2011 - Hotel Freizeit In Göttingen - Germany</emphasis> (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 29.1.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxjournal.com/content/libreoffice-33-release-brings-new-features">LinuxJournal/Susan Linton: The New Features in LibreOffice 3.3</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Despite earlier reports that very few if any new features would likely be seen in The
        Document Foundation&apos;s first LibreOffice release, the influx of new developers allowed much
        more work to be done. In fact, it was even released ahead of schedule. So, what kind of new
        goodies might one find? (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 1.2.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.desktoplinux.com/news/NS7312694782.html">DesktopLinux/Eric Brown: Linux distros move toward common app installer API</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Recent meetings held among the RedHat, Fedora, Debian, Ubuntu, OpenSUSE, Mandriva, and
        Mageia communities has resulted in an informal agreement on an architecture for a common app
        installer API. Yet the dream of a universal GNU/Linux app-store may be much farther off. </para>
      <para>Word of the app-installer meetings at OpenSUSE&apos;s Nuremberg, Germany, offices earlier
        this month emerged last week in a <ulink url="http://blog.karlitschek.de/2011/01/2-amazing-meetings-to-change-world.html">blog post</ulink> by OpenDesktop.org&apos;s Frank Karlitschek on Jan. 24. This was followed by a
        more detailed Jan. 26 report on the meetings by Swapnil Bhartiya <ulink url="http://www.muktware.com/a/1/4/26/2011/709?page=0,0">in <emphasis role="italic">Muktware</emphasis></ulink>. </para>
      <para>On Jan. 31, LinuxInsider&apos;s Katherine Noyes <ulink url="http://www.linuxinsider.com/story/Linux-and-the-Great-App-Store-Agenda-71752.html">sampled the Linux blogs and forums</ulink> for feedback, and found general support for a
        common app installer, but with plenty of observers predicting doom for the project. The more
        distant dream of a common app-store for Linux, which was not formally discussed at the main
        Nuremberg meetings, seemed even more far-fetched to many, though many others deem it a
        worthy goal. </para>
      <para>Having a common installer -- and ultimately, a universal app store -- should help
        attract new users and third-party developers to desktop Linux, goes the general consensus.
        It would help to cushion the fragmentation of the desktop Linux market while easing the pain
        of dealing with the complexity of most package managers. Yet, many other attempts at unified
        standards among Linux communities have ended in failure, note skeptics. </para>
<!--($ ld: 3.2.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://www.itworld.com/personal-tech/134954/sony-announces-ngp-aka-psp2-and-talks-playstation-gaming-android">ITworld/Peter Smith: Sony announces NGP (aka PSP2) and talks Playstation gaming on Android [video</ulink>]</title>
      <para>It was quite a day for Sony portable fans. Earlier today (well, technically yesterday) <ulink url="http://www.engadget.com/2011/01/26/sony-ericsson-xperia-play-playstation-phone-preview/">Engadget posted</ulink> about some hands-on experience with the Xperia Play, aka the Playstation Phone. It sure looks real to me. Engadget is being coy about where this unit came from but post author Richard Lai says he&apos;s been using it as his primary phone for a few days now, with generally good results.

</para>
      <para>No &apos;official&apos; games are available for it, but Lai loaded up some emulators and mapped the hardware buttons to emulator controls and had a go. This isn&apos;t final hardware but for an early look it seems promising enough. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 4.2.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.enterprisenetworkingplanet.com/news/article.php/3923031">Enterprise Networking Planet/Sean Michael Kerner: Last of the IPv4 Addresses Allocated</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>IPv4 is dead. Long Live IPv6.</para>
      <para>Early this morning, the Asia Pacific Network Information Centre (APNIC) announced that it had been allocated two /8 address blocks from the Internet Assigned Numbers Authority (<ulink url="http://www.webopedia.com/TERM/I/IANA.html">IANA</ulink> ). Those two blocks, 39/8 and 106/8, were the last unallocated blocks in the IANA free pool of IPv4 address available to Regional Internet Registries (RIR). With the allocation, the final days of IPv4 have moved closer as the number of available addresses that can be allocated will dwindle. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 4.2.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://dissociatedpress.net/2011/02/02/one-year-after-novell/">Joe Brockmeier: One year after Novell…</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>I’m usually big on milestones — anniversaries, birthdays, holidays, etc. But it wasn’t until I was going to bed last night that it hit me: It’s been a year since I left Novell and started working for myself full-time. Here’s how it’s going so far… (read on if you’re interested, but this is mostly full of personal stuff so feel free to skip down to some of the more interesting stuff on technology if you like…)</para>
      <para>My last day with Novell was January 31st, 2010. Pretty much exactly two years after I started with the company (February 1st, 2008). I put in notice about two weeks before that, but had been considering quitting long before. I’m not going to go into a lot of backstory here, but the long and short of it was that after two years the job was not what I wanted to be doing. Some jobs you can do whether your heart is in them or not (I worked at a car seat factory for three and a half years, and I don’t think my heart was ever in that…), but community management is something that you need to be all-in for. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 4.2.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://itmanagement.earthweb.com/osrc/article.php/3923351/OpenOfficeorg-vs-LibreOffice.htm">Datamation/Bruce Byfield: OpenOffice.org vs. LibreOffice</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>On September 28, 2010, LibreOffice was announced as a fork of the OpenOffice.org office suite. In the weeks since then, there have been promises of innovation and change from LibreOffice, and an attempt at dignified silence from OpenOffice.org.</para>
      <para>However, it was only last week that the two rivals released their 3.3 versions, and users had the chance to see whether the differences in the culture of the projects made any difference in the code. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 4.2.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
<!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/security/news/item/Phrack-hole-closed-in-ProFTPD-1156782.html">h-online: Phrack hole closed in ProFTPD </ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The development team behind <ulink url="http://www.proftpd.org/">ProFTPD</ulink> has
        released version <ulink url="http://www.proftpd.org/docs/RELEASE_NOTES-1.3.3d">1.3.3d</ulink>, which closes a critical security hole in the SQL module of all previous
        versions. The flaw was <ulink url="http://www.phrack.org/issues.html">reported</ulink>
        roughly a month ago in Phrack, the hacker magazine. A buffer overflow in the function
        sql_prepare_where() allows attackers to remotely execute arbitrary code on the server. The
        developers themselves suffered when this vulnerability was exploited by still unknown
        parties, who entered the project server and <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/news/item/Back-door-in-ProFTPD-FTP-server-1146592.html">installed</ulink> a back door in the source code.</para>
      <para>The new version also fixes a number of additional <ulink url="http://www.proftpd.org/docs/NEWS-1.3.3d">bugs</ulink>; as a result, the GPL-licensed
        server is reportedly now more stable. At the same time, the developers have also published
        the first release candidate for version <ulink url="http://www.proftpd.org/docs/RELEASE_NOTES-1.3.4rc1">1.3.4</ulink>. (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> --><!--
  <sect2>
    <title>LOL</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://e-tote-kala.blogspot.com/2011/01/first-joke-of-year-if-operating-systems.html"
          >Kostas Koudaras: First Joke of the year: If Operating Systems Ran The Airlines</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The first joke of the year :-) </para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> --></sect1>
