<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
<!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.novell.com/news/press/2011/5/suse-announces-executive-leadership-team-with-dedicated-focus-on-driving-growth-and-innovation-in-the-linux-marketplace.html">SUSE Announces Executive Leadership Team with Dedicated Focus on Driving Growth and Innovation in the Linux Marketplace</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>SUSE, a new business unit of The Attachmate Group, today announced its organizational focus on developing, marketing and supporting a portfolio of innovative solutions centered around SUSE® Linux Enterprise, the most interoperable platform for <ulink url="http://www.novell.com/linux/missioncritical.html">mission-critical computing</ulink> across physical, virtual and cloud environments. Nils Brauckmann, a 20-year industry veteran with both Attachmate and Novell® heritage, will lead the SUSE organization&apos;s passionate commitment to quality engineering, excellent customer service and open source innovation.</para>
      <para>(...)</para>
      <para>&quot;I am thrilled to lead this business and team in our pursuit of providing comprehensive Linux solutions that solve real problems for IT and the line of business. With a laser focus on making SUSE successful, we are committed to the products and services that our customers and partners rely on to run their businesses. Moreover, we recognize and celebrate the value of the <ulink url="http://www.opensuse.org/">openSUSE</ulink> Project and will remain a strong supporter of the openSUSE community,&quot; said Brauckmann. &quot;We reiterate our long-term commitment to the open source communities at the heart of our ecosystem. Our presence in these communities will help our customers benefit from the rich value of Linux, while encouraging the collaboration that has made Linux the foundation of so many computing environments today.&quot;</para>
      <para>Leading SUSE from its newly based headquarters in Nuremberg, Germany, Brauckmann and his team of experienced industry executives will be responsible for the organization&apos;s continued development and sale of solutions based on SUSE Linux Enterprise, through the Open Platform Solutions division of the former Novell, Inc. Specifically, Brauckmann will drive SUSE sales, marketing, engineering, technical support and consulting and training services that align with customer needs and demands. He will passionately advocate enterprise adoption of open source solutions and support the activities of the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Project">openSUSE community</ulink>. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 19.5.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.openvirtualizationalliance.org/news/">BMC Software, Eucalyptus, HP, IBM, Intel, Red Hat and SUSE Create Open Virtualization Alliance</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">SAN FRANCISCO, MAY 17, 2011</emphasis> - BMC Software (NASDAQ:BMC), Eucalyptus Systems, HP (NYSE:HPQ), IBM (NYSE: IBM), Intel (NYSE: INTC), Red Hat, Inc. (NYSE: RHT) and SUSE today announced the formation of the Open Virtualization Alliance, a consortium committed to fostering the adoption of open virtualization technologies including <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kernel-based_Virtual_Machine">Kernel-based Virtual Machine (KVM)</ulink>. The consortium will promote examples of customer successes, encourage interoperability and accelerate the expansion of the ecosystem of third party solutions around KVM, providing businesses improved choice, performance and price for virtualization. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 20.5.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://tirania.org/blog/archive/2011/May-16.html">Announcing Xamarin</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Today we start<ulink url="http://www.xamarin.com/"> Xamarin</ulink>, our new company focused on Mono-based products.</para>
      <para>These are some of the things that we will be doing at Xamarin:
        
      </para>
      <para>* Build a new commercial .NET offering for iOS
      </para>
      <para>* Build a new commercial .NET offering for Android
      </para>
      <para>* Continue to contribute, maintain and develop the open source Mono and Moonlight components.
      </para>
      <para>* Explore the Moonlight opportunities in the mobile space and the Mac appstore. </para>
      <para>(...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 19.5.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/open/news/item/GNOME-and-KDE-2011-Desktop-Summit-programme-published-1246775.html">h-online/Chris von Eitzen: GNOME and KDE 2011 Desktop Summit programme published</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The GNOME Foundation and KDE e.V. boards have published the <ulink url="https://www.desktopsummit.org/program">programme</ulink> for this year&apos;s <ulink url="https://www.desktopsummit.org/about">Desktop Summit</ulink>. Following the opening keynote, attendees can visit one of four different rooms, each with a variety of tracks including community, applications, platforms, tablets, development and accessibility &amp; help.</para>
      <para>The 2011 event will take place over the course of a week from 6 to 12 August at the <ulink url="http://www.hu-berlin.de/standardseite-en">Humboldt University</ulink> in Berlin, Germany; it is open to developers, community members and users alike. The joint conference is supported locally by the Berlin Senate and the TSB Innovation Agency Berlin GmbH, and is expected to bring together more than one thousand core contributors, open source leaders and representatives from government, education and corporate environments. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 21.5.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.h-online.com/security/news/item/Getting-a-grip-on-Flash-cookies-Adobe-publishes-Flash-10-3-1242645.html"
          >ZDNET/Steven J. Vaughan-Nichols &amp; Paula Rooney: Where Novell &amp; SUSE Linux goes
          from here</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><ulink url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/novell-deals-done/8755">Attachmate’s
          purchase of Novell is done</ulink>, and now we’re beginning to see it plans develop for
        the open-source power. First, and foremost, <ulink url="http://www.attachmate.com"
          >Attachmate</ulink> is dividing up <ulink url="http://www.novell.com/home/"
        >Novell</ulink>’s programs into three nominally independent divisions. These are <ulink
          url="http://www.netiq.com">NetIQ</ulink>, which gets Novell identity and security programs
        and some of Novell data center solutions; Novell, which will manage the company’s older
        technologies such as <ulink url="http://www.novell.com/products/openenterpriseserver"
          >NetWare</ulink>; and <ulink url="http://www.novell.com/linux/">SUSE</ulink>, which will
        produce SUSE Linux and oversee the <ulink url="http://www.opensuse.org/en">openSUSE</ulink>
        community Linux distribution. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 24.5.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.anselmolsm.org/blog/meego-conf-2011-san-francisco/">anselmolsm: Meego
          Conf 2011 – San Francisco</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>I am in San Francisco (again! =), now for the MeeGo Conference 2011. The event is about
        to begin with the keynote “The Future of MeeGo Starts Now” presented by the president of
        Linux Foundation, Jim Zemlin. This time, I’m going to present a talk in the event too! The
        talk is today and the topic is “Writing applications for multiple MeeGo devices”. There are
        other talks by openBossa/INdT guys, check the schedule! (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 24.5.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/open/news/item/New-SUSE-chief-openSUSE-is-very-prominent-in-my-thinking-1245495.html">h-online/Dj Walker-Morgan: New SUSE chief: openSUSE is very prominent in my thinking</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Attachmate&apos;s <ulink url="http://www.novell.com/linux/">SUSE</ulink> division has
        confirmed, as The H reported <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/news/item/Novell-deal-completed-Update-1233824.html">three weeks ago</ulink>, that Nils Brauckmann is the new head of the freshly created business
        unit which will be headquartered in Nuremberg. For the first time, The H talked with
        Brauckmann about his new position and how the changes in the SUSE division will affect
        openSUSE. The H pointed out to Brauckmann that there was only one mention of <ulink url="http://www.opensuse.org/en/">openSUSE</ulink> in the press release on SUSE and that
        might be taken to mean that the open source version of SUSE Linux was being downgraded. </para>
      <para>He replied that openSUSE was very prominent in the company&apos;s thinking saying &quot;Frankly
        the opposite will be the case&quot; and that SUSE understood the value of the openSUSE community
        and working with the wider open source community. Inside the company &quot;many people are very
        happy with the renewed focus and the revitalised brand&quot; said Brauckmann, who also pointed
        out that many SUSE developers are also openSUSE contributors. He hoped to enable them to
        make more effective contributions in future by providing tools to help enhance and automate
        Q&amp;A, build and test processes too. Support can also include funding too he noted and, as
        an example, SUSE will be funding this year&apos;s openSUSE conference. (...)</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Related article from other source</emphasis>:<ulink url="http://www.linuxfordevices.com/c/a/News/Attachmate-names-Nils-Brauckmann-as-SUSE-president/?kc=rss"> LinuxforDevices</ulink></para>
<!--($ ld: 19.5.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://linuxconfig.org/linux-job-portal-launched-linuxcareercom">Linuxconfig.org: Linux job portal launched: LinuxCareer.com</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>As a demand for Linux-related jobs has jumped unexpectedly high in the last couple of years, <ulink url="LinuxCareer.com">LinuxCareer.com</ulink> as a new Linux related job portal attempts to compensate for this sudden surge in demand for Linux skilled professionals and will surely accommodate both employers and job seekers.  LinuxCareer.com is not affiliated with any local or international company, nor is it a recruitment or employment agency and it is specialising only in Linux based careers and closely related Information Technology fields. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 19.5.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.brighthub.com/hubfolio/matthew-casperson/articles/117315.aspx">Hubfolio/Matthew Casperson: Run Linux in your web browser with JSLinux</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The Chrome OS project is putting a browser on top Linux to provide a fast and functional operating system. But one guy has done the reverse, emulating an x86 PC in JavaScript and using it to run Linux.</para>
      <para>There is nothing like a few benchmarks to encourage companies to push their technologies to the next level. With web browsers, JavaScript performance is often advertised as a killer feature. But, as any web developer will tell you, more often than not web 2.0 applications are developed targetting a low common denominator: Internet Explorer (versions less than 9 anyway).</para>
      <para>Still, that doesn&apos;t stop hobbiest from exploring the possibilities that are provided by the latest wave of high performance JavaScript engines. <ulink url="http://bellard.org/jslinux/">JSLinux</ulink> is one such example. It emulates a 486 based PC and uses it to run a 2.6.20 Linux kernel based OS, and includes a host of terminal tools like vi, emacs, tiny c compiler and more. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 20.5.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linux.com/learn/tutorials/446736-stop-spam-with-bogofilter-on-linux">Linux.com/Jack Wallen: Stop Spam with Bogofilter on Linux </ulink>
      </title>
      <para>There are two things in life that are assured: taxes and spam. There is little that can
        be done about taxes. As for spam, you can find a solution. Ideally, ISPs handle this and
        spam never makes its way to an end user system. This rarely happens, though, so measures
        must be taken to prevent the deluge from coming.</para>
      <para>There are a number of tools available for Linux to prevent spam. One of those tools,
        Bogofilter, is an incredibly well done system that seamlessly integrates into both <ulink url="http://projects.gnome.org/evolution/">Evolution</ulink> and <ulink url="http://www.claws-mail.org/">Claws-Mail</ulink>. This tutorial will walk you through
        the process of getting Bogofilter integrated with two of the more popular Linux email
        clients as well as helping you train Bogofilter for spam and ham.</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 19.5.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxaria.com/pills/cheat-sheet-collection-best?lang=en">Linuxaria: Cheat Sheet collection</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>For <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cheat_sheet">Wikipedia</ulink>: A cheat sheet or crib sheet is a concise set of notes used for quick reference. “Cheat sheet” may also be rendered “cheatsheet”.
        
      </para>
      <para>People working in informatics in general and on unix terminals in particular know that is not so easy remember every single command and so it’s usual to have “Cheat Sheet”, a collection of the most useful commands in a single A4 page for a particular program or environment.
        
      </para>
      <para>And this is my small collection. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 19.5.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://royal.pingdom.com/2011/05/12/the-top-20-strongholds-for-desktop-linux/">Pingdom: The top 20 strongholds for desktop Linux</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>As a server OS, Linux has long been highly successful and a poster child for open source. For example, Linux currently powers a majority of the world’s web servers and supercomputers. As a desktop OS, however, Linux has yet to gain mainstream acceptance.</para>
      <para>That said, there are some countries where people have embraced Linux on the desktop to a greater degree than most.</para>
      <para>Since you probably wouldn’t be able to guess which these countries are no matter how hard you tried, we have highlighted them in this article. Read on to find out where desktop Linux is most popular, plus some nice bonus stats. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 20.5.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.itworld.com/unified-communications/166637/5-skype-alternatives-linux-users?page=0,0">ITWorld/Steven J. Vaughan-Nichols: 5 Skype alternatives for Linux users</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>While many people use Skype for its free voice over IP (VoIP) services, Linux users have
        a love/hate relationship with it. Yes, Skype will run on some versions of Linux, but it
        doesn&apos;t run on all of them, and the Linux version (2.2-beta) lags far behind the Windows
        version (Skype 5.3). That&apos;s three major generations behind. Need I say more?</para>
      <para>Much as I dislike <ulink url="http://www.itworld.com/networking/163569/microsoft-agrees-buy-skype-85-billion">Microsoft&apos;s recent purchase of Skype</ulink> and even though I think <ulink url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/networking/how-skype-does-and-doesn-8217t-work/1051">Skype&apos;s technology</ulink> is held together by bailing wire and duct tape, maybe Skype
        will become better for Linux with Microsoft. After all, it couldn&apos;t be much worse!</para>
      <para>That said, there are numerous Linux VoIP programs and they&apos;re also free as in
        &quot;free beer,&quot; as well as free as in &quot;free software.&quot; Most of these
        programs use the open SIP (<ulink url="http://www.ietf.org/rfc/rfc3261.txt">Session Initiation Protocol</ulink>) standard or Extensible Messaging and Presence Protocol
          (<ulink url="http://xmpp.org/">XMPP</ulink>) If they use the same protocol, you should be
        able to use one client to call another. To do this, of course, they must be on the same SIP
        or XMPP network. For example, I use the Ekiga.net VoIP network for SIP calls. </para>
<!-- ($ ld: 20.5.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.dedoimedo.com/games/humble-bundle-part-3.html">Dedoimedo: The Humble Frozenbyte Bundle Reviewed </ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Time for another Humble Bundle review! After parts <ulink url="http://www.dedoimedo.com/games/humble-bundle-part-1.html">one</ulink> and <ulink url="http://www.dedoimedo.com/games/humble-bundle-part-2.html">two</ulink>, the Humble
        Indie Bundle project ran their third collection, which earned just short of one million in
        one week of sales. Unlike the previous two, the third Humble Bundle offering focuses on a
        single game vendor, Frozenbyte, with three complete games, one online pre-order demo and one
        early beta pre-order prototype. The games include Trine, a side-scrolling action and puzzle
        game, Shadowgrounds, a shoot &apos;em up shooter and its sequel Shadowgrounds: Survivor, Jack
        Claw, which is going to focus on realistic physics combat in a modern urban environment, and
        Splot, which is going to be a 2D adventure arcade. </para>
<!--($ ld: 21.5.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.fsf.org/blogs/rms/microsoft-skype">Free Software Foundation/Richard Stallman: Microsoft Skype</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>How will this affect the success of Skype&apos;s spyware, they ask? Was it good strategy for
        one or the other? Did Microsoft pay too much? How does this affect the possible success of
        this or that other company? Questions whose perspective regards people as nothing more than
        terrain for these nonhumans to squabble over. </para>
      <para>All those questions alter nothing that matters for us. </para>
      <para>The Skype client program is nonfree software: it gives its owner power over its users.
        Presently it will give the same power to a different company. The identify of the master is
        just a detail, because freedom means not having a master. </para>
      <para>One part of freedom, for computer users, is not using Skype. </para>
      <para>The GNU Project is developing <ulink url="http://www.gnutelephony.org/index.php/GNU_Telephony">free software to do more or less the same job</ulink>, and multiple free programs <ulink url="http://directory.fsf.org/category/tel/">by others</ulink> also already do the basics.
        When free software makes it possible to do full-featured VOIP while maintaining your
        freedom, that will be a real change. </para>
      <para>Replacing Skype with free software is an FSF <ulink url="http://www.fsf.org/campaigns/priority-projects/#skypereplacement">High Priority Project</ulink>.</para>
      <!--($ ld: 18.5.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://omgsuse.com/content/yet-another-flash-player-security-update">OMG!SUSE! team: Yet another Flash Player security update</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Security Team member <ulink url="http://www.suse.de/~thomas/">Thomas Biege</ulink>
        published an advisory this morning more critical security updates in..you guessed it:
        <emphasis role="bold">flash-player</emphasis>.</para>
      <para>According to the security announcement this package update affects openSUSE 11.3, 11.4
        as well as SUSE Enterprise Linux Desktop 10 SP4 and 11 SP1. This announcement also mentions
        that this is a <emphasis role="bold">remote code execution</emphasis> vulnerability, which
        means not updating to the latest flash-player package will leave you open to attackers
        running programs and exploits on your machine!</para>
      <para>Adobe has posted more <ulink url="http://www.adobe.com/support/security/bulletins/apsb11-12.html">details on this bulletin on their site</ulink> if you&apos;re <emphasis role="italic">that</emphasis>
        interested in the different issues this fix addresses.</para>
      <para>For most users, you&apos;ll just need to follow these steps:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Open up <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/YaST2-GTK">Yast2</ulink><emphasis role="bold">or</emphasis> click on the &quot;Online Update&quot; applet running in your GNOME or
            KDE panels</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Select the flash-player update and install it</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Make sure you restart <emphasis role="bold">
            <emphasis role="italic">all</emphasis>
          </emphasis> of your browsers, this will ensure that no program is
            running the older vulnerable flash-player package</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Relax with a Long Island Ice Tea</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
          </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
<!--<sect2>
  <title>LOL</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://xkcd.com/874/">XKCD: Time Management</ulink>
    </title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/time_management.png" width="50%"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.5/">CC-BY-NC</ulink></para>
  </blockquote>
</sect2>--></sect1>
