<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://anditosan.blogspot.com/2011/01/where-is-linux-desktops-aim.html">Andres
        Silva: Where is the Linux Desktop's Aim?</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>By a very definition, it seems that working for the Linux desktop is like shooting darts
      in the dark. Obviously, one would not be able to see where the dart goes, neither if you are
      hitting the target. However you are definitively hitting something, but you do not seem to
      know what. </para>
    <para>In comparison, the Linux desktop aiming at the end user seems to fall under this category.
      The bigger question will always be, who are we trying to satisfy through our Linux product?
      Given the vastness of reach that Linux has on thousands of coders, the Linux desktop project
      is bound to receive a great array of views, ideas and currents of thought that will lead the
      Linux desktop from one place to the other. Believing that coming together in order to work on
      a particular project is hard for me. However, projects such as KDE 4 have shown great strength
      in coming together and creating something revolutionary and beautiful. Other efforts to make
      the Linux desktop a reality have also come together in order to create similar results to what
      KDE did. Gnome has followed in the footsteps of KDE and has also gathered its
      community-enthusiasts and created the new Gnome 3 iteration. </para>
    <para>However, the Linux desktop is still immature--I do not say this with malice--in the sense
      that projects that aim towards a goal seem to center their understanding of what the Linux
      desktop is in a less opened environment to which they could gather to and understand what it
      is that simple, non-tech savy people understand about the way we have made their graphical
      environments. I am referring to what the voice of users has to say about the way THEY use
      their computers as opposed to what we Linux Desktop thinkers believe is good for them. </para>
    <para>For example, if I am not mistaken, KDE 4 was an aim that grew deep in the KDE community
      overtime, believing that their product KDE 3 was outdated and needed to be revamped. All over
      the internet there were calls for change and some even ventured to creating new ideas about
      the way KDE 4 was going to be. I remember seeing new icons at the Oxygen Icons website which
      promised to deliver a new way of interaction with the desktop through their plasma desktop. I
      was dazzled by the beautiful icons created in order to show the newness of approach that KDE 4
      was going to take. It took icons to make people excited over the project. Gnome followed a
      similar path. Seeing that KDE 4 has so drastically changed the aspect of its default desktop,
      it decided to launch their newest major revision, Gnome 3. Their approach came from
      often-unloved Gnome Shell. Brainstormers created a new way to interact with the desktop based
      on a combination of very active desktops and windows as well as an ease of access to files and
      applications. </para>
    <para>While all this speaks to the minds of users that projects such as Gnome and KDE did their
      best in adapting to changing times, the old problem also became apparent. The community effort
      derived into personal effort, which in turn made it seem as if these projects were put on the
      shoulders of the few who could make ideas come true through their code as opposed to asking
      the people, like the rest of us, what WE think of their creation. I am a document developer,
      and I do not appreciate it when people tell me that my earnest efforts do not fit their life.
      I become unhappy and probably bitter since all my work was worth nothing in the eyes of users.
      But alas, this is something that happens in man development teams. It is part of the process
      to let a rough stone roll down the hill until it becomes smooth. However, efforts coming from
      KDE and Gnome, although being amazingly written do not seem to tackle non-tech users as well
      as it does for them, why? because the rest of us are unable to code but they are. We do not
      have a voice because no one asks us what we think. </para>
    <para>Did KDE 4 and Gnome 3 ever conducted surveys to people in order to understand their
      interaction with computers? Do these two projects ever reach out to the community (non Linux
      users) in order to find out their needs? If they did, it was little. I hereby advocate a
      stronger case for the unheard, for the ones who will be placed these great tools in our hands.
      To these two amazing projects I say, be great listeners, seek out opportunities to understand
      the rest of us. Do not be like the people in this video giving out a Christmas present that
      only fits some. </para>
    <para>Let's shoot our darts with the lights on. :D</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 1.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/02/03/join-us-for-the-first-virtual-launch-party-opensuse-11-4/"
        >Bruno Friedmann: Join us for the first virtual launch party openSUSE 11.4</ulink></title>
    <para>Annoncing the first virtual launch party </para>
    <para>Dear folk, we are organizing a special event for the openSUSE 11.4 launch, and you’re
      invited. Virtually all of you can participate, and increase the success of it. And spend a
      good time. </para>
    <para>Too soon? Not really, we are in the process to organize also pre-release party, certainly
      for the RC1 and RC2 launch. So you can practice before the real event. Prepare your
      environment, and dress your avatars with decent clothes, and gadgets. </para>
    <para>We will do our best to welcome you in english, french &amp; greek. </para>
    <para>If you want you can also anwser our <ulink
        url="https://connect.opensuse.org/pg/polls/read/bruno_friedmann/11711/virtual-party-will-you-be-there"
        >short pool</ulink> we are looking about help.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Where?</emphasis></para>
    <para>On secondlife.com, go to area macedonia. at 183,213,21 coordinates Or fire the search
      engine, and look after Geekos group, then join that group</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">When? </emphasis></para>
    <para>During 3 days March 9 10 &amp; 11 2011 Party start at 16:00 UTC ( 8am SL time)</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">What?</emphasis></para>
    <para>Join our special place build for that event and let’s get<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Dance party</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Free drink</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Goodies</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Wall of pictures</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>11.4 installations movies</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>open minded discussions</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Experience exchange</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Who?</emphasis></para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/liz_tigerfoot.png"/>
      </imageobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/liz_morgane.png"
        />
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Your guests would be myself (tigerfoot) &amp; Morgane Marquis. A team of excellent dj’s as
      Lillith from Australia, Esquievel from USA, Stefanos from France, or our great Greeks
      neighbors.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Why?</emphasis></para>
    <para>Hey not so long ago I was kicked by <ulink url="http://blog.hennevogel.de/kick-ass/"
        >H</ulink>! Because it’s a place where people have also fun, and we want to talk with them
      about the freedom &amp; openSUSE. Did you never attempt to realize something that has not been
      made yet? Just to have a lot of fun! The full explanation <ulink
        url="http://blog.hennevogel.de/why-we-are-here/">Here</ulink>.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">How?</emphasis></para>
    <para>To access that 3D virtual world, you need a recent computer 1.5Ghz or +, and good internet
      access >3500/300bps, and a 3D enabled graphics cards like radeon HD4xxx or more, Nvidia
      Geforce >9600, Intel > i945 &amp; Intel Extreme.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">To be continued</emphasis></para>
    <para>In the next weeks, I will publish an more technical article about how to get 3D world
      viewer installed on your openSUSE. And we are just finishing the picture gallery about that
      project which should be online next week (due to <ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/02/03/join-us-for-the-first-virtual-launch-party-opensuse-11-4/fosdem.org"
        >FOSDEM</ulink>) this week-end. </para>
    <para>Stay tuned !</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 4.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://stick.gk2.sk/blog/2011/02/novell-hackweek-6-game-jam-prague-2011/"
        >Pavol Rusnak: Game Jam Prague 2011</ulink></title>
    <para>When I was last time in Germany, Leinir told me about an event called Global Game Jam. I
      liked its idea very much – 48-hour game coding marathon. I was amused when a couple of days
      later (just one day before the event took place) my friends Split, Lokiman and Frem told me
      about the Prague chapter called Game Jam Prague and invited me to join them. We decided to go
      there under the name they already used for a couple of their projects – Hyperbolic Magnetism
      aka @hypmag. </para>
    <para>The event started on Friday evening. When we arrived, the place was already full of other
      teams preparing their stuff. This was very different from other (mostly open-source related)
      events I attend where I usually know at least a few people. Here, I knew no one except my
      team! :-) At around 6pm we were given a topic that should be somehow present in our game –
      Extinction. I was very surprised that we were able to brainstorm over 15 ideas in less than
      half an hour. Later we discarded most of them (because they were too obvious or too complex)
      and we ended up with two. </para>
    <para>We agreed that for idea one to be successful we would need to create nice graphics and
      because none of us was confident enough, we decided to pick the another one where simple
      graphics would suffice. So we started to work on a game with the working title “Nations”. The
      idea was really simple: you have a couple of nations, represented by triangles (people) moving
      inside the circle (border). Each nation expands in time and when the circles start to overlap,
      triangles inside the intersection start to fight together. Moreover, if the nation is big
      enough, it starts to produce A-bombs which are then launched at other nations. Your task is to
      maintain balance between the nations, so none of them is completely destroyed. This is
      achieved by applying positive or negative force on some places of the game area. Positive
      force causes affected triangles to reproduce more, negative force causes the affected
      triangles to disappear. We implemented basic behaviour of the game mechanics and went to sleep
      on Saturday morning. </para>
    <para>We met again on Saturday evening and we coded and tweaked and coded and tweaked … It was a
      long way, but at some point (I guess it must have been something around Sunday 4AM) we
      realised we want to change the whole game logic completely. How about we had only two types of
      nations – green controlled by the user and cyan ones by AI? What if player could decide to
      split the nation into two halves or join two nations into a bigger one? Bigger nation of
      course produces A-bombs faster, but is also easier to target. We replaced most of the code and
      I started to work on an AI, which suddenly became necessary. We worked until Sunday noon when
      we were finally satisfied with the result. In the meanwhile Split composed a great music track
      and we quickly hacked game menu, intro screen and other cosmetic stuff. That’s how it looked
      in the end:</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://stick.gk2.sk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/ggj11-nuclear-crisis-logo-150x150.png"
        />
      </imageobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://stick.gk2.sk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/ggj11-nuclear-crisis-iphone-150x150.png"
        />
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>I’ll attach the gameplay video to give you even better idea how the game is played:</para>
    <para><ulink url="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JdRjlPJ0ay0">Youtube</ulink></para>
    <para>At the end of the event all contestants judged the produced games and the first three
      places were announced – check the list for all other games and the result. The first team also
      got a very nice pacman-themed cake (which was also very tasty, thanks for sharing!). Although
      we didn’t make it into the Top 3, I think it was a great success for us. We tried something
      completely new and we also met a lot of interesting people (one of them being Antonin, author
      of the legendary TotalFinder). I also hope that we’d be able to finish the game and publish it
      into Apple App Store (and probably later into Android Market).</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://stick.gk2.sk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/179638_194546517237518_162802187078618_726903_3532401_n-150x150.jpg"
          width="20%"/>
      </imageobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://stick.gk2.sk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/ggj11-all.jpg"
          width="20%"/>
      </imageobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://stick.gk2.sk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/ggj11-cake.jpg"
          width="20%"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Finally I present you the photo of amazing Hyperbolic Magnetism shortly after we submitted
      our game at the end of the 48-hour session. :-)</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://stick.gk2.sk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/ggj11-hypmag.jpg"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>See you next year!</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 4.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://saigkill.wordpress.com/2011/02/04/german-weekly-news-relaunched/"
        >Sascha Manns: German Weekly News relaunched</ulink></title>
    <para>I’m pleased to announce the relaunch of the german openSUSE Weekly News. </para>
    <para>If you’re interested in knowing more, just click <ulink url="http://wiki.open-slx.de/OWR"
        >there</ulink>. </para>
    <para>We are using an Etherpad Clone for preparing the News. We are happy if many people want to
      working with us.<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://wiki.open-slx.de/OWR">http://wiki.open-slx.de/OWR</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://forum.open-slx.de/forum/opensuse-wochenrueckblick/"
              >http://forum.open-slx.de/forum/opensuse-wochenrueckblick/</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 4.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
