<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="status-updates">
  <title>Status Updates</title>

  <!--
  <sect2 role="board">
    <title>Board</title>
    <blockquote>
      <para>...</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->

  <sect2 role="distribution">
    <title>Distribution</title>

<!--* interesting topics relating factory (opensuse-factory) (mostly status) * topics from yast/zypp teams (mostly status) * topics from kde/gnome teams (mostly status) As needed. -->
   <!-- 
    <blockquote>
      <title></title>
      <para></para>
      </blockquote>  -->
   
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink 
        url="http://www.suse.de/~coolo/opensuse_11.4/"
        >Schedules for the next week</ulink></title>
      <para>openSUSE 11.4 Milestone 5 release</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem><para>Milestone: installation workflow is feature frozen</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>Proofreading of all software starts so that we have a new baseline.</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>Milestone: Feature and version freeze for the complete distribution (exception: patchlevel update of leaf packages until Beta1+)</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>Milestone: All features are coding and function complete.</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>Milestone: Kernel and install works on all targeted machines.</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>Milestone: Last round of software translation starts - "hard text freeze"</para></listitem>
        <!-- ($ ld: 11.12.10 sm $) -->
      </itemizedlist>
    </blockquote>

    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Important Links</title>

      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://tinyurl.com/392jnb">Detailed Bugzilla
        Report</ulink></para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Submitting_bug_reports">Submitting
        Bug Reports</ulink></para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Bug_reporting_FAQ">Bug Reporting
        FAQ</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>

  <!--
  <sect2 role="susestudio">
    <title>SUSE Studio</title>

    <blockquote>
      <title>Interesting article</title>

      <para>blah laber</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->

  <sect2>
    <title>Team Report</title>

    <!--
    <sect3 role="artteam">
      <title></title>
      <blockquote>
        <title></title>
        <para></para>
      </blockquote>
    </sect3> -->

    <!--
    <sect3 role="boosters">
      <title>Boosters Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3> -->

    <sect3 role="buildserviceteam">
      <title>Build Service Team</title>

     <!-- News related to Build Service (mostly status) * meeting minutes As needed. -->

      <blockquote>
        <title><ulink
            url="http://tittiatcoke.wordpress.com/2010/12/13/opensuse-kdeunstablesc-repo-builds-newer-snapshots-of-4-6-with-all-opensuse-packages/"
            >Raymond Wooninck: openSUSE KDE:Unstable:SC repo builds newer snapshots of 4.6 with all
            openSUSE packages</ulink></title>
      <para>Are you using the openSUSE KDE 4.6 Beta 2 packages and you would like to try a newer
          version ? Then for the time being you could switch over to the KDE:Unstable:SC repository. </para>
        <para>About 2 weeks ago, I copied the official KDE 4.6 Beta 2 packages over from the
          KDE:Distro:Factory repository to the KDE:Unstable:SC repository. This has two effects,
          namely: </para>
        <para>1) People using 4.6 Beta 2, can easily update to a slightly newer version to see if
          bugs have been resolved, without loosing important patches that are openSUSE specific. </para>
        <para>2) It gives us, the openSUSE KDE team the change to easier and faster adopt to a newer
          release (e.g. RC1, RC2, etc), as that all patches are matches on a weekly basis to the
          newer source code. </para>
        <para>If you decide to switch repository, then make sure that you keep an eye on this blog,
          as that on a certain moment the KDE:Unstable:SC will switch to very unstable snapshots of
          the future KDE 4.7. I will however blog here to let you know that you should switch back
          again repostories, before I will publish the first KDE 4.7 snapshot. </para>
        <para>Feel free to contact me over email or on IRC (tittiatcoke) if you have any questions
          about this. So far KDE 4.6 has been a very stable release and also KDEPIM 4.6 is looking
          better. Let’s hope that the last glitches are also resolved, before KDE 4.6 is released. </para>
      </blockquote>
      <blockquote>
        <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/12/16/how-we-use-our-power/">Stephan
            Kulow: How we use our power</ulink></title>
        <para>I had a side project the last two weeks: Make the build service more fun to use. </para>
        <para>No matter how much fun you have creating packages, if they don’t build, there is
          little point in using a Service that has Build in its name, no? So one of the major goals
          of the service is actually to help those that want to build packages as good as possible.
          But there is a problem: </para>
        <para>Let me quote from the landing page of <ulink url="https://build.opensuse.org/"
            >build.opensuse.org</ulink>: “The openSUSE Build Service hosts 16,414 projects, with
          107,691 packages, in 26,259 repositories and is used by 25,967 confirmed users.”. That are
          quite some high numbers – especially in the relation to the ~25 servers we have for
          actually building. </para>
        <para>If you look at the build statistics of the last month (and this is just i586, x86_64
          has around the same), you notice that there is not much purple in the “Busy workers / Idle
          workers” graphic:</para>
        <figure id="fig.buildservice">
          <title>Buildservice</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/Bildschirmfoto11.png" width="50%"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>(..)</para>
      </blockquote>
      <!-- ($ ld: 16.12.10 sm $) -->
      
      <formalpara>
        <title>Build Service Statistics</title>

        <para>Statistics can found at <ulink url="http://build.opensuse.org"
          >Buildservice</ulink></para>
      </formalpara>
    </sect3>

    <!--
    <sect3 role="education">
      <title>Education Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3>

    <sect3 role="forums">
      <title>Forums Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3> -->

    <sect3 role="gnometeam">
      <title>GNOME Team</title>

      <blockquote>
        <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/12/07/indicator-me-has-landed/">Nelson
          Marques: Indicator ME has landed!</ulink></title>
        <para>The first package I pushed to openSUSE was Notify OSD (Canonicals Notification
          Agent/Bubble) with a small patch for extended features (skinning/theming) maintained by Roman
          Sukochev. This patch is popular and wasn’t merged with Notify OSD because it ‘breaks’ the spec
          of Notify OSD that states it shouldn’t be skinnable/themable on Ubuntu. </para>
        <para>Now I’ve packaged a lot of dependencies… cracked and patched GTK with a patch taken from
          Ubuntu, spended hours of mind crushing frustration…. but finally it has landed! The first
          ‘Indicator’ has landed… Often known as “Ubuntu Me Menu”, under openSUSE it will be known as
          ‘indicator-me’.</para>
        <figure id="fig.indicator">
          <title>Indicator ME Screenshot 1</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/Screenshot-1.png" width="75%"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>This screenshot was taken on openSUSE Factory 11.4 Milestone 4. It’s a clean install with
          Sonar and the only tweak is the Faenza-Dark icon theme, which I also packaged and pushed to
          openSUSE:Contrib. <xref linkend="fig.indicator"/></para>
        <para>Top right corner… Indicator ME on openSUSE. It works… I won’t backport it and will only
          maintain it from 11.4 forward. I’m doing this for personal reasons, mainly to become an
          alternative on a localized openSUSE Spin that will be named ‘openSUSE IBERIA’, which was
          already taken into openSUSE-Project by Javier Llorente. </para>
        <para>The main reason to bring this to openSUSE and into IBERIA is tightly related to the fact
          that most people on the Iberian Peninsula use Ubuntu, so we find the best approach possible to
          offer something as close as Ubuntu and hopefully even a better offer when it comes to
          localization. We don’t want to make of openSUSE a ‘clone’ of Ubuntu, instead we want to make
          the openSUSE experience more close to what people already use. </para>
        <para>I’m also going to post a small pic of the same software, this time with Canonical’s
          Radiance Theme, which introduces a small ‘tab’ like visual on the bar. This theme is awesome…
          regardless of what people think of Ubuntu and Canonical… This is the kind of polishing that
          makes Canonical successful, not just the ‘marketing’ many point and even despise.</para>
        <figure id="fig.indicator1">
          <title>Indicator ME Screenshot 2</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/Screenshot-2.png" width="75%"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>Indicator ME as landed… soon others will follow… My plans are to submit this pieces of
          software to GNOME:Apps, and not to push as default, but instead offer them at the distance of
          a ‘zypper in package’ to the openSUSE users out there. And at the same time, since the
          libraries behind it are also packaged… be more attractive to developers who might want to use
          them. I see no loss neither an identity crisis on openSUSE by providing more packages and
          alternative software to improve users Desktop experience… <xref linkend="fig.indicator1"/></para>
        <para>Future work (after indicators):<itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Synapse Launcher;</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Unity (depending on some wild dependencies and some progress in understanding
              cmake).</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
      </blockquote>
      <blockquote>
        <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/12/09/indicator-sessionnetwork/">Nelson
            Marques: indicator-{session,network}</ulink></title>

        <para>I’ve manage to hammer in 2 more indicators. Indicator-session provides a quick and
          easy method to manage your GNOME session. The options are pretty intuitive and it works ok
          so far. A simple screenshot. </para>
        <figure id="fig.gnometeam">
          <title>Screenshot</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/Screenshot.png" width="50%"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
          </figure>
          <para>Then we have also indicator-network which was a bit more problematic to build and required a couple of very ugly quick fixes. Though I’ve built a package for it and it’s dependencies (including The Connection Manager). My concerns about it: <xref linkend="fig.gnometeam"/></para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem><para>It’s a piece of software under heavy development;</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>The user configuration interface is very fuzzy and provides cool clear text passwords for LAN;</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>nm-applet is far superior;</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>Requires ‘connection manager’ – Connection Manager is a pretty cool application, and it’s compat mode with Network Manager makes it’s integration pretty easy… Though ‘connection manager’ seemed to be an outstanding piece of software, I’m not going through all the trouble to package and integrate it in openSUSE (integration should be pretty fast, just a init script, since it allows compat mode with Network Manager).</para></listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
        <para>I personally don’t like this network indicator… Though I’ve packaged it,  I’ve decided not to share it because of 4 points above. I really don’t see anything positive about having it for openSUSE users, it would most likely turn their GNOME experience into something a bit fuzzy.</para>
        <para>Either way… that’s how it looks…</para>
        <figure id="fig.gnometeam2">
          <title>Screenshot 2</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/Screenshot-41.png" width="50%"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para><xref linkend="fig.gnometeam2"/>
        </para>
      </blockquote>
      <blockquote>
        <title><ulink
            url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/12/10/new-indicators-the-saga-continues/">Nelson
            Marques: New Indicators… the saga continues…</ulink></title>
        <para>As the indicator saga continues… some new indicators were built… Indicator-messages is
          a small indicator that pics up messages and stuff from applications to display them on a
          nice all-around indicator. It works fine with evolution (plugin also built and doesn’t
          require patching for what I’ve seen). </para>
        <para>This indicator support more applications, though they require some patching. As being
          discussed on the opensuse-GNOME mailing list as as proposed by Vincent Untz, this
          indicators are moving to GNOME:Apps and there _might_ an effort to support some features
          in applications like empathy. Keep in mind this is not a priority, but if it’s possible to
          support some more feature, it might happen.</para>
        <figure id="fig.gnomeindicator">
          <title>Screenshot</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/Screenshot-21.png" width="50%"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>Additionally<xref linkend="fig.gnomeindicator"/>, I’ve also tried some other indicators… indicator-application for what I
          can tell is an indicator that removes the menu’s from the GTK applications and places them
          on the panel (MAC style). I’ve built this indicator, but I have no means to test yet
          because further patching is required at least in GTK and eventually on glib. I don’t think
          there’s actually any need to have this indicator, specially when it will bring additional
          efforts on GTK maintenance, and this feature is somehow supported by software like
          gnome-globalmenu (which I’ve also packaged for myself and works dearly with supported
          apps). </para>
        <para>I’ve done some hammering on indicator-sound as well… Ubuntu’s sound widget… I’m stuck
          with some error and I have 2 possibilities… downgrade to the last version of the previous
          branch which should built, or work the current branch (more dependency demanding). I’m
          working on it… it will happen one way or another during the next days. I guess this one is
          actually one of the most wanted :) </para>
        <para>There are few other indicators… for time and date, calendar and so on… Those will be
          last ones. After indicator-sound is done, I’m starting to clean up the packaging and make
          sure it’s compliant to the GNOME team methodology and submit them to GNOME:Apps and the
          support libraries that are required as dependencies forwarded to projects where they might
          be useful (need to check out with the people which ones those will be). </para>
        <para>A special thanks to Ken Vandine from Canonical for some guidance with libindicate. </para>
        <para>I’ve seen around some ‘hate’ waves towards Canonical, and I would like to say that so
          far in the few times I’ve interacted with them, either on bug submission or asking help,
          they have been awesome and caring. It’s really something I would like to point… they are
          pretty cool, and their devs are very helpful (but hey… so are our devs ;) ). Also a very
          special thanks to Vincent Untz, Dimstar and mrdocs which have been a great help and from
          whom I’ve learned already a lot.</para>
        <para>So picking up the useful stuff… and placing it up together in a single Indicator:</para>
        <figure id="fig.gnomeindicator2">
          <title>Screenshot 2</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/Screenshot-11.png" width="50%"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para><xref linkend="fig.gnomeindicator2"/></para>
        <!-- ($ ld: 10.12.10 sm $) -->
      </blockquote>     
    </sect3>

    <!--
    <sect3 role="kdeteam">
      <title>KDE Team</title>

      <blockquote>
        <title></title>

        <para></para>
      </blockquote>
    </sect3> -->

    <!--
    <sect3 role="marketingteam">
      <title>Marketing Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3>

    <sect3 role="medical">
      <title>Medical Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3>

    <sect3 role="monoteam">
      <title>Mono Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3> -->

    <sect3 role="openfateteam">
      <title>openFATE Team</title>
  
      <sect4>
        <title>Top voted Features</title>
        <para>* Features with highest vote, but no one has been assigned to yet. We are looking for volunteers to implement. </para>
        <blockquote>
          <title><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/120340">Run download and install in parallel (Score: 320)</ulink></title>
          <para>Network installation could be improved by running package download and package installation in parallel.</para>        
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/305493">Look at plymouth for splash during boot (Score: 148)</ulink></title>
          <para>"I wanted to open a fate feature about this when I first heard of plymouth, but reading http://fedoramagazine.wordpress.com/2008/10/21/interview-fedora-10s-better-startup/ really makes me think we should go this way. (...)"</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/305305">1-click uninstall (Score: 115)</ulink></title>
          <para>"An easy way to remove Software! For  example: you installed an application with "1-click install" (which  will install all the packages that you need), there should be an easy  way (also with 1 click) to remove what you have installed with that  1-click operation... in another words: an "1-click Uninstall" to remove  installed software (dependencies and packages included)."</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/308357">Please, replacement for Sax2 in 11.3, and now for 11.4 (Score: 81)</ulink></title>
          <para>"We  need a replacement for sax2 in 11.3, as a safety measure for when  auto  configuration fails to detect certain monitors/keyboards/mice. (...)"</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/305548">YaST-Qt: More informative "Installation Summary" (Score: 60)</ulink></title>
          <para>"The  YaST Qt package manager should provide as much information in the   "Installation Summary" view as zypper, esp the overall download size to   expect and how much disk space will be freed/used after performing the   operation."</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/305582">Off-Line one click install (MSI for Linux) (Score: 52)</ulink></title>
          <para>"Idea from community member Raúl García.
            Same  concept as MSI packages for Windows but exploiting the One Click   Install concept of openSUSE (and therefore inheriting the simplicity,   code and security. (...)"</para>
        </blockquote>
      </sect4>
      <sect4>
        <title>Recently requested features</title>
        <para>* Features newly requested last week. Please vote and/or comment if you get interested.</para>
        <blockquote>
          <title><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310937">Mobile Broadband Assistant Wizard</ulink></title>
          <para><ulink
            url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-help-here/network-internet/450790-mobile-broadband-assistant-would-further-enhance-opensuse.html#post2261514"/>
            <ulink
              url="http://blogs.gnome.org/dcbw/2009/06/22/mobile-broadband-assistant-makes-it-easy/"/>
            can I suggest this could be valuable addition to openSUSE for mobile broadband?"</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310938">Support Harddrives with more than 3TB capacity</ulink></title>
          <para>As harddrives with capacities more than 3TB's are available, we need to ensure that those drives are fully supported. (...)</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310939">[zypper] add package counter</ulink></title>
          <para>When installing/updating with zypper and "--download in-advance" zypper  shows a counter of how many packages are to be downloaded and at which  position we currently are: (...)</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310940">Mumble into Distribution</ulink></title>
          <para>"Mumble, a groupchat system, should go into next Release. It could improve the support. A testchannel "openSUSE" is alreday set up at "openMafia.org". Working repos exist at buildservice."</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310942">include BCache (cache on SSD) in kernel</ulink></title>
          <para>"Bcache is a patch to use SSDs to transparently cache arbitrary block  devices. Its main claim to fame is that it's designed for the  performance characteristics of SSDs - it avoids random writes and  extraneous IO at all costs, instead allocating buckets sized to your  erase blocks and filling them up seqentially. It uses a hybrid  btree/log, instead of a hash table as some other caches."</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310944">openSUSE 11.4 Manuals</ulink></title>
          <para>"We need for openSUSE 11.4 a review and update of the startup guidee and of other manuals. Let us add in the comments what we need to change in the documentation."</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310945">extend chkconfig to dbus services</ulink></title>
          <para>"chkconfig can be used to enable/disable init scripts and [x]inetd services. e.g. 
            chkconfig vsftpd on -> disable xinetd config and turns on vsftpd init script
            chkconfig vsftpd xinetd -> turns off init script and enable xinetd config
            chkconfig vsftpd off -> turns off init script and/or xinetd config (...)"</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title><ulink
            url="https://features.opensuse.org/310955">Include PAC Manager in openSUSE</ulink></title>
          <para>"The description from the application's website [
            <ulink
              url="http://gtk-apps.org/content/show.php/PAC+Manager?content=125533"/>]
            "PAC is a Perl/GTK Gnome replacement for  SecureCRT/Putty/...
            It provides a GUI to configure SSH/Telnet  connections: users, passwords, EXPECT regular expressions, macros, etc...""</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310958">Amarok 2.4 for opensuse 11.4</ulink></title>
          <para>"as per the first beta announcement:
            <ulink
              url="http://amarok.kde.org/en/releases/2.4/beta/1"/>
            "This new release brings a lot of new features. The following  features are critical and need a lot of testing to make sure they are  top-notch for final release at the beginning of 2011. We need your help  with this, so try them out and report any problems you find! (...)""</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310963">Make openSUSE releases with more life time than 18 months</ulink></title>
          <para>"It would be nice if OpenSUSE would make special releases which have much  life time than 18 months, as like as Ubuntu does with its LTS releases.
            Ubuntu  release a LTS version each two years, and they have five years of  support, updates, and repository life. OpenSUSE could adopt a similar  policy about this.
            Believe me, many people love to can install an OS  and not have to touch it in years, and this is a main reason about why I  deploy Ubuntu LTS releases in some systems instead of OpenSUSE."</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310964">Add YAST module to set up an OpenVPN server</ulink></title>
          <para>"Many people today use an OpenVPN server to access their personal networks or networks at work.
            The set up of an OpenVPN server is complex also, as several adjustments must be made at various points in the system.
            e.g. OpenVPN Configfile, SUSEFirewall, /etc/sysconfig Files.
            A module would make it easier to set up a OpenVPNserver."</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title><ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310975">Video Driver Pre-Install Script for ATI Installation</ulink></title>
          <para>"Installing ATI Catalyst is problematic, possibly due to pre-existing  FGLRX drivers which need to be removed before installation of the ATI  drivers. It's remarkably easy for a non technical user to come up with a  botched installation. Doubly so for the 64 bit version which has 32 bit  dependencies. (...)"</para>
        </blockquote>
      </sect4>
      <!-- ($ ld: 11.12.10 sm $) -->
      <sect4>
        <title>Feature Statistics</title>
        <para>Statistics for openSUSE 11.4 <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/statistic/product/22236">in openFATE</ulink></para>
      </sect4>
    </sect3>
        
    <!--
    <sect3 role="oooteam">
      <title>OpenOffice Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3>

    <sect3 role="testing">
      <title>Testing Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3> -->

    <sect3 role="translationteam">
      <title>Translation Team</title>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Daily updated translation statistics are available on the
          <ulink url="http://i18n.opensuse.org/">openSUSE Localization
          Portal</ulink>.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><ulink
          url="http://i18n.opensuse.org/stats/trunk/toplist.php">Trunk
          Top-List</ulink> – <ulink
          url="http://en.opensuse.org/OpenSUSE_Localization_Guide">Localization
          Guide</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </sect3>
    
    <!--
    <sect3 role="wiki">
      <title>Wiki Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3>

    <sect3 role="yast">
      <title>YaST Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3> -->
  </sect2>
</sect1>
