<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
  %myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="kernel">
  <title>Kernel Review</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://article.gmane.org/gmane.linux.kernel.mm/63589">Linus Torvalds: (Short?) merge window reminder</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>So I&apos;ve been busily merging stuff, and just wanted to send out a quick
reminder that I warned people in the 39 announcement that this might
be a slightly shorter merge window than usual, so that I can avoid
having to make the -rc1 release from Japan using my slow laptop (doing
&quot;allyesconfig&quot; builds on that thing really isn&apos;t in the cards, and I
like to do those to verify things - even if we&apos;ve already had a few
cases where arch include differences made it less than effective in
finding problems).</para>
    <para>(...)</para>
    <para>PS. The voices in my head also tell me that the numbers are getting
too big. I may just call the thing 2.8.0. And I almost guarantee that
this PS is going to result in more discussion than the rest, but when
the voices tell me to do things, I listen.
</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 27.5.11 sat $) -->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-kernel/2011-05/msg00090.html">Michal
        Marek: announcing kernel.opensuse.org</ulink></title>
    <para>The opensuse kernel git trees have a new home at http://kernel.opensuse.org/?a=git . It
      should be more reliable than gitorious, which sometimes has problems cloning the nearly 1GB
      repository. We continue to sync to gitorious as well, so nothing should break for anyone. If
      you want to switch an existing clone to kernel.opensuse.org, however, it's as simple as
      <screen>git config remote.origin.url \ git://kernel.opensuse.org/kernel-source.git</screen></para>
    <para>and analogously for the kernel.git repository. We will add more stuff to
      kernel.opensuse.org website in near future, next in the todo list is LXR and either gitweb or
      cgit. Have fun! Michal</para>
    <!--($ ld: 27.5.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
