<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="tipsandtricks">
  <title>Tips and Tricks</title>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Desktop Users</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://vavai.net/2011/04/opensuse-multi-boot-system-opensuse-fedora-linuxmint-ubuntu-free-doswindows/"
          >Masim Sugianto: openSUSE Multi Boot System : openSUSE, Fedora, LinuxMint, Ubuntu</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>I’m currently using 5 OS in my Laptop, HP 4421s : FreeDOS/Windows, openSUSE, LinuxMint,
        Fedora &amp; Ubuntu. The main goals are for testing purpose only but I would prefer to
        install all of those OS in physical instead of virtual because I’m trying to use different
        OS for work and daily usage. Our client has various Linux system and I must support them for
        managing their system. Using multiple Linux OS keep me open minds (:-D ) with the features
        and native command of each OS. </para>
      <para>Free DOS bundled and installed automatically with laptop while the others installed
        manually. openSUSE 11.4 “Celadon” is my first choice, then LinuxMint 10 “Julia”, follows by
        Fedora 14 “Laughlin” and last (but my be not least :-) ) is Ubuntu LTS 10.04.2 Lucid Lynx.
        Among the installed OS, LinuxMint and Ubuntu is the winner for setting up grub bootloader.
        LinuxMint and Ubuntu detected all of OS and added the OS choice into bootloader
        successfully. openSUSE was only successful for FreeDOS/Windows and Fedora but it fails to
        detect LinuxMint and Ubuntu, similar thing with Fedora bootloader. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 10.5.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://vavai.net/2011/04/upgrading-zimbra-mail-server-6-x-x-into-zimbra-mail-server-7-x-x/"
          >Masim Sugianto: Upgrading Zimbra Mail Server 6.x.x into Zimbra Mail Server 7.x.x</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><ulink url="http://www.zimbra.com">Zimbra</ulink> has released Zimbra 7 for about a
        month and it seems quite stable for production use. As major upgrade to Zimbra 6, Zimbra 7
        comes with tons of bug fixes and new features including security feature to prevent virus
        and spam.</para>
      <para>Does the upgrade process should be applied for production use ? The answer depends on
        your environment. If an existing system quite stable with minor problem, you may stick with
        your existing Zimbra system but if you need some features that only provided by Zimbra 7,
        upgrading may be the best option. I’m currently manages some Zimbra for production mail
        server system on some client, most of them are corporate with user 100-10k users.
        (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 12.4.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>For Commandline/Script Newbies</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.unixmen.com/linux-commands/1602-watch-al-jazeera-live-with-one-command">Unixmen/M. Zinoune (Zinovsky): Watch Al Jazeera Live in Linux with one command</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>If you are a fun of Aljazeera News channel, this is a nice command that allow you to
        watch Al Jazeera live in your Linux desktop. I tested the command and is working like a
        charm.</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://cdn.unixmen.com/images/stories/thumbnails/images-stories-videos-aljazeera1-400x225.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>First check if you have rtmpdump installed, if not install it using the command
        :<screen>sudo apt-get install rtmpdump</screen></para>
      <para>Now to start watching Aljazeera live, open terminal and enter the following
        command</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">To use Mplayer :</emphasis><programlisting><emphasis role="bold">$ rtmpdump -v -r rtmp://livestfslivefs.fplive.net/livestfslive-live/ -y \\ &quot;aljazeera_en_veryhigh&quot; -a &quot;aljazeeraflashlive-live&quot; -o -| mplayer -</emphasis></programlisting></para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">To use VLC player:</emphasis><screen>$<emphasis role="bold"> rtmpdump -v -r rtmp://livestfslivefs.fplive.net/livestfslive-live/ \\ -y &quot;aljazeera_en_veryhigh&quot; -a &quot;aljazeeraflashlive-live&quot; -o -| vlc -</emphasis>
          </screen></para>
      <para>Enjoy :)</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Editors Note:</emphasis> For openSUSE you should install via:
          <emphasis role="italic">zypper in rtmpdump</emphasis> instead of sudo apt-get</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
  <sect2>
    <title>For Developers and Programmers</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://jeffreystedfast.blogspot.com/2011/04/optimizing-merge-sort.html">Jeffrey
          Stedfast: Optimizing Merge Sort</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>A number of years ago I wrote about the <ulink
          url="http://jeffreystedfast.blogspot.com/2007/02/merge-sort.html">Merge Sort</ulink>
        algorithm. One of the advantages of <emphasis role="italic">Merge Sort</emphasis> is that it
        is a stable sort, meaning that elements that compare as being equal remain in their original
        order after being sorted.</para>
      <para>Well, today I had need of employing a stable sorting routine for sorting elements by a
        ZIndex in <ulink url="http://www.moonlight-project.com">Moonlight</ulink>. Up until today,
        we had been using <emphasis role="italic">qsort()</emphasis> which, while not guaranteed to
        be a stable sort on any platform, happens to be implemented in <emphasis role="italic"
          >glibc</emphasis> as a stable sort except in out-of-memory conditions. Since we'd like
        Moonlight to work on platforms other than Linux+glibc (such as Mac OS or BSD), it has become
        important enough to implement properly. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 8.4.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For System Administrators</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.howtoforge.com/installing-apache2-with-php5-and-mysql-support-on-opensuse-11.4-lamp">HowtoForge/Falko Timme: Installing Apache2 With PHP5 And MySQL Support On OpenSUSE 11.4 (LAMP)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>LAMP is short for <emphasis role="bold">L</emphasis>inux, <emphasis role="bold">A</emphasis>pache, <emphasis role="bold">M</emphasis>ySQL, <emphasis role="bold">P</emphasis>HP. This tutorial shows how you can install an Apache2 webserver on an OpenSUSE 11.4 server with PHP5 support (mod_php) and MySQL support. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 8.4.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.novell.com/communities/node/12703/howto-openldap-24x-replication-sles11sp1">Novell Cool Solutions/fpernet: HOWTO: OpenLDAP 2.4.x Replication on SLES11 SP1</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Introduction</emphasis></para>
      <para>YaST has a module for the server and the client part of OpenLDAP (plus a very basic LDAP browser / editor).

</para>
      <para>On SLES11 we had the following problems regarding the use of the YaST module and OpenLDAP server configuration:

    </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Database version only to store the configuratio (cn=config).</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>No way to set up any replication method or mode using this module.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>OpenLDAP modules available build in the SLAPD binary.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>Then your choices in this SLES11 version:

    </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Use the configuration file /etc/openldap/slapd.conf but in this case, forget YaST for ever.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Use YaST to set up a basic OpenLDAP server then use an external tool to set up the rest.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>If use of YaST only is mandatory, forget the replication.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>An RFE (Request For Enhancements) was created at this time, to be able to set up replication from the YaST module, on SLES11 SP1. They did it! So, let’s check how it works.

</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Note</emphasis>: On SLES11 or SLES11 SP1, by playing with /etc/sysconfig/opendlap, you can use the configuration file (/etc/openldap/slapd.conf) to configure OpenLDAP server but in this case do not use YaST anymore. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 8.4.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://www.linux.com/learn/tutorials/428331:ipv6-crash-course-for-linux"
          >Carla Schroder:  IPv6 Crash Course For Linux </ulink></title>
      <para> You might be used to working with IPv4 on Linux, but like it or not IPv6 is on its way
        in. Roll up your sleeves, spit on your palms, and get ready to go to work because this is
        your crash course in actually using IPv6. It hardly hurts at all. Linux has supported it
        since the 2.1 kernel, so you shouldn't have to install anything. Make sure you have the
        ping6, ip, and ifconfig commands.</para>
      <para> Let's get my favorite nitpick out of the way right now — we do not have IPs, we have IP
        addresses. IP stands for Internet Protocol. As my wise grandmother used to say, sloppy
        speech equals sloppy habits, which equals a trip to hell in a handbasket. (...)</para>
      <!--($ Id: 8.4.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
