<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
  <!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.novell.com/news/press/2011/2/novell-makes-it-easier-to-run-business-critical-linux-workloads-on-hp-proliant-and-bladesystem-servers-.html"
          >Novell Makes it Easier to Run Business-Critical Linux Workloads on HP ProLiant and
          BladeSystem Servers</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Novell today announced it has made it easier and more affordable for customers to run
        business-critical applications in a Linux* environment on HP ProLiant* and BladeSystem*
        servers. Available immediately, Novell has bundled <ulink
          url="http://www.novell.com/products/highavailability/">SUSE® Linux Enterprise High
          Availability (HA) Extension</ulink> for no additional cost with select SUSE Linux
        Enterprise Server subscriptions sold through HP and authorized resellers for a limited time.
        (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 10.2.11 sat $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://lwn.net/Articles/426842/">The Ada Initiative launches</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Ada Initiative launches to promote women in open technology and culture </para>
      <para>Open source activists Valerie Aurora and Mary Gardiner announce the launch today of the
        Ada Initiative (http://adainitiative.org/), a non-profit organization to promote
        women&apos;s participation in open technology and culture. </para>
      <para>Open technology and culture, including open source software, open content, and related
        communities, suffer from a dearth of women at all levels. &quot;Open technology and culture
        are shaping our future and must reflect all people. Involving more women in the creation of
        our future is a critical step in building a healthy Internet world,&quot; says Mitchell
        Baker, chair of the Mozilla Foundation. The Ada Initiative will concentrate on focused,
        direct action programs, including recruitment and training for women, education for
        community members, and working with companies and projects to improve their outreach to
        women. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 10.2.11 sat $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://camp.kde.org/">Welcome to Camp KDE 2011!</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The 3rd annual Camp KDE will be held on the 4th and 5th of April, 2011 in San Francisco,
        California at <ulink url="http://www.jdvhotels.com/hotels/kabuki">Hotel Kabuki</ulink>. Held
        annually in the United States, Camp KDE provides a regional opportunity for KDE contributors
        and enthusiasts to gather, learn about the latest KDE happenings and share their
        experiences. The event will feature in-depth talks by core KDE developers. </para>
      <para>This year Camp KDE is co-located with the <ulink
          url="http://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/collaboration-summit">Linux Foundation
          Collaboration Summit</ulink>, which takes place April 6-8, 2011. Co-location with the
        Collaboration Summit will allow Camp KDE attendees a unique opportunity to learn from and
        share their experiences with members of many other successful Free and Open Source software
        projects and companies. All Camp KDE attendees are invited to attend the Collaboration
        Summit. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 10.2.11 sat $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://genek.net/wordpress/">Adventures in Linux: Software Review: The KDE 4.6
          Desktop Environment</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Author’s note: </emphasis></para>
      <para>most of the screenshots contained herein were taken from the KDE release announcement.
        Thanks to KDE for making these pics available for re-use. </para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Ancient History: </emphasis></para>
      <para>It’s been three years, and it’s still hard to put the KDE 4.0 debacle behind me. I was
        running KDE 3.5 on Debian stable happy as a clam, and then one fine day in January of 2008
        the KDE folks dumped their brand-new, completely re-vamped desktop environment into our
        laps. I couldn’t get it for Debian so I installed another distro just to check it out… and
        used it for less than 24 hours. I could see what they were trying to do, and there were some
        good ideas there, but the implementation was so unbelievably bad that I missed out on the
        next two releases altogether. I didn’t try KDE 4.x again until January of last year, when I
        installed Debian testing with the KDE 4.3 desktop. It was great! Since then KDE has gone
        from strength to strength. KDE 4.4 was mature and stable, and KDE 4.5 added polish and
        finesse. KDE 4.6, released a little over a week ago, ups the ante once again. (...)</para>
      <!--($ ld: 10.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.desktoplinux.com/news/NS7312694782.html">Prashanth Venkataram:
          Preview - GNOME 3 </ulink>
      </title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_c0--RsXwTkw/TUx7fv5mxCI/AAAAAAAABNQ/uNZlx1MtApA/s320/Screenshot1.png"
          />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>Usually, when I review desktop environments, I review KDE, specifically version 4. Why?
        It&apos;s constantly evolving and improving, and it&apos;s nice to be able to see such
        changes occurring on all fronts so quickly. By contrast, GNOME and Xfce (not to mention
        other WMs like Openbox) have remained relatively the same over the past few releases. Sure,
        Nautilus got tabbed browsing in version 2.22 (I think) and split-pane viewing in version
        2.30. Sure, there may have been a couple other back-end changes. But generally speaking,
        where KDE 4 has changed pretty noticeably between point releases, GNOME has been quite
        stable. That&apos;s all going to change, because GNOME is about to be released under a whole
        new number: 3. That&apos;s right: the number preceding the decimal point in a GNOME release
        will no longer be &apos;2&apos;.</para>
      <para>There are some pretty big changes in store for GNOME 3, much of which can be seen in the
        front-end. Because many major distributions are planning to upgrade to GNOME 3 once that
        gets released (in a few weeks, apparently), it&apos;s important that users try GNOME 3
        beforehand both to get accustomed to it as well as to find and report lingering bugs.
        Happily, the good people at Fedora and openSUSE have put together live CD ISO files with
        vanilla GNOME 3 on them, just for the purpose of trying out GNOME 3. I downloaded both files
        and intended to make a multiboot live setup using MultiSystem, but unfortunately MultiSystem
        reacted with error messages to both ISOs. Knowing that openSUSE doesn&apos;t play well with
        UnetBootin, I decided to just try out the Fedora version on a live USB through UnetBootin.
        Follow the jump to see how it goes.</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_c0--RsXwTkw/TUx7f_2UmHI/AAAAAAAABNU/-BlafqbqZQg/s320/Screenshot2.png"
          />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>Unfortunately, I initially had a bit of booting trouble when I selected the default boot
        menu option. The OS hung halfway through booting, so I forced a cold restart. I then
        selected the <quote>Boot </quote>option instead of either <quote>Default</quote> or
          <quote>desktop_[stuff] </quote>(the name of the ISO file) and that seemed to work fine — I
        even got to see the lovely Fedora boot splash screen (the Fedora logo <quote>filling
          up</quote>). After the boot process came the login screen. I guess GDM hasn&apos;t changed
        a whole lot since GNOME 2.30, though for some reason the GTK+ theming looked really ugly.
        Upon seeing it, I hoped it was just an issue with GDM and not the whole GNOME desktop
        theming ability, and thankfully, as I found out shortly thereafter, I was right. I then
        proceeded to the desktop. (...)</para>
      <!--($ ld: 10.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.computing.co.uk/ctg/news/2024721/oracle-ibm-share-source-java-leadership"
          >Computing.co.uk/Derek du Preez: Oracle and IBM to share open-source Java
          leadership</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Oracle has agreed to share governance of the OpenJDK Java community with IBM, in a move
        that demonstrates considerable good will, according to one analyst.</para>
      <para>The company has created a series of <ulink
          url="http://cr.openjdk.java.net/~mr/bylaws/draft-openjdk-bylaws-07.html">bylaws</ulink>
        outlining the way the governance will be structured, with Oracle appointing itself chairman
        and the OpenJDK lead, and IBM taking the role of vice chairman. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 10.2.11 sat $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://asiajin.com/blog/2011/02/08/facebook-japan-takes-hard-line-banning-pseudo-names-and-requires-id/"
          >Asiajin/Akky Akimoto: Facebook Japan Takes Hard Line, Banning Pseudo Names And Requires
          ID</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Today February 8, some Japanese web users who are influential in tech communities like
        Hatena and Twitter, started reporting they were locked out from Facebook. After trying to
        log in, they were taken to the form, which title is “Complaints against a ban of your
        account, identity demanded”. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 10.2.11 sat $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://blog.qt.nokia.com/2011/02/12/nokia-new-strategic-direction-what-is-the-future-for-qt/"
          >QTBlog/Daniel Kihlberg: Nokia new strategic direction. What is the future for
        Qt?</ulink></title>
      <para>Wow, what a day… Nokia outlined its new platform strategy for smartphones, with Windows
        Phones as it primary smartphone platform in a proposed partnership with Microsoft… and
        Microsoft’s tools would be used for Nokia Windows Phone application development … and guess
        what, it has raised a lot of questions in the Qt community. </para>
      <para>So the question is, what is the future for Qt? </para>
      <para>Qt will continue to play an important role in Nokia. Consider the following:<itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>The retention of Nokia’s 200 million Symbian-users is vital and Nokia has targeted
              sales of 150 million more Symbian-devices in years to come. To achieve that Nokia
              needs to continue the modernization of Symbian in Qt – to keep existing consumers
              engaged and to attract new customers, either upgrading from existing Symbian devices
              to Qt enabled devices or entirely new to Nokia.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Nokia also announced it will ship its first MeeGo-related device in 2011, which
              will rely on the Qt ecosystem – and then will continue with MeeGo as an open source
              project for future disruption. Nokia can’t afford to be behind the next disruption
              again and Qt can play an important role in making sure it isn’t.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>With Qt Quick and Qt SDK 1.1 releases in the coming months we are expecting the Qt
              developer community to continue to grow – adding to the 400.000 developers using Qt
              today. Qt is developed together with the community and we expect the pace of
              innovation to increase even further as the community grows.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>We in Nokia are one of tens of thousands of companies in multiple industries
              actively using and contributing to Qt, making Qt relevant for both mobile, desktop and
              other embedded developers</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Qt expansion: We have continued to hire Qt developers and we will continue to
              improve and expand Qt in the future. Qt is great at delivering innovation; we have
              been doing that for 15 years. With the upcoming release of Qt Quick, we will reach out
              to new users and make it even easier to create great apps and UIs for many platforms
              including Symbian and MeeGo.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>The new Qt SDK 1.1 technology preview. We now offer only one SDK for both desktop
              and mobile developers, which makes it easier to target more platforms by using just
              one SDK.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Qt everywhere. Qt continues to make vast inroads into especially low end Linux
              devices and distro’s. Qt also continues to provide a platform for others to innovate
              and differentiate upon. For example Dreamworks switching all their internal animation
              tools to Qt and making cool movies like “MegaMind” and “How to Train Your
              Dragon”.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
      <para>Qt is increasingly popular. During 2010, we had 1.5+ million downloads at qt.nokia.com
        (alone) – twice as much as during 2009 – and with the up-coming innovation and additional
        investments in Qt combined with the introduction of open governance, I believe Qt will be
        used more than ever before.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 10.2.11 sat $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linux.com/learn/tutorials/403466-review-hands-on-libreoffice-33"
          >Linux.com/Brian Proffitt: Review: Hands on LibreOffice 3.3</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The Document Foundation released the first new version of its LibreOffice suite on
        January 25th, and it was far too tempting not to grab a copy and run it through its paces.
        And while there are a few new features of note, this is still pretty much OpenOffice.org,
        with all the attendant advantages and foibles.</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata width="25%" fileref="http://www.linux.com/images/stories/calc.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>This is to be expected, of course, since the fork of LibreOffice from the
        Oracle-controlled (formerly Sun-controlled) OpenOffice.org project only occurred four months
        ago. Expecting a drastic change is folly in that timeframe. But it still bears noting,
        because a lot of the problems users may have with the OpenOffice.org suite could still be
        present. </para>
      <para>A lot, but not all, so let&apos;s give credit where credit is due. The feature I found
        most helpful in LibreOffice 3.3 was a much better improvement in file importing from
        Microsoft Office. OpenOffice.org has long-touted its capability to open and save Office
        files, but in reality most users know that any file with any kind of complexity was going to
        have to have problems coming across. </para>
      <para>In LibreOffice, that&apos;s no longer the case. Opening some heavily-revised and
        commented chapter files from my last book in OpenOffice.org usually leads to mis-rendered
        comments and loads of font issues. LibreOffice Writer didn&apos;t even blink: all revisions,
        comments, and fonts came across perfectly. This was good news, since I would much rather use
        LibreOffice on Linux than fire up a Windows VM when I&apos;m writing for publishers
        insistent on clean .docx files. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 8.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.tildehash.com/?article=interview-with-richard-stallman-2011"
          >Tildehash: Interview with Richard Stallman (2011)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><ulink url="http://www.stallman.org/">Richard M. Stallman</ulink> (born March 16, 1953),
        often shortened to RMS, is an American software freedom activist and computer programmer. In
        September 1983, he launched the GNU Project to create a <ulink
          url="http://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.html">free</ulink> Unix-like operating system,
        and has been the project&apos;s lead architect and organizer. With the launch of the <ulink
          url="http://www.gnu.org/">GNU Project</ulink>, he initiated the <ulink
          url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free_software_movement">Free Software Movement</ulink>;
        in October 1985 he founded the <ulink url="http://www.fsf.org/">Free Software
          Foundation</ulink>. </para>
      <para>Richard Stallman pioneered the concept of <ulink
          url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Copyleft">Copyleft</ulink> and he is the main author of
        several copyleft licenses including the <ulink
          url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GNU_General_Public_License">GNU General Public
          License</ulink>, the most widely used Free Software license. Since the mid-1990s, Richard
        Stallman has spent most of his time advocating for Free Software, as well as campaigning
        against both <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_patent">software
          patents</ulink> and what he sees as excessive extension of copyright laws. Stallman has
        also developed a number of pieces of widely used software, including the original <ulink
          url="http://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/">Emacs</ulink>, the <ulink
          url="http://gcc.gnu.org/">GNU Compiler Collection (GCC)</ulink>, the <ulink
          url="http://www.gnu.org/software/gdb/">GNU Debugger (GDB)</ulink>, and many tools in the
          <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coreutils">GNU Coreutils</ulink>. He co-founded
        the <ulink url="http://www.progfree.org/">League for Programming Freedom</ulink> in 1989. </para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 8.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.unixmen.com/gaming-on-linux/1131-19-awesome-opensource-games-for-linux-"
          >Unixmen/M. Zinoune (Zinovsky): 19 Awesome Open source games for Linux</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>This is a nice collection of 19 open source games for Linux that contains most
        addictive, fun and refined games. For some of these games, also installation steps are
        included. Enjoy</para>
      <!--($ ld: 8.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxjournal.com/content/cups-and-sun">Linux Journal/Johan Thelin:
          CUPS and Sun</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>I recently spent some time getting one of my long term projects built. For quite some
        time I&apos;ve had an old desktop computer serve as my printer server. As this machine is
        kind of loud, I&apos;ve turned it off when not using it. This led to some client machines
        not appreciating the printer becoming available at the wrong time.</para>
      <para>In my posession I also had an old mini-itx board with passive cooling (large heat sinks)
        and a pair of sun portable scsi hdd cases. Incidentally, the latter fit into the former. The
        plan for a new print server was born. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 10.2.11 sat $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.net-security.org/secworld.php?id=10544">HELP NET SECURITY: USB
          autorun attacks against Linux</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Many people think that Linux is immune to the type of Autorun attacks that have plagued
        Windows systems with malware over the years. However, there have been many advances in the
        usability of Linux as a desktop OS - including the addition of features that can allow
        Autorun attacks.</para>
      <para>This Shmoocon presentation by Jon Larimer from IBM X-Force starts off with a definition
        of autorun vulnerabilities and some examples from Windows, then jumps straight into the
        Linux side of things. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 10.2.11 sat $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>LOL</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://e-tote-kala.blogspot.com/2011/01/first-joke-of-year-if-operating-systems.html"
          >Kostas Koudaras: First Joke of the year: If Operating Systems Ran The Airlines</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The first joke of the year :-) </para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
</sect1>
