<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/05/14/atiamd-fglrx-8-850-catalyst-11-5-available-for-opensuse-11-2-11-3-11-4-factory/"
        >Bruno Friedmann: ATI/AMD fglrx 8.850 Catalyst 11.5 available for openSUSE 11.2, 11.3, 11.4,
        Factory</ulink></title>
    <para>Please refer to my <ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/?p=6680">previous
        article</ulink> where all the installation procedure is explained. </para>
    <para>At least after a wrong 11.4 version, and a first buggy 11.5 catalyst version, the new one
      is finally build and ready to install from the repo. Like for 11.3 I’ve clean up all previous
      version which are not xpic, so everybody can easily know which drivers he has to install. I’ve
      resigned all rpm with my key. And the tests made show them working. </para>
    <para>Warning </para>
    <para>Some instabilities have been reported. In case of crash like no keyboard, mouse, and
      blackscreen on reboot. Try to shutdown properly your computer with the shutdown poweroff
      button. On reboot, just add 3 at the end of grub line to restart in console mode. Then with
      yast or zypper you can always try the previous version. </para>
    <para>All credits to Sebastian Siebert (freespacer) : <ulink url="http://bit.ly/l6Ddyc">11.5
        article</ulink> (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 16.5.11 sm $)-->    
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://people.gnome.org/~michael/blog/2011-05-09-libreoffice-fud.html">Will
        Stephenson: Have you BURPed yet today?</ulink></title>
    <para>Well, have you? ýNot the satisfying expulsion of excess gas, but the simplest way you can
      materially contribute to openSUSE.</para>
    <para>I was just hanging in the #active channel, watching my KDE chums make their <ulink
        url="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iA9zaBZysfI">new touchscreen interface</ulink> (video),
      when somebody complained that <ulink
        url="http://sourceforge.net/projects/oscaf/files/shared-desktop-ontologies/0.7/"
        >shared-desktop-ontologies</ulink> does not yet contain the latest release needed by KDE git
      master. ýAnd instead of updating the package myself, I suggested they just BURP:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Branch</emphasis>,</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Update</emphasis>,</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Request</emphasis>,</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>the <emphasis role="bold">Package</emphasis></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>And by doing so we all get the latest versions in the devel project and soon in Tumbleweed
      and openSUSE Factory. ýSo ambassadors, boosters and motivated contributors know how to do that
      right? ýNow you can use this glib little acronym to persuade friends and colleagues to do the
      same.</para>
    <para>Happy BURPing!</para>
    <!--($ ld: 17.5.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
