<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/01/11/reviewing-the-trademark-guidelines/">Reviewing
        the Trademark Guidelines</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>In 2009, a set of <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Trademark_guidelines"
        >trademark guidelines</ulink> were created to help define how the community and beyond could
      use the openSUSE logo and related trademarks in their own products and services. Along with
      this, Novell granted powers to the openSUSE Board to be the guardians of the openSUSE
      trademarks. This included ensuring that proper usage followed the guidelines as well as giving
      the Board the ability to review special use cases.</para>
    <para>It also helped those who wanted written permission from the Board authorizing the use of
      trademarks on their products and services. Formal requests for such permissions were sent to
        <email>permission@novell.com</email>, and Novell would forward the request to the Board for
      review. </para>
    <para>As you know, trademark protection is important because it represents the identity of an
      organization. Trademark usage also provides an important tool for the community that wishes to
      promote openSUSE. The use of the trademarks makes it easier to share and spread openSUSE
      works. Of course, regulating the appropriate usage of the trademarks is also a necessary evil
      to prevent abuse. </para>
    <para>As with anything in life, time gives perspective. There has been sufficient time since the
      implementation of the first guidelines to observe real use cases where the guidelines were
      either effective or ineffective. And for the Board, this includes identifying a more
      responsive workflow to addressing requests for authorization of usage, as we, and others,
      recognize the current process as being perfectible. </para>
    <para>The Board, along with others in the community, would like to begin a review of the current
      state of our trademark guidelines and identify where it can be strengthened and be more
      effective. To this end, our first step is to open an <ulink
        url="https://features.opensuse.org/311039">openFATE Feature request</ulink> for comments. We
      invite the community and beyond to review the current guidelines and offer their input on
      language and past use case experiences. </para>
    <para>While we would like comments submitted on openFATE, if you prefer, you can post your
      comments here or send your thoughts directly to <email>board@opensuse.org</email>. A specific timeline for
      completion of this process has not been determined yet, but it is the intention of the Board
      to move forward on this topic in order to help the community at large move forward on their
      own projects.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 11.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/01/06/putting-our-accessibility-heads-together-2/"
        >Putting our Accessibility Heads Together</ulink></title>
    <para>Accessibility has become an important selling point in getting computing solutions into
      many organizations. Organizations are faced with legislations and regulations that require
      their environments be accessible and they take it into account when looking for a solution
      that fits their needs. For government organizations, software that doesn’t live up to certain
      accessibility standards is simply not an option. </para>
    <para>Let’s just be frank here. While the openSUSE community cares about accessibility as much
      as anyone else does in FOSS, we haven’t done that well in delivering the best accessible
      solution. There are various people who look at the situation in their own corners and try to
      make the best of it. Andrew Wafaa highlighted some of the challenges in two recent articles. </para>
    <para>Meanwhile openSUSE presents a very unique advantage that hasn’t been leveraged yet. With
      DBUS, the GNOME and KDE communities have worked together to leverage GNOME’s long-standing
      applications to work well on KDE. As openSUSE is a major distribution that provides support
      equally to GNOME and KDE, we have a distinct opportunity to provide the best integration of
      KDE and GNOME with accessibility. Thus offering prospective users and organizations a real
      choice on a distro that is known for its stability and support.</para>
    <para>So what’s the problem? </para>
    <para>Well, its a variety of things. And most certainly not because no one cares.</para>
    <para>While other distributions have formal accessibility teams, we don’t. And we don’t advocate
      for that. After all, one has to realize that a11y doesn’t mean accessibility for people with
      special needs. It means accessibility for all regardless of what your needs are. And that
      means that accessibility issues should be raised in mainstream conversations, not segregated
      off to some corner where no one else knows what’s going on. Therefore, if there’s a problem in
      openSUSE-GNOME accessibility, it should be discussed on that team’s thread. If there’s a
      problem with the installer, it should be discussed on the Factory mailing list, and so on.
      While, philosophically, we still believe in this, in practice, it hasn’t been a perfect world.
      We ended up being like a bunch of loose chickens running around without any real concerted
      effort. And this is a shame because over the years, we’ve had many great accessibility experts
      both in the community and on staff at Novell.</para>
    <para>So what’s the solution? </para>
    <para>Put our heads together! </para>
    <para>At this point in time, we still aren’t going to put together a formal mailing list and
      such, but we do have an #opensuse-a11y channel that has recently begun to grow in population.
      Its a place where we all can kind of chat and keep tabs with each other about what’s going on
      while still focusing on our primary areas of work around the Project. </para>
    <para>On Thursday, 13 January 2011, at 17:00 UTC, we’re going to have a meeting. We’re not going
      to use a formal agenda at this time but rather more like a kvetching where we’ll talk about
      our views of what we see as the obstacles. From there, we hope to have a better and bigger
      picture and develop an idea of how we can go forth collectively and individually in our
      accessibility work. </para>
    <para>If you’ve had some interest in accessibility and have some thoughts or want to learn what
      others are saying, we invite you to join us. We’ll be giving out free virtual coffee and hot
      chocolate throughout the meeting. :-)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 6.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
