<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 id="gsoc" role="gsoc">
  <title>Google Summer of Code</title>
  <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
      <imagedata fileref="http://michal.hrusecky.net/wp-content/uploads/GSoC2011_300x200.png"
        width="20%" align="center"/>
    </imageobject>
  </mediaobject>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://redache.wordpress.com/2011/06/25/entomologist-ui-changes-weekly-report-5/">David
        Williams: Entomologist UI changes Weekly Report #4</ulink></title>
    <para>This week has been a bad one for getting work done as I managed to lose a lot of my work
      mid week. I’ve spent the rest of the week trying to get back to where I was and finishing up
      the New Comments Dialog. I also repeated the mantra “commit often” to remind myself to do it
      so much more often than I do to ensure I can’t lose work when QT Creator decides to delete
      things.</para>
    <para>The New Comments Dialog is at its first iteration and I am going to spend the next 2 – 3
      days fixing any bugs and resolving some issues with the tabbed interface. Then on Monday I
      will start the TODO lists in earnest and get back to being on track with my timeline. </para>
    <para>Luckily time is something I do have and I think I gave myself plenty of breathing space in
      the timeline I submitted with my GSoC application. I’d rather take my time and get things done
      properly with breathing room than cram in as much functionality as possible into the 12 weeks
      and then end it with a massive chunk of badly written and probably broken code. This breathing
      room helped me this week.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 26.6.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://nbprashanth.wordpress.com/2011/06/27/gsoc-report-%E2%80%93-3/"
        >N.B.Prashanth: GsoC Report – 3</ulink></title>
    <para>Yes. Sorry. It is another report. But i ll try my best to keep this one short though. <inlinemediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="http://s2.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif?m=1301511873g"/>
        </imageobject>
      </inlinemediaobject></para>
    <para>Last week was all about the GTK plugin. This plugin was different from the other plugins
      and was dependent on libzypp. And libzypp was dependent on libsatsolver and that was dependent
      on…. well, you get the point. The libzypp dependecy had to be removed and that was my
      job.</para>
    <para>Most of the time was spent in analysing how (and why) libzypp was used by the plugin. Once
      i figured that out and got the plugin to compile without libzypp, I was faced with more
      problems. Initial builds were fine on my Fedora box (F15). But when I built it on OBS, the F14
      build failed. After reading the logs, i found out that gdk-pixbuf package by default installs
      itself in a different location in F14. This broke the build on F14. </para>
    <para>The Deb builds were more problematic. They failed on my build system (ubuntu 11.04). CMake
      seemed to have difficulties in finding GTK includes and libs. After trying to tweak the code
      and check for alternatives using pkg-config, i finally stumbled on to a link where i found out
      that this was a known issue with CMake on Ubuntu 11.04.</para>
    <para>Well, after this it seemed to be a waste to carry on with CMake when 50% of the builds
      failed. So i started off on a quest to convert the packages to autotools. Now, the GTK plugin
      completely uses autotools and works fine on Ubuntu 11.04 and F15. I am in the process of
      converting the other packages to use autotools as well for the sake of uniformity and
      maintainability. But that would ofc, depend on the approval of the respective package
      maintainers.</para>
    <para>Another change this week is the removal of the git repo at gitorious.org/libyui/libyui.
      This space will be filled by the official libyui repository once the svn-git conversion is
      complete. The old repo can be found at gitorious.org/libyui/gsoc2011. I ll be maintaining all
      project related files there including the source packages that have been converted to
      autotools and examples. I am no expert at autotools. Infact, i had to do quite a bit of
      studying to replace cmake. So if anyone with a good autotools background finds any flaws with
      the packages, please leave a comment below.</para>
    <para>The documentation would be the next task. At present, the documentation is generated by a
      makefile using doxygen. This is not linked to the documentation servers at openSUSE and hence,
      there are no weekly updates yet. This would be implemented once the YUI repo is shifted to
      git.</para>
    <para>The GTK package will be added to OBS soon.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 28.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://pinguimengenheiro.blogspot.com/2011/06/gsoc-podcast-subscription.html"
        >Lucas Lira Gomes: Podcast Subscription Synchronisation</ulink></title>
    <para>It’s been two weeks since my last update about progress on gpodder integration with
      Amarok, so here we go.Amarok is now fully capable to receive podcasts from gpodder.net and to
      synchronize them with your own local podcasts, and the other way around. Every podcast, from
      gpodder.net, will be synchronized with it respective, from local podcasts, using the playlist
      synchronisation implemented in the first part of this project.Now, take a look at some
      screenshots and free your imagination:</para>
    <para>
      <figure id="gpodder1">
        <title>Immediately after Amarok initialization.</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-JEjM5DXWCZ4/TgkXFxMFurI/AAAAAAAAADU/etkMf3EkeiI/s640/amarok_before_sync.jpeg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </para>
    <para>Notice that when Amarok started there is only one podcast on local podcasts.</para>
    <figure id="gpodder2">
      <title>Right after the subscription synchronisation process ends.</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-iVV-PP6isQk/TgkXFNiKEyI/AAAAAAAAADQ/OEOdxkIZZz0/s640/amarok_after_sync.jpeg"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>After some necessary delay, gpodder service promptly synchronized all podcasts, from gpodder.net, with your local podcasts, thereby adding the missing ones.</para>
    <figure id="gpodder3">
      <title>Removal of a subscription from local podcasts.</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-agI7JkE6lPA/TgkXEiNpQPI/AAAAAAAAADM/h5QRLWn1Ivo/s640/amarok_after_delete.jpeg"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>If you try to remove a local podcast, that is synced with a gpodder podcast, then Amarok will ask you if you want to remove it from your gpodder.net subscriptions too. In a similar manner, once you add a new podcast, to your local podcasts, you will be asked if you want to add it to your gpodder.net subscriptions too.</para>
    <para>So, remember to keep in touch with this blog. Next week, I will be back to update you with fresh news.</para>
    <para>All hail the KDE!!! \o/</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 28.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
