<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="tipsandtricks">
  <title>Tips and Tricks</title>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Desktop Users</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.muktware.com/articles/3038">Muktware/Swapnil Bhartiya: How To Install Restricted Drivers, Formats In openSUSE 12.1</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>OpeSUSE, like Fedora, doesn&apos;t support non-free/proprietary formats in the community version. So, if you want to use proprietary or restricted codecs you will have to install restricted formats. It&apos;s extremely easy using openSUSE KDE.

Just visit this <ulink url="http://opensuse-community.org/Restricted_formats/12.1">page</ulink> and select the easier <ulink url="http://opensuse-community.org/codecs-kde.ymp">1-click</ulink> installation. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 01.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.muktware.com/articles/3037">Muktware/Swapnil Bhartiya: How To Set Up Printers In openSUSE</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>I had to struggled a bit to connect my HP Photosmart Prem c410 printer on openSUSE. Coming from Ubuntu, I was used to &apos;add printer&apos; button and just follow the click-next procedure.</para>
      <para>Under openSUSE it&apos;s a bit different. openSUSE 12.1 comes with HPLIP Tool which makes it easier to install and configure HP printers. If your printer is connected through the wireless (as was mine), you can set it up using this tool.</para>
      <para>HPLIP wants the user to be added to several groups (I learned that after 3 failed attempts, so I am saving your time). Before firing the HP Tool, go to YaST and click on &apos;User and Group Management Accounts&apos;. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 01.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.muktware.com/articles/3039">Muktware/Swapnil Bhartiya: How To Setup Networking In openSUSE 12.1 KDE</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>There is a very tiny (extremely tiny, as tiny as a microbe) price you have to pay when you use a highly customizable desktop environment like KDE. I had issues with networking (which was more to do with my ignorance than KDE) under openSUSE KDE 12.1.</para>
      <para>While the live version showed the network icon in the tray, once I installed it on my desktop it was gone. There was no Internet.  I noticed this behavior only on the desktop, everything was fine on my laptop.</para>
      <para>The reason being KDE defaults to YaST&apos;s Network setting if it detects that you are running a desktop. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 01.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Commandline/Script Newbies</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://bashshell.net/exercises/exercise-test-multiple-aspects/">BashShell.net/Mike: Exercise: Test Multiple Aspects</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>In many situations you will want to test for multiples aspects of the file or directory.    There are also a number of ways that you can set up these multiple tests.  This example looks for a file that exists and is writable. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 01.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Developers and Programmers</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://how-to.linuxcareer.com/c-development-on-linux-flow-control-iv">LinuxCareer.com/Rares Aioanei: C development on Linux - Flow Control - IV</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">1. Introduction</emphasis></para>
      <para>You have already been exposed to a small part of what flow control is in our <ulink url="http://how-to.linuxcareer.com/c-development-on-linux-types-variables-operators">previous part</ulink>, namely the section about relational operators. As you start writing more complex programs, you will feel the need to control the order in which your program executes various parts. Flow control is present in most programming languages in one form or another, and what you&apos;re about to read here is essential to writing C programs.Everything you might want to ask or discuss you can take to our new <ulink url="http://forum.linuxcareer.com/">forums</ulink>, as before. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 01.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://zoumpis.wordpress.com/2011/11/28/how-to-install-eclipse-3-7-indigo-sr1-in-opensuse-12-1-kde-only-within-10-steps/"
          >Rousinopoulos Athanasios-Ilias: How-to Install Eclipse 3.7 (Indigo SR1) in openSUSE 12.1
          (KDE) only within 10 Steps</ulink></title>
      <para>This is my first blog post for the assignment “Development Tools” , so i could say that
        i am very happy with this matter!</para>
      <para>Well i use openSUSE Linux 12.1 and i am very proud of that! Sometimes i face problems
        like , lack of packages for programs, but this matter doesn’t mean that you cannot install
        the software you wish. In my case i installed Eclipse 3.7 (Indigo SR1) due to i have to use
        the <ulink url="http://marketplace.eclipse.org/">Eclipse Marketplace</ulink>. Eclipse
        Marketplace offers a thousand of plug-ins and extra features available for Eclipse platform.
        It is a truth that i searched a lot in order to find a package or a “one-click install” file
        but the result was an installation of 3.6.2 version. As we all know in FLOSS always there is
        a way to overcome problems and also fix them. Furthermore as a developer i have to use the
          “<ulink
          url="http://www.eclipse.org/downloads/packages/eclipse-ide-java-ee-developers/indigor"
          >Eclipse IDE for Java EE Developers</ulink>“. Here are the instructions on how-to install
        (via terminal) this edition of Eclipse. (Some images are in greek language , due to the fact
        that i use the greek language as System language) (...)</para>
      <!--($ Id: 02.12.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For System Administrators</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.howtoforge.com/perfect-server-opensuse-12.1-x86_64-with-nginx-ispconfig-3">HowtoForge/Falko Timme: The Perfect Server - OpenSUSE 12.1 x86_64 With Nginx [ISPConfig 3]</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>This tutorial shows how to prepare an <emphasis role="bold">OpenSUSE 12.1 64bit (x86_64)</emphasis> server with nginx for the installation of <ulink url="http://www.ispconfig.org/">ISPConfig 3</ulink>, and how to install ISPConfig 3. Since version 3.0.4, ISPConfig comes with full support for the nginx web server in addition to Apache, and this tutorial covers the setup of a server that uses nginx instead of Apache. ISPConfig 3 is a webhosting control panel that allows you to configure the following services through a web browser: nginx and Apache web server, Postfix mail server, MySQL, Dovecot POP3/IMAP, BIND or MyDNS nameserver, PureFTPd, SpamAssassin, ClamAV, and many more.</para>
      <para>If you want to use nginx instead of Apache with ISPConfig, please note that your nginx version must be at least 0.8.21, and you must install PHP-FPM as well. For CGI/Perl support, you must use fcgiwrap. This is all covered by this tutorial. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 02.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://blog.adityapatawari.com/2011/11/using-twitter-to-monitor-your-linux.html">Aditya Patawari: Using Twitter To Monitor Your Linux Server! </ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Yes, you can use Twitter for monitoring your server. I won&apos;t say that it is a complete monitoring solution nor I will ask you to throw away your existing monitoring mechanisms. In fact the script I am talking about, <ulink url="http://myst.adityapatawari.com/">MYST</ulink> (AGPLv3), was not created for this purpose. It was created so that I could tweet without using browser with inspiration from Hiemanshu, a Fedora contributor, using <ulink url="http://code.google.com/p/python-twitter/">python-twitter</ulink> api.
(...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 01.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://how-to.linuxcareer.com/guide-to-rsnapshot-and-incremental-backups-on-linux">LinuxCareer.com/Javier L. Velasquez: Guide to rsnapshot and incremental backups on Linux</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">1. Introduction</emphasis></para>
      <para>rsnapshot is a backup tool written in Perl that utilizes rsync as its back-end. rsnapshot allows users to create customized incremental backup solutions. This article will discuss the following: the benefits of an incremental backup solution, rsnapshot&apos;s installation, its configuration, and usage examples. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 01.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://vavai.net/2011/11/installing-rapidssl-certificate-on-zimbra-mail-server/"
          >Masim Sugianto: Installing RapidSSL Certificate on Zimbra Mail Server</ulink></title>
      <para>By default, Zimbra <emphasis role="italic">c</emphasis>reate and installing<emphasis
          role="italic"> Self-Signed Certificate</emphasis> on installation process for https
        transport protocol. Self-signed certificate used for Apache jetty web server (both Zimbra
        webmail and Administration console), POP3 SSL, SMTP SSL and IMAP SSL. Self-Signed
        certificate doesn’t automatically trusted because the certificate was not issued &amp;
        certify by authorized SSL certificate provider such as Verisign, Cybertrust, Godaddy,
        RapidSSL, etc.</para>
      <para><inlinegraphic
          fileref="http://vavai.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/certificate-untrusted11.png"
          width="30%"/></para>
      <para>Below are step-by-step how to install RapidSSL certificate on Zimbra Mail Server.
        (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ Id: 03.12.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://vavai.net/2011/12/installing-opensuse-12-1-from-existing-opensusesles-without-cddvd/"
          >Masim Sugianto: Installing openSUSE 12.1 from Existing openSUSE/SLES Without
          CD/DVD</ulink></title>
      <para>openSUSE 12.1 (and also prior version) can be installed without using a cd or dvd. This
        is the most efficient way if we have running system and do not want to waste a cd/dvd. This
        also the most efficient way ifý we have prior versionýand want to upgrade or clean install
        running system directly through the network. We can use a brilliant script called <ulink
          url="http://www.suse.de/%7Elnussel/setupgrubfornfsinstall.html"
          >setupgrubfornfsinstall</ulink>.</para>
      <para>How to use this small script to fit with our requirement ? (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ Id: 03.12.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://vavai.net/2011/12/installing-virtualbox-vboxheadless-phpvirtualbox-on-opensuse-12-1-minimalis/"
          >Masim Sugianto: Installing VirtualBox VBoxHeadless</ulink></title>
      <para>VirtualBox is one of the tools that are used for Desktop Virtualization : running an OS
        within the OS. VirtualBox usually installed on the operating system that already has the
        VirtualBox GUI to manage it. But, how to manage VirtualBox without VirtualBox GUI?
        VBoxHeadless is the answer if we want to install VirtualBox on minimal Linux server and
        manage it via Browser.</para>
      <para>I’m using openSUSE 12.1 64 bit on this tutorial but the steps can also be applied to
        earlier versions (11.x) as well as on SLES 11 SP1. I also use VirtualBox for All
        distributions binary package, although for openSUSE we can also use an RPM-binary package.
        (...)</para>
      <!--($ Id: 03.12.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://sellingfreesoftwareforaliving.blogspot.com/2011/12/air-video-server-on-opensuse-121.html"
          >Han Wen Kam: Air Video Server on openSUSE 12.1</ulink></title>
      <para>In short, <ulink url="http://www.inmethod.com/air-video/index.html">Air Video</ulink> is
        a client-server product that streams, via live conversion, videos of many formats to any iOS
        device (eg iPhone, iPad etc).ý The server software is free-of-charge but only runs on Mac
        OSX and Windows.ý The client is also free-of-charge for iOS devices but "crippled".ý If you
        like the solution, you pay for the client. </para>
      <para>Since the Air Video Server is written in Java and uses a customized version of FFMPEG,
        it would be possible to run it on Linux.ý The folks behind Air Video though supportive but
        are NOT offering official support for Linux. </para>
      <para>I have been successful in making Air Video Server (AVS) work on openSUSE 11.3, 11.4 and
        12.1. Here are the steps: (...)</para>
      <!--($ Id: 03.12.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
