<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
<!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->  <important>
    <para>The Articles inside this Section are in full. If you are already knowing the stuff in
      news.opensuse.org, then you can skip this section through using the TOC.</para>
  </important>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://blog.jospoortvliet.com/2011/07/os-strategy.html">openSUSE Conference CfP
        deadline extended</ulink>
    </title>
    <para><inlinegraphic
        fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/rwx3b-300x123.png"
        align="right"/></para>
    <para>Over the last month the conference team has received a large number of proposed sessions
      for the openSUSE conference. However, we also realize we have not entirely capitalized on the
      potential for especially the ‘interactive’ sessions we wanted. So we extend the deadline with
      two weeks to allow more BoF, Workshop and Hack sessions to be submitted. And we’ll release
      some more articles to explain what we want!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Interactive</emphasis></para>
    <para>As we wrote in the initial <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/05/16/opensuse-conference-2011-to-be-creative-and-open/"
        >call for papers</ulink>, it is our ambition to make the openSUSE conference about community
      and getting things done. Two-way communication, not one-way! Interactivity, creativity, fun.
      The awesome <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Conference_Location_Zentrifuge"
        >Zentrifuge</ulink> location is there to inspire us and we choose the subtitle of <emphasis
        role="bold">rwxý</emphasis>, commonly known as the UNIX acronym for <emphasis role="italic"
        >“Read, Write, Execute”</emphasis> for our conference.</para>
    <para>More importantly, we asked for ‘interactive session proposals’. And that is also where we
      failed a bit. Not everyone in openSUSE is familiar with workshops, BoFs or Hack sessions. We
      introduced <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/14/opensuse-conference-and-rw-sessions-the-bof/">the
        BoF in an article</ulink> but the other sessions have not seen any explanation besides what
      can be found on the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Conference_Planning_2011_guidelines_for_speakers"
        >speaker guideline page</ulink>.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">So more time and explanation</emphasis></para>
    <para>In short, the four sessions explained:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">BoF</emphasis> – “Birds of a Feather”. Basically means ‘members
          of a team”. Can be best described as an informal team meeting to discuss a variety of
          things and make decisons. (<ulink
            url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/14/opensuse-conference-and-rw-sessions-the-bof/"
            >article desribing the BoF</ulink>)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Workshop</emphasis> – teaching session. In a workshop, a number
          of participants sit down to learn in a hands-on manner (via exercises) a particular skill
          like packaging or testing an application and submitting a bugreport.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Hack Session</emphasis> – coding session. A group of
          developers/packagers/artist/writers/etc gets together to get a particular job done. For
          example to get certain packages build, a feature integrated or a document written.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>In the coming two weeks we will release articles on giving a workshop and leading a hack
      session. We hope that this will inspire you all to come up with good ideas and help you
      organize, plan and <ulink
        url="http://conference.opensuse.org/indico//conferenceDisplay.py?confId=2">send in a session
        for the openSUSE conference</ulink>!</para>
    <para>Watch this space for the write-ups on workshops and hack sessions and read <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/14/opensuse-conference-and-rw-sessions-the-bof/">this
        article about the BoF</ulink> to find out how to best organize a team meeting!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Send your Proposals</emphasis></para>
    <para>Once you’ve identified what you’d like to do at the conference, <ulink
        url="http://conference.opensuse.org/indico//conferenceDisplay.py?confId=2">send in a
        proposal</ulink>. Don’t worry about your skills and if you’re good enough, nor about if you
      can finance the trip. If you WANT to do it, that’s enough! We’ll provide support at the
      conference in leading the sessions and we also will have travel sponsorship available for
      those tight on mony, watch this space for news on that soon.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Helping Out</emphasis></para>
    <para>On a sidenote, the conference team is still looking for help! If you want to get involved
      and help us make the openSUSE conference possible, please subscribe to the team mailinglist:
        <ulink url="mailto:opensuse-conference@opensuse.org"
        >opensuse-conference@opensuse.org</ulink> and checkout the planning page.</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 11.7.11 sat $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/07/08/have-a-computer-then-you-can-participate-in-the-hcl-week/">Have a computer? Then you can participate in the HCL Week!</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>Aloha openSUSE Users!</para>
    <para>Now is an excellent time to help openSUSE! If you have openSUSE running on your system, all you have to do is add your hardware to the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Hardware">openSUSE Hardware compatibility List</ulink>. Add your pheriphials like printers, scanners and webcams. Or add internal stuff like graphics and sound cards, mother boards, wifi cards and every thing else from your netbooks, notebooks, desktops and workstations!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">How does it work?</emphasis></para>
    <para>Go to the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Hardware">hardware portal</ulink> and add your info in the table in the proper category. We suggest to read the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Smolt">Smolt</ulink> wiki page to find out how to get details on you hardware.</para>
    <para>If anyone is interested in helping out to improve this process, for example by creating a way to transform a smolt url to an entry in the wiki, that would be immensely helpful! Suggestions and offers for help are welcome <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/other-forums/community-fun/opensuse-wiki-discussions/">in this forum thread</ulink>.</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 10.7.11 sat $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://conference.opensuse.org/indico//confRegistrationFormDisplay.py?confId=2">openSUSE Conference 2011: Registration</ulink>
    </title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Registration opening day</emphasis>: 08 July 2011</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Registration deadline</emphasis>: 10 September 2011</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Contact info</emphasis>: conference@opensuse.org</para>
    <para>The registration for the openSUSE Conference 2011 is now open. Please make sure to register to help us planning for a great event.</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 10.7.11 sat $)-->  </blockquote>
</sect1>
