<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
<!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.novell.com/news/press/2011/4/novell-offers-industrys-longest-enterprise-linux-support-program-.html">Novell Offers Industry&apos;s Longest Enterprise Linux Support Program</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Novell today announced the expansion of its Long Term Service Pack Support (LTSS) program for SUSE® Linux Enterprise Server, lengthening customers&apos; access to the company&apos;s <ulink url="http://www.novell.com/linux/support-survey.html">industry-leading Linux* support</ulink> for each service pack release. For the first time, long term support is also provided globally for SUSE Linux Enterprise Server for System z*. Novell further announced the immediate availability of SUSE Linux Enterprise 10 Service Pack 4 (SP4), bundling all previously released patches, fixes and updates for SUSE Linux Enterprise 10, while supporting the newest hardware, storage systems and networking devices, including Intel&apos;s latest Xeon* E7 processor family and AMD&apos;s latest Opteron* processors. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 13.4.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.marketwire.com/press-release/Oracle-Announces-Its-Intention-to-Move-OpenOfficeorg-to-a-Community-Based-Project-NASDAQ-ORCL-1428324.htm">Oracle Announces Its Intention to Move OpenOffice.org to a Community-Based Project</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>REDWOOD SHORES, CA--(Marketwire - April 15, 2011) - Oracle Corporation (NASDAQ: ORCL) today is announcing its intention to move OpenOffice.org to a purely community-based open source project and to no longer offer a commercial version of Open Office.</para>
      <para>&quot;Given the breadth of interest in free personal productivity applications and the rapid evolution of personal computing technologies, we believe the OpenOffice.org project would be best managed by an organization focused on serving that broad constituency on a non-commercial basis,&quot; said Edward Screven, Oracle&apos;s Chief Corporate Architect. &quot;We intend to begin working immediately with community members to further the continued success of Open Office. Oracle will continue to strongly support the adoption of open standards-based document formats, such as the Open Document Format (ODF).&quot; (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 16.4.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.communityleadershipsummit.com/">Community Leadership Summit 2011: 23rd-24th July, 2011 – Portland, Oregon</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Community Leadership Summit 2011</emphasis> is the <emphasis role="italic">third</emphasis> incarnation of the popular event designed to bring together community leaders and managers and the projects and organizations that are interested in growing and empowering a strong community.

</para>
      <para>The event provides an unconference style schedule in which attendees can discuss, debate and explore topics. This is augmented with a range of scheduled talks, panel discussions, networking opportunities and more.

</para>
      <para>The event provides the first opportunity of its kind to bring together the leading minds in the field with new community builders to discuss topics such as <emphasis role="italic">governance, creating collaborative environments, conflict resolution, transparency, open infrastructure, social networking, commercial investment in community, engineering vs. marketing approaches to community leadership</emphasis> and much more. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 16.4.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/Kernel-Log-Coming-in-2-6-39-Part-1-Network-drivers-and-infrastructure-1227053.html">h-online/Thorsten Leemhuis: Kernel Log: Coming in 2.6.39 (Part 1) - Network drivers and infrastructure</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">The addition of ipset support makes it easier to run a firewall, as it means that only one table needs to be modified in order to block a specific IP address. The situation with regard to drivers for WLAN chips continues to improve, with Ralink and Realtek now actively involved in developing the Linux kernel drivers.</emphasis></para>
      <para>Linus Torvalds&apos; release emails for the <ulink url="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.kernel/1123040">second</ulink> and <ulink url="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.kernel/1124982">third</ulink> pre-release
        versions of Linux kernel 2.6.39 both note a comparative lack of changes. The calm prior to
        the RC2 release even prompted him to speculate whether the kernel developers were &quot;up to
        something&quot;. More jocularity of this ilk was evident on the release of RC3 on Tuesday, but
        both emails make it clear that he welcomes the tranquillity and is looking forward to a
        quiet development cycle.</para>
      <para>As usual, the bulk of the changes in the next major kernel revision found their way into
        the main development tree during the merge window. Kernel Log is therefore already in a
        position to offer a comprehensive overview of the major changes in kernel 2.6.39, scheduled
        for release in mid to late May. A range of articles will deal with different functional
        areas of the kernel in turn. The &quot;Coming in 2.6.39&quot; series opens here with the major changes
        in the network stack and associated drivers. Over the next few weeks, this will be followed
        by articles covering graphics drivers, storage support, file systems, architecture code,
        infrastructure and drivers for other hardware. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 13.4.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://opensourcetogo.blogspot.com/2011/04/removingconfiguring-facebook-apps-do.html">Open Source to Go: Removing/Configuring Facebook Apps: Do You Know How?</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>I know a number of folks in the community are Facebook users—despite the dire warnings
        of some about &quot;CIA plots&quot; and the like—but with the dramatic increases in &quot;rogue&quot; apps there
        and &quot;like-jackings&quot; and such, I&apos;m not sure everyone knows how to remove an application you
        don&apos;t want, or to configure one to limit the information it can access (when it&apos;s possible
        to do so).</para>
      <para>Facebook seems to want to make this as difficult as possible, by hiding the settings in
        not-easy-to-locate places, by moving things around, etc. Accordingly, I wrote up <ulink url="http://caffeine.shugendo.org/2011/04/14/configuring-and-removing-facebook-apps-heres-how/">a quick guide</ulink>, with screen shots, over on my other blog, for those who are
        interested... </para>
<!--($ ld: 15.4.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://dasublogbyprashanth.blogspot.com/2011/04/review-gnome-3.html"> dasublogbyprashanth: Review: GNOME 3 </ulink>
      </title>
      <para>About 2 months ago, I <ulink url="http://dasublogbyprashanth.blogspot.com/2011/02/preview-gnome-3.html">previewed</ulink> GNOME 3. At that time, it was many weeks away from the final release,
        so there were still many things to be done. Since then, many things have changed, and a few
        days ago, GNOME 3 was finally released for the whole world to see. </para>
      <para>The biggest change in GNOME 3 is of course the GNOME 3 Shell. This has gotten several
        changes, updates, and other revisions through its development. Since then, however, a GNOME
        3 fallback mode has also been added. One of the common complaints about GNOME 3 has been
        that the new Mutter WM requires 3D effects to work correctly, and not all computers have
        this, especially older ones. This is where GNOME 3 fallback mode comes in, so in addition to
        trying out GNOME 3 Shell, I have also tried GNOME 3 fallback mode. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 12.4.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://ostatic.com/blog/testing-plasma-active">OStatic/Susan Linton: Testing Plasma Active</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Yesterday when I <ulink url="http://ostatic.com/blog/kdes-new-project-for-portable-devices">introduced Plasma Active</ulink>, I secretly thought to myself &quot;oh no, so it&apos;s begun.&quot; See, I have this underlying fear that KDE is going to go the way of GNOME 3 and Unity and finding the removal of user choice in upcoming KDE software compilations sowed the seeds. Despite my biased first impressions, I booted the live ISO provided by open-six.

</para>
      <para>open-six used openSUSE as the basis for <ulink url="http://download.open-slx.com/iso/11.4/plasma-active.i686-1.0.6.iso">it&apos;s live CD</ulink>. It was a bit slow to boot, but truthfully, I didn&apos;t really expect it to finish. Afterall, the list of known working devices is short and I was booting on my regular desktop machine with NVIDIA graphics and two monitors. Well, it did finish booting and it even started the Plasma Active desktop. (The desktop was cloned across the two monitors - which is really best-case scenario without proprietary graphic drivers.)

</para>
      <para>And darn it all, I really hate to admit this... but my first word, my first thought was, &quot;Wow!&quot; This Plasma Active thing might really be cool on a little netbook or tablet. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 16.4.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://geekybodhi.net/habari/interview-with-vincent-untz-at-gnome-asia-summit-2011">Mayank Sharma: Interview with Vincent Untz at Gnome Asia Summit 2011</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><ulink url="http://geekybodhi.net/habari/www.vuntz.net">Vincent Untz</ulink> is the uber-geek release manager for Gnome. We catch him at the <ulink url="http://2011.gnome.asia/">Gnome Asia Summit</ulink> in Bangalore for a quick chat on all things <ulink url="http://gnome3.org/">Gnome 3</ulink> (and some things not).

</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Mayank Sharma: What&apos;s your role in the GNOME project?</emphasis>

</para>
      <para>Vincent Untz: My current role is Release Manager of GNOME, which more or less means cheering the release team, because in the release team we all work together, and we are all on the same equal footing.

</para>
      <para>The release team exists to make sure that we release Gnome on time with the quality we all expect, and to make important decisions when decisions need to be taken, like which new modules are to be part of Gnome, to publish the schedule for the release cycle, and everything that is related to release engineering a big project like Gnome. Because Gnome is actually made of more than 100 modules, so it&apos;s really a lot of coordination between the modules to make sure everything works.

</para>
      <para>So that&apos;s my main role. I am also maintaining a few modules, and doing many other things. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 16.4.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.theinquirer.net/inquirer/news/2043530/wordpresscom-hacked">the INQUIRER/Asavin Wattanajantra: Wordpress.com gets hacked</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>OPEN SOURCE blogging website Wordpress.com suffered a hack attack on its servers, prompting the company behind the popular content management system to issue a warning about passwords.

</para>
      <para>In a brief but honest note from Automattic, it said that there had been a low-level (root) break-in to several servers, where <ulink url="http://en.blog.wordpress.com/2011/04/13/security/">anything on them could have been revealed</ulink>. (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.petur.eu/blog/?p=349">Petur.eu: Linux can be hacked with an USB device</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>I have to admit, over the years I haven’t given openSUSE enough love or credit for being
        the outstanding Linux distribution is it. With that said, I wanted to give some attention to
        the latest release coming out of the openSUSE project. And, since the default desktop for
        openSUSE 11.4 is KDE, I will be giving a little extra attention to the KDE desktop. Since
        both might well gain some serious ground, when Ubuntu 11.04 is released, it will be nice for
        users to not only know of its existence, but to also know that openSUSE 11.4 is, in fact, a
        solid distribution worth giving a look. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 16.4.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxpromagazine.com/Online/News/Adobe-Issues-Security-Advisory-for-Flash-Player">Linux Pro Magazine/Amber Graner: Adobe Issues Security Advisory for Flash Player</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">A security advisory warning has been issued by Adobe for a critical vulnerablity in its Flash Player 10.2.153.1 and more.</emphasis>

</para>
      <para>According <ulink url="http://www.adobe.com/support/security/advisories/apsa11-02.html">to the advisory</ulink>, &quot;A <ulink url="http://www.adobe.com/devnet/security/severity_ratings.html">critical</ulink> vulnerability exists in Flash Player 10.2.153.1 and earlier versions (Adobe Flash Player 10.2.154.25 and earlier for Chrome users) for Windows, Macintosh, Linux and Solaris, Adobe Flash Player 10.2.156.12 and earlier versions for Android, and the Authplay.dll component that ships with Adobe Reader and Acrobat X (10.0.2) and earlier 10.x and 9.x versions for Windows and Macintosh operating systems.&quot;

</para>
      <para>This vulnerablility could, according to Adobe, cause a crash and potentially allow an attacker to take control of the affected system. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 16.4.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
<!--<sect2>
  <title>LOL</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://xkcd.com/874/">XKCD: Time Management</ulink>
    </title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/time_management.png" width="50%"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.5/">CC-BY-NC</ulink></para>
  </blockquote>
</sect2>--></sect1>
