<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
<!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->  
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://labs.qt.nokia.com/2011/10/21/the-qt-project-is-live/">The Qt Project is live!</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>I’m happy to announce that the Qt Project officially went live today. Starting today, development of Qt will be governed as a true open source project.</para>
      <para>We now have <ulink url="http://qt-project.org/">qt-project.org</ulink> – a website where all development of Qt will be centered, providing the same infrastructure and processes for everybody that wants to contribute to Qt. (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
<!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.socallinuxexpo.org/blog/design-logo-scale-10x-win-trip-la">Design a logo for SCALE 10X, win a trip to LA!</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Want a free trip to SCALE 10X in Los Angeles this January?</emphasis></para>
      <para>In marking 10 years of the Southern California Linux Expo (SCALE) and 20 years of Linux, the SCALE team wants to incorporate an open-source approach to this year’s expo logo designs for publications and for swag. 

With this in mind, the SCALE team announces a contest to select the artwork for use on this year&apos;s t-shirts, attendee bags, and other conference materials.</para>
      <para>The designer of the winning submission will win a free pass to <ulink url="http://www.socallinuxexpo.org/scale10x/">SCALE 10x</ulink>, including airfare within the continental United States, as well as a three-night stay at the <ulink url="http://www.hilton.com/en/hi/groups/personalized/L/LAXAHHH-LNX-20120116/index.jhtml?WT.mc_id=POG%20target=">Hilton Los Angeles Airport</ulink>. (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/linux-foundation-proposes-to-use-uefi-to-make-pcs-secure-and-free/9827">ZDNet/Steven J. Vaughan-Nichols: Linux Foundation proposes to use UEFI to make PCs secure and free</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Microsoft’s proposed use of <ulink url="http://www.uefi.org/home/">Unfied Extensible Firmware Interface (UEFI)</ulink> in Windows 8 could be used to <ulink url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/microsoft-to-stop-linux-older-windows-from-running-on-windows-8-pcs/9589">block all other operating systems from Windows 8 systems</ulink>. <ulink url="http://www.linuxfoundation.org/">The Linux Foundation</ulink> and partners have a better idea: Secure computers with UEFI and give users freedom of operating system choice.</para>
      <para>In the Linux Foundation document, <ulink url="http://www.linuxfoundation.org/publications/making-uefi-secure-boot-work-with-open-platforms">Making UEFI Secure Boot Work With Open Platforms</ulink> (PDF Link), James Bottomley, CTO of Server Virtualization at <ulink url="http://www.parallels.com/">Parallels</ulink> and Linux Foundation Technical Advisory Board Chair Jonathan Corbet, Editor at <ulink url="http://lwn.net/">LWN.net</ulink> and fellow Linux Foundation Technical Advisory Board Member, after consulting with other Linux leaders, explain how “Linux and other open operating systems will be able to take advantage of secure boot if it is implemented properly in the hardware.” (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 5.11.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/open/news/item/Ruby-1-9-3-arrives-with-licence-change-1368959.html">h-online/Chris von Eitzen: Ruby 1.9.3 arrives with licence change</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The <ulink url="http://www.ruby-lang.org/en/">Ruby</ulink> development team <ulink url="http://www.ruby-lang.org/en/news/2011/10/31/ruby-1-9-3-p0-is-released/">announced</ulink> the release of version 1.9.3 of its open source programming language. <ulink url="http://blade.nagaokaut.ac.jp/cgi-bin/scat.rb/ruby/ruby-core/40527">Described as</ulink> basically being &quot;an implementation-improved version of Ruby 1.9.2&quot;, the first release of the new stable series of Ruby improves library loading performance and brings changes to the Ruby licence.</para>
      <para>Ruby 1.9.3 p0 source code is made available under a 2-clause BSD Licence and the<ulink url="http://www.ruby-lang.org/en/LICENSE.txt"> Ruby Licence</ulink>; previous versions of Ruby were released under the GPLv2 and Ruby Licence. Other changes include improved locking in multi-threaded programs, regular expression support for Unicode 6.0 and a new library io/console for simple portable access to the console. Also among the modifications are changes to Random.rand and extra String methods such as prepend and byteslice, though generally, the developers say you should be able to safely switch to Ruby 1.93 from 1.9.2. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 5.11.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/microsoft-contributes-open-source-code-to-samba/9860">ZDNet/Steven J. Vaughan-Nichols: Microsoft contributes open-source code to Samba</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Freak snowstorm reported in hell. Tea party agrees Obama is the best candidate for 2012 presidential election. Microsoft submits open-source code under the GPLv3 to Samba. Those are all pretty unlikely, but <ulink url="http://samba.org/samba/news/developers/ms-patch.html">Microsoft really did submit code to the Samba</ulink> file server open-source project.</para>
      <para>This might not strike you as too amazing. After all, Microsoft has supported some open-source projects at <ulink url="http://www.codeplex.com/">CodePlex</ulink> for some time now and they will work with some other projects such as the <ulink url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/microsoft/microsoft-rolls-out-open-source-python-extension-for-visual-studio/10478">Python</ulink> and <ulink url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/microsoft-makes-pledges-to-support-apache-php-ruby/2704">PHP</ulink> languages and the <ulink url="http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/openness/story/plays-well-with-others/microsoft-plus-drupal.aspx">Drupal content management system (CMS)</ulink>. But, Samba, Samba is different. They’re an old Microsoft enemy. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 5.11.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxjournal.com/content/four-hidden-tools-scribus">Linux Journal/Bruce Byfield: Four Hidden Tools in Scribus</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Scribus is a powerful tool, but its menus are poorly laid-out. While you can usually
        find the features you most frequently use without any trouble, others may be hidden almost
        anywhere. From the Extras, Script, and Windows menus to the Document Setup dialog, useful
        features can be positioned almost anywhere, with only the most token regard for logic. </para>
      <para>The tools described here are ones that took some time for me to discover in Scribus.
        None are worth more than a few hundred words of description, but I mention them here because
        all of them can be useful to know. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 03.11.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.junauza.com/2011/10/how-to-convince-your-friends-into-using.html">Jun Auza: How to Convince Your Friends to Use Linux Without Being a Jerk</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Linux is one of the most secure and stable operating systems around, and yet, its user base hasn’t really grown as everyone expected it to. There are many reasons for this, and we won’t go into those right now. However, if you, like any other Linux user, are disappointed by the current market share stats, we can tell you some simple tips that will help you convince your Windows or Mac-crazy friends into using Linux.</para>
      <para>Now, many Linux users have already tried to coax their friends and family members to try out this popular and newbie-friendly distro called Ubuntu. A select few have succeeded and many have failed. So here, we will give you some important tips to help you spread the word about Linux without sounding like that arrogant nerd who has nothing but contempt for Windows or Mac. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 5.11.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.digitaltrends.com/web/spammers-create-and-launch-url-shortening-services-to-hide-links/">Digital Trends/Mike Flacy: Spammers create and launch URL shortening services to hide links</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">While spam continues to be a major problem for email providers and consumers, spammers have come up with a new way to hide links and slip through the spam filters.</emphasis></para>
      <para>According to new information from researchers at Symantec, a group of spammers have created a group of 87 spam-friendly, public URL shortening services and are actively using them to circumvent spam filters on popular sites. Using URL shortening scripts that are free and open source, the spammers are churning spam through the service and the public is also free to create links through the URL shorteners, perhaps an attempt to pass off the links as legitimate. All the URL shorteners are using the .info domain and are being operated through contacts in Moscow as well as a hosting company in the United Kingdom. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 28.10.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
<!--
  <sect2>
    <title>LOL</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://like-a-boss.org/2011/09/30/hacking-the-imperial-death-march/">like-a-boss.org: hacking the imperial death march</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>One of the great things about the original Star Wars trilogy, was the “lived in”, junky, hacked together aesthetic of the Star Wars universe. Everything was a bit trashed, as if real people actually lived there. Thankfully, that’s one of the things that George Lucas hasn’t tinkered with in his endless quest to ruin the childhood memories of a generation. So it’s heartening to see this tradition carried on with the playing of the imperial death march on miscellaneous hacked together hardware. Enjoy … (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> --></sect1>
