<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://kdeatopensuse.wordpress.com/2011/08/06/raw-image-processing-with-digikam/"
        >Sebastian Kügler: Desktop Summit Thoughts</ulink></title>
    <para>I’ve been to the <ulink url="http://desktopsummit.org/">Desktop Summit</ulink> in Berlin
      for the past few days, we’re now around the middle of the event, after the conference, before
      the workshop and BoF sessions, so I thought I might share some thoughts I’ve gathered in idle
      moments in the past few days.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">boredom and diversity</emphasis></para>
    <para>Last night, the build system BoF was planned, a team session where we look at the way how
      we develop our software. I have to admit that to me, this is quite a boring (but nevertheless
      very important topic). As it also affects the way we release software, I’ve put my release
      team hat on and joined the session. I was a bit afraid that since it’s not the most sexy topic
      in the world, that little people would show and we end up with incomplete or broken ways to
      release the KDE SC, and KDE Frameworks in the future. My worries were ungrounded as quite some
      people showed up and we made good progress on all the topic we talked about. (If you’re
      interested what we talked about, keep an eye on the kde-core-devel and kde-buildsystem
      mailinglists.) What struck me is that in KDE, there’s enough people who feel responsible, even
      for boring topics. When I shared my (ungrounded) concerns with Stephen Kelly, he looked at me
      with this empty expression on his face and told me “but that’s exciting, it’s the way we build
      our software!”, and given his enthusiasm, I believe him (even if I don’t exactly personally
      share his excitement). Diversity makes us strong. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 10.08.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
