<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <important>
    <para>The Articles inside this Section are in full. If you are already knowing the stuff in
      news.opensuse.org, then you can skip this section through using the TOC.</para>
  </important>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/08/09/strategy-done/">Strategy DONE!</ulink>
    </title>
    <para><inlinegraphic fileref="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4004/4356906718_7165a0b695_m.jpg"
        width="20%"/></para>
    <para>Almost 2 years ago, at the first openSUSE conference, a discussion started about Strategy.
      A few months ago a final document was ready and on July 14th 2011, the strategy voting ended.
      Over 200 of the<ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Members">openSUSE
      Members</ulink> voted, with 90% in favor of the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Strategy">current strategy document</ulink>. What’s
      next?</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Looking back</emphasis></para>
    <para>It’s been a long ride, and we’d like to give a short overview of the strategy discussion
      in the openSUSE community over the last 2 years.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">The beginning</emphasis></para>
    <para>The strategy process was started after the first openSUSE conference, now almost 2 years
      ago. In that time, quite a number of people have participated in the strategy team: Michael
      Löffler, Joe Brockmeier, Kurt Garloff, Jan Weber, Pascal Bleser, Andreas Jaeger, Bryen
      Yunashko, Pavol Rusnak, Jos Poortvliet and Thomas Thym. Of course, many others contributed by
      commenting on the proposals via mailing plists, forums, blogs and other channels.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Meetings</emphasis></para>
    <para>Initially, the team met weekly and focused on learning about strategy and how to apply it
      to a community project like openSUSE. A competition analysis was done, as well as an
      assessment of strength and weaknesses and an overview of the challenges openSUSE is facing was
      made. In May 2010 a face to face meeting was held and the team came up with a community
      statement and three different ambitious and narrow high-level visions that we planned to
      evolve and combine later.These visions were then presented to the community and we hoped for
      new scenario’s to come from then.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Change</emphasis></para>
    <para>Where the team started out quite ambitiously, trying to define new niches and a clear
      direction, it became visible that the majority of the community lost interest along the way.
      In November 2010, the team had decided to do an u-turn and</para>
    <blockquote>
      <para>focus on describing who we are, as a community, instead of finding new ways to
        go.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <para>The new goals where to:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Highlight the story behind openSUSE</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Identify what users we target and illustrate what we offer to them,</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Connect it with the issues that matter most to our community</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">New tools and lots of input</emphasis></para>
    <para>Much of the input given by community members throughout the process was looked at again
      and integrated in a <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/09/16/opensuse_finding_target/"
        >first draft</ulink> focusing on the <ulink
        url="https://lite.co-ment.com/text/lNPCgzeGHdV/view/">target users of openSUSE</ulink>. With
      this draft, a new way of discussing the document was introduced:<blockquote>
        <para><ulink url="http://www.co-ment.com/about/">co-ment</ulink>, a pretty awesome
          commenting tool under the <ulink url="http://www.fsf.org/licensing/licenses/agpl-3.0.html"
            >GNU Affero GPL</ulink></para>
      </blockquote></para>
    <para>Co-ment made it easy to give input on a specific sentence or word and discuss that in a
      structured manner, and a lot of input came in from the whole openSUSE community, with <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/09/27/opensuse-target-aquired/">the second
        revision</ulink>, introducing <emphasis role="italic">“what openSUSE offers its
        users”</emphasis>, and <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/10/07/opensuse-strategy-the-third-and-fourth-part-of-the-trilogy/"
        >the third</ulink>, <emphasis role="italic">“what does openSUSE <emphasis role="bold"
          >not</emphasis> do”</emphasis>, each drawing in almost 100 comments on co-ment alone. More
      responses were gathered and processed from various channels like <ulink
        url="http://list.opensuse.org/">mailinglists</ulink>, <ulink
        url="http://forums.opensuse.org/">the openSUSE forums</ulink>and <ulink
        url="http://omgsuse.com/content/bertel-beat-thoughts-strategy">many other
      means</ulink>.</para>
    <para>The <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/10/15/finalizing-who-we-are/">last
        posting</ulink> before the openSUSE conference attempted to shorten the document. At the
      conference, the<ulink url="http://lwn.net/Articles/412025/">strategy was presented</ulink> and
      discussed. This <ulink url="http://michal.hrusecky.net/2010/11/opensuse-conference-2010/"
        >re-invigorated interest in the strategy</ulink> for some and a new <ulink
        url="http://ungethym.blogspot.com/2010/10/opensuse-conference-2010-is-over.html">team
        member</ulink>joined the strategy discussions. Based on the feedback at the conference the
      document gained some clarity as well as a short introduction.</para>
    <para>On the 20th of December 2010, the strategy team sent the ‘final’ document to the openSUSE
      board to facilitate the member voting process.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Finishing</emphasis></para>
    <para>Due to the busy time before the openSUSE 11.4 release, it took a while for the board to go
      over the document. Some minor nitpicks arose and the new initiative Tumbleweed was added but
      after that the board asked Thomas Thym to start the voting. In the end, Jos Poortvliet put a
      vote on<ulink url="http://connect.opensuse.org/">connect</ulink> as Thomas was not openSUSE
      Member yet and the team<ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/07/time-to-vote-on-the-opensuse-strategy/">announced
        the start of the voting</ulink>. Shortly before the 30th of June, the deadline was extended
      to have time for a mass-mailing to all openSUSE Members. It had turned out that quite a few
      hadn’t noticed the strategy voting yet and the Board wanted to give them a chance to provide
      their input as well.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">The results</emphasis></para>
    <para>So on the 14th, the voting ended with a total of 204 votes, 90% of which were supportive
      of the strategy document (see table). As the voting page said, this support<blockquote>
        <para>does not mean that you have to fully agree or that it is exactly how you want it – we
          are a diverse community with many opinions and individual goals. We can never all agree on
          anything, unless it is so completely vague it doesn’t mean anything. This document is the
          product of a compromise, but the team feels it does adequately describe who we are and
          where we want to go.</para>
      </blockquote></para>
    <para>It does mean that the openSUSE Membership feels the document adequately describes the
      openSUSE community and what it does and doesn’t do.</para>
    <para>“Having the strategy document in place provides the project an anchor to reflect upon when
      project questions and issues arise”, openSUSE Board Chairman Alan Clark said. “It is a very
      good reference point for those either new to the project or those wanting to capture a glimpse
      of what openSUSE is and why one should come join us.”</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">openSUSE – the world’s most flexible and powerful Linux
        distribution</emphasis></para>
    <para>The <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Strategy">strategy</ulink> is a document
      which describes openSUSE as a community. Our values, goals and the way we work. It starts with
        the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Strategy_Community_Statement">‘community
        statement’</ulink>:<blockquote>
        <para>We are the openSUSE Community – a friendly, welcoming, vibrant, and active community.
          This includes developers, testers, writers, translators, usability experts, artists,
          promoters and everybody else who wishes to engage with the project.</para>
      </blockquote></para>
    <para>And then summarizes what we do as follows:<blockquote>
        <para>The openSUSE project is a worldwide effort that promotes the use of Linux everywhere.
          The openSUSE community develops and maintains a packaging and distribution infrastructure
          which provides the foundation for the world’s most flexible and powerful Linux
          distribution. Our community works together in an open, transparent and friendly manner as
          part of the global Free and Open Source Software community.</para>
      </blockquote></para>
    <para>After that, the strategy goes into more detail, talking about our target users, our
      philosophy when it comes to development, our focus on collaboration and the things we don’t
      do. While reading the strategy, you need to keep two things in mind: it is meant as an
      internal document – it’s not marketing speak. And it’s not meant to tell anyone what to do or
      not to do – we are an open community!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">The future</emphasis></para>
    <para>The team noted that the<blockquote>
        <para>strategy is of course not set in stone for eternity although we probably won’t go
          through this process every year…</para>
      </blockquote></para>
    <para>and asked for further feedback in the mass mailing to the membership. Some comments did
      indeed come in, most notably asking for the ARM port and mobile devices as well as the impact
      of the openSUSE Foundation.</para>
    <para>In the future, the strategy documents will surelyrequire some revision. Once somebody in
      the openSUSE community steps up to do an ARM port, which is likely to attract significant
      help, the document will have to be revisited to reflect this, just like <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Tumbleweed">Tumbleweed</ulink> resulted in a change.
      And once a openSUSE Foundation is established it is likely this new organisation will
      become ‘owner’ of this document. For such changes, the <email>opensuse-strategy@opensuse.org</email>
      mailinglist is still open and it will remain so. Obviously a discussion can also be held on
      the opensuse-project mailing list or in other places!</para>
    <para><!-- ($ ld: 10.8.11 sm $)--></para>
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
