<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <important>
    <para>The Articles inside this Section are in full. If you are already knowing the stuff in
      news.opensuse.org, then you can skip this section through using the TOC.</para>
  </important>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/27/opensuse-strategy-voting-close-to-the-finish-line/"
        >openSUSE strategy voting close to the finish line!</ulink></title>
    <para>As we wrote <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/07/time-to-vote-on-the-opensuse-strategy/">three weeks
        ago</ulink>, June 30th is the deadline for <ulink url="http://bit.ly/kZaAC2">voting for the
        openSUSE Strategy</ulink>!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Relevance</emphasis></para>
    <para>2 years ago the subject came up at the openSUSE conference: <emphasis role="italic">what
        do we want</emphasis>? That is not a simple question. We are a large community with
      wide-ranging diverse backgrounds, goals and interests.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Having a coherent answer matters</emphasis>: it shows potential new
      contributors what they can (although not limited) contribute to; it helps us make decisions.
      Do we focus on fancy web stuff? Do we go for a stable or more experimental product? Do we
      simplify at all costs or cater to more advanced users? These and more are questions brought up
      in our strategy discussion.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Discussion</emphasis></para>
    <para>It took a long time – we are an open community and as such, strategic discussions take
      time. However, we went through the effort. Lots of input came from a variety of people – each
      iteration had sometimes over a hundred comments. You can view some of the  <ulink
        url="https://lite.co-ment.com/text/lNPCgzeGHdV/history/">although you should notice that
        co-ment is just one of the ways we collected feedback (others being the mailing lists, IRC,
        forums and more)</ulink>.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Serious</emphasis></para>
    <para>While the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Strategy">current proposal</ulink>
      is not meant to be limiting new directions or will be forever set in stone, it is meant to
      provide clarity to our community for the time being. So we do want it to be taken seriously.
      We develop major software products promoting open source and the use of Linux world wide.
      We’re a major Linux distribution, the second largest by most metrics. We provide a packaging
      build service that is used by distributions more than just openSUSE. We have an obligation to
      deliver a consistent, quality product to our users. And to provide an open and fun place to be
      around for contributors. We can’t satisfy every need to the fullest, but what we can do is
      make clear what we are trying to do here.</para>
    <para>Providing that clarity to our users and contributors through this strategy is a major step
      towards our future. So, we need our membership to vote. To make your voice heard and to know
      if it truly has the support it needs.</para>
    <para>So, if you’re an openSUSE Member, go,<ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Strategy"
        >read the document one more time</ulink> and <ulink url="http://bit.ly/kZaAC2">cast your
        vote</ulink>!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Editor's note</emphasis>: Althogh the deadline for voting has passed
      already, and even if you are not a Member, we strongly recommend you to read the proposal once
      again.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 28.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/29/opensuse-continues-brazilian-blaze/"
        >openSUSE Continues Brazilian Blaze!</ulink></title>
    <para>Continuing the great work of our Ambassadors of the Southern Hemisphere, our Brazilian
      openSUSE team once again gets ready for a strong openSUSE presence in Brazil beginning today
      at <ulink url="http://softwarelivre.org/fisl12">FISL 12-Software Livre in beautiful Porto
        Alegre</ulink>. A major FOSS event in South America, FISL 12 is expecting 8,000 attendees
      this year.</para>
    <para><inlinegraphic fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/FISL12.png"
        width="10%"/></para>
    <para>The openSUSE Brazilian Ambassador team has been making strong inroads introducing not just
      our distro but also our many Project offerings, such as the <ulink
        url="http://buildservice.org">Open Build Service</ulink>, <ulink url="http://susestudio.com"
        >SUSE Studio</ulink>, and <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Education-Li-f-e"
        >Edu-L-Ife</ulink>. openSUSE has played such an important role from the classroom to the
      corporate offices across the country and most importantly, building community within
      Brazil.</para>
    <para>So, if you just happen to be in the Porto Alegre area (or heck, if you feel the urge to
      jump on a plane from anywhere in the world right now) hop on down to FISL 12 and stop by the
      openSUSE Booth. The team will be in force and will be ready to answer all your questions about
      openSUSE and give you free LiveDVDs. You can also catch them throughout the event giving talks
      on OBS, Edu-L-Ife, giving general updates about the latest in the openSUSE Project. And you
      won’t want to miss the openSUSE Community Meeting where you get to express your views and
      support for openSUSE.</para>
    <para>It’s definitely an event you won’t want to miss, and it’s all happening right there in
      Porto Alegre. So stop by as soon as you can.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 29.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
