<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://blog.jospoortvliet.com/2011/04/libreoffice.html">Jos Poortvliet:
        LibreOffice</ulink></title>
    <para>I just stumbled upon <ulink url="http://www.gnome.org/%7Emichael/blog/2011-03-31.html"
        >mmeeks blog</ulink> where he mentions some of his favorite projects from the <ulink
        url="http://wiki.documentfoundation.org/Development/Gsoc/Ideas">LibreOffice GSoC
        ideas</ulink>. And it made me happy. </para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-88Cy1AaM0HM/TZdPqCrYfrI/AAAAAAAABdw/yv2wyv4KsDg/s320/openoffice-logo1-300x185.png"
          width="20%"/>
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">OpenOffice = blegh</emphasis></para>
    <para>Now I've never been a big fan of OpenOffice. I saw it as a huge pile of legacy code with
      little future. Part of that was due to the <quote>WE OWN OPENOFFICE</quote> Governance from
      Sun/Oracle, part due the the slowness and UI horror. And part due to developers saying things
      like </para>
    <para><quote><emphasis role="italic">developing OpenOffice is like brushing your teeth with a
          chainsaw</emphasis></quote></para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-XODnpXc4DIU/TZdPalYv0CI/AAAAAAAABdo/s-BpTewrlqY/s400/libreoffice_Icon.png"
          width="20%"/>
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">LibreOffice an improvement</emphasis></para>
    <para>The LibreOffice fork solves the governance issue and focusses strongly on cleaning up the
      code. Still I felt they still had the <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Millstone"
        >Millstone</ulink> of the old codebase around the neck. I've always seen a lot more future
      for <ulink url="http://www.calligra-suite.org/">Calligra suite</ulink> which has a modern code
      base and innovative features, especially since the inception of <ulink
        url="http://www.kogmbh.com/">KO GmbH</ulink>. For me, LibreOffice did not seem relevant for
        anything other than bridging the gap until Calligra was end user ready.. </para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-CwfIo2lwwl4/TZdP5OrMmYI/AAAAAAAABd4/BHnqNupWrjQ/s320/calligra.png"/>
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Light at the end of the tunnel</emphasis></para>
    <para>So the <ulink url="http://www.gnome.org/~michael/blog/2011-03-31.html">post by
        Meeks</ulink> lighted up a little spark in me when he mentioned moving over the Canvas to
      Cairo. Yes, I'm no developer, but I do know that Cairo is a modern technology, good enough to
      be adopted as the new canvas by the upcoming Qt4 port of <ulink
        url="http://www.scribus.net/canvas/Scribus">Scribus</ulink> (part of openSUSE 11.4). And it
      is what GNOME Shell is build upon, not exactly irrelevant either. Meeks also mentions an
      Android port which would force work on improving performance like it did for Calligra office.
      So why is this so special? It's not like OO.o didn't have any plans... Well, frankly, the only
        <emphasis role="italic">improvements</emphasis> I've seen from OO.o over the last years was
      an addition like Java. Sorry but why oh why add Java to an office suite which is already slow
      as crap and big as a mountain? Oh, and the discussions about the <quote>awesome UI
        redesign</quote> (<quote>let's copy the ribbon, badly</quote>). I didn't hear about taking
      advantage of modern technologies like Cairo. Frankly, the improvements were mostly putting
      lipstick on a pig, if you ask me.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">LibreOffice REALLY brings change!</emphasis></para>
    <para>So now I have the impression that LibreOffice <emphasis role="bold">really</emphasis>
      represents a change. Sure, it's all perception, I know. I'm sure the OO team did some
      replacing-of-legacy-stuff. And LibreOffice still has a HUGE amount of work to do. They still
      have the old code base. But the project is revitalized! With all the new developers and
      LibreOffice in GSoC, there is change in the air. With <ulink
        url="http://www.calligra-suite.org/news/calligra-suite-the-first-three-months/">Calligra
        going incredibly strong as well</ulink> (just see the number of ppl <ulink
        url="http://blog.cberger.net/2011/04/01/calligra-sprint-spring-2011-day-0/">here</ulink>)
      the Free Software office space looks to be gearing up to good stuff. <emphasis role="bold">I
        for one welcome our new Office overlords, evil or not ;-)</emphasis></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">CC-BY-SA</ulink></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 3.4.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
