<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="forums">
  <title>openSUSE Forums</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/other-forums/community-fun/surveys-polls/459331-you-contributor.html">Are you a contributor</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>
      This thread does not need much introduction. A community based distribution needs a community. But what do it's members do to contribute. Here's a survey + poll.
    </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/install-boot-login/459751-boot-problem-after-update.html">Boot problem after update</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>
      Like most distributions openSUSE has an update system, sometimes refered to as YOU, Yast Online Update. The updates provided vary from new program releases to serious system updates. Now, this thread reports issues, and solutions, for boot problems related to a recent kernel update. Meanwhile there's quite some info available about the boot process.
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/multimedia/459785-unable-capture-sound.html">Unable to capture sound</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>
      Over the past decade computers have become true muldimedia machines. We use them to play our music and videos, some of us watch TV, many of us use VOIP, we make music. To do so, one of the things that needs to work is sound capture, for example recording through a microphone in a laptop. Here's a user with problems in capturing sound, the thread ends in a very happy ending. Read what's done to help the poster out.
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
    <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/multimedia/456987-opensuse-11-4-kmix-too-few-channels-probably-due-pulseaudio.html">openSUSE 11.4 Kmix too few channels</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>
      Another one from the multimedia area. A nice thread for those used to KDE4 and Kmix's interface, since there have been some changes in how sound is handled. This has resulted in a different layout of the Kmix interface. If you have sound working OK, but are wondering where all the channels you used to see in Kmix have gone, this should be a good read for you.
      </para>
<!-- ($ ld: 19.05.2011 gl $) -->  </blockquote>
</sect1>
