<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/01/18/obs-books-project/">OBS Books Project</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>openSUSE Build Service (OBS) has a problem. It is horrible powerful, but no one knows. Or
      no one knows how to make use of it in short. </para>
    <para>Our documentation exists only in the wiki so far. While the wiki is still and will remain
      as a documentation resource, several of us OBS users and developers think we need something
      more structured and edited. A real book in short, which you can read to get an entire
      overview. </para>
    <para>Therefore we started to create the infrastructure to write such books, it is part of the
      openSUSE documentation project. This means the documentation is written in docbook and hosted
      in svn. </para>
    <para>The docbook code get currently generated into html once a day. There are currently two
      books set up, one as <ulink
        url="http://doc.opensuse.org/products/draft/OBS/obs-reference-guide/">reference
        guide</ulink> and one as <ulink
        url="http://doc.opensuse.org/products/draft/OBS/obs-best-practices/">best practice
        guide</ulink>. </para>
    <para>The great thing about docbook is that we can put also instance specific content inside,
      for example chapters or paragraphs which are only valid for build.opensuse.org or for
      build.meego.com for example. We can generate specific books out of this common source
      afterwards. </para>
    <para>So far the only article which really exists in these books is the how to to join book
      writing. So come, provide patches or create an account on <ulink
        url="http://developer.berlios.de/account/register.php">berlios</ulink> for direct submission
      permissions. It is not needed currently that you need to know OBS perfectly, it is enough to
      know something in some area. We will improve it afterwards. </para>
    <para>Don’t care about the current structure either a lot atm. We will rethink about it once we
      have more content. </para>
    <para>Please read also the current <ulink
        url="http://doc.opensuse.org/products/draft/OBS/obs-best-practices/pr01.html"
        >preface</ulink> which defines the goals of these books. </para>
    <para>Also the license of these books is the same as the license of the texts in the openSUSE
      wiki (GFDL). This means we can copy all text parts from the wiki to the book and vice versa. </para>
    <para>And of course, come to the <ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-buildservice/"
        >opensuse-buildservice mailing list</ulink> for discussing any of the articles, goals or
      suggestions. Nothing is in stone :)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 18.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/01/19/hackweek-vi/">Hackweek VI</ulink></title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Hackweek VI</emphasis> will take place January 24th – 28th,
      2011.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata width="25%"
          fileref="http://en.opensuse.org/images/thumb/3/32/Hackweek-mug.png/270px-Hackweek-mug.png"
          align="center"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Hackweek is one of Novell’s biggest ways of giving back to the openSUSE community – by
      providing developers the opportunity to spend their paid work week contributing to free and
      open source software instead of their assigned projects. Hackweek V produced an amazing
      variety of projects, including <ulink url="http://www.froxlor.org/">froxlor</ulink> (server
      management panel), a <ulink url="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vYER9WaPXg0">donor management
        app</ulink> for <ulink url="http://www.shelterbox.org/">Shelterbox</ulink>, a <ulink
        url="http://blog.cornelius-schumacher.de/2010/06/hackweek-v-graphical-suse-studio-client.html"
        >GUI client</ulink> for <ulink url="http://susestudio.com">SUSE Studio</ulink>, and <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Hackweek_V">hundreds more</ulink>. Prior Hackweeks have
      spawned projects that are now desktop Linux mainstays, like <ulink
        url="http://live.gnome.org/Tasque">Tasque</ulink> and <ulink
        url="http://code.google.com/p/giver/">Giver</ulink>. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Hackweek VI</emphasis> features the theme <quote>Engineering
        Cloud</quote> and allows developers to get their hands on related projects. In order to
      support that approach, we are providing access to a few select cloud providers and a setup
      where you can deploy cloud infrastructure software (e.g. Eucalyptus). Your favorite
      hack-project may or may not relate to that theme, it may well be experimental, as long as it
      is Linux- or SUSE-related. </para>
    <para>As in previous years, we will be using <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org"
        >openFATE</ulink> to track your ideas and coordinate with others that might want to join a
      project. Make sure to check out all ideas listed in the<emphasis role="bold">
        <ulink url="">Hack Week VI</ulink>
      </emphasis>product category. </para>
    <para>We also plan to nominate the 3 best projects that relate to the <quote>Engineering
        Cloud</quote> theme and hand out Amazon gift vouchers. For your project to be considered we
      ask you to:<orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>submit your idea until Friday Jan 21st at openFATE (opens Jan, 13)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>provide a introductory video of your project on Monday, Jan, 24th</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>wrap up and do a final video submission no later than Friday, Feb 4th</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist></para>
    <para>As usual, Novell extends the invitation to openSUSE Community contributors. Participating
      Novell locations also try to provide a <quote>hackspace</quote>, some comfy place to meet,
      work together and snack. </para>
    <para>Finally, we are trying to spread the word via <ulink
        url="http://twitter.com/#!/search/%23hackweek6">#hackweek6</ulink> on twitter and look
      forward to hear about your updates there. For more information, follow up on the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Hackweek">Hackweek Portal</ulink> at <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Hackweek">http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Hackweek</ulink>,
      and have fun!</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 19.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
