<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 id="gsoc" role="gsoc">
  <title>Google Summer of Code</title>
  <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
      <imagedata width="20%" align="center" fileref="http://michal.hrusecky.net/wp-content/uploads/GSoC2011_300x200.png"/>
    </imageobject>
  </mediaobject>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://alex.eftimie.ro/2011/07/17/packagekit-backend-for-software-center-short-week-7-report/"
        >Alex Eftimie: PackageKit backend for Software Center: short week 7 report</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>Short weekly report is short, this week’s achievements:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>fixed the install/remove simulation bits (it can now tell what packages will be
            removed after applying changes)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>improved PackageInfo testing (works with both AptCache and PackageKit)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>found the problem with dynamic/static libs conflict: it is gio statically
            loaded from gtk and then Gio dynamically loaded from PackageKitGlib; loading Gio before
            everything seems to fix the conflict for now;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>got another <ulink
              url="http://code.launchpad.net/~alexeftimie/software-center/backend-refactor"
              >round</ulink> of refactor changes into trunk, thanks to mvo; this way my PK branch is
            one step closer to merging into software-center</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
<!-- ($ ld: 18.7.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/07/17/gsoc-osc-code-cleanup-–-summary-of-week-8/"
        >Marcus Hüwe: osc code cleanup – summary of week 8</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>Here’s a small summary of the 8th (coding) week. This week I spentmost of my time with
      rewriting the working copy code.</para>
    <para>Done:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>added support to add and delete packages</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>added some “abstractions” for the tracking file format:currently packages and files
            are tracked in a xml file</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>thought about the package update algorithm. Basicallyit’ll work like this (verfy
            simplified version):<itemizedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>perform update in a tmpdir (phase 1)</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>if the tmp update finished, copy/rename all files tothe wc (phase 2)</para>
                <para>Advantage:If the update is interrupted in phase 1 the wc wasn’t touchedat all
                  and nothing should be broken.If the update is interrupted in phase 2 the wc is
                  _inconsistent_but a subsequent “update” call can resume the update and
                  everythingshould be consistent afterwards (in this case only files
                  arecopied/renamed)</para>
              </listitem>
            </itemizedlist></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>TODO:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>implement update + commit algorithm</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>If everything works as expected most parts of working copy codecleanup should be finished
      after this week.</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 18.7.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/archive/opensuse-project/2011-07/msg00037.html">N B
        Prashanth: GsoC Midterm Consolidated Report - Separating libYUI</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>I would like to summarize my progress so far. I am working on thelibyui project as
      mentioned above. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 16.7.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/archive/opensuse-project/2011-07/msg00038.html">Mihnea
        Dobrescu-Balaur: Suse Bug Reporter - GSoC midterm reports</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>The expected/requested functionalities for the project are done. I'mtalking about the CLI
      version of the tool.Its main functionalities are splitted in four categories at the moment:
      (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 16.7.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://www.sebastianoliva.com/en/2011/07/gsoc-midterm-report/">Sebastian Oliva:
        GSOC, midterm reports</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>This is my mid-term report for my GSoC project for the openSUSE project. As for now, I
      have a basic working web service, using Python and MongoDB. I have implemented the JSON device
      properties specification by the OpenICC group. The web service still needs improvements on
      look, and to improve error handling.</para>
    <para>The code is available on <ulink url="https://gitorious.org/gsoc-2011/gsoc-2011"
        >gitorious.org/gsoc-2011/gsoc-2011\</ulink></para>
    <para>The objectives are now:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Creating a Gnome/GTK, and a KDE client to submit and retrieve profiles
            automatically</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Performance profiling</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Improving look and feel</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Improving the search algorithm</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>100% test coverage and more testing</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Clearing up requirements to apply for infrastructure support on the openSUSE project
            (including creating an snazzy project name </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>That’s it for the midterms, feel free to comment or contacting me,</para>
    <para>Regards, Sebastian</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 16.7.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/archive/opensuse-project/2011-07/msg00043.html">Eric
        Yang: Porting Wubi to OpenSUSE [midterm report]</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>here is an overview of my project:work has been done:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>wubi program has been modified so that it could do the first installationstage work
            for openSUSE, including iso image download/validation, creationof related files in
            windows, and collection information for automaticinstallation.</para>
          <para>after the windows program running and exit, there will be an install entry inwindows
            boot menu, the automatic installation would follow that entry.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>Work to do:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>patch the init program so that it could recognize virtual disks which areregular
            files under widows.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>create customized autoyast control file to support automatic installation.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>Current Ptoblem:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>the "init" program in initrd is a single binary program (in Ubuntu it's a shell
            script), which is hard to patch on the fly.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>if you have any suggestion or comment, please do not hesitate to send me:)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 16.7.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/archive/opensuse-project/2011-07/msg00057.html">Ratan
        Sebastian: SSC Project mid-term reports</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>The following is the mid-term report for the SSC (Suse Studio Comandline Client)
      Project</para>
    <para>Tasks completed:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Framework for the command line client including argument parser andhandlers for the
            various accessible "objects"(repos, packages, files,templates) in Suse Studio.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Directory management utilities: The app requires the creation andmanagement of an
            appliance directory for local caching of changesuntil ready to be pushed to
            Studio.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Test suite for those actions that are independent of the web API</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>Tasks to be completed:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>The update, status and commit commands: These would be the commandsthat make use of
            the locally cached information from the appliancedirectory. This is the last remaining
            feature in the app.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Integration tests: Tests that include requests to the web API.Without tests of this
            nature it is not possible to affectively testlarge portions of the app.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Documentation: code level and sample use cases.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>Please do <ulink url="http://gitourious.org/ssc/ssc">checkout the code</ulink> and do a '$
      rake install' to installthe gem. You can then try '$ ssc help' to see the usage
      instructions.</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 16.7.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/archive/opensuse-project/2011-07/msg00058.html">Christos
        Bountalis: Utility of merging configuration sysconfig files -Midterm-</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>This e-mail is a brief summary of the progress in the project till this moment as part of
      the midterm evaluation. </para>
    <para>What is done until done:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>created and retaining a git repo for testing purposes</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>learn the basic of obs that will be needed of the integration in opensuseand created
            the appropriate repo</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Getting familiar with the Augeas procedures,api etc</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>created a find lens procedure and created my first patch :)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Created the tree traversal and tree matching functions</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Modified the augtool of Augeas, in order to be able to carry the above
            actions </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Created some other utility functions necessary for the above</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>So what is to do till the end of the GSoC:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Finish the matching procedures.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Test and work on the sysconfig lens used by Augeas.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Integrate the utility in opensuse</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Finish the documentation</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>This is all i can think at the moment, you can find more information in the previous
      messages i sent in this list as well as in my blog <ulink url="http://cbounta.wordpress.com/"
        >http://cbounta.wordpress.com/</ulink> I am back to work cause time is ticking and there are
      many things to be done :) </para>
<!-- ($ ld: 16.7.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/archive/opensuse-project/2011-07/msg00061.html">Nikolay
        Rysev: Archlinux backend for Open Build Service midterm reports</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>Sorry for the long silence, I had some problems with my health, butnow all is ok.This mail
      is brief midterm report for «Archlinux backend for OBS».</para>
    <para>What is done:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Arch module for build which can:<itemizedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>parse PKGBUILDs and extract dependencies</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>parse .PKGINFO files from .pkg.tar.?z pakages and get info about it</para>
              </listitem>
            </itemizedlist></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Helper script, which gets repository metadata and prints informationabout packages
            in build corresponding format (package metadata parsingfunctions are also in arch
            module, so anyone can use them if needed)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>What is needed now for ability to build packages:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Setup build environment in init_buildsystem</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Support for calling makepkg in build script</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>What is also to be done:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Integration into OBS</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Documentation</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>You can find the code in my <ulink
        url="https://gitorious.org/~madgnu/opensuse/madgnu-archlinux-build">repository on
        gitorious</ulink>.If you have any questions or suggestions — welcome!</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 16.7.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/archive/opensuse-project/2011-07/msg00067.html">David
        Williams: Entomologist UI Changes - Midterm Reporter</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>You can find my midterm report at <ulink
        url="http://redache.wordpress.com/2011/07/14/midterm-report-things-completed-so-far/"
        >http://redache.wordpress.com/2011/07/14/midterm-report-things-completed-so-far/</ulink> and
      the text below. I really recommend reading the blog post as it has screenshots of everything
      :).</para>
    <para>This report is a summary of all the work that I've completed so far for my Summer of Code
      and what is to come :).</para>
    <para>Porting Entomologist to Windows and Mac OS X:Entomologist works mostly flawlessly on Mac
      OS X. Windows was an awkward platform to port for and it still doesn't function as well as it
      could but once we hit version 1.0 a lot of the problems can be addressed.</para>
    <para>Tabbed Interface for selecting Trackers:</para>
    <para>This took a few weeks to complete as it was awkward to get everything to work correctly, I
      also had the learning curve/understanding new code slowing me down whilst doing it. Overall
      I'm pretty happy with how it looks and how it works.</para>
    <para>New Comments Dialog:</para>
    <para>Next on the list was creating a New Comments Dialog. The goal was to make it easier to
      select a bug and see the comments and add new comments for that specific bug. The dialog works
      by either highlighting a bug in the table and hitting Ctrl + Shift + N(Cmd + Shift + N on a
      Mac) or by clicking the new comments button in the expanded comments dialog. If no bug is
      highlighted it defaults to opening the first bug in the list.</para>
    <para>ToDo Lists:</para>
    <para>This is probably the most helpful feature I've worked on throughout the project. It has
      been a bit of a learning curve and I think I'm starting to 'Get' QT and I can definitely see
      why QT is usually classed as better than GTK. This feature still isn't finished but it is
      nearly all there and I'm currently working on the mechanism to add new ToDoLists. Once that's
      completed the first basic iteration will be there and it should be useful in that
      state.</para>
    <para>Post Midterm Plans:</para>
    <para>Post midterm I want to add cloud sync to the ToDoLists so you can sync the items to
      whichever tracker you feel is appropriate. This should help in organising data and
      recording milestones through bugs :). I think I'll start by having it export to
      calendar formats that can be read by normal desktop viewers and they can handle the sync. But
      the plan is to add that service integration to entomologist itself.</para>
    <para>After that work is completed I will look at how we can integrate QML into Entomologist so
      the trackers that it supports can be extended by using QML. This would take a lot of work away
      from Matt as he won't have to add new trackers, the users that want them can use QML to define
      them and they can submit them as an extension :). I think this is the best way to manage most
      bug trackers as there are a lot of different ones out there.</para>
    <para>So that's it for the work completed so far. Hopefully at the end we'll reach version 1.0
      of Entomologist and move on with adding shiny new things :).</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 16.7.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
</sect1>
