<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <important>
    <para>The Articles inside this Section are in full. If you are already knowing the stuff in
      news.opensuse.org, then you can skip this section through using the TOC.</para>
  </important>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/14/opensuse-conference-and-rw-sessions-the-bof/"
        >openSUSE Conference and RW sessions – the BoF</ulink></title>
    <para><inlinegraphic fileref="http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1233/928122581_043479bfd5_m.jpg"
      /></para>
    <para>The openSUSE conference team adopted the UNIX acronym <emphasis role="bold"
      >RWX</emphasis> for this year’s conference. The goal with this theme is to emphasize the
      stronger focus on getting-things-done and hands-on sessions. So, what sessions are we talking
      about? In this article we’ll dive into one type of interactive session: the <ulink
        url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Birds_of_a_Feather_(computing)">BoF</ulink>.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Definition</emphasis></para>
    <para>Wikipedia <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Birds_of_a_Feather_(computing)"
        >defines</ulink> a BoF as ‘an informal discussion group’, ‘often formed in an ad-hoc
      manner’. It also describes a BoF as ‘an informal meet-up at conferences, where the attendees
      group together based on a shared interest and carry out discussions without any pre-planned
      agenda’.</para>
    <para>The central concepts are informal, shared interests and ad-hoc. What is not mentioned are
      goals, the why of such a session. But based on the concepts, you can get an idea. The informal
      factor means everyone is equal and can and should voice their opinions. The shared interests
      mean you get together people who care about a particular subject. The ad-hoc factor merely
      re-inforces the other two. A BoF is very much like meeting for dinner: you talk as friends
      about whatever interests you! That is not to say a BoF can’t have goals. Often, BoFs have a
      number of things the participants want to discuss. The person organizing the BoF is usually
      the person who puts one or more topics forward, but everyone is free to bring up other issues.
      This is central to the concept of a BoF – discuss things.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Why?</emphasis></para>
    <para><inlinegraphic fileref="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2363/2311306708_5a29c44a0b_m.jpg"
      /></para>
    <para>Free Software communities work online in a collaborative fashion. That’s marketing speak
      for: we work together, alone. While each of us sits behind his computer, either alone or with
      others in an office, we form one team. We communicate over mail, IRC and other online
      channels.</para>
    <para>For asking questions, basic decision making or just getting work done, this is excellent.
      For socializing, it is less optimal, but you’ll still find plenty of social interactions
      especially in IRC channels. It gets much harder however, when complicated issues surface. If
      decisions have to be made about processes or fundamental technical directions, the online
      aspect gets in the way. You quickly run into misunderstandings and while our hacker culture
      compels us to fairly direct (‘rude’) communication, still emotions can run wild.</para>
    <para>At the conference, <emphasis role="bold">Cédric Bosdonnat</emphasis> wants to discuss
      using statistics from the LibreOffice git repositories to show information about contributions
      and contributors. He will first present the way statistics are extracted from the repository
      and then pose the question how to turn these rough statistics into valuable, meaningful
      numbers. How do you relate the lines-of-code added to the complexity of a change? How can one
      decide, from the stats, if someone is a long-term contributor? A core developer?</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">This is where face to face meetings help</emphasis>. Getting to know
      each other over dinner or during a party is a powerful enabler for future online
      communication. But it is also the perfect moment to make those <emphasis role="bold">hard
        decisions!</emphasis> And that is where the BoF comes in.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">How?</emphasis></para>
    <para><inlinegraphic fileref="http://farm1.static.flickr.com/49/171249238_1421d15dca_m.jpg"
      /></para>
    <para>Discussions about future directions or day to day business like improving a review process
      or working together more efficiently – all things done better in person. In a BoF, a team
      working together on-line meets and discusses these things, face to face, in an open manner.
      Not completely unstructured, mind you, but still very open. The organizer of the BoF is there
      merely to start up the discussion and possibly facilitate it. Facilitate by making sure some
      decisions are actually taken. And recorded!</para>
    <para>A typical BoF starts with a short ‘hi all, thanks for coming’, and if needed an
      introduction of the participants. Then, it is time to find the subjects of the discussion at
      hand. The organizer can coin a few things he or she things need to be discussed and others can
      chime in. From there on, it’s a matter of actually going over the subjects one by one.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Jean-Daniel Dodin</emphasis> is involved with testing in openSUSE.
      At the conference, he wants to have a BoF centered around improving the process of testing
      multimedia applications. Many of these applications don’t work as expected or not at all. How
      can we ensure applications are tested reliably and don’t end up on a user’s desktop just if
      theycompile but only after they are proven to actually work?</para>
    <para>The <emphasis role="bold">challenge</emphasis> now is to keep the discussion from going in
      all directions – something which is fine at a dinner but not productive at a BoF. Gently
      reminding the team of what the goal of the current topic is is usually sufficient. You all
      share the same goals, after all. The second challenge is to make sure decisions are
      taken and recorded. Creating the typical action list of who does what is the best way to go.
      It might make sense, with a large BoF team, to have one person lead the discussion while
      someone else takes notes.</para>
    <para>Know that the person organizing the BoF does not have to be a ‘team leader’, nor a ‘great
      communicator’! Every attendee is equally responsible for the quality and results of the
      discussion. Organizing the BoF is merely a technical detail – not a huge deal at all, and
      anyone can do it.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Responsibilities and tools</emphasis></para>
    <para>Organizing a BoF is surprisingly simple if the right people turn up. For that, a <emphasis
        role="bold">clear description</emphasis> is usually enough. A title like “Factory review
      process discussion” will most likely attract those involved with review of packages in Factory
      and interested in improving the process. If the review process has had hickups in the last few
      months it is highly unlikely that the discussion won’t be attended or not attract the right
      people. Nor is it likely to not have ‘enough to talk about’. The problem is usually more one
      of getting sidetracked and not actually finishing discussing the topic with a proper todo
      list!</para>
    <para>What do you need to organize a BoF? Almost nothing. Pen and paper (for the todo!) will
      usually suffice. A whiteboard might be nice for more complicated problems like mapping out a
      new API, creating a flow diagram of a process or simply noting down the agreed-upon topics for
      the BoF. Otherwise, just talk! Introduce the topic quickly and ask for opinions will fire it
      off easily.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Scheduling BoF’s</emphasis></para>
    <para><inlinegraphic fileref="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2797/4537737867_3ebfc19183_m.jpg"
      /></para>
    <para>Usually, BoF’s are scheduled ‘on the spot’ using a big whiteboard in the main hall of the
      conference or on an open wiki page. That can lead to two similar BoF’s or two BoF’s targeting
      the same team at the same time, however. It also means you might not have a spot at a decent
      time. Which might result in being forced to plan a BoF in the time slot of a talk about the
      same subject . This is why the openSUSE CfP team asks you to plan BoF’s in advance!</para>
    <para>The biggest perceived problem with planning a BoF is the inherent contradiction in
      ‘planning’ and ‘BoF’. Yes, you might not know now what will be an issue 3 months from now.
      However, you don’t have to nail the agenda down today, that would indeed run counter to the
      whole concept of a BoF. If you think your team will benefit from having a good, open
      discussion about what you do and how you (want to) do it, simply send in a quick proposal to
      the openSUSE Conference Paper Committee. It is no problem if something more urgent pops up and
      you discuss that instead of following the initial description. The main reason for ‘planning’
      (part of) the BoF’s beforehand is to allow the CfP team to try and schedule things in such a
      way there is little overlap with talks and other BoF’s and to allow teams to reserve a
      room.</para>
    <para>So go to the conference page and add a BoF!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GFDL 1.2</ulink></para>
    <!--($ ld: 14.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/07/time-to-vote-on-the-opensuse-strategy/"
        >Time to vote on the openSUSE Strategy!</ulink></title>
    <para>Over the last year an openSUSE strategy discussion has been ongoing. Beginning this year
      things went quiet for a while as everyone was busy with the openSUSE 11.4 release and now the
      conference but we’re at the final stage and want to finish this. Time to vote!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Forward</emphasis></para>
    <para>The openSUSE board has reviewed the text and after fixing one or two typo’s and updating
      it to the latest state of affairs, they have asked Thomas Thym from the strategy team to start
      a vote among <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Members">openSUSE Membership</ulink>.
      So every <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Members">Member</ulink> can go to <ulink
        url="http://bit.ly/kZaAC2">connect</ulink> and vote on the proposal!</para>
    <para>We’re not asking everyone if they think it is a perfect fit for themselves – we’re a
      diverse community and we’ll never fully agree on anything. But this proposal has seen lots of
        <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Strategy">thought</ulink>, <ulink
        url="http://lwn.net/Articles/392467/">discussion</ulink>, <ulink
        url="https://lite.co-ment.com/text/lNPCgzeGHdV/view/">revision</ulink>, <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/10/07/opensuse-strategy-the-third-and-fourth-part-of-the-trilogy/"
        >input</ulink> – it is arguably the best we could come up with to describe who we are and
      where we want to go. So the question is – do we agree this describes us? Is it good enough for
      us to support? Can we move on with this?</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Results</emphasis></para>
    <para>You can find the result of our one-and-a-half year discussion on the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Strategy">openSUSE Strategy wiki page</ulink>. Note
      that the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Strategy_Community_Statement">Community
        Statement</ulink> is an integral part of it.</para>
    <para>This is the start of our Strategy document, describing our <emphasis role="italic"
        >mission</emphasis>:<blockquote>
        <para>The openSUSE project is a worldwide effort that promotes the use of Linux everywhere.
          The openSUSE community develops and maintains a packaging and distribution infrastructure
          which provides the foundation for the world’s most flexible and powerful Linux
          distribution. Our community works together in an open, transparent and friendly manner as
          part of the global Free and Open Source Software community. </para>
      </blockquote>So, if you’re an openSUSE Member, it is time to <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Strategy">read the document one more time</ulink> and
        <ulink url="http://bit.ly/kZaAC2">cast your vote</ulink>!</para>
    <para>Note that the voting page is only accessible to logged in openSUSE Members and the results
      are hidden until June 30th.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GFDL 1.2</ulink></para>
    <!--($ ld: 8.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/08/opensuse-conference-looking-for-sponsors/">openSUSE
        conference looking for sponsors</ulink></title>
    <para>Like the previous years, the openSUSE conference team is looking for sponsors. The <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Conference">conference</ulink> has grown 35% last year
        and we expect it to grow even more this year so financial help is needed!</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/RWX3-300x127.png"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">openSUSE Conference</emphasis></para>
    <para>Now in its third year, the openSUSE Conference has become one of the most dynamic and
      collaborative events in the FOSS world, by bringing together both openSUSE contributors and
      other members of the open source community. Last year we welcomed participants from Fedora,
      Debian, the GNOME project and numerous others, creating a rich environment for innovation.
      Topics for the openSUSE Conference range from technical talks about packaging, Open Build
      Service and development tools to more community-oriented discussions about our future and
      direction. With over 35% more attendees than in 2009, last year’s conference was a resounding
      success and this year promises to be even greater with an expected number of 500
      attendees.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Sponsors needed</emphasis></para>
    <para>To make this event possible, the community needs help. Sponsorship is required for travel
      costs for speakers and attendees as well as facilities costs. As the openSUSE community is
      very international, we want to support people from Brazil, India, Australia and many other
      countries to come to Nuremberg. By securing sponsorships, companies can demonstrate their
      support for the community and garner valuable brand recognition. If you are interested in
      sponsoring this event, please see the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/images/1/1f/OpenSUSEandSUSELabs2011SponsorshipBrochureWebsite.pdf"
        >online sponsorship brochure</ulink> or contact us for more information on the sponsor
      benefits and offerings. If you know someone who might be interested in sponsoring, please help
      us reach out to them!</para>
    <para>Our contact person is: </para>
    <para>Izabel Valverde <email>izabelvalverde@opensuse.org</email></para>
    <para>Sponsorship manager </para>
    <para>openSUSE Conference Organization</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">This year: Read, Write, Execute and SUSE LABS</emphasis></para>
    <para>In 2011, the theme of the combined openSUSE and SUSE Labs Conference is <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/05/16/opensuse-conference-2011-to-be-creative-and-open/"
        >RWX, the UNIX acronym for Read-Write-Execute</ulink>. To bring this theme to life, the
      sessions at oSC 2011 will have a strong focus on getting decisions made and work done in
      small, collaborative teams. Again many visitors from other projects will be invited and by
      co-locating with the SUSE Labs Conference, the larger number of community members at the
      conference will greatly increase its impact.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">SUSE Labs</emphasis></para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/Zentr_impress-300x148.jpg"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>The SUSE Labs Conference is a SUSE internal conference that has been organized by SUSE
      engineers for SUSE engineers for many years. Most SUSE technical employees travel to meet once
      a year and exchange ideas, share their work and learn from each other. The topics for the SUSE
      Labs Conference tend to be very technical, ranging from Kernel, Samba and GCC to high
      performance networking technology.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Place and date</emphasis></para>
    <para>The openSUSE Conference and SUSE Labs Coference 2011 takes place in Nuremberg, Germany at
      Zentrifuge Nurenberg, from September 11 to September 14. Zentrifuge is an independent cultural
      center providing room for art and music performances and exibitions. This location gives the
      openSUSE Conference a culturally rich, creative environment, challenging visitors to bring
      their best!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GFDL 1.2</ulink></para>
    <para><!--($ ld: 9.6.11 sm $)--></para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/09/world-ipv6-day-results/">World IPv6 Day
        Results</ulink></title>
    <para>Yesterday was World IPv6 Day and openSUSE <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/05/31/opensuse-and-world-ipv6-day/">participated</ulink>
      in it. We hope the experiment was as successful for the other participants as it was for
      us!</para>
    <para>Here is a short status update from the openSUSE infrastructure. openSUSE has currently two
      major server locations and we tested IPv6 at both separately. Note that there are more
      openSUSE infrastructure locations, including the server which runs the popular <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/09/planet.opensuse.org">planet.opensuse.org</ulink>
      (which supports IPv6 as well now)!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Nürnberg</emphasis></para>
    <para>In Nürnberg, Germany, the following main services were enabled:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>download.opensuse.org</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>build.opensuse.org</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>lists.opensuse.org</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>{many_web_sites}.opensuse.org</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>Just two services did not make it in time: the torrent tracker and the email servers. Our
      current tracker software does not support IPv6 – and the dedicated new tracker needs more love
      from our packager. The mail servers are provided by our ISP so we left them as they
      were.</para>
    <para>All our other services are <emphasis role="bold">RUNNNING on IPv4+IPv6</emphasis> and
        <emphasis role="bold">WILL STAY on IPv4+IPv6</emphasis> even if the IPv6 day is over now. We
      have seen an increase from ~1% IPv6 bandwidth usage to ~7% bandwidth usage today, which is
      impressive and encouraging!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Provo</emphasis></para>
    <para>In Provo, US, the following main services were enabled:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>{lang}.opensuse.org wikis</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>forums.opensuse.org</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>lizards and news.opensuse.org</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>Currently these services provide IPv6, but we are facing two kinds of problems, proving
      how useful the World IPv6 day was for us:</para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Native IPv6 users reported problems which are MTU related. Manually lowering the MTU
          on the client side fixed their problems, but this is something that we are working on
          closely together with our ISP.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Some sites are not accessible from some clients. But clients from the same subnet did
          not have the problems. More mysterious: the problematic clients can reach other servers
          without problems. This is currently the problem which needs some deep
          investigation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>We are currently discussing whether we can solve these issues quickly or have to disable
      IPv6 again for our servers in Provo.</para>
    <para>The following problems were solved during World IPv6 day:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>One package on our openSUSE distribution needed patches: the apache2-mod_geoip package
          used on download.opensuse.org</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>we found two packages (vsftpd and torrent-seeder) which can’t handle IPv4 and IPv6 at
          the same time</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>In conclusion, the world IPv6 day participation showed openSUSE to be quite ready for IPv6
      – and we will work on fixing the few problems we encountered.</para>
    <para>I’d like to mention two people especially and thank them for their hard work, great help
      and enthusiasm:</para>
    <para><emphasis role="italic">Christian Deckelmann</emphasis> (who provides us with the needed
      infrastructure, resources and knowledge) and <emphasis role="italic">Markus Rýckert</emphasis>
      (who handled all the configuration changes and patches that are needed on our servers).</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GFDL 1.2</ulink></para>
    <!--($ ld: 9.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/09/new-leadership-inside-the-medical-project/">New
        Leadership inside the Medical Project</ulink></title>
    <para>During the first openSUSE Conference in 2009, the idea was born to start a project to
      package and publish software for medical purposes. Since then, many packages were built and
      updated: software from the FreeMedForms project, OpenEMR, GnuMed, software for viewing images
      in DICOMM format and recently, a plasmoid for diabetics.</para>
    <para>The first stable release (v 0.0.6) was released on November 2010, based on openSUSE 11.3
      and as contestant in the “<ulink
        url="http://www.novell.com/promo/suse/the-disters-contest.html">The
      Disters</ulink>“-Contest. This release was produced with <ulink url="http://susestudio.com/"
        >SUSE Studio</ulink>, and published via <ulink url="http://susegallery.com/browse">SUSE
        Gallery</ulink>.</para>
    <para>The goal of this openSUSE derivative was to give medical people all they need in their
      daily work. So the image contained OpenOffice, KMyMoney, mail, calendering and all other basic
      office tools. And of course the content from the <ulink
        url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/medical/">medical repository</ulink>. There
      was some press attention in <ulink url="http://lwn.net/Articles/415542/rss">Linux Weekly
        News</ulink> and<ulink
        url="http://linuxtoday.com/news_story.php3?ltsn=2010-11-17-001-35-OS-SS-RL"
        >Linuxtoday</ulink>!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Provided Software</emphasis></para>
    <para>openSUSE Medical provides tools from the <ulink url="http://www.freemedforms.com/en/start"
          ><emphasis role="bold">FreeMedForms Project</emphasis></ulink>. FreeMedForms is a
        <emphasis role="bold">Electronic Medical Record Application</emphasis>. There doctors can
      manage clients data and diagnostic information. The second Application from this Project is
      FreeDiams, a <emphasis role="bold">electronic prescriber.</emphasis> And FreeICD helps to find
      the right <emphasis role="bold">ICD Code</emphasis>.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://en.opensuse.org/images/thumb/6/64/Freemedforms_screenshot.png/200px-Freemedforms_screenshot.png"
          depth="99" width="200"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>The <emphasis role="bold"><ulink url="http://wiki.gnumed.de/bin/view/Gnumed"
          >GNUmed</ulink></emphasis> project builds free, libre open source <emphasis role="bold"
        >Electronic Medical Record</emphasis> software in multiple languages to assist and improve
      longitudinal care (specifically in ambulatory settings, i.e. multi-professional practices and
      clinics). It is made available at no charge and is capable of running on GNU/Linux, Windows
      and Mac OS X. It is developed by a handful of medical doctors and programmers from all over
      the world. It can be useful to anyone documenting the health of patients including, but not
      limited to,ýdoctors, physical therapists, occupational therapists, acupuncturists, nurses and
      psychologists.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold"><ulink url="http://code.google.com/p/tempo/"
        >TEMPO</ulink></emphasis> is open source software for <emphasis role="bold">3D visualization
        of brain electrical activity</emphasis>. TEMPO accepts EEG file in standard EDF format and
      creates animated sequence of topographic maps. Topographic maps are generated over a 3D head
      model and the user is able to navigate around the head and examine maps from different points
      of view. Most mapping parameters are adjustable through the graphical user interface. Also,
      individual topographic maps could be saved in PNG format for future examination or
      publishing.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://en.opensuse.org/images/thumb/f/fa/Tempo.png/200px-Tempo.png"
          depth="150" width="200"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>The software from the <emphasis role="bold"><ulink url="http://www.oyranos.org/">Oyranos
          Project</ulink></emphasis> is also part of the medical repository and in openSUSE Medical.
      It allows medical professionals to view medical file formats like DICOMM Files.</para>
    <para>The newest addition to the medical repository is <ulink url="http://bit.ly/lQuA0S"
        >plasmoid-glucose</ulink>, a KDE Plasmoid for diabetics.</para>
    <para>The openSUSE medical project has been a success. The SUSE gallery image has been
      downloaded well over 1400 times and was cloned by 162 users so they could provide their own
      variations of openSUSE Medical!</para>
    <para>The team is very much interested in more feedback, however. Especially when it comes to
      real-life usage of openSUSE Medical. Feedback from professionals in the field using the
      software can be very valuable in improving it and would be highly appreciated. So if you study
      medicine, work at a pharmacy or are a doctor and you use or might use openSUSE Medical, please
      let us know! You could tell the whole team by <ulink
        url="mailto:opensuse-medical+subscribe@opensuse.org">subscribing to the openSUSE Medical
        mailing list</ulink> which is very low-trafic (3-4 mails per week) or contact one of the
      team members like <ulink url="mailto:saigkill@opensuse.org">Sascha Manns</ulink> directly. Of
      course you are also very much welcome on the <ulink
        url="irc://irc.opensuse.org/opensuse-medical">openSUSE Medical IRC channel</ulink> and can
      join the <ulink url="http://on.fb.me/clGDk7">facebook page</ulink>!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">New leadership and project plans</emphasis></para>
    <para>Today, the team announces a shift in leadership and a road map for the future.</para>
    <para>Two years after the start of this project, the former team leader Sascha Manns has stepped
      down and Thanasis Rous will take over. Last November, the first official release was published
      with a range of desktop and server packages. openSUSE medical is now part of the <ulink
        url="http://www.linux.com/community/groups/viewgroup/1264-Medical+Task+Force">Linux Medical
        Taskforce</ulink> and has exciting plans for the future. These include:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Importing more applications dealing with diabetes care and diabetics</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Importing applications that would be useful for medical students (some educational
          applications like Kalzium are already added)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Bug testing applications (maybe create a new mailing list for this purpose e.g
          “opensuse-medical-bugs”)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Translating the included applications into more languages</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>The new leader Athanasios-Ilias yesterday has released the new image under <ulink
        url="http://susegallery.com/a/UbPYJM/opensuse-medical-114">SUSE Gallery</ulink>. Also
      available at : OVF image, VMware Image, Live CD/DVD.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">More information and helping out</emphasis></para>
    <para>Anyone interested in the project can read more about it at the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Medical">Medical wiki portal</ulink>.</para>
    <para>There are many ways to help with working in the project – you don’t need to be a developer
      or packager, nor do you need to be a medical specialist, though of course these skill sets are
      very welcome. If you’re not sure how to help, sign up to the mailing list and introduce
      yourself. If you’re a user of this software and would like to see it develop in certain
      directions, this is also a great place to get your ideas heard.</para>
    <para>If you want to get involved, subscribe to the mailing list with “<ulink
        url="mailto:opensuse-medical+subscribe@opensuse.org"
        >opensuse-medical+subscribe@opensuse.org</ulink>“. We very much welcome your
      feedback!</para>
    <para>Have a lot of fun :-)</para>
    <para><emphasis role="italic">Contributed by Sascha Manns, Athanasios-Ilias Rousinopoulos and
        Jos Poortvliet.</emphasis></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GFDL 1.2</ulink></para>
    <!--($ ld: 10.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>  
</sect1>
