<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
  <!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
  %myentities;
]>
<sect1 role="forums">
  <title>openSUSE Forums</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-help-here/pre-release-beta/450297-m-4-a.html"
        >M 4 (Milestone 4)</ulink></title>
    <para>
      On the road to openSUSE 11.4 the news to wait for was the release of Milestone 4. This thread is a good example of how things like that go on the forums: users keep eachother informed on latest developments, exchange their first experiences. 
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
      url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-help-here/applications/450459-download-rsync-all-packages-make-local-repo.html"
      >Download all packages with rsync to make a local repo</ulink></title>
    <para>Here's a user with sort of a download problem. He wants to download entire repos at a friend's place, and use rsync to do so. Like often, the problem is not whether this is possible or not, the problem is which choices to make to get optimal result. Contains some good advice and suggestions.
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
      url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-help-here/network-internet/450601-setting-up-nis.html"
      >Setting up NIS</ulink></title>
    <para>
      More and more people look for solutions to make their networks manageable. Linux provides some very nice solutions. This thread is started by a user that wants to use NIS to centralize his user administration and homedirectories. What starts as a bit of advice, becomes a small wiki on how to implement NIS and NFS on openSUSE with the use of Yast. Interested in having all your linux users and their data and settings in one place? Read ahead.
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>This week's subforum: 
      <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/information-new-users/">
      Information for New Users
      </ulink></title>
    <para>
      This subforum of the <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org">openSUSE Forums</ulink> has three subforums: <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/information-new-users/new-user-how-faq-read-only/">New User Howto and FAQ</ulink>, <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/information-new-users/advanced-how-faq-read-only/">Advanced Howto and FAQ</ulink>and <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/information-new-users/unreviewed-how-faq/">Unreviewed HOWTO and FAQ</ulink>. The first two are maintained by the forums staff, the last one is open for contributions from the forums members. The content is not only valuable for new users of openSUSE, these subforums also provide a knowledge base for more experienced users. Thanks to user contributions a wide area of subjects is covered, varying from hardware driver install to software migration. New users: a bit of reading in these subforums may save you a lot of time in getting aquainted with openSUSE and linux in general.
    
    </para>
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
