<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
  <!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.winehq.org/announce/1.3.12">The Wine development release 1.3.12 is
          now available</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>What's new in this release (see below for details):<itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Support for multiple icon sizes in winemenubuilder.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Improvements to the help browser.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Initial stab at DOSBox integration.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Various MSI fixes.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Some fixes to the Wine debugger.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Various bug fixes.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
      <para>(...) Other Sources: <ulink
          url="http://www.h-online.com/open/news/item/Wine-1-3-12-integrates-DOSBox-1175811.html"
          >h-online</ulink></para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 24.1.11 sat $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.texaslinuxfest.org/callforpapers/">Texas Linux Fest 2011 Call For
          Papers is open!</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>We are proud to officially open the call for papers for Texas Linux Fest 2011, scheduled
        for April 2 at the Hilton Austin hotel in downtown Austin, Texas. </para>
      <para>Texas Linux Fest 2011 is the second annual Linux and open source software event for
        Texas and the surrounding region. We are assembling a one day program for the business and
        home Linux user, and for the experienced developer and newcomer alike. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 22.1.11 sat $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.conceivablytech.com/5206/products/how-fast-is-firefox-4/"
          >h-online/ehe: Dell joins the SUSE Appliance Program</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><quote>Novell has announced that Dell has become the latest participant in the <ulink
            url="http://www.novell.com/partners/isv/appliance/">SUSE Appliance Program</ulink>. This
          program allows the use of <ulink url="http://susestudio.com/">SUSE Studio</ulink> to
          develop software applications and for their subsequent distribution. According to Novell,
          just a few weeks after its introduction in mid-2009, 2,000 ISVs had signed
        up.</quote></para>
      <!--($ ld: 26.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://www.zdnet.co.uk/blogs/jamies-mostly-linux-stuff-10006480/whats-up-with-opensuse-10021549/"
          >ZDNet/J.A. Watson: What's Up with openSuSE?</ulink></title>
      <para>This post is not intended as criticism of the openSuSE project in any way. Most of what
        I am writing about here concerns their <emphasis role="italic">next</emphasis> release,
        which is currently at Milestone 5. I understand quite well what pre-release software is, and
        the uncertainty and instability it can be subject to. What I am trying to do is bring some
        attention to something I have noticed, which concerns me, and perhaps get some comments from
        others who have similar/better/worse experiences. If I am very lucky, I might even hear from
        someone who can point out that I am doing something wrong! </para>
      <para>There has been quite a bit of commentary and speculation about the Novell takeover and
        the possible impact on the SuSE/openSuSE products and development. (Note that I am avoiding
        the patent controversy here, intentionally.) The official statements from Novell and SuSE
        have been basically that there should be little or no impact, product development and
        releases should continue as normal. However, I have been following the openSuSE 11.4
        (factory) pre-release development pretty closely because some of the newest things being
        developed are important to my Lenovo S10-3s netbook (Broadcom brcm, and Synaptics ClickPad).
        What I have seen and experienced since the sale/takeover was announced has been troubling -
        or else I am doing something wrong. </para>
      <para>First, the openSuSE ISO images are supposed to be what they call "hybrid images", which
        can either be burned to a CD/DVD or copied directly to a USB flash drive. Writing to USB can
        be done either directly with <emphasis role="italic">dd</emphasis> (for hard-core old
        geezers like me), or using the openSuSE Imagewriter utility. It has always worked quite well
        for me, until sometime around their 11.4 Milestone 5 release. Suddenly, the USB image
        wouldn't boot. I tried both the 32 and 64 bit images, and I tried using both dd and
        Imagewriter, and it just won't boot. It goes through what should be a process of
        reconfiguring the disk label, and then panics. Ugh. It still works when burned to a CD, so
        the basic Live image is ok. When this first happened, I believe it was shortly before
        Christmas, I assumed that it would be noticed and fixed in short order. It has been this way
        for a month now, and it is still the same as of the most recent daily, Build 1030.</para>
      <!--($ ld: 26.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6tw2JOuct7k">Linux User &amp; Developer/Jos
          Poortvliet:The openSUSE column #96 with Jos Poortvliet</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">openSUSE community manager, Jos Poortvliet, talks about the latest
          in openSUSE projects and developments since the successful openSUSE Conference last
          October… </emphasis></para>
      <para>Since the openSUSE Conference in Nuremberg in October, the openSUSE community has been
        extremely active. New projects announced there have progressed, and others have emerged. One
        example of the latter would be the announcement of Project Tumbleweed by kernel hacker and
        openSUSE contributor Greg Kroah-Hartman. The goal of this project is to create a
        ‘rolling-release’ version of openSUSE. A rolling-release distribution (like Arch Linux or
        Gentoo) always offers the latest stable versions of a package in updates so that when a new
        release surfaces, users actually don’t have to do an upgrade! </para>
      <para>Tumbleweed is something you could probably only pull off in openSUSE. While openSUSE is
        a fixed-schedule release project (with a release every 8th), we provide newer stable
        packages for a variety of things on the openSUSE Build Service (OBS). OBS warrants an
        article on its own – a rather unique project (a tutorial for which featured in last month’s
        magazine). We use it to build our distribution, but also packages for other distributions,
        including Fedora, CentOS, Mandriva, Debian, Ubuntu and – seriously – Windows support is
        under development. Hence the OBS mainframes handle the building of over 100,000 packages
        from 25,000 users working on 15,000 different projects. OBS can provide newer packages for
        older openSUSE versions because it is easy: from the web interface our packagers just select
        the older versions and OBS takes care of it – it’s really that easy. OBS accomplishes this
        by starting a fresh virtual machine (of the chosen distro and version) for each package that
        has to be built. It then installs all build dependencies and builds the package. Any errors
        are relayed back to the packager via the web (or command-line) interface. And OBS can take
        code directly out of CVS/SVN/Git and has built-in live CD generation (so yes, an automatic
        daily live CD of Git GNOME can be accomplished with ease). It’s unique and free software, so
        OBS is used by a variety of other projects, including VLC and MeeGo. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 21.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://dot.kde.org/2011/01/14/opinion-why-kde-people-not-software"
          >KDE.news/Oriol Mirosa: Search this site: Opinion: Why KDE is People, Not Software</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>As the first of several opinion pieces exploring current issues in KDE, we offer you a
        video of Aaron Seigo explaining how KDE&apos;s success as a community producing all kinds of
        software led to outgrowing our old name, the &quot;K Desktop Environment&quot;, what KDE
        means now and why it matters. Aaron Seigo on KDE Branding (Ogg Theora version)</para>
      <para>A little over a year ago, an article was published on the Dot titled &apos;Repositioning
        the KDE Brand&apos;. The article publicized the outcome of a process within KDE to make
        sense of the relationship between the community and its products, and to reach a durable
        solution regarding the terms that should be used to refer to both. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 22.1.11 sat $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.georgetoon.com/blog/working-with-the-gimp/">The Georgetoon.com:
          Working with the GIMP</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>There are lots of graphics software applications out there. Photoshop is the big dog on
        the block and many professional artists, cartoonists, and film makers use it for a variety
        of tasks. There are also graphics applications that rival Photoshop and do just about as
        much as Photoshop but a t a lower cost. It all depends on the job you’re tackling and how
        many digital tools you require. </para>
      <para>I’ve found that <ulink url="http://www.gimp.org/">The Gimp</ulink> does just about all I
        need when producing my comic features. And the costs is much less than Photoshop. Gimp is
        free. And because I use <ulink url="">Linux</ulink>, The Gimp already comes pre-installed.
        When you install Linux, Gimp is right there ready to go to work for you. </para>
      <para>Gimp has all the neat little filters, bells, and whistles that all the other graphics
        software apps have. I use ‘em all, but one filter, specifically, comes in quite handy when
        drawing cartoons. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 18.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/security/news/item/Phrack-hole-closed-in-ProFTPD-1156782.html">h-online: Phrack hole closed in ProFTPD </ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The development team behind <ulink url="http://www.proftpd.org/">ProFTPD</ulink> has
        released version <ulink url="http://www.proftpd.org/docs/RELEASE_NOTES-1.3.3d">1.3.3d</ulink>, which closes a critical security hole in the SQL module of all previous
        versions. The flaw was <ulink url="http://www.phrack.org/issues.html">reported</ulink>
        roughly a month ago in Phrack, the hacker magazine. A buffer overflow in the function
        sql_prepare_where() allows attackers to remotely execute arbitrary code on the server. The
        developers themselves suffered when this vulnerability was exploited by still unknown
        parties, who entered the project server and <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/news/item/Back-door-in-ProFTPD-FTP-server-1146592.html">installed</ulink> a back door in the source code.</para>
      <para>The new version also fixes a number of additional <ulink url="http://www.proftpd.org/docs/NEWS-1.3.3d">bugs</ulink>; as a result, the GPL-licensed
        server is reportedly now more stable. At the same time, the developers have also published
        the first release candidate for version <ulink url="http://www.proftpd.org/docs/RELEASE_NOTES-1.3.4rc1">1.3.4</ulink>. (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>LOL</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://e-tote-kala.blogspot.com/2011/01/first-joke-of-year-if-operating-systems.html"
          >Kostas Koudaras: First Joke of the year: If Operating Systems Ran The Airlines</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The first joke of the year :-) </para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
</sect1>
