<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/02/26/opensuse-11-4-rc2-steps-out/">openSUSE 11.4 RC2 Steps Out</ulink>
    </title>
    <note>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is Licensed under the <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GNU Free
        Documentation License version 1.2.</ulink></emphasis></para>
    </note>
    <para>With red carpets rolling out in Hollywood, you’d expect some applause for the openSUSE 11.4 RC2 release, which has now gone live ahead of 11.4 proper. But with much of 
      the hard work going in behind the scenes, this superb release candidate isn’t getting the fanfare it deserves. The recent Bug Squashing day saw 132 bugs updated so few 
      serious issues remain. Improvements in the ‘backend’ work includes some tweaks to Wifi supplicant and drivers, and a host of small fixes across the distribution which enhance 
      stability and performance. The addition of MediaCurl backend with zsync support to libzypp iut is already being noticed. openSUSE user and forum member Pier Andreit comments 
      that “YaST install/remove software is a thunderbolt!”</para>
    <para>The transition from OpenOffice.org to LibreOffice still has a few minor documentation blips but more importantly, users should be cautious. The raft of new functionality 
      has created a few specific issues, such as loss of data in tables. Though not quite ready for the production environment, user feedback is critical for smoothing performance 
      and reliability. </para>
    <para>KDE SC 4.6 is also running beautifully though 32 BIT nVidia users may have a bug.</para>
    <para>If you’d like to help add the final touches of celebrity glam prior to the ‘big event’ of 11.4 release, <ulink 
      url="http://download.opensuse.org/distribution/11.4-RC2/iso/">download it here</ulink> and check out the <ulink 
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Most_annoying_bugs_11.4_dev#openSUSE_11.4_RC2">most annoying bugs</ulink>.</para>    
    <!-- ($ ld: 27.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/02/build-service-team-releases-new-versions-fixing-security-problems/">Build Service team releases new versions fixing security problems</ulink></title>
    <note>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is Licensed under the <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GNU Free
        Documentation License version 1.2.</ulink></emphasis></para>
    </note>
      <para>The openSUSE Build Service team has released verison 2.0.8 and 2.1.6. of OBS. Both versions are fixing a critical security leak which can be miss-used to modify 
        projects or packages without having write permission there. We highly recommend to update your instance of OBS as soon as possible to these new versions. Version 1.7 is 
        not affected by this issue.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="italic">Thanks to Marcus Hüwe for reporting this issue.</emphasis></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Details on OBS 2.1.6</emphasis></para>
    <para>OBS 2.1.6 is also fixing security issues in LDAP mode and a possible crossite scripting attack vector on the login screen (full XSS protection in all webui interfaces 
      will be part of OBS 2.3). <emphasis role="italic">Thanks to Dean Pierce from Intel for discussing these issues and possible solutions with us.</emphasis></para>
    <para>Version 2.1.6 can be downloaded as usual from gitorious, openSUSE:Tools (or openSUSE:Tool:2.0 for version 2.0.8) project repositories or as <ulink 
      url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Build_Service_Appliance">appliance for testing and production systems</ulink>.</para>
    <para>OBS 2.1.6 contains several further changes, please read the release notes below.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">openSUSE Build Service 2.1.6</emphasis></para>
    <para>Updaters from any OBS 2.1 release can just upgrade the packages and restart all services. Updaters from former releases should read the README.UPDATERS file.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Security fixes</emphasis></para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>api: fix security leak which allowed to modify packages or projects without write access (CVE-2011-0466)</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>api: change password in LDAP mode was possible for foreign user (bnc #648982)</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>webui: Fix possible XSS attack vectors in login page (bnc #669909, CVE-2011-0462)</para></listitem>      
    </itemizedlist>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Feature backports</emphasis></para>
    <para>None</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Changes</emphasis></para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>openSUSE 11.4 and Debian 6.0 got added as default target.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>adding reviewers or changing the review state is only allowed for requests which are in review state now.</para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Bugfixes</emphasis></para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>webui: Fix link to moved OBS web forums</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>webui: Fix adding of repositories from remote projects in advanced repository interface</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>api and webui: Do not use (and fail with) rails 3 environment</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>api: allow admins to raise “sourceaccess” permissions on existing projects or packages</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>api: do not allow to create packages with invalid chars via branch command</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>api: do not fail on “mbranch” when a package gets found directly and indirectly via project link</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>backend: Allow browsing of repositories of remote projects (fixes advanced webui view for adding repos)</para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <!-- ($ ld: 3.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
