<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
  %myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="kernel">
  <title>Kernel Review</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://article.gmane.org/gmane.linux.kernel/1124982">Linus Torvalds: Linux 2.6.39-rc3</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>It&apos;s been another almost spookily calm week. Usually this kind of
calmness happens much later in the -rc series (during -rc7 or -rc8,
say), but I&apos;m not going to complain. I&apos;m just still waiting for the
other shoe to drop.

</para>
    <para>And it is possible that this really ended up being a very calm release
cycle. We certainly didn&apos;t have any big revolutionary changes like the
name lookup stuff we had last cycle. So I&apos;m quietly optimistic that no
shoe-drop will happen.

</para>
    <para>Anyway, not only has it been calm, it&apos;s been pretty normal. Two thirds
drivers is pretty normal, with the rest being fairly spread out all
over:

   </para>
    <para>3.5% Documentation/
   </para>
    <para>2.8% arch/arm/
  </para>
    <para>10.2% arch/
   </para>
    <para>2.0% drivers/media/video/
   </para>
    <para>3.3% drivers/media/
   </para>
    <para>2.6% drivers/net/wireless/
  </para>
    <para>10.3% drivers/net/
   </para>
    <para>5.5% drivers/scsi/
   </para>
    <para>8.4% drivers/staging/memrar/
  </para>
    <para>24.2% drivers/staging/
   </para>
    <para>3.5% drivers/video/
  </para>
    <para>62.0% drivers/
   </para>
    <para>2.0% fs/xfs/linux-2.6/
   </para>
    <para>4.3% fs/xfs/
   </para>
    <para>9.6% fs/
   </para>
    <para>2.2% include/linux/
   </para>
    <para>3.7% include/
   </para>
    <para>4.4% net/
   </para>
    <para>2.5% sound/

</para>
    <para>and the appended shortlog shows more details if you care. Nothing
earth-shattering.

</para>
    <para>Let&apos;s hope the release cycle continues like this. I _like_ it when
people really seem to follow the whole &quot;big changes during the merge
window&quot; rules.

</para>
    <para>Thanks guys,

                   </para>
    <para>Linus</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 16.4.11 sat $) -->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://article.gmane.org/gmane.linux.kernel/1126873">Greg KH: Linux 2.6.38.3</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>I&apos;m announcing the release of the 2.6.38.3 kernel.

</para>
    <para>All users of the 2.6.38 kernel series must upgrade.

The updated 2.6.38.y git tree can be found at:
        </para>
    <para>git://git.kernel.org/pub/scm/linux/kernel/git/stable/linux-2.6.38.y.git
</para>
    <para>and can be browsed at the normal kernel.org git web browser:
        </para>
    <para>http://git.kernel.org/?p=linux/kernel/git/stable/linux-2.6.38.y.git;a=summary

</para>
    <para>thanks,

</para>
    <para>greg k-h</para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
   <ulink
    url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/Kernel-Log-Coming-in-2-6-39-Part-1-Network-drivers-and-infrastructure-1227053.html"
    >h-online/Thorsten Leemhuis: Kernel Log: Coming in 2.6.39 (Part 1) - Network drivers and
    infrastructure</ulink>
  </title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">The addition of ipset support makes it easier to run a firewall, as it means that only one table needs to be modified in order to block a specific IP address. The situation with regard to drivers for WLAN chips continues to improve, with Ralink and Realtek now actively involved in developing the Linux kernel drivers.</emphasis></para>
    <para>Linus Torvalds&apos; release emails for the <ulink url="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.kernel/1123040">second</ulink> and <ulink url="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.kernel/1124982">third</ulink> pre-release versions
      of Linux kernel 2.6.39 both note a comparative lack of changes. The calm prior to the RC2
      release even prompted him to speculate whether the kernel developers were &quot;up to something&quot;.
      More jocularity of this ilk was evident on the release of RC3 on Tuesday, but both emails make
      it clear that he welcomes the tranquillity and is looking forward to a quiet development
      cycle.</para>
    <para>As usual, the bulk of the changes in the next major kernel revision found their way into
      the main development tree during the merge window. Kernel Log is therefore already in a
      position to offer a comprehensive overview of the major changes in kernel 2.6.39, scheduled
      for release in mid to late May. A range of articles will deal with different functional areas
      of the kernel in turn. The &quot;Coming in 2.6.39&quot; series opens here with the major changes in the
      network stack and associated drivers. Over the next few weeks, this will be followed by
      articles covering graphics drivers, storage support, file systems, architecture code,
      infrastructure and drivers for other hardware. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 15.4.11 sm $) -->  </blockquote>
 <blockquote>
  <title><ulink url="http://schaiba.wordpress.com/2011/04/16/kernel-weekly-news-16-04-2011/">Rares
    Aioanei: kernel weekly news – 16.04.2011</ulink></title>
  <para>Rares finished his this weekly review from the Kernel.</para>
  <!--($ ld: 16.4.11 sm $)-->
 </blockquote>
</sect1>
