<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1>
  <title>openSUSE Conference 2011</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://opensuseambassadors.blogspot.com/2011/09/opensuse-conference-first-day.html"
        >Greek openSUSE Ambassadors: openSUSE Conference: First Day</ulink></title>
    <para>In Friday morning, at 4:50 Kostas “Warlordfff” Koudaras , George “Etern4L” Bratsos,
      Eustathios “efagra” Agrapidis and Stella “differentreality” Rouzi met in Thessaloniki’s
      airport. We were about to travel to Nuremberg, Germany to go at the openSUSE Conference at
      Zentrifuge. </para>
    <para>After we met up at the airport we checked in and we entered the airplane. It is the first
      journey of the Greek community to a Conference like that. After two and a half hours we
      arrived at Zurich airport where we stayed for two hours waiting for the next flight to
      Nuremberg. The flight between Zurich and Nuremberg lasted half an hour an finally after 4 hour
      traveling we arrived at Nuremberg. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 12.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://opensuseambassadors.blogspot.com/2011/09/opensuse-conference-day-2-conference.html"
        >Greek openSUSE Ambassadors: openSUSE Conference: Day 2, The Conference
      Begins</ulink></title>
    <para>Awesome! The sun goes up in Nuremberg... The Greek team woke up early in the morning in
      order to get ready for the first day of the conference... We had a good breakfast and we
      started heading for the Zentrifuge in order to meet the other guyz and attend the Conference.
      On our road to the openSUSE Conference we met the Chinese community and we both head to the
      conference together. When we arrived people were awesome. Everyone was there... </para>
    <para>The day's program was printed so we took a copy in order to see and decide which awesome
      presentations we will attend! (...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 15.09.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://opensuseambassadors.blogspot.com/2011/09/opensuse-conference-day-3-conference.html"
        >Greek openSUSE Ambassadors: openSUSE Conference: Day 3, The conference continues, the
        Greeks attack!</ulink></title>
    <para>Greek team woke up in the cloudy morning in Nuremberg. We ate our breakfast at hotel and
      we started heading to the openSUSE Conference.</para>
    <para>We arrived a bit late but luckily they haven't started yet! There were again many
      interesting presentations among about community, distribution and about technology.
      Presentations that stood out where “openSUSE Tumbleweed” Mr. KH, Greg, “Ambassador Program:
      Current status,potential changes and improvements” by Mr. KOUDARAS, Kostas (openSUSE), Mr.
      GUPTA, Manu (openSUSE), “Our experience in organizing a local community: The Greek example” by
      by Mr. KOUDARAS, Kostas (openSUSE) and “How to get more Women into openSUSE” by PINTSCHER,
      Lydia (KDE). Do not forget the LPI exams we had at the conference. (...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 15.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://oyranos-cms.blogspot.com/2011/09/taxi-rwx.html">Kai-Uwe Behrmann: Taxi
        @ rwx³</ulink></title>
    <para>Sebastian Oliva presented today at the <emphasis role="italic">openSUSE
        conference</emphasis> the results of his<emphasis role="italic"> ICC Device Profile
        Repository</emphasis> project to his mentoring organisation as participant of the <emphasis
        role="italic">Google Summer of Code 2011</emphasis> program. As profile creation is
      expensive to most users, he emphasised the importance to easily share ICC profiles among these
      users. During the summer project, which is called now <ulink
        url="http://openicc.git.sourceforge.net/git/gitweb.cgi?p=openicc/taxi;a=summary">taxi,
      </ulink> he developed a <ulink
        url="http://openicc.git.sourceforge.net/git/gitweb.cgi?p=openicc/taxi;a=blob;f=docs/api_doc.txt"
        >generic API</ulink> to store and obtain ICC profiles through JSON requests.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 15.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://oyranos-cms.blogspot.com/2011/09/dispcalgui-07-rwx.html">Kai-Uwe
        Behrmann: dispcalGUI 0.7 @ rwx³</ulink></title>
    <para>My yesterday held workshop for calibrating and profiling monitors using
      dispcalGUI+ArgyllCMS in Nuremberg was a nice experience. Around ten people from the openSUSE
      Conference gathered, all being eager to do something for their health of colour vision. We
      wanted to create ICC device profiles and collect them for later publishing. Following is a
      small report and review from the workshop. </para>
    <para>We had available a i1display, a DTP94 and a i1pro as measurement devices, which no of the
      attendees owned privately. Installation on openSUSE-11.4 went pretty smooth. ArgyllCMS is in
      the multimedia:photo repository and dispcalGUI is in multimedia:color_management. Both are
      easily searchable through the http://software.opensuse.org URL. One hacker had all packages
      installed in advance and could start instantly with the i1display. With the default settings
      in dispcalGUI appeared a small terminal and required to adjust native monitor settings or
      continue with calibration. We pressed number 7 and continued with the calibration part. This
      lasted relatively long. dispcalGUI and in the background ArgyllCMS took quite some work to
      iterate over the calibration for four times with lots of "regression getting worse" style
      messages. This indicated to us, that it reached an end for improvement or the application
      where not satisfied according to each persons like. The profiling and installation finished
      after quite some time and the new calibration and profile could be used in colour managed
      applications. In Gimp the monitor profile was not used by default. The Colour Management tab
      in Gimp's preferences needs to manually enable the system profile, which is a troublesome
      exercise to figure out. Instead colour managed applications should look first at the system
      profile. Overriding the system profile by default is dangerous for a good user
      experience.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 15.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://opensuseambassadors.blogspot.com/2011/09/opensuse-conference-day-4.html">Greek
        openSUSE Ambassadors: openSUSE Conference: Day 4</ulink></title>
    <para>The Greeks woke up early today. The cloudy weather of Nuremberg didn't stopped us from
      taking the road to openSUSE Conference. We also had Lydia Pintschert of KDE keep us company
      for the way to Zentrifuge.</para>
    <para>Today there are many interesting presentations about community tools and about new
      technologies in Linux. We started from Lydia's awesome presentation about “Social skills for
      geeks”. After that we attended the presentation of Mr. Vogelsang, Hendrik about “How to
      contribute to the openSUSE Wiki” which was very interesting and we all were there get informed
      on our next community target ;). Also, we attended at the main hall the presentation of an
      important member of SUSE and openSUSE Mr. Milller Michael who told us about his experience
      with SUSE and openSUSE. After we ate, talked with people and rest ourselves we attended the
      conversation about “Playing with Geeko: Contribution can be fun” by Koudaras, Kostas and
      Gupta, Manu where they presented to the community why and how we can contribute at the
      project.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 15.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
