<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/04/06/plus-ca-change-plus-cest-la-meme-chose/"
        >Plus ça change, plus c’est la même chose…</ulink></title>
    <para>Or in other words, <quote>The more things change, the more they stay the
      same…</quote></para>
    <para>openSUSE does not ship major/minor releases, but our numbering/naming scheme – NN.X – has
      led to a common misperception that a .0 release was major and a .x release was an update. This
      created a number of issues, including lack of media attention for .x releases, and user
      misconceptions about stability of .0 releases.</para>
    <para>We have traditionally released versions as 11.0, 11.1, 11.2 and so on up to .3. (The
      exception was 11.4 because the Project wasn’t sure what to number the next release.)</para>
    <para>The only really clear thing was our release cycle timing, as follows:</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold"><quote>openSUSE releases on a fixed schedule every 8 months no
          matter what. Therefore, all releases occur in November, July and
      March.</quote></emphasis></para>
    <para>There has been a lot of discussion over time within our community about our versioning
      scheme for distribution releases. We want to ensure our growing community, including users and
      media, have a clear and correct understanding of our release cycle – so naming or numbering
      needed to reflect that, and not cause misunderstanding.</para>
    <para>Recently, the Project took these discussions to a poll, to gauge community feeling about
      the different options. Generally, the community expressed that they wanted a scheme that was
      uniquely openSUSE’s and reflected our release methodology. We looked at other distros for
      examples, and while we felt many had come up with excellent versioning schemes for their
      distros, none properly reflected our own cycle.</para>
    <para>From this discussion and results of the poll, we have come up with the following
      scheme:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>The .x shall henceforth reflect the month of release <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>1 = November</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>2 = July</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>3 = March</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>We will no longer ship a .0 version.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>This solution brings a meaningful rationale to the scheme, without completely revising the
      look. And thus, our next release in November will be 12.1. In July 2012, we will ship 12.2 and
      in March 2013, we will ship 12.3. Then in November 2013, we will ship 13.1.</para>
    <para>So as you can see… same great versioning look, now with explanation.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/openSUSEVersion.png"
          width="30%"/>
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GFDL 1.2</ulink></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 7.4.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/04/08/welcome-gnome-3-we-have-a-present-for-you/">Welcome
        GNOME 3! We have a present for you…</ulink></title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Front-e1302271632204-300x268.png"
          width="10%"/>
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Dear GNOME 3,</emphasis></para>
    <para>So, you’re born, and we here at openSUSE Project are very excited to welcome you into the
      world. We’ve been watching with anticipation and excitement as the many thousands of
      developers and contributors mobilized around the world to make your first steps into this
      world a reality.The videos and plethora of information shown on <ulink
        url="http://gnome3.org/">gnome3.org</ulink> make clear that you’re very welcome!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">A little present</emphasis></para>
    <para>You are surely be the most anticipated GNOME ever and we congratulate your <ulink
        url="http://mail.gnome.org/archives/devel-announce-list/2011-April/msg00004.html">proud
        parents with their achievement</ulink>! Of course, we also feel very proud as we are closely
      related and have done our very best to help bring you into this world. While you are still
      young, we are already very impressed with what you can do and we therefor have decided to help
      your friends and supporters tell the world about you! </para>
    <para>Building on our strong technology we have created <emphasis role="bold">10.000 Live
        DVD’s</emphasis> to present you in all your glory. These will be given to the GNOME
      Foundation who will take care of distributing them all around the world and handing them out
      at events!</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://gnome3.org/img/video-workspaces.png"/>
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <para>We hope you will enjoy the present!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Get GNOME 3</emphasis></para>
    <para>For openSUSE users, GNOME 3 will be available next week from the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/GNOME_repositories#GNOME:STABLE:x.yy_.2F_G:S:x.yy_.28where_x.yy_.3D_GNOME_version.29"
        >GNOME Stable repository</ulink>. The GNOME team wants to ensure it is stable before
      unleashing it on you all. Of course, experimental packages are available already, see link
      above.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GFDL 1.2</ulink></para>
    <!--($ ld: 9.4.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/04/08/linux-is-20-years-old/">Linux is 20 years
        old!</ulink></title>
    <para>We have two birthdays this week!</para>
    <para>While on April 6th GNOME 3 was born, another kid became 20 years old! The Linux Foundation
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxfoundation.org/20th/">celebrates the 20th anniversary of
        Linux</ulink> with among other things <ulink
        url="http://video.linux.com/categories/video-contests/20th-anniversary-linux-video-contest"
        >a video contest</ulink>. We <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/25/linux-foundation-20th-anniversary-of-linux-campaign-and-video-contest/"
        >already mentioned it</ulink> but it’s now time to get those video’s to the Linux
      Foundation!</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://www.linuxfoundation.org/20th/images/linux20infographic.png"
          width="50%"/>
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Contest</emphasis></para>
    <para>The video should be 60 second long and celebrate the 20th Anniversary by showing the
      impact of Linux on culture and IT over the last 20 years. The more inspiring you can make it,
      the better!</para>
    <para>Youtube: <ulink url="http://www.youtube.com/v/5ocq6_3-nEw"
        >http://www.youtube.com/v/5ocq6_3-nEw</ulink></para>
    <para>The winner of this year’s 20th Anniversary of Linux Video Contest will win airfare,
      registration and hotel expenses to attend one of the following events of their choice: <ulink
        url="http://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/linuxcon">LinuxCon North America</ulink>,
        <ulink url="http://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/linuxcon-europe">LinuxCon
        Europe</ulink>, SXSW 2012 or the LA Film Festival. The winning video will be unveiled at
        <ulink url="http://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/linuxcon">LinuxCon</ulink> in Vancouver
      BC August 17-19, 2011.</para>
    <para>Ranking is based on community voting with the final decision being made by uber-penguin
      Linus Torvalds himself!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">More</emphasis></para>
    <para>However, the Linux Foundation does more: all events where they have a booth will have recording equipment where you can record a message and share your favorite Linux moment or talk about the future. There will also be a series of articles on trainings for Linux professionals.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Join</emphasis></para>
    <para>We’re surely proud of our Penguin! Join the celebration and visit the <ulink
        url="http://www.linuxfoundation.org/20th/">Linux Foundation 20th birthday
        site</ulink>.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://www.linuxfoundation.org/20th/images/lf_linux20_webbadge.png"
          width="35%"/>
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GFDL 1.2</ulink></para>
    <!--($ ld: 9.4.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
