<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://kohei.us/2011/11/21/redesigned-autofilter-popup/">Jörg Stephan: [Quick
        view:] btrfs</ulink></title>
    <para>The real great feature in openSUSE 12.1 for me (as I am a server administrator) is btrfs
      &amp; snapper. After installing the new server environment i guess its time to talk about this
      feature a bit in detail. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 24.11.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://www.oyranos.org/2011/11/quality-of-default-icc-profiles/">Kai-Uwe Behrmann:
        Quality of Default ICC Profiles</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>On the internet are many places to download ICC profiles, which promise to implement
      standards. But how reliable are these profiles and why should users and distributors care
      about their quality? </para>
    <para>Why quality counts? For many users is real value in reliable colour space definitions.
      Most professionals and advanced amateurs know that wrongly implemented colorimetry can cause
      them unwanted modifications and will sum up over repeated conversions and colour space
      assignments until the error has rendered the colour material useless. But profile conformance
      to the standard, which these profiles claim to represent, is not so obvious. A profile checker
      can only detect conformance to the ICC standard itself, which is about the file format, but
      not about the quality of the encoded data. </para>
    <para>The preferred solution for professionals is to download ICC profiles only from trusted
      vendors. Unfortunately for the open source community, most ICC profiles for common standards
      are restrictively licensed and allow no modifications. However these licenses are a reaction
      to people, who want to push stuff at whim and fake profile names. After all spreading low
      quality fakes will mostly harm users. Such faked profile made it in many open source packages.
      It would help the open source community, if vendors license their ICC profiles for standard
      conditions after the new non restrictive ICC profile license. Then faking profiles, by the
      reasoning of providing them under a free license, would not be needed any more. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 26.11.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://sellingfreesoftwareforaliving.blogspot.com/2011/11/my-opensuse-12-journal-3-lotus-notes.html"
        >Han Wen Kam: My openSUSE 12 Journal - 3: Lotus Notes 8.5.3</ulink>
    </title>
    <para><ulink url="http://www-01.ibm.com/software/lotus/products/notes/">Lotus Notes</ulink> is
      what I use at work and the latest v8.5.3 works well on openSUSE 11.4. Although it installed
      without a hitch on 12.1, things goes awry when I start using it. Here are my observations and
      how I managed to get it working again. :) </para>
    <para>For starters, Lotus Notes 8.5.3 only managed to render about half of its interface. For
      example, I could see my inbox but email preview pane is blank. Integrated <ulink
        url="http://www-01.ibm.com/software/lotus/sametime/">SameTime</ulink> worked but workspaces
      and replication tabs were blank too. I suspect it could be some incompatibility or confusion
      with the GTK libs and I was right... Google is my friend and I discovered a brilliant soul who
      had the same challenge, created a <ulink
        url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-bugs/2011-11/msg03695.html">bug report</ulink>
      against openSUSE and even created a workaround/fix.</para>
<!--($ ld: 26.11.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
</sect1>
