<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://michal.hrusecky.net/2011/10/how-do-i-handle-all-those-mysqls/">Michal
        Hrušecký: How do I handle all those MySQLs</ulink></title>
    <para>In openSUSE we’ve got currently MySQL Community Server, MariaDB and MySQL Cluster. From
      all of these we have even multiple versions. Although these packages are different, they are
      quilte similar. So I’m handling them in a little bit special way. When I was adding MariaDB I
      knew that packaging will be quite similar to the MySQL Community Server. So I took some parts
      of .spec file away into separate files so I can sync them easily and left only package
      dependent parts in .spec files. Later on, I created special git repository and few scripts to
      handle patches and patch sharing among these variants. And lately I automatized tre rest of
      the manual syncing I was diong. So today I want to present how do I do MySQL packaging today.
      And that is also some tutorial on how you can modify these packages easily or even create
      packages for other variants like Percona.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 19.10.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://blog.jospoortvliet.com/2011/10/almost-too-much-going-on.html">Jos Poortvliet: Almost too much going on...</ulink></title>
    <para>Been a busy week, last week. There was <ulink
        url="http://www.kde.org/announcements/plasma-active-one/">Plasma Active One</ulink>, <ulink
        url="http://owncloud.org/announcement/">OwnCloud 2.0</ulink>, <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/10/11/opensuse-announces-first-public-release-of-openqa/"
        >openQA 1.0</ulink> and <ulink url="http://dot.kde.org/2011/10/05/freedom-15-years-party"
        >KDE's 15th birthday</ulink>. Each of them deserves a lot of attention, which they got. I'll
      just add my thoughts! (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 19.10.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
