<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://vizzzion.org/blog/2011/04/im-going-to-the-kde-ux-sprint-then-tokamak-is-coming-to-me/"
        >Sebastian Kügler: I’m going to the KDE UX sprint, then Tokamak is coming to
      me!</ulink></title>
    <para> On Thursday, I’ll be travelling to Berlin for the KDE UX sprint, which is kindly hosted
      by relevantive in their office in the heart of Berlin. I’ll be meeting Nuno, Celeste, Hugo and
      a few others there, and we’ll be making plans. Topics are the human interface guidelines,
      getting more designers involved with KDE, and of course <ulink
        url="http://vizzzion.org/blog/2011/04/plasma-active-a-desirable-user-experience-encompassing-the-device-spectrum/"
        >Plasma Active</ulink>. </para>
    <para> A few days after coming back, hell will break loose in Nijmegen, as the Plasma crew holds
      their Tokamak gathering here. Here means at our new house in Nijmegen in the east of the
      Netherlands (which is in the west of Europe ;)). I’m really looking forward to having my
      fellow Plasma hackers here, especially with all the excitement, new ideas and concepts coming
      along with Plasma Active. I’m sure it will be an epic Tokamak, and a really long one, too.
      Between first arrivals and least departures, there will be a whopping 12 nights. We’ll likely
      be doing an Open Day, so if you’re in the region, drop me an email if you’d like to come by to
      see the magic happen.</para>
    <para> Speaking of Plasma Active itself, it’s off to a good start. We’ve spent crazy amounts of
      hours in very little time before I announced it on my blog, and we kicked off a surge of blog
      posts about this subject — with more to come. I’m really happy with the positive interest it
      generated so far, very promising.</para>
    <para> With the past two weeks spending most of my time on documentation, packaging and
      communication, I got back into hacking mode today, and polished up my small metadata engine I
      had started writing not long ago. It’s working now, you can query all kinds of resources,
      either by filename, URL, Nepomuk Identifier or simple query term, and it gives you back a list
      of Nepomuk resources and their metadata. It’s pretty simple, but very powerful. It already
      provides most of what you need to write a simple filebrowser, or search widget in Plasma
      Quick. I’ll write a more detailed blog post (including screenshots) once I’m more happy with
      it, also visually. The basic metadata engine is already in master, and will be appearing in
      the next update of the Plasma Active packages, probably tomorrow. Now, back to hacking. =) </para>    
    <!--($ ld: 13.4.11 sm $)-->    
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://anksos.blogspot.com/2011/04/keep-your-suse-rolling.html">Anastasios
        Ksouzafeiris: Keep your SUSE rolling!</ulink></title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">One of the new features the recent major release of openSUSE brought
        with it that *really* caught my attention is the ability to turn the distribution into a
        rolling one, effectively bringing it to the camp of the likes of Gentoo and Arch. As a
        former long time user of Gentoo I thought I’d install openSUSE and take it for a drive – but
        most importantly add the Tumbleweed repo to it and see what happens from
      there.</emphasis></para>
    <para><ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tumbleweed">Tumbleweed</ulink> is the name of the
      repository that once added to your openSUSE installation allows the whole system to be
      regularly upgraded to the latest and greatest software, without the need of ever upgrading the
      OS to a newer, major version of the distribution. The good news is that <quote>latest and
        greatest</quote> doesn’t mean <quote>bleeding edge</quote>. That may be the case with the
      openSUSE Factory repo, but not with Tumbleweed. The bad news is that by turning openSUSE into
      a rolling distro you’ll find yourself re-compiling and re-installing any closed-source drivers
      you rely on more often than you’re probably used to – and in most cases that entails some
      extra labor. But that couldn’t possibly stop me from trying Tumbleweed, so I set off to a
      quest for transforming a local openSUSE 11.4 VMware VM (GNOME edition) into an installation of
      a rolling distribution. Well, it very soon turned out that I was in for a pretty short yet
      quite enjoyable quest. Before I go any further, I should point out that I’m no openSUSE
      expert. I have used the distribution in the past but it never really won me. Despite that, I
      always enjoy trying out new operating systems in general and Linux distributions in particular
      – especially when there’s a new version of a popular brand out. I should probably mention here
      that this time around openSUSE left me with an excellent impression and that’s mainly because
      of zypper, the distribution’s command-line tool for package management. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 7.4.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/2011/04/05/smb-traffic-analyzer-sambaxp-conference-2011/"
        >Holger Hetterich: SMB Traffic Analyzer @ SambaXP conference 2011</ulink></title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://holger123.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/smbta1281.png?w=128&amp;h=128"
          depth="128" width="5%"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>The last time <ulink url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/smb-traffic-analyzer/"><emphasis
          role="bold">SMB Traffic Analyzer</emphasis></ulink> was present at the <ulink
        url="http://www.sambaxp.org">Samba eXPerience conference</ulink> was in<emphasis role="bold"
        > 2009</emphasis>. Lots of stuff happened, and we gained a slot<ulink
        url="http://holger123.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/smbta1281.png">
      </ulink> at this wonderful conference to take a short look back at <emphasis role="italic"
          ><emphasis role="bold">what happened since the end of 2009, where we currently are, and
          where we go to</emphasis></emphasis>. This time, we’ll do a presentation featuring two
      speakers of the SMBTA team (<emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="bold"
        >me</emphasis></emphasis> and <emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="bold">Benjamin
          Brunner</emphasis></emphasis>), and will hopefully be able to <emphasis role="italic"
          ><emphasis role="bold">live-demonstrate </emphasis></emphasis>our latest development, an
      easy to use and intuitive <emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="bold">web-interface for
          smbtaquery, and smbtamonitor, our real time client.</emphasis></emphasis> Get the
      conference schedule <ulink url="http://sambaxp.org/index.php?id=21">here</ulink>. We’ll be
      around at the conference and welcome to talk to users and developers! </para>
    <!--($ ld: 7.4.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/04/06/versionitis/">Andreas Jaeger:
        Versionitis</ulink></title>
    <para>The voting on how to do the versioning is over and the <quote>old school</quote> has won
      by 55 per cent (of 98 participants). Thanks to all that participated in the two votes and the
      discussion around the topic.</para>
    <para>As Coolo said in on the <ulink
        url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-project/2011-03/msg00516.html">project list</ulink>,
      we’d like to make a small change to the numbering:</para>
    <para>We will not have a .0 release but only .1, .2, .3 release. Since we have releases in three
      months, the November</para>
    <para> release is always the .1 release, the July release the .2 and the March release the
      .3.</para>
    <para>So, the plan is that the next release will be called openSUSE 12.1 and launched on the
      10th of November, 2011! Two years later – on the 14th of November, 2013 – we will then have
      the openSUSE 13.1 release.</para>
    <para>So, the next four releases are called:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para> November 2011: openSUSE 12.1</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para> July 2012: openSUSE 12.2</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para> March 2013: openSUSE 12.3</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para> November 2013: openSUSE 13.1</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>Detailed results for logged-in openSUSE members are available at the <ulink
        url="https://connect.opensuse.org/pg/polls/read/a_jaeger/12979/opensuse-release-versioning"
        >connect poll page</ulink> and I have reproduced them here as well:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>A: “old school”: Like currently but only counting the right number until 3:</para>
        <para> 55% (54 votes)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>B: “Fedora style”: Just integers:</para>
        <para> 29 % (28 votes)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>C: “Ubuntu style”: YY.MM:</para>
        <para> 16 % (16 votes)</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>This is also consistent with the <ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/03/28/opensuse-release-versioning-poll-on-last-three-options/"
        >results of the first public voting</ulink>.</para>
    <para>Note that openSUSE does not have a major and minor numbering, even if it seems so. There
      is right now no difference in any way between what we would do for openSUSE 11.4 or 12.0 or
      12.1 – and no sense to speak about openSUSE 11 or openSUSE 11 family. We also had in the past
      no process on how to name the next release (when to increase which parts of the
      number).</para>
    <para>I think this new versioning is still consistent with the old one but also an improvement
      since it’s now clear that we change the first digit every two year. The first poll showed that
      half of our users prefer a date based versioning and the other a consecutive numbering. So,
      depending on your point of view, you can see this as a mixture of both or as consecutive
      numbering <inlinemediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif"
          />
        </imageobject>
      </inlinemediaobject></para>
    <para>So, time now to make openSUSE 12.1 a great release!</para>
    <!--($ ld: 7.4.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
