<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
  %myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="kernel">
  <title>Kernel Review</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/Kernel-Log-native-KVM-tool-new-kernels-galore-1229981.html">h-online/Thorsten Leemhuis: Kernel Log: Coming in 2.6.39 (Part 2) – Storage and file systems</ulink>
    </title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Various internal changes to the block layer that were specifically mentioned by Linus Torvalds are designed to enhance performance and scalability. The Ext4 file system is also said to offer improvements in this respect. Still classified as experimental, Btrfs now offers Batched Discard functionality, and LIO (Linux-Iscsi.org) includes a loop-back function.</emphasis></para>
    <para>At the end of last week, Andi Kleen published a <ulink url="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.kernel/1129793">series of patches</ulink> that
      fixes a performance problem between the Virtual File System (VFS) and the security
      infrastructure; this was an unwanted side effect from the <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/Kernel-Log-Coming-in-2-6-38-Part-2-File-systems-1192694.html">optimisation to the VFS</ulink> that was merged in Linux 2.6.38. Torvalds showed <ulink url="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.kernel/1129793/focus%3D52980">great interest</ulink> in them and <ulink url="http://git.kernel.org/linus/8c9e80ed276fc4b9c9fadf29d8bf6b3576112f1a">merged one</ulink> into the main development tree; a second fix that is based on the three patches
      from Kleen <ulink url="http://git.kernel.org/linus/9ade0cf440a1e5800dc68eef2e77b8d9d83a6dff">followed on Monday</ulink> and fixes the problem in the SELinux codebase. It&apos;s still
      undecided if these or similar patches will make it into a stable kernel 2.6.38, as Torvalds
      mentioned at one point that he was considering.</para>
    <para>Torvalds did not yet produce a fifth release candidate for Linux 2.6.39 – but it should
      emerge in the next few days, as the <ulink url="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.kernel/1128248">RC4</ulink> is already more than
      one week old. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 27.4.11 sm $) -->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="https://lkml.org/lkml/2011/4/27/8">Linus Torvalds: Linux 2.6.39-rc5</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>Another week, another keyboard destroyed by spilling coffee on it..
C&apos;est la vie.

</para>
    <para>We have slightly fewer commits than in -rc4, which is good. At the
same time, I have to berate some people for merging some dubious
regression fixes. Sadly, the &quot;people&quot; I have to berate is me, because
-rc5 contains what technically _is_ a regression, but it&apos;s a
performance thing, and it&apos;s a bit scary. It&apos;s the patches from Andi
(with some editing by Eric) to make it possible to do the whole RCU
pathname walk even if you have SElinux enabled.

</para>
    <para>I&apos;ve been alternately kicking myself for merging it, and just being so
pleased with the rcu pathname walk now extending outside of the
no-security confines ... I dunno. The patches are all pretty simple
(there&apos;s also a few dentry cleanup patches that were the result of me
looking at profiles and generated code), and it really is a rather
important performance thing, but at the same time I would shout at
others for trying to merge it to me this late. So I&apos;ll consider myself
properly chastised.

</para>
    <para>Other than that? We should have all the fallout from the block layer
plugging changes fixed now, and Tejun fixed the infinite CD-ROM
disk-change notification thing. So that&apos;s hopefully all good and done.

</para>
    <para>And then there are all the usual driver noise (including some hwmon
documentation), some ecryptfs and gfs2 updates and just various small
random fixups. The diffstat actually looks pretty good, most of it is
just one-liners and stuff like a few new device ID&apos;s etc.

</para>
    <para>Go forth and test,

                     </para>
    <para>Linus
</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 30.4.11 sat $) -->  </blockquote>
</sect1>
