<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/04/06/plus-ca-change-plus-cest-la-meme-chose/"
        >Plus ça change, plus c’est la même chose…</ulink></title>
    <para>Or in other words, <quote>The more things change, the more they stay the
      same…</quote></para>
    <para>openSUSE does not ship major/minor releases, but our numbering/naming scheme – NN.X – has
      led to a common misperception that a .0 release was major and a .xý release was an update.
      This created a number of issues, including lack of media attention for .x releases, and user
      misconceptions about stability of .0 releases.</para>
    <para>We have traditionally released versions as 11.0, 11.1, 11.2 and so on up to .3.ý (The
      exception was 11.4 because the Project wasn’t sure what to number the next release.)</para>
    <para>The only really clear thing was our release cycle timing, as follows:</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold"><quote>openSUSE releases on a fixed schedule every 8 months no
          matter what.ý Therefore, all releases occur in November, July and
        March.</quote></emphasis></para>
    <para>There has been a lot of discussion over time within our community about our versioning
      scheme for distribution releases. We want to ensure our growing community, including users and
      media, have a clear and correct understanding of our release cycle – so naming or numbering
      needed to reflect that, and not cause misunderstanding.</para>
    <para>Recently, the Project took these discussions to a poll, to gauge community feeling about
      the different options.ý Generally, the community expressed that they wanted a scheme that was
      uniquely openSUSE’s and reflected our release methodology.ý We looked at other distros for
      examples, and while we felt many had come up with excellent versioning schemes for their
      distros, none properly reflected our own cycle.</para>
    <para>From this discussion and results of the poll, we have come up with the following
      scheme:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>The .x shall henceforth reflect the month of release <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>1 = November</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>2 = July</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>3 = March</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>We will no longer ship a .0 version.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>This solution brings a meaningful rationale to the scheme, without completely revising the
      look.ý And thus, our next release in November will be 12.1.ý In July 2012, we will ship 12.2
      and in March 2013, we will ship 12.3.ý Then in November 2013, we will ship 13.1.</para>
    <para>So as you can see… same great versioning look, now with explanation.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/openSUSEVersion.png"/>
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GFDL 1.2</ulink></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 7.4.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
