<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/04/23/gnome-3-0-arrives-for-opensuse-11-4/"
        >GNOME 3.0 arrives for openSUSE 11.4</ulink></title>
    <para>The wait is finally over and the much anticipated release of GNOME 3 on openSUSE’s latest
      distro release, 11.4 is ready for download at a desktop near you. Frederic Crozat, a member of
      the openSUSE GNOME Team, has been working tirelessly, burning the midnight oil getting GNOME3
      stable enough for you all to use. See his blog for the full details. Our friends from GNOME
      Foundation also welcomed GNOME 3 for openSUSE with a welcome tweet. (...)</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GFDL 1.2</ulink></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 25.4.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/04/19/infrastructure-updates/">Infrastructure
        Updates</ulink></title>
    <para>We had way too many server downtimes during the last month in our infrastructure. These
      were caused by an unreliable login proxy. We have now developed and setup a new login proxy
      and use it for the following sites:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>build.opensuse.org</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>api.opensuse.org</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>hermes.opensuse.org</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>notify.opensuse.org</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>features.opensuse.org</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>We hope that this new proxy is working reliably now.ý The new proxy is open source and
      source code can be found <ulink
        url="https://www.gitorious.org/opensuse/apache-mod_auth_memcookie">on gitorious.org</ulink>.
      A future version of the openSUSE Build Service (OBS) (not 2.3) will come with this proxy as
      authentication mechanism as well.</para>
    <para>For the openSUSE Build Service, another change is that we switched to apache and the
      passenger module on our productive system, following the new default of OBS 2.3. This should
      also fix some cases of invalid http answers.</para>
    <para>In short, we have changed some key parts of our infrastructure and introduced a new login
      proxy, so there might still be some pitfalls. But we have it under our control now and can
      debug and even fix any issue with it. In case of problems, please speak up on the
      opensuse-buildservice mailing list.</para>
    <para>Your make-OBS-stable-team, Michael Schröder, Stephan Kulow and Adrian Schröter</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GFDL 1.2</ulink></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 23.4.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>  
</sect1>
