<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="forums">
  <title>openSUSE Forums</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/other-forums/community-fun/surveys-polls/459461-please-share-experience-sd-card-drive-use-linux.html">Please share experience with SD card 'drive' use in Linux</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>
      In most linuces the developpers spent lots of time and energy to improve boottime and startup time of applications. Work has been done to the kernel, we have systemd and the desktop environment developpers have done their share too. The last couple of years we've also seen the introduction of Solid State Disks, "disks" based on memory cards, instead of turning platters. One of the main advantages of these SSDs is that their access for reading and writing is much faster than the traditional HDD's, so booting and starting applications should be faster, and indeed is faster. Disadvantage is the difference in price per GB of storage. Recently less expensive SSDs have appeared on the market, our admin oldcpu is asking people to share their experiences.
    </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/other-forums/community-fun/general-chit-chat/459591-microsoft-buys-skype.html">Microsoft buys Skype</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>
      Since Skype, the free (as in free of charge) Voice Over IP Client for internet telephony, had linux versions available, it was clear that the news of Microsoft buying it would draw a lot of attention, This thread shows how users react, additions to the initial news are quoted. Always interesting to see how the community takes news like this.
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/applications/458014-problems-updating-dowloading-certain-softfware-opensuse-11-4-a.html">Problems updating or dowloading certain softfware openSUSE 11.4</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>
      People coming from "the other operating system" are used to download desired software, install it. Linux distributions are different, they all use some form of "package management". One could see this thread as a collection of detailed information on how to use such a package management system. Nice read for those starting with openSUSE to get some basic knowledge on how downloading and installing software works in openSUSE.
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
    <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/applications/459146-do-you-use-anti-virus-opensuse-one.html">Do you use Anti-Virus on openSUSE? Which one?</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>
      A returning issue in the forums. Of course, linux is not invulnerable, but we've never seen serious linux virusses out in the wild. Yet we have anti virus programs available. Our member Daax pops the question, the replies flying in show it's still some kind of a hot issue. If you want to know how openSUSE users respond to the title's questions, read ahead
      </para>
<!-- ($ ld: 12.05.2011 gl $) -->  </blockquote>
</sect1>
