<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
<!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->  <important>
    <para>The Articles inside this Section are in full. If you are already knowing the stuff in
      news.opensuse.org, then you can skip this section through using the TOC.</para>
  </important>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://blog.jospoortvliet.com/2011/07/os-strategy.html">oS strategy</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>The voting for the oS strategy ended on the 30th but the board decided to extend it a bit. Which makes sense, quite a few members were not aware of the voting. Seems like many of them don&apos;t read the planet very often ;-)</para>
    <para>So, we will extend it with two weeks &amp; send out a mail to all members notifying them of the voting...

</para>
    <para>Obviously, you don&apos;t have to wait for that mail - if you read this you can also
<ulink url="http://bit.ly/kZaAC2">go here, log in and vote</ulink>!</para>
    <para>From the email:</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">What do I vote for?</emphasis></para>
    <para><foreignphrase>We realize the vast majority of you simply prefer to focus on writing code and building packages. &apos;strategy&apos; might not be the most interesting thing in the world. However, it does influence at the very least how we communicate about ourselves and how we are seen. Think about texts on our websites, what our ambassadors say about us at conferences. This is an important goal of the strategy - not only decide upon the direction we want (after all, the current document simply describes the status quo) but also define our communication! </foreignphrase></para>
    <para>Obviously there are many more reasons why we did the strategy discussion - after all, many people asked for it, not just marketing. But communication is an important part of it... And:</para>
    <para><foreignphrase>We need to know if the end result of the discussions about strategy reflect how you see openSUSE. Even if you disagree, it is important for us to know that - we accept any outcome!</foreignphrase></para>
    <para><foreignphrase>In short, please vote, even if you want to neither answer yes or no - there is a third option (&quot;Abstain, I can&apos;t decide&quot;).</foreignphrase></para>
    <para>Note that the document isn&apos;t meant to be final and should be revised in the future. That&apos;s also why we&apos;re still very much open to feedback! </para>
<!-- ($ ld: 10.7.11 sat $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/07/08/have-a-computer-then-you-can-participate-in-the-hcl-week/">Have a computer? Then you can participate in the HCL Week!</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>Aloha openSUSE Users!</para>
    <para>Now is an excellent time to help openSUSE! If you have openSUSE running on your system, all you have to do is add your hardware to the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Hardware">openSUSE Hardware compatibility List</ulink>. Add your pheriphials like printers, scanners and webcams. Or add internal stuff like graphics and sound cards, mother boards, wifi cards and every thing else from your netbooks, notebooks, desktops and workstations!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">How does it work?</emphasis></para>
    <para>Go to the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Hardware">hardware portal</ulink> and add your info in the table in the proper category. We suggest to read the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Smolt">Smolt</ulink> wiki page to find out how to get details on you hardware.</para>
    <para>If anyone is interested in helping out to improve this process, for example by creating a way to transform a smolt url to an entry in the wiki, that would be immensely helpful! Suggestions and offers for help are welcome <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/other-forums/community-fun/opensuse-wiki-discussions/">in this forum thread</ulink>.</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 10.7.11 sat $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://conference.opensuse.org/indico//confRegistrationFormDisplay.py?confId=2">openSUSE Conference 2011: Registration</ulink>
    </title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Registration opening day</emphasis>: 08 July 2011</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Registration deadline</emphasis>: 10 September 2011</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Contact info</emphasis>: conference@opensuse.org</para>
    <para>The registration for the openSUSE Conference 2011 is now open. Please make sure to register to help us planning for a great event.</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 10.7.11 sat $)-->  </blockquote>
</sect1>
