<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="status-updates">
  <title>Status Updates</title>
  <!--
  <sect2 role="board">
    <title>Board</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>openSUSE Weekly News searches for contributors</title>
      <figure>
        <title>Merry Christmas (c) Péronne vd Ham / pixelio.de</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata width="45%" fileref="http://images.pixelio.de/data/media/51/sterre_22_wr_Large.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>Hello Mates. The last year was a great year. We had seen many funny things. The Relaunch
        of the openSUSE BuildService now provides many Features for packager. Then the
        kde-obs-generator makes the life easier for cross packaging. The openSUSE Conference was
        another interesting Highlight, and last but not least the sell of Novell. </para>
      <para>The openSUSE Weekly News Team searches the whole week for new things. Now we searching one
        or two new Contributors who are collecting news with us. In the past we have given one part
        of the news to one person, and that person was responsible for this part of the Weekly News.
        As Example you provide the Section &quot;Tips and Tricks&quot; so you can add and remove that Section
        what do you think is the best.</para>
      <para>ATM we can give the following Sections to a good Hand:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Tips and Tricks</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>In the Community</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>On the Web.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>What do you need for working in the english newsletter? If you can read and a little bit
        write XML, and you know how to svn up, then you&apos;re the perfect Candidate. If you can&apos;t this
        things, and would like to learn it, you are a perfect Candidate.</para>
      <para>If you&apos;re interested in helping us, just send a Mail to: <ulink url="mailto:saigkill@opensuse.org">saigkill@opensuse.org</ulink></para>
      <para>Last but not least the openSUSE Weekly News team with the translations into hungarian,
        greek and japanese wishes merry cristmas to all people across the world.</para>
      </blockquote>
      </sect2> -->
  <sect2 role="distribution">
    <title>Distribution</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/2011/01/25/smb-traffic-analyzer-submitted-to-opensuse-tumbleweed-rolling-update-distro/"
          >Holger Hetterich: SMB Traffic Analyzer submitted to openSUSE Tumbleweed rolling update
          distro</ulink></title>
      <para>The complete <ulink url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/smb-traffic-analyzer/">SMB
          Traffic Analyzer</ulink> (SMBTA in the following) software package (up to date Samba
        including SMBTA VFS module, smbtad and smbtatools) are now available in <emphasis
          role="bold">openSUSE’s Tumbleweed distribution</emphasis>, making it ready to run SMBTA
        out of the box. Since my blog is read by quite some people outside of the openSUSE
        community, I am using this space to shortly introduce the Tumbleweed project, as it might
        raise interest to those who were not aware of it. </para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">openSUSE Tumbleweed</emphasis> is a project to provide the
        openSUSE Distribution in form of <emphasis role="bold">rolling updates</emphasis>. At a
        glance, this means in the ideal world: Install Tumbleweed once, and never run out of updates
        or maintenance, as Tumbleweed will update itself to always match the current package
        versions that openSUSE’s maintainers or the according open source projects consider as the
        current stable release of a package. In difference to the <ulink
          url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Factory">openSUSE Factory distribution</ulink>, which
        simply provides the current development state of openSUSE, Tumbleweed will <emphasis
          role="bold">not provide unstable or experimental packages</emphasis>. The projects idea
        was being discussed for longer time in the community, and finally brought to life and
        implementation by Greg Kroah-Hartman, who <ulink
          url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-project/2010-11/msg00206.html">announced a
          Tumbleweed repository in the openSUSE Buildservice</ulink>. In it’s current form,
        Tumbleweed is driven by a number of package maintainers and developers who want to make
        Tumbleweed to happen, and relies on package maintainers to support Tumbleweed by submitting
        their packages to the repository. </para>
      <para>It’s <emphasis role="bold">very easy</emphasis> to jump from openSUSE 11.3 to Tumbleweed
        by using zypper, to give it a try. I run it successfully in a virtual machine since
        Tumbleweed was announced, and consider to make it my distribution for development/work as it
        brings advantages that I don’t want to miss. Being able to release a new <emphasis
          role="bold">SMB Traffic Analyzer version and having it available for users and packaged in
          a distribution</emphasis> in a matter of hours is one of them. Read more about that on
          <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Tumbleweed">the Tumbleweed page in the openSUSE
          wiki</ulink>.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 26.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.suse.de/~coolo/opensuse_11.4/">Schedules for the next week (Thu, 20
          Jan 2011 14:00:00 GMT)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>openSUSE 11.4 Milestone 6 release</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Milestone: First localized build</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Milestone: Localization testing starts</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Milestone: Only major/critical/blocker bugfixes allowed.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </blockquote>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Important Links</title>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://tinyurl.com/392jnb">Detailed Bugzilla Report</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Submitting_bug_reports">Submitting Bug
            Reports</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Bug_reporting_FAQ">Bug Reporting
            FAQ</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
  <!--
  <sect2 role="susestudio">
    <title>SUSE Studio</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.lenzg.net/archives/332-Updated-Drupal-7-appliances-to-version-7.0-final.html">Lenz Grimmer: Updated Drupal 7 appliances to version 7.0 final</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Congratulations to the Drupal community for getting <ulink url="http://drupal.org/drupal-7.0">version 7.0</ulink>
        <ulink url="http://drupal.org/drupal-7-released">released</ulink>! This is a major mile
        stone and an excellent reason to <ulink url="http://www.drupal7releaseparty.org/">celebrate</ulink>! If you want to give Drupal 7 a try without having to install anything,
        I&apos;ve now updated my Drupal 7 appliances on <ulink url="http://susestudio.com/">SuSE Studio</ulink> to the latest release. The appliance is based on <ulink url="http://software.opensuse.org/113/en">openSUSE Linux 11.3</ulink> and is available in
        two variants:<itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>A <ulink url="http://susegallery.com/a/Byn5dM/drupal-7-testdrive">text-mode</ulink> only appliance to which you connect using your local web browser
              via the network.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>A <ulink url="http://susegallery.com/a/Byn5dM/drupal-7-testdrive-gui">GUI version</ulink> that starts up the Firefox browser in a minimalistic GNOME desktop
              to perform the installation locally. Remote network access is available, too.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
      <para>The database backend is phpMyAdmin has been added to support web-based administration of
        the MySQL server. You can access it via http://localhost/phpMyAdmin/. I also added <ulink url="http://drush.ws/">drush</ulink>, the Drupal command line shell and scripting
        interface and some additional packages (yast2-http-server, bind-utils, php5-ctype, patch). I
        also bumped up the appliance&apos;s version number to 7.0.0, to match the version number of
        Drupal included. </para>
      <para>The appliance is available in various formats:<itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>A live raw disk image, ready to be written to an USB stick or flash drive</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>A live ISO image, to be burned on a CD or used in a virtual machine</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>A hard disk image, to be dumped on a hard disk drive</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Various virtual disk formats, e.g. OVF, VMWare/VirtualBox/KVM and Xen</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
      <para>Please see the installation instructions provided on the download pages for details on
        how to use the various image formats. </para>
      <para>So congratulations to the Drupal developer community for reaching this goal and thanks
        to SuSE/Novell/Attachmate for providing the infrastructure for creating such appliances. I
        also would like to especially thank <ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/author/rbos/">Richard Bos</ulink> for the testing and many suggestions for improvement of these
        appliances!</para>
      </blockquote>
      </sect2> -->
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Team Report</title>
    <sect3 role="artteam">
      <title>Art Team</title>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/01/13/wallpaper-community-pack-1/">Nelson
            Marques: Wallpaper Community Pack #1</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>I’ve received some emails and some positive feedback about one wallpaper I used for a
          couple of screenshot’s I’ve used in the past, including also information requests about
          where that very same wallpaper could be found. I’m happy people liked my choice. </para>                
      </blockquote>
      </sect3> -->
  <!--
    <sect3 role="boosters">
      <title>Boosters Team</title>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/29/opensuse-boosters-year-2010/">openSUSE
            Boosters Year 2010</ulink>
        </title>
        <figure id="fig.boosters">
          <title>The elusive Thirsty Thirteen</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata width="50%" align="center"
                fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/Opensuse-boosters-300x200.jpg"
              />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>At the end of the year it is the time for reviews and the openSUSE Booster <xref
            linkend="fig.boosters"/> team did not want to let that opportunity slip. So what was
          important in 2010 from an openSUSE Boosters perspective? What happened, what progress was
          made, how did the boosters help openSUSE? A report from Klaas Freitag.</para>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Who are the Boosters</emphasis></para>
        <para>For those who do not know who <ulink
            url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Boosters_team">the Boosters</ulink> are: We’re not
          Tuxies favorite boy group, but a bunch of people dedicated to help the openSUSE Project in
          any way we can. The team consists of 13 people (BTW: widely known as the thirsty thirteen)
          with skills ranging from low level C hackery over Ruby on Rails mastering to Graphical
          Design or Project Management. Our team picks milestones and works on them in a agile
          fashion while always following our mantra: Grow community by enabling community. You can
          meet us at the usual places like IRC, the mailinglists or events were we show up and
          spread the word about openSUSE. We’re there to make contributors life easier and more fun,
          so if you have anything do not hesitate to talk to us. We’re here for you.</para>
        <para role="bold"><emphasis role="bold">Events in 2010</emphasis></para>
        <para>So let’s quickly fly over the year of 2010 and see what was nice and important.</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>FOSDEM</para>
            <para>Lets start with a very important event, FOSDEM in Brussels in February. We
              traveled there by coach the first time. That was remarkable because there were some
              push back against before (long journey) but we did it because it is cheaper, which
              means more people can go. The result was that we all were quite pleased by the coach
              trip as it was comfortable and fun, and finally not so much longer than the flight.
              And yes, consider how much carbon dioxide was saved? Since that trip I am constantly
              nagging for budget for an openSUSE Coach…</para>
            <para>I held a talk about Hermes at FOSDEM which was, well, not a great success, that
              thing seems hard to market. That happens, others were more succesfull, like
              Christopher with his talk about image building with Kiwi. Michal had a meeting with
              MySQL packagers from all over the world at FOSDEM, which was probably the first real
              initiative to collaborate on cross distro topics. I also bought a GNOME T-Shirt, met
              tons of old friends, had cherry beer and got a cold as usual on FOSDEM.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Dev meeting</para>
            <para>Also in February, we hosted a dev meeting of 25 KDE hackers here in the Nuremberg
              office. They worked on the highly rated plasma workspace for KDE 4.5. I still wonder
              how Will managed to get around with definitely no sleep for days.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Bento and wiki work</para>
            <para>At home, at the beginning of the year we worked on projects called
                <quote>Integrate all Infrastructure under one Umbrella</quote> which resulted in the
              Bento web theme nowadays at all openSUSE sites use. It provides short ways from one
              site to another by thought through and pretty menus. Robert did a real great job with
              that and we got a lot of external recognition for it. At the same time the Wiki
              project started which was a huge project the Wiki community was pulling together with
              Henne and Tom. The decision was to create a new Wiki from scratch, implement reviewing
              features and transfer all relevant content into the new one while making sure to not
              transfer stuff nobody needs and maintains any more. That was a big thing and caused a
              lot of discussion. Today we can look back and say that we now have a well structured
              Wiki with valuable content. Fortune favors the bold :-)</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>OBS</para>
            <para>In parallel to that, Coolo and Tom were contributing to the new BuildService
                <ulink url="http://build.opensuse.org">web interface</ulink>. After long working
              hours we finally came out with a great web interface for OBS which was a big bum for
              the whole project, as it makes working in OBS much more fun. I remember that whole
              thing being started as a sprint called “Factory status”, aiming to provide a good
                <ulink url="https://build.opensuse.org/projectstatus?project=openSUSE%3AFactory"
                >overview page</ulink> for the Factory project in OBS. It grew a bit more ambitions,
              but, well, that’s how it goes if things are in movement ;-)</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>LinuxTag</para>
            <para>In June, there was LinuxTag in Berlin where most of us participated with talks in
              the free program or workshops on our booth. We educated a lot of people how to
              contribute to openSUSE in various ways. From submitting code fixes through the Build
              Service to creating great Geeko graphics with Inkscape to how to twist their own Geeko
              out of pipe cleaners.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>openSUSE 11.3</para>
            <para>In July, openSUSE 11.3 was released. That was lots of work beforehand with quite
              some boosters involvement, as Mr. Distro Coolo is part of the team. However not only
              he is contributing to the distribution, we all have our shares in it. 11.3 was a good
              one, it got good press and showed that we as a community are doing great. All over the
              world release parties were organized, some Boosters took over the one here in
              Nürnberg. <ulink
                url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/07/16/opensuse-11-3-launch-party-in-nurnberg/"
                >Nice party</ulink> with some talks, along with BBQ and beer. The latter ran out at
              7pm, because many community members showed up. Cool, I love that kind of stress to
              organize food and beer quickly to let the party go on :-)</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>GNOME and KDE conferences</para>
            <para>Also in Summer, GUADEC as well as Akademy took place for our desktop Boosters.
              Vincent rocked GUADEC and gave away Geekos and stuff and advertised openSUSE as a good
              platform for the upcoming GNOME3. Will could not go to Akademy this year for a very
              good reason called Anna :-)</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>openSUSE conference</para>
            <para>In autumn, the for me most exciting event of the year took place, the second
                <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Conference">openSUSE Conference</ulink>.
              We were heavily involved in organizing, program committee work, giving talks and
              presentations and all what is involved with that kind of large event. It was a huge
              success, as a very active and passionate community showed up. Discussions went from a
                <quote>This is what we did</quote> in the last year to a <quote>this is what we
                could do</quote> which is so great to see as that is resulting in innovation for the
              whole project. As a result some very concrete sub projects were created such as
                <quote>Project Brezn</quote> and openSUSE Invis which slowly evolves.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>openFATE, Connect and more</para>
            <para>After the conference and the release of 11.3 we started to dig into milestones
              again with <ulink url="http://features.opensuse.org">openFATE</ulink> and <ulink
                url="http://connect.opensuse.org">Connect</ulink>. Since a couple of weeks we have a
              nice looking openFATE that has the features that make it possible for the feature
              screening team to work on one of our most important tasks in our project: Looking into
              the future of the distribution with feature evaluation. We also implemented the future
              of the user/group handling for all the openSUSE services with a social twist: Connect.
              Our own instance of a social network that makes it possible to connect the people that
              make this project what it is and at the same time makes it possible to centralize the
              user data.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Busy 2010</emphasis></para>
        <para>So all in all the boosters had a very busy and prosperous year 2010. All of us carried
          their individual share of work in the various areas of the openSUSE project we participate
          in, be it in the openSUSE KDE and GNOME Teams, the openSUSE Distribution, the openSUSE
          tools or the openSUSE Board. We attended a lot of events and organized a couple of our own
          with great success. And we worked together on the most pressing milestones we saw for
          contributor growth in a fun and clever way. All in all we helped a lot of contributors to
          stand up, take responsibility and do get their hands dirty for the openSUSE Project. That
          makes us proud and we will do this smarter, faster, better and stronger in 2011.
          Promised!</para>
      </blockquote>
      </sect3> -->
  <sect2 role="buildserviceteam">
    <title>Build Service Team</title>
    <para/>
    <!--
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="http://michal.hrusecky.net/2011/01/mysql-5-5-in-opensuse-build-service/">Michal Hrusecky: MySQL 5.5 in openSUSE Build Service</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>MySQL 5.5 is GA for more then a month already. If you are reading some news, you
          probably already heard, that it is great, million times faster, has trillion new features
          that you desperately need and much more. Of course, I’m exaggerating a little bit. But
          anyway, MySQL 5.5 is new version everybody talks about. So now when do you get it? It is
          already lying around for some time in server:database:UNSTABLE repository. It was there
          since beta, but took me some time to get final version ready. Just add it to your
          repositories for example by:</para>
        <screen>zypper ar -f http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/server:/database:/UNSTABLE/openSUSE_11.3 server-database-unstable&gt;</screen>
        <para>and then install it by</para>
        <screen>zypper in mysql-community-server_55</screen>
        <para>As it conflicts with whatever MySQL variant you currently have, it will ask you to
          confirm uninstallation of your currently installed MySQL. Then it will replace it and you
          can start trying it.</para>
        <para>And to answer question when it will be in official openSUSE. For 11.4 is too late. I
          know it was made GA last year already, but as many things depends on MySQL, I don’t want
          to accidentally break something. So you can expect it in next openSUSE (11.5 or 12.0, not
          sure what the name would be). And maybe in Tumbleweed a little bit sooner, after some
          testing, but currently don’t know when. And of course, it is build not only for openSUSE
          11.3, so here comes full list of repositories it is built for:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/server:/database:/UNSTABLE/Fedora_12/">Fedora 12</ulink></para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/server:/database:/UNSTABLE/Fedora_13/">Fedora 13</ulink></para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/server:/database:/UNSTABLE/SLE_11/">SLE_11</ulink></para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/server:/database:/UNSTABLE/SLE_11_SP1/">SLE_11_SP1</ulink></para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink url="">openSUSE 11.1</ulink></para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/server:/database:/UNSTABLE/openSUSE_11.2/">openSUSE 11.2</ulink></para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/server:/database:/UNSTABLE/openSUSE_11.3/">openSUSE 11.3</ulink></para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/server:/database:/UNSTABLE/openSUSE_Factory/">openSUSE Factory</ulink></para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>     
        </blockquote> -->
    <formalpara>
      <title>Build Service Statistics</title>
      <para>Statistics can found at <ulink url="http://build.opensuse.org"
        >Buildservice</ulink></para>
    </formalpara>
  </sect2>
  <!--
    <sect2 role="education">
      <title>Education Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 role="forums">
      <title>Forums Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
      </sect2> -->
  <sect2 role="gnometeam">
    <title>GNOME Team</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/01/22/unity-compiz-and-ati/">Nelson Marques:
          Unity, Compiz and ATI…</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>I’ve finally added the Compiz packages to my development repository and unity itself
        alongside with some tools.</para>
      <para>There are several bug reports on launchpad concerning ATI users, involving RADEON DRM
        driver and FireGL (fglrx) drivers. Unfortunately for me, I’m also a very happy ATI
        customer.</para>
      <para>I’ve struggled yesterday with some ABI problems on compiz, this was mainly because I had
        git snapshots from different days, and updating and rebuilding it, really solved the
        issue.</para>
      <para>Today I’ll be implementing the required patches for compiz by Ubuntu,, and hopefully
        this will enable me to test Unity, this time on a spare laptop with Intel Graphics chipset.
        I was hoping to pop some screenshots today, unfortunately, I’m having a couple of problems
        with Compiz that hopefully a couple of missing patches will solve.</para>
      <para>I’ve left behind the ‘clutk’ package, as it’s currently broken and I need to take closer
        look into ‘glew’ and work it out. Something for monday/tuesday spare time.</para>
      <para>For the time being, the only screenshot I have to show is the one of CCSM
        (compizconfig-settings-manager) with the Unity plugin.</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata width="45%" align="center"
            fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/Screenshot-CompizConfig-Settings-Manager.png"
          />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>(...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 23.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2 role="kdeteam">
    <title>KDE Team</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://vizzzion.org/blog/2011/01/4-6-0-available/">Sebastian Kügler: 4.6.0
          Available</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>I’ve just pushed the relevant buttons to make the release of 4.6.0 a public fact.
        Packages should appear shortly for your favourite operating system, I know that openSUSE
        packages are available from Factory now, so start your zypper already.4.6.0 Released.</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="http://vizzzion.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/4.6-elegantly-yours.png"
            width="25%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>The release is actually a pretty big thing, it adds a lot of new features, some of which
        very visible, others being less noticable. There’s the mobile profile for example, which
        makes it much easier to use KDE frameworks in your mobile application. Then we have the
        re-vamped activity manager, that adds a way to group applications in their context and makes
        it possible to manage these activities like sessions. So head over and read what’s new in
        the <ulink url="http://www.kde.org/announcements/4.6/plasma.php">Plasma Workspaces</ulink>,
        the <ulink url="http://www.kde.org/announcements/4.6/applications.php">applications</ulink>
        and the <ulink url="http://www.kde.org/announcements/4.6/platform.php">KDE development
          platform</ulink>.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 27.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/01/27/6481/">Will Stephenson: openSUSE KDE
          Team activity, Jan 2011</ulink></title>
      <para>What’s been going on in the openSUSE KDE team this week? The news on everybody’s lips is
        that the KDE project released 4.6.0 yesterday. Naturally, we’ve got it available for
        download for all current openSUSE releases as we prepare 4.6 for openSUSE 11.4. 4.6 brings
        better performance and improved power management control to the Plasma workspaces. The KDE
        4.6 application releases include features such as navigation capabilities in the Marble map
        app, more ways to search your files in Dolphin, and photo sharing via social networks. KDE
        4.6.0 is currently available in the KDE:Distro:Factory repositories. A KDE:Release:46
        repository will shortly be made available, providing the point releases in the KDE 4.6
        series.</para>
      <figure id="fig.kde1">
        <title>Plasma Desktop with Dolphin browsing this week’s modified files, and Speaker Setup
          dialog</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/plasma_workspace-150x150.png"
              width="25%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <figure id="fig.kde2">
        <title>Krita, KPlato, KSpread, KWord, about to transform into Calligra Office</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/koffice-150x150.png"
              width="25%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <figure id="fig.kde3">
        <title>Amarok 2.4.0 playing last.fm using Phonon 4.4.4 and GStreamer</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/amarok-150x150.png"
              width="25%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <figure id="fig.kde4">
        <title>Some code I wrote with my feet in a bucket of water in 2004</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/kdevelop-150x150.png"
              width="25%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>But that’s not all that we’ve been up to. Amarok 2.4.0 continues to help you rediscover
        your music, with better automatic playlists and removable device support. We’ve packaged
        KOffice 2.3.1 including the realistic natural medium paint app, Krita. KDevelop 4.2, also
        released today, is already on our mirrors. C++ and PHP coders should check it out for its
        powerful code completion and refactoring support, augmented with better search and replace,
        improved Kate text editor, and QtHelp documentation support. digiKam 1.8.0 leads the way in
        professional Free Software photo management. </para>
      <para>The team continues to work to prepare openSUSE 11.4. The openSUSE updater applet is
        being replaced by the more polished KPackageKit from KDE. Our beta testers have already
        resolved several critical bugs before 4.6.0 was released, and is assessing PulseAudio and
        the range of Phonon sound system options for the best audio experience when 11.4 is
        released. All dependencies on the old HAL system for hardware in KDE have now been replaced
        with udev, and have received a lot of testing. KSynaptiks has been configured by default to
        allow touchpad taps, but disable the touchpad when typing. And the team has been assiduously
        packaging new dependencies in KDE’s 4.6 releases so they are fully featured, including the
        Okteta hex editor plugin for KDevelop, the R backend for the Cantor math app, and the new
        speaker setup config module. </para>
      <para>Artwork and branding for 11.4 is nearly complete, featuring the Celadon Stripes
        wallpaper by KDE’s﻿ Ivan Čukić . The mysterious-looking upstream default wallpaper ‘Horos’
        is also available – just install the package kdebase4-workspace-branding-upstream. KDE’s
        Oxygen look and feel becomes possible in GTK apps by installing the new Oxygen GTK theme.
        And a number of minor tweaks to the default KDE in a new installation of 11.4 add up to
        improved performance, for example by deferring starting services until they are needed. </para>
      <para>If you want to join the fun or just need a helping hand, the expert and fanatical
        openSUSE KDE team can be found in #opensuse-kde on IRC, at
          <email>opensuse-kde@opensuse.org</email> or at <ulink
          url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:KDE">http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:KDE</ulink>. You can
        skip to the end and leave a response. Pinging is currently not allowed. </para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 27.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://vizzzion.org/blog/2011/01/slicing-up-the-web/">Sebastian Kügler:
          Slicing up the Web</ulink></title>
      <para>The Webslice applet has been in Plasma (kdeplasma-addons, to be precise) since 4.4
        already. It allows the user to display a part of a webpage on the desktop. This can be
        useful for monitoring only a specific part of a webpage, or just to display something nice. </para>
      <para>The Webslice applet has been written by Richard Moore and me as a functional prototype,
        but didn’t see much love since it was added to Plasma for 4.4 in 2009. Its basic mechanism
        is that you specify a “slice” within a website, which is a rectangular region. This region
        then gets shown in the applet, and resizes dynamically with it, zooming the “slice” in and
        out. The widget basically worked, but had two significant problems: Resizing was very
        sluggish and bound to a kept aspect ratio, and you needed to know CSS2 selector syntax to
        actually use it. </para>
      <para>Earlier tonight, I’ve committed a set of changes which address these problems, and
        backported them after review on the plasma-devel mailing list to the 4.6 branch, so these
        changes become part of Plasma 4.6.1, which will be the first service and translation update
        to 4.6.0, which we released yesterday.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">performance</emphasis></para>
      <figure id="fig.performance">
        <title>performance</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://vizzzion.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/webslice-3-slices-268x300.png"
            />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>First, the resize issue. The Webslice applet <xref linkend="fig.performance"/> uses a
        webkit view, which displays the page and is positioned (basically scrolled with scrollbars
        switched off) and zoomed to fit into the area the applet covers — fairly simple in fact. The
        performance problem was caused by too much resizing which got passed down the stack (if you
        scroll and zoom a website every couple of milliseconds, it becomes quite heavy on the CPU
        easily. I’ve addressed this by cleaning up the codepathes that lead to resizing, so that it
        only causes the resize (and thus the repositioning and zoom of the webpage) when absolutely
        necessary. Resize events from the applet are now compressed a bit, so that we don’t get more
        than 10 resizes a second. That’s “good enough” for the user to see what effect his
        mouse-dragging has, but doesn’t have the sluggish effect. Then, while resizing, I’m freezing
        webkit’s tiled backing store, for an additional performance boost. The result is very
        noticeable, the lag and CPU-hogging while resizing is gone, and the sizing of the applet is
        much less unwieldy with these changes. In that process, I’ve also switched to a non-fixed
        aspect ratio. Bug #1 thoroughly fixed. </para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">improving interaction</emphasis></para>
      <figure id="fig.improving">
        <title>improving interaction</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://vizzzion.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/webslice-config-preview-300x154.png"
            />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>Next-up, slice selection. As I already mentioned, that was neither easy, nor
        user-friendly. (If you’re running, 4.4+, give it a shot, it really sucks ;-).) First off,
        you need to know CSS2 selectors (they’re quite easy, in most cases you want #myid for an
        element in the page being marked with id=”myid”), but still limit the utility of the widget
        to a rather select group. (Does this make the widget 1337?)I’ve been pondering how to best
        offer this to the user. It should be easy to pick a slice from all the elements that are
        there. The first thing I did was to turn the lineedit where you’d input the CSS selector
        (#myid or whatever) into an editable combobox, already containing elements to choose from.
        That made picking a slice much more “determistic”. Still, the #myid names are not always
        telling you what part of the page their actually displaying, so some more feedback is
        desirable. My approach there is the following: When the user opens the configuration dialog
          <xref linkend="fig.improving"/>, the page is zoomed out and fully shown in the webslice
        applet, it switches to a preview mode. The user can now enter a different URL, and temporary
        load this in the slice applet. The combo box containing the elements is now updated to
        contain the elements of the new page. Website picked, now let’s pick a slice. By selecting a
        slice from the combobox, the preview mode highlights the position of the currently selected
        slice in the widget. You apply and it zooms in there. A nice touch is that you can “scroll”
        through the slice by hovering over the combobox, or flip through them using the arrow keys
        while focusing the combobox. All in all, not quite unintrusive changes, but considering the
        widget wasn’t of much use due to above described problems anyway (there was one bug filed
        against it — likely a bad sign, I’m not that good a hacker). Marco and Aaron were kind
        enough to review the patches and agreed that they won’t hurt much, but do provide a nice set
        of improvements we’d like our users to get fairly quickly, not just next summer with 4.7. </para>
      <para>There are a couple of loose ends left for 4.7, though. As I wanted to keep the
        possibility of a backport open, I’ve not changed any strings in the widget, adding an
        explaining tooltip here or there might be useful, but also some more flexible sizing options
        (what proportions to use for the initial rendering — that matters for fluid layouts, how to
        clip if the size of the widget doesn’t match the aspect ratio of the slice, etc. I’ve chosen
        “sane defaults” for these things now, but it’ll probably be nice having that available as an
        option to the user. </para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Create your own webslice Plasma widgets in 4 minutes</emphasis>
      </para>
      <para>There’s one neat thing left to tell about the webslice: You can easily create your own
        preconfigured slices. In order to do that, copy and rename the .desktop file, change name,
        comment, icon, if you wish, then add a line
        like<screen>X-Plasma-Args=http://mysite.org,#myid </screen></para>
      <para>Copy the file to ~/.kde(4)/share/kde4/services/, run <emphasis role="italic"
          >kbuildsycoca4</emphasis> and add your newly created webslice to your Plasma using the
        widget explorer. </para>
      <para>A possible direction we can take this is to add a webslice category to opendesktop.org,
        and start sharing our webslices with each other…</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 28.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <!--
    <sect2 role="marketingteam">
      <title>Marketing Team</title>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="http://dev-loki.blogspot.com/2011/01/review-of-opensuse-trademark-guidelines.html">Pascal Bleser: Review of openSUSE Trademark Guidelines</ulink>
        </title>
        <para><ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/User:Byunashko">Bryen</ulink> just opened an <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311039">interesting feature request about a review of the current openSUSE trademark guidelines (#311039).</ulink>
        </para>
        <para>The current state of things is that Novell owns the openSUSE and openSUSE related
          trademarks (which include things like the openSUSE name and the openSUSE branding). While
          at some point I would love to see those trademarks go into the ownership of the openSUSE
          foundation (but let&apos;s first actually have that foundation ;)), it is better to keep
          them with Novell until we have a properly working and funded foundation, because owning
          trademarks is also an obligation to enforce them. And that potentially means legal
          enforcement as well. </para>
        <para>As the trademarks are owned and enforced by Novell, permissions to use trademarked
          material must be sent to Novell (<email>permission@novell.com</email>, actually), but in
          practice, Novell&apos;s legal team has been delegating the responsibility of evaluating
          such requests to the openSUSE board. </para>
        <para>Nevertheless, the board has to take decisions within a certain framework. Part of that
          framework, obviously, are a few legal aspects, but more prominently, it is what is
          currently defined in the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Trademark_guidelines">openSUSE Trademark Guidelines</ulink> document. </para>
        <para>Bryen&apos;s feature request (which is essentially filed as such because <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Openfate">openFATE</ulink> gives us a good tool for
          transparency and collecting feedback) is precisely about that point: let&apos;s take a
          step back and rethink our trademark guidelines. </para>
        <para>The task isn&apos;t as simple as it might sound, of course, as we have to find a good
          balance between a few, most probably contradictory things:<itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>make the rules short and simple: the simpler they are, the easier to grasp and
                the less daunting to approach</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>enable derivatives of openSUSE: yes, we&apos;d love to see more and more
                derivative works based on openSUSE (but the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Trademark_guidelines">current guidelines</ulink>, which the board has to abide by, do not really reflect
                that)</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>prevent abuse</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist></para>
        <para>Which is why we&apos;d love to hear from YOU what you believe are genuinely good use
          cases that we want to enable and support and what you believe would be cases of abuse,
          especially if you have been involved or have been pondering about making a derivative of
          openSUSE or, more generally, use the openSUSE trademarks in one way or another. </para>
        <para>To do so, <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311039">just click here</ulink>,
          log in with your openSUSE account, and give us constructive feedback. Thanks !</para>
    </blockquote>
    </sect2> -->
  <!--
    <sect2 role="medical">
      <title>Medical Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 role="monoteam">
      <title>Mono Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
      </sect2> -->
  <sect2 role="openfateteam">
    <title>openFATE Team</title>
    <sect3>
      <title>Top voted Features</title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Features with highest vote, but no one has been assigned to yet.
          We are looking for volunteers to implement. </emphasis></para>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/120340">Run download and install in parallel
            (Score: 334)</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>&quot;Network installation could be improved by running package download and package
          installation in parallel.&quot;</para>
      </blockquote>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/305493">Look at plymouth for splash during boot
            (Score: 166)</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>&quot;I wanted to open a fate feature about this when I first heard of plymouth, but
          reading
          http://fedoramagazine.wordpress.com/2008/10/21/interview-fedora-10s-better-startup/ really
          makes me think we should go this way.</para>
        <para>Ray&apos;s comment starting with &quot;Every flicker and mode change in the boot
          process takes away from the whole experience.&quot; is especially interesting. Is it okay
          to track the &quot;don&apos;t show grub by default&quot; here?&quot;</para>
      </blockquote>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/305305">1-click uninstall (Score: 134)</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>&quot;An easy way to remove Software! </para>
        <para>For example: you installed an application with &quot;1-click install&quot; (which will
          install all the packages that you need), there should be an easy way (also with 1 click)
          to remove what you have installed with that 1-click operation... in another words: an
          &quot;1-click Uninstall&quot; to remove installed software (dependencies and packages
          included).&quot;</para>
      </blockquote>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/308357">Replacement for Sax2 (Score:
            106)</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>&quot;We need a replacement for sax2 in 11.3, as a safety measure for when auto
          configuration fails to detect certain monitors/keyboards/mice. (...)&quot;</para>
      </blockquote>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/305877">Popularity contest (Score: 84)</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>&quot;We need a feedback about packages that are preferred by users and actively used.
          Debian already has a tool named Popularity contest (popcon) (...)&quot;</para>
      </blockquote>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/305582">Off-Line one click install (MSI for
            Linux) (Score: 69)</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>&quot;Idea from community member Raúl García. Same concept as MSI packages for Windows
          but exploiting the One Click Install concept of openSUSE (and therefore inheriting the
          simplicity, code and security. (...)&quot;</para>
      </blockquote>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/305548">YaST-Qt: More informative
            &quot;Installation Summary&quot; (Score: 64)</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>&quot;The YaST Qt package manager should provide as much information in the
          &quot;Installation Summary&quot; view as zypper, esp the overall download size to expect
          and how much disk space will be freed/used after performing the operation.&quot;</para>
      </blockquote>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/307255">Less scary yast conflict dialogs (Score:
            50)</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>&quot;The YaST2 sw_single dialog for conflicts, vendor change, architecture change
          etc. is very scary for many users.</para>
        <para>The dialog asks the user to select one of usually three offered solutions for each
          problem without giving much help. This is a cause for many complaints, and contributes to
          myths of RPM dependency hell still existing today. (...)&quot;</para>
      </blockquote>
      <!-- ($ ld: 22.1.11 sat *updated* $) -->
    </sect3>
    <sect3>
      <title>Recently requested features</title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Features newly requested last week. Please vote and/or comment if
          you get interested.</emphasis></para>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311068">Akmod Equivalent for openSUSE</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>Tumbleweed related as opposed to 11.4 related.</para>
        <para>Fedora has this really nice tool called Akmod or Automatic Kernel Module, which builds
          kmods on boot when you load into a new kernel that doesn&apos;t have kmods or to use the
          openSUSE term kmps. As we now have a rolling release in openSUSE: Tumbleweed this kind of
          functionality is more important than ever. Unless there are plans for rebuilding the kmps
          for Tumbleweed each time there is a new kernel. Which doesn&apos;t seem to be the case
          with the Nvidia kmp only supporting up to 2.6.34 series.</para>
      </blockquote>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311069">Simple default file share config (ala
            Ubuntu/MacOSX)</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>Enable simple Share and Dropbox folders by default on each account.</para>
        <para>Home network filesharing should be easy for the home user. Ubuntu does this very
          elegantly, with simple sharing and permission management. Current tools in most distros
          are very confusing to the point of being nearly unusable, including OpenSUSE. I recommend
          cloning the samba etc. technique as used in Ubuntu/Kubuntu.</para>
      </blockquote>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311076">Change MAC via YaST</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>YaST can&apos;t change MAC-address. Now, for change this address need do ifconfig eth0
          hw ether 00:00:00:11:22:33. Think, it&apos;s not SUSE-way. </para>
        <para>Change MAC-address may be simple. With YaST.</para>
      </blockquote>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311077">Themeing (SuSE-Elegant?)</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>What about changing the Default-Theme to SuSE-Elegant from Cristian Rodriguez? See
          http://kde-look.org/content/show.php/SuSE+Elegant?content=117251 + the there mentioned
          links for the look.</para>
        <para>At least providing a package for simple change of the various
          grub/boot/kdm/kde-screens would be neat.</para>
      </blockquote>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311089">Disable system bell by default if sound
            card is installed</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>One of the first things I do after installing openSUSE is disabling the system bell by
          adding this to ~/.inputrc:</para>
        <para><emphasis role="italic">set bell-style none</emphasis></para>
        <para>Its volume is needlessly high. The bell scares the hell outta me whenever it creeps up
          because I backspaced too much on the command line.</para>
        <para>My suggestion: disable the system bell by default, unless no sound card is
          installed.</para>
      </blockquote>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311114">xfce 4.8 in 11.4</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>To get the new xfce 4.8 into openSUSE for 11.4.</para>
      </blockquote>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311124">Consolidate faillog, pam_tally,
            pam_tally2, pam_faillock</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>There are four different ways to track the number of failed logins and react to this:
          faillog, pam_tally, pam_tally2, pam_faillock. They are all incompatible together and
          pretty hard next to impossible to configure.</para>
        <para>Goal: Write one new module &quot;pam_faillog&quot;, which replaces all of them. Should
          be able to read all current databases, supports all features together but uses advanced
          PAM functionality to make configuration very easy.</para>
        <para>The module depends on correct behavior of calling application, which means we need
          some checks if application behaves correct and maybe fix them.</para>
      </blockquote>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311132">Compile Mesa and x-server with
            --enable-glx-tls</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>Most famous Linux distributions are compile Mesa and x-server with
          --enable-glx-tls.</para>
      </blockquote>
      <!-- ($ ld: 22.1.11 sat *replaced with newer ones* $) -->
    </sect3>
    <sect3>
      <title>Feature Statistics</title>
      <para>Statistics for openSUSE 11.4 <ulink
          url="https://features.opensuse.org/statistic/product/22236">in openFATE</ulink></para>
    </sect3>
  </sect2>
  <!--
    <sect2 role="oooteam">
      <title>OpenOffice Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
      </sect2> -->
  <sect2 role="testing">
    <title>Testing Team</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-testing/2011-01/msg00000.html">Larry Finger:
          Weekly News for January 1</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The next Testing Core Team IRC meeting has not been scheduled, but I expect it to Jan.
        31, 2011 if M6 is released next week. </para>
      <para>A number of problems still need to be fixed before M6 can be released. Stephan Kulow
        lists them as:</para>
      <para>blocking issues (for M6):<itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>/etc/mtab still is not right (broken by yast during installation
              bnc#665437)</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Artwork is a bad mixture and this is the last milestone (bnc#665439)</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>kernel on i586 still acting up (bnc#660464)</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
      <para>minor issues (for M6):<itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>the progress bar of the live cd is not moving between 16-92% (bnc#665413)</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>the live cd does not boot into the kernel (kexec broken?)</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>the kde live cd runs slowly</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 22.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2 role="translationteam">
    <title>Translation Team</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Daily updated translation statistics are available on the <ulink
            url="http://i18n.opensuse.org/">openSUSE Localization Portal</ulink>.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://i18n.opensuse.org/stats/trunk/toplist.php">Trunk Top-List</ulink> –
            <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/OpenSUSE_Localization_Guide">Localization
            Guide</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
  <!--
    <sect3 role="wiki">
      <title>Wiki Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3> -->
  <!--
    <sect3 role="yast">
      <title>YaST Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
      </sect3> -->
</sect1>
