<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 id="gsoc" role="gsoc">
  <title>Google Summer of Code</title>
  <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
      <imagedata fileref="http://michal.hrusecky.net/wp-content/uploads/GSoC2011_300x200.png"
        width="20%" align="center"/>
    </imageobject>
  </mediaobject>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://redache.wordpress.com/2011/06/25/entomologist-ui-changes-weekly-report-5/">David
        Williams: Entomologist UI changes Weekly Report #4</ulink></title>
    <para>This week has been a bad one for getting work done as I managed to lose a lot of my work
      mid week. I’ve spent the rest of the week trying to get back to where I was and finishing up
      the New Comments Dialog. I also repeated the mantra “commit often” to remind myself to do it
      so much more often than I do to ensure I can’t lose work when QT Creator decides to delete
      things.</para>
    <para>The New Comments Dialog is at its first iteration and I am going to spend the next 2 – 3
      days fixing any bugs and resolving some issues with the tabbed interface. Then on Monday I
      will start the TODO lists in earnest and get back to being on track with my timeline. </para>
    <para>Luckily time is something I do have and I think I gave myself plenty of breathing space in
      the timeline I submitted with my GSoC application. I’d rather take my time and get things done
      properly with breathing room than cram in as much functionality as possible into the 12 weeks
      and then end it with a massive chunk of badly written and probably broken code. This breathing
      room helped me this week.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 26.6.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/06/19/gsoc-osc-code-cleanup-summary-of-week-4/"
        >Marcus Hüwe: [gsoc] osc code cleanup – summary of week 4</ulink></title>
    <para>here’s a small summary of the 4th (coding) week. I spent most of the time with writing the
      RemoteFile classes and the BuildResult class (+ testcases of course:) ).</para>
    <para>TODO for this week:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>improve RemoteFile classes</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>add APIInfo class:</para>
        <para> - resolve url-like parameters (api://foo/bar repo/arch)</para>
        <para> - raise an exception if required parameters are missing</para>
        <para> - initialize optional parameters with the config default</para>
        <para> - encapsulate “context-sensitivity” logic (sometimes parameters should be read from
          the working copy (like apiurl, project or package))</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <!-- ($ ld: 20.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
