<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
  <!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
  %myentities;
]>
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://nowwhatthe.blogspot.com/2010/11/catching-up.html">Jos Poortvliet:
        catching up</ulink></title>
    <para>Hi! It feels like ages since I blogged, so here goes. A lot has happened since my last
      blog - Latinoware is over (and was frickin' awesome), I had a week off which I enjoyed in
      Brazil and now I'm at the Nuremberg offices due to Michl who just left. We had some catching
      up to do before he went - same with AJ who has decided to enjoy some parental leave. And
      Jaqueline who will have to fill the shoes of these two fine gentlemen. Meanwhile I am trying
      to catch up to mail and news - there is a lot of both. Mail catching up has been limited quite
      a bit by the KDE Factory OBS repository for 11.3 upgrading to KDE's 4.6 release of platform
      (Akonadi!), apps (KMail2) and desktop workspace. The two I mentioned (Akonadi &amp; kmail2)
      have been a royal pain in the ass, to be honest. The migration of my old accounts took a night
      (>100.000 mails) but didn't actually import those mails. Hence they had to be downloaded from
      gmail. With the VERY frequent disconnections and regular hanging of the Akonadi resource this
      has taken a while to say the least - lots of babysitting (restarting Akonadi etc) required. I
      hope the KDE Pim* dudes and dudettes can get this stable (and faster!) before the release...
      Oh, and Virtuoso-t keeps hogging 100% CPU untill I decide to just kill it - after which I
      don't notice any bad or strange behavior. Maybe I should auto-kill it on login ;-) but in the
      end, it's all working reasonably well now, albeit a bit slower than KMail1.x. Yay yay.
      (...)</para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://www.rosenauer.org/blog/2010/11/30/community-powered-long-term-support-for-opensuse/"
        >Wolfgang Rosenauer: community powered long term support for openSUSE?</ulink></title>
    <para>Just recently I found again that openSUSE is not really positioned for some usecases. In
      my personal case that is especially the usage as a web/mail/dns/etc server on hosted
      environments. IMHO it just doesn’t make sense to roll out a distribution which is supported
      for only 18 months to a hosted system with limited access to it. I still have been doing that
      with previous openSUSE releases but it’s so annoying that I really regret it. Also the
      possibility to zypper dup doesn’t really fix that issue for different reasons. Anyway this
      post is not about whining about that fact or to explain why I don’t like to update these type
      of systems remotely every &lt;= 18 months. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">A possible solution?</emphasis> Sometime last year there was a
      discussion about options for something like an “openSLE” or “openSUSE LTS” distribution. There
      is an external page where some outcome was documented here. The dicussions stopped mainly
      because of health issues of the main initiator. There was done some planning and voting on the
      different options but no real results ever happened (as far as I know). So I’m trying to
      resurrect that topic a bit once again: The amount of work related to such a project is the
      critical part and therefore my proposal is to try to start off with a “lightweight” approach.
      (...) </para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://metaverse.wordpress.com/2010/11/30/the-future-of-opensuse-looks-pretty-bright-to-me/"
          >Mike McCallister: The Future of openSUSE: Looks pretty bright to me</ulink></title>
      <para>I’ll be the first to tell you I am close to clueless about business trends. Anyone who’s
        ever read <ulink
          url="http://metaverse.wordpress.com/2006/11/02/suse-windows-dual-booting-to-get-easier/"
          >my reaction to the Novell-Microsoft agreement</ulink> can figure that out pretty quickly.
        That said, it’s been a week since Attachmate “agreed to acquire” (amazing phrase, that)
        Novell, the parent company of the SUSE Linux products, and unquestionably a major sponsor of
        the <ulink url="http://www.opensuse.org">openSUSE community</ulink>. </para>
      <para>Since then, there’s been a fair amount of activity among the openSUSE faithful: <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>The community board <ulink
              url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/11/22/novell-agrees-to-be-acquired-by-attachmate-corporation/"
              >released this statement</ulink> declaring (among other things) that “it’s business as
            usual and we are continuing to work on, rather than predicting, the future of this
            project and have a lot of fun!“</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para> Last Saturday was <ulink
              url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/11/22/opensuse-bug-day-on-saturday-november-27th/"
              >Zombie Bug Squashing Day</ulink>, where 10-15 volunteers combed through bugs for
            v10.2, 10.3 and 11.0 still marked Open in the Bugzilla database, and<ulink
              url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-project/2010-11/msg00205.html"> disposed of
              something close to half of them</ulink>, as reported to the <ulink
              url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OpenSUSE_Project">opensuse-project</ulink> mailing
            list. This project may continue soon.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Both the<ulink
              url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/11/30/feature-handling-for-opensuse-reworked/">
              openFATE feature request</ulink> process and the <ulink
              url="http://news.opensuse.org/">openSUSE News</ulink> page are becoming a bit more
            professional, with the help of still more volunteers.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>And maybe I’m a little too excited about this, but <ulink
              url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greg_Kroah-Hartman">Greg Kroah-Hartman</ulink>
            announced on Tuesday the beginning of a new “Tumbleweeds” project. Greg describes it
            like this: </para>
          <para>a repo that is a rolling updated version of openSUSE containing the latest “stable”
            versions of packages for people to use. </para>
          <para>I’d describe it like this: An “in-between” version of openSUSE that offers packages
            that are a little bit more current than the most recent release, but not as buggy as the
            cutting-edge Factory repository. For those of us who like stability, but don’t want to
            miss out on the latest. </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>So what does this have to do with the Attachmate-Novell hookup? It tells me
      that regardless of what happens at the corporate level, there is energy in our community.
      There’s reason to believe that energy can sustain this distribution for a long time. Got any
      thoughts about the future of openSUSE, and other community distributions with a major
      corporate sponsor? Add a comment here. (EDITMARK)</para>
    </blockquote>
</sect1>
