<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://www.vuntz.net/journal/post/2011/04/18/Taking-my-release-manager-hat-off">Vincent
        Untz: Taking my release manager hat off</ulink></title>
    <para>Back in June 2005, I noticed that we were lacking some <quote>tarballs due</quote> mails
      for the GNOME 2.11 release cycle and I sent a <ulink
        url="http://mail.gnome.org/archives/release-team/2005-June/msg00003.html">small mail</ulink>
      to get this fixed. This is how I got trapped: after this mail got read by <ulink
        url="http://blogs.gnome.org/markmc/">Mark McLoughlin</ulink>, he suggested I could replace
      him on the GNOME release team. A few years later, in September 2007, Elijah chose to <ulink
        url="http://mail.gnome.org/archives/desktop-devel-list/2007-September/msg00612.html">pass
        his GNOME release manager hat</ulink> to me. And now, in April 2011, it's time for me to
      pass the baton: <ulink url="http://elleuca.blogspot.com/">Luca Ferretti</ulink> is replacing
      me on the release team (he joined as a trainee in the past few months), and my good friend
        <ulink url="http://www.0d.be/">Frederic Peters</ulink> becomes the new GNOME release
      manager.</para>    
    <!--($ ld: 23.4.11 sm $)-->    
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://masterpatricko.blogspot.com/2011/04/development-and-build-environments.html"
        >Tejas Guruswamy: Development and build environments: the search -- part 1</ulink></title>
    <para>One of the problems I often face is keeping my productive system I use for work, separate
      from my development environment with broken versions of programs and loads of extra packages
      installed. </para>
    <para>For a while my solution was to create virtual machines in <ulink
        url="http://www.virtualbox.org/">VirtualBox</ulink> - which works great but has a very high
      overhead for the task. Especially when I am away from my desktop and only have my slightly
      underpowered laptop (no VT-x extensions, only 2GB RAM), running an entire virtualized system
      just to try out some packaging changes was painful.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">CC-BY-SA</ulink></para>
    <!--($ ld: 23.4.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://masterpatricko.blogspot.com/2011/04/development-and-build-environments_20.html"
        >Tejas Guruswamy: Development and build environments: schroot on openSUSE -- part
      2</ulink></title>
    <para>So in <ulink
        url="http://masterpatricko.blogspot.com/2011/04/development-and-build-environments.html"
        >part 1</ulink> I detailed my search for something that would allow my development and
      productive environments to coexist on the same machine, and how I discovered schroot.</para>
    <para><ulink url="http://packages.debian.org/search?keywords=schroot">Schroot</ulink> is a
      "chroot manager" - it allows configuring chroots so that users on the system can run shells
      and processes in them, and it takes care of all the setup/tear down I described at the end of
      my previous post. It is a part of the Debian buildtools, for building Debian packages in a
      safe and repeatable environment, just like openSUSE uses build.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 23.4.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
