<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/05/31/opensuse-and-world-ipv6-day/">openSUSE
        and World IPv6 Day</ulink></title>
    <para>In a little over a week it will be <ulink url="http://isoc.org/wp/worldipv6day/">World
        IPv6 day</ulink>. This day is meant to call attention to the fact that IPv4 addresses have
      run out and the web has to move on to IPv6. openSUSE will be part of this initiative, joining
      the ranks of Google, Yahoo and Facebook in making sure its infrastructure is IPv6 capable on
      June 8th.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">IPv4 and IPv6</emphasis></para>
    <para>An IP address is the ‘address’ of a device connected to the web. Be it a web server,
      smartphone, laptop or printer – if they are on a network, they need an address. Using these
      addresses computers can make sure packets arrive at the right place. The human-readable
      addresses like <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/05/31/opensuse-and-world-ipv6-day/openbuildservice.org"
        >http://openbuildservice.org</ulink> are translated at your provider to an IP address
      through a name server. Currently, the web runs on ‘IPv4′. IPv4 provides 4 blocks of 3 numbers
      or 32 bits, adding up to a little over 4 billion addresses. With many households having many
      Internet-capable devices these days this is not enough. The successor of IPv4, IPv6, offers
      128 bits (in decimal a 3 with 38 zeroes) and is thus a lot more ready for the future.</para>
    <para>Since the beginning of this year, the <ulink url="http://www.iana.org/numbers/">Internet
        Assigned Numbers Authority</ulink> which hands out IP addresses to providers to assign to
      devices, is out of IPv4 addresses. The Asian/Pacific “RIR” (Regional Internet registries) ran
      out on April 15. Most local providers and the other regional registries still have a small
      pool of unassigned IP numbers. Unfortunately, with the quickly growing number of devices and
      the world population increasing its access to the Internet, especially providers in the
      quickly growing developing countries, the days of the iconic IPv4 numbering system is
      numbered.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Separation of worlds</emphasis></para>
    <para>However, IPv4 and IPv6 offer separate worlds. An IPv4 server can not talk to an IPv6
      client and the other way around. Many users still have IPv4 only routers and modems at home
      and can’t even join the IPv6 world if they wanted to. This is especially true for older
      routers and modems – like those in countries which adopted the web early, like in Europe and
      the US. As most users there already have Internet, the need for new addresses is less dire.
      This has limited the uptake of IPv6 by the web, especially since offering both IPv4 and IPv6
      can result in problems for IPv4 only users. So major providers and users like Facebook and
      Google, Amazon and the many other important sites on the web don’t offer IPv6 connectivity
      yet. Meanwhile, in China, India and other quickly developing countries, things are decidedly
      different. IPv6 will be crucial if China is to connect it’s vast population to the web. If
      everyone in South America wants a smartphone, a netbook and a desktop – IPv4 won’t cut it. So
      there, IPv6 services are quickly coming up.</para>
    <para>We have to take steps to ensure we don’t create a gap between the quickly developing
      countries and the West. This means making sure our infrastructure is ready for IPv6! This is
      what World IPv6 Day is all about. On that day, major websites and providers around the world
      will test out their IPv6 infrastructure and make sure they are available for everyone.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">We’ll be ready</emphasis></para>
    <para>The <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Services_team">openSUSE sysadmin</ulink>
      team is working hard to bring IPv6 services up. They started a few weeks ago and plan to be
      ready on June 8th, the World IPv6 day. On that day, all external servers will be reachable via
      both IPv4 and IPv6. This includes our <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Main_Page"
        >wiki</ulink>, <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org">forums</ulink>, <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org">news</ulink>, <ulink url="http://doc.opensuse.org"
        >documentation</ulink> and of course <ulink url="http://openbuildservice.org"
      >OBS</ulink>.</para>
    <para>If you want to help out, there are a few things you can do. First of all, you can check
      the <ulink url="http://isoc.org/wp/worldipv6day/participants-dashboard/">participants
        dashboard</ulink> to see how we are doing. Furthermore, you can <ulink
        url="http://test-ipv6.com/">check if you and your provider are IPv6 ready</ulink> and if you
      are, visit our servers and see for yourself!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GFDL 1.2</ulink></para>
    <!--($ ld: 1.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/01/first-step-towards-12-1-with-milestone-1/">First
        step towards 12.1 with Milestone 1</ulink></title>
    <para>Milestone 1, the first step towards the upcoming openSUSE 12.1 release, is now available.
      It is the first milestone, hence far from stable, but the images are now finally building, so
      we have a good starting point for further development.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Many updates, systemd still optional</emphasis></para>
    <para>With over 800 updates, including minor and major updates, the current milestone is ready
      for some serious testing. This iteration already sees some major upgrades taking place, with
      the kernel moving on to 2.6.39 and GNOME to 3.0. In addition we have popular GNOME
      applications like Evolution, Eye of GNOME and others all synchronized, and KDE’s Plasma
      Desktop coming along nicely with a minor version upgrade to 4.6.3. You will also find upgrades
      to GCC, glibc, Perl, Python, and the RPM package manager. Much work has also been put into the
      much-lauded systemd which has now been upgraded to version 26.</para>
    <para>You can read some info on the progress in this recent <ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/05/27/factory-progress/">blog on progress in
        Factory</ulink> by Andreas Jaeger.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Helping out easier than ever!</emphasis></para>
    <para>As expected from a development release, there is still a lot of work to do, so your input
      at this early stage will be a huge help in making the final release into the beautifully
      polished work that we aim for. openSUSE 12.1 Milestone 1 has a <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Most_annoying_bugs_12.1_dev">list of most annoying bugs
        here</ulink>, please add issues you find and help fix them. As Will Stephenson <ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/05/16/have-you-burped-yet-today/">recently
        blogged</ulink>, fixing an issue is a matter of <emphasis role="bold">BURP</emphasis>ing on
        <ulink url="http://build.opensuse.org">build.opensuse.org</ulink>! Find a how-to <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Build_Service_Collaboration#Example_with_web_interface"
        >here</ulink>.</para>
    <para>So run, don’t crawl, to your nearest downloader and see for yourself what the next version
      of openSUSE has in store for you at our <ulink url="http://software.opensuse.org/developer/en"
        >download center</ulink>.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GFDL 1.2</ulink></para>
    <!--($ ld: 2.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/02/opensuse-conference-cfp-going-strong/"
        >openSUSE Conference CFP going strong!</ulink></title>
    <para>The openSUSE Conference 2011 has been announced and already we’re getting some strong
      proposals for topics to cover during our conference.  It’s not too late for you to send in
      your proposal or even suggest ideas that others can take on!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Goal of the Conference</emphasis></para>
    <para>The RWX3 theme says it all..  Its about collaboration.  Its about you.  And its about what
      we, as a Project, can do for ourselves and for the world.That means we are *NOT* going to be
      sitting around for four days listening to folks drone all day long while we stare at slide
      presentations.  It means we all get to roll up our sleeves and jump right into it.  Sure there
      will be some ‘slide presentation’ sessions (and you can bet we’re going to have some great
      ones) but the focus will be on hands on and plenty of <ulink
        url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Birds_of_a_Feather_(computing)">BoF (Birds of a
        Feather)</ulink> sessions where we can all make a direct contribution to the things that
      impact the Project and FOSS.And speaking of FOSS, as always, not everything we do is only to
      benefit openSUSE Project. The Project itself has a strong goal of creating and supporting
      initiatives that have a much wider scope.  So, if you’ve got a great software or community
      project you’ve been working on and need the backing of a larger community of contributors,
      this is the conference you want to bring your initiative to!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">How to submit a CFP</emphasis></para>
    <para>If you have something to share, want to teach a workshop or need to solicit input from
      others on a subject, you can send a talk proposal to the openSUSE Conference paper committee.
      Following the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Conference_Planning_2011_guidelines_for_speakers"
        >guidelines &amp; tips for speakers</ulink> you can submit a paper on the <ulink
        url="http://conference.opensuse.org/indico/">openSUSE Conference website</ulink>. </para>
    <para>Stay tuned for our upcoming articles detailing some of the sessions the Conference Program
      Team is reviewing.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GFDL 1.2</ulink></para>
    <!--($ ld: 3.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/06/get-your-fresh-kernels-from-opensuse-and-test-linux-3-0/"
        >Get your fresh kernels from openSUSE and test Linux 3.0!</ulink></title>
    <para>The openSUSE kernel developers have recently announced that the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/Kernel">kernel</ulink> git trees have moved to <ulink
        url="http://kernel.opensuse.org/git">kernel.opensuse.org/git</ulink>, providing better
      reliability than gitorious. Gitorious had trouble with cloning the nearly 1GB repository
      sometimes, but the developers will keep syncing to gitorious so nothing should break.
      Moreover, <ulink url="http://kernel.opensuse.org/">kernel.opensuse.org</ulink> offers an easy
      interface to install openSUSE kernels on a variety of openSUSE releases.</para>
    <para>More things are planned for kernel.opensuse.org including the introduction <ulink
        url="http://lxr.linux.no/">LXR</ulink>. <ulink url="http://hjemli.net/git/cgit/about/"
        >cgit</ulink> was already added during the writing of this article!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">What is there – daily fresh kernels!</emphasis></para>
    <para><ulink url="http://kernel.opensuse.org">kernel.opensuse.org</ulink> offers an interface
      for users to find a specific version of a kernel for openSUSE. As <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/Kernel">the wiki</ulink> states, there is a number of different
      kernels build for openSUSE. This includes the default kernel (usable for desktops and
      real-hardware servers), the desktop kernel, optimized for desktop usage and a number of more
      specialized kernels including Xen and EC2 ready kernels, debug, trace and of course a vanilla
      (standard kernel.org) kernel. On kernel.opensuse.org you can find (links to) repositories for
      all current openSUSE and SLE releases with up to date versions of all the mentioned kernels
      and more. Most of these are build daily to keep ‘em fresh!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Follow upstream</emphasis></para>
    <para>If you want to follow upstream kernel development closely, <ulink
        url="http://kernel.opensuse.org/branches/vanilla">vanilla</ulink> is probably your thing.
      This will turn into the upcoming <emphasis role="bold">Linux 3.0 kernel</emphasis>! If you
      feel adventurous and want to test patches that are not yet ready to go in the mainline kernel,
      check the <ulink url="http://kernel.opensuse.org/branches/linux-next">linux-next
        branch</ulink>. These are patches which will go into ‘Linux 3.1′, the upcoming+1 version of
      the Linux kernel.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Or track openSUSE</emphasis></para>
    <para>Or, you might want to test what is coming in the next openSUSE release via the <ulink
        url="http://kernel.opensuse.org/branches/master">‘master branch’</ulink>. This will give you
      a kernel that is ahead even of the Factory kernel! Each of those kernels is build for a large
      number of build targets including openSUSE 11.2, 11.3, 11.4 and a number of SLE versions.
      Clicking on Packages (under the Tools menu top-right) and then the kernel branch you like (the
      kernel from openSUSE 11.4, SLES10_SP3, linus’ git tree ‘vanilla’, etc) will show you the
      repository and how to add it. These kernels are build daily, so tracking what the kernel
      developers are up to is easy as pie!</para>
    <para>Michal Marek, working on kernel.opensuse.org told us that:</para>
    <blockquote>
      <para>master, openSUSE-11.3, openSUSE-11.4, vanilla, stable and linux-next should work on any
        of 11.3, 11.4 and Factory. I fixed the spec files now so that the packages also install on
        11.2, but that release is out of support, anyway.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">How to use it</emphasis></para>
    <para>To add a specific kernel to openSUSE, click on the branch you are looking for and then on
        <emphasis role="italic">packages</emphasis> under the Tools menu. You will then see the
      zypper command which will help you add this kernel to your openSUSE installation.</para>
    <para>By default, the kernel will replace your old kernel. If you want to be keep the old one as
      a fallback, go to /etc/zypp/zypp.conf and uncomment the line starting with "multiversion =".
      For the vanilla and linux-next branches, this is not needed, the default configuration puts
      Linus’ kernel-vanilla next to your default kernel-desktop in parallel. Having the kernel
      available as option the boot menu and not replacing your current kernel protects you from
      issues with the latest piece of technology you are testing out!</para>
    <figure id="fig.git">
      <title>openSUSE kernel commit activity overview</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/kernel-activity-300x120.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>If you want to get the source code of the kernel branch, or browse its git tree, click on
        <emphasis role="italic">GIT Clone</emphasis> or <emphasis role="italic">GIT
        Browse</emphasis> under the Tools menu to get the commands for cloning the repository to
      your drive or see the code. You can also follow development and see what patches are added by
      who in the <emphasis role="italic"><xref linkend="fig.git"></xref>GIT Browse</emphasis> page. For example, <ulink
        url="http://kernel.opensuse.org/cgit/kernel/log/?h=master">this link</ulink> brings you to a
      page showing the latest activity of the openSUSE kernel developers in Factory.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">More coming</emphasis></para>
    <para>For developers, the site provides a <ulink url="http://kernel.opensuse.org/cgit">git
        viewer based on cgit</ulink>. An LXR source code browser is planned in the future. <ulink
        url="http://lxr.linux.no/">LXR</ulink> is a tool that displays source files with links to
      function, macro and type definitions and usage.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GFDL 1.2</ulink></para>
    <!--($ ld: 7.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/07/time-to-vote-on-the-opensuse-strategy/"
        >Time to vote on the openSUSE Strategy!</ulink></title>
    <para>Over the last year an openSUSE strategy discussion has been ongoing. Beginning this year
      things went quiet for a while as everyone was busy with the openSUSE 11.4 release and now the
      conference but we’re at the final stage and want to finish this. Time to vote!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Forward</emphasis></para>
    <para>The openSUSE board has reviewed the text and after fixing one or two typo’s and updating
      it to the latest state of affairs, they have asked Thomas Thym from the strategy team to start
      a vote among <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Members">openSUSE Membership</ulink>.
      So every <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Members">Member</ulink> can go to <ulink
        url="http://bit.ly/kZaAC2">connect</ulink> and vote on the proposal!</para>
    <para>We’re not asking everyone if they think it is a perfect fit for themselves – we’re a
      diverse community and we’ll never fully agree on anything. But this proposal has seen lots of
        <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Strategy">thought</ulink>, <ulink
        url="http://lwn.net/Articles/392467/">discussion</ulink>, <ulink
        url="https://lite.co-ment.com/text/lNPCgzeGHdV/view/">revision</ulink>, <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/10/07/opensuse-strategy-the-third-and-fourth-part-of-the-trilogy/"
        >input</ulink> – it is arguably the best we could come up with to describe who we are and
      where we want to go. So the question is – do we agree this describes us? Is it good enough for
      us to support? Can we move on with this?</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Results</emphasis></para>
    <para>You can find the result of our one-and-a-half year discussion on the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Strategy">openSUSE Strategy wiki page</ulink>. Note
      that the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Strategy_Community_Statement">Community
        Statement</ulink> is an integral part of it.</para>
    <para>This is the start of our Strategy document, describing our <emphasis role="italic"
        >mission</emphasis>:<blockquote>
        <para>The openSUSE project is a worldwide effort that promotes the use of Linux everywhere.
          The openSUSE community develops and maintains a packaging and distribution infrastructure
          which provides the foundation for the world’s most flexible and powerful Linux
          distribution. Our community works together in an open, transparent and friendly manner as
          part of the global Free and Open Source Software community. </para>
      </blockquote>So, if you’re an openSUSE Member, it is time to <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Strategy">read the document one more time</ulink> and
        <ulink url="http://bit.ly/kZaAC2">cast your vote</ulink>!</para>
    <para>Note that the voting page is only accessible to logged in openSUSE Members and the results
      are hidden until June 30th.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GFDL 1.2</ulink></para>
    <!--($ ld: 8.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/08/opensuse-conference-looking-for-sponsors/">openSUSE
        conference looking for sponsors</ulink></title>
    <para>Like the previous years, the openSUSE conference team is looking for sponsors. The <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Conference">conference</ulink> has grown 35% last year
        and we expect it to grow even more this year so financial help is needed!</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/RWX3-300x127.png"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">openSUSE Conference</emphasis></para>
    <para>Now in its third year, the openSUSE Conference has become one of the most dynamic and
      collaborative events in the FOSS world, by bringing together both openSUSE contributors and
      other members of the open source community. Last year we welcomed participants from Fedora,
      Debian, the GNOME project and numerous others, creating a rich environment for innovation.
      Topics for the openSUSE Conference range from technical talks about packaging, Open Build
      Service and development tools to more community-oriented discussions about our future and
      direction. With over 35% more attendees than in 2009, last year’s conference was a resounding
      success and this year promises to be even greater with an expected number of 500
      attendees.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Sponsors needed</emphasis></para>
    <para>To make this event possible, the community needs help. Sponsorship is required for travel
      costs for speakers and attendees as well as facilities costs. As the openSUSE community is
      very international, we want to support people from Brazil, India, Australia and many other
      countries to come to Nuremberg. By securing sponsorships, companies can demonstrate their
      support for the community and garner valuable brand recognition. If you are interested in
      sponsoring this event, please see the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/images/1/1f/OpenSUSEandSUSELabs2011SponsorshipBrochureWebsite.pdf"
        >online sponsorship brochure</ulink> or contact us for more information on the sponsor
      benefits and offerings. If you know someone who might be interested in sponsoring, please help
      us reach out to them!</para>
    <para>Our contact person is: </para>
    <para>Izabel Valverde <email>izabelvalverde@opensuse.org</email></para>
    <para>Sponsorship manager </para>
    <para>openSUSE Conference Organization</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">This year: Read, Write, Execute and SUSE LABS</emphasis></para>
    <para>In 2011, the theme of the combined openSUSE and SUSE Labs Conference is <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/05/16/opensuse-conference-2011-to-be-creative-and-open/"
        >RWX, the UNIX acronym for Read-Write-Execute</ulink>. To bring this theme to life, the
      sessions at oSC 2011 will have a strong focus on getting decisions made and work done in
      small, collaborative teams. Again many visitors from other projects will be invited and by
      co-locating with the SUSE Labs Conference, the larger number of community members at the
      conference will greatly increase its impact.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">SUSE Labs</emphasis></para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/Zentr_impress-300x148.jpg"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>The SUSE Labs Conference is a SUSE internal conference that has been organized by SUSE
      engineers for SUSE engineers for many years. Most SUSE technical employees travel to meet once
      a year and exchange ideas, share their work and learn from each other. The topics for the SUSE
      Labs Conference tend to be very technical, ranging from Kernel, Samba and GCC to high
      performance networking technology.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Place and date</emphasis></para>
    <para>The openSUSE Conference and SUSE Labs Coference 2011 takes place in Nuremberg, Germany at
      Zentrifuge Nurenberg, from September 11 to September 14. Zentrifuge is an independent cultural
      center providing room for art and music performances and exibitions. This location gives the
      openSUSE Conference a culturally rich, creative environment, challenging visitors to bring
      their best!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GFDL 1.2</ulink></para>
    <para><!--($ ld: 9.6.11 sm $)--></para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/09/world-ipv6-day-results/">World IPv6 Day
        Results</ulink></title>
    <para>Yesterday was World IPv6 Day and openSUSE <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/05/31/opensuse-and-world-ipv6-day/">participated</ulink>
      in it. We hope the experiment was as successful for the other participants as it was for
      us!</para>
    <para>Here is a short status update from the openSUSE infrastructure. openSUSE has currently two
      major server locations and we tested IPv6 at both separately. Note that there are more
      openSUSE infrastructure locations, including the server which runs the popular <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/09/planet.opensuse.org">planet.opensuse.org</ulink>
      (which supports IPv6 as well now)!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Nürnberg</emphasis></para>
    <para>In Nürnberg, Germany, the following main services were enabled:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>download.opensuse.org</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>build.opensuse.org</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>lists.opensuse.org</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>{many_web_sites}.opensuse.org</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>Just two services did not make it in time: the torrent tracker and the email servers. Our
      current tracker software does not support IPv6 – and the dedicated new tracker needs more love
      from our packager. The mail servers are provided by our ISP so we left them as they
      were.</para>
    <para>All our other services are <emphasis role="bold">RUNNNING on IPv4+IPv6</emphasis> and
        <emphasis role="bold">WILL STAY on IPv4+IPv6</emphasis> even if the IPv6 day is over now. We
      have seen an increase from ~1% IPv6 bandwidth usage to ~7% bandwidth usage today, which is
      impressive and encouraging!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Provo</emphasis></para>
    <para>In Provo, US, the following main services were enabled:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>{lang}.opensuse.org wikis</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>forums.opensuse.org</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>lizards and news.opensuse.org</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>Currently these services provide IPv6, but we are facing two kinds of problems, proving
      how useful the World IPv6 day was for us:</para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Native IPv6 users reported problems which are MTU related. Manually lowering the MTU
          on the client side fixed their problems, but this is something that we are working on
          closely together with our ISP.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Some sites are not accessible from some clients. But clients from the same subnet did
          not have the problems. More mysterious: the problematic clients can reach other servers
          without problems. This is currently the problem which needs some deep
          investigation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>We are currently discussing whether we can solve these issues quickly or have to disable
      IPv6 again for our servers in Provo.</para>
    <para>The following problems were solved during World IPv6 day:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>One package on our openSUSE distribution needed patches: the apache2-mod_geoip package
          used on download.opensuse.org</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>we found two packages (vsftpd and torrent-seeder) which can’t handle IPv4 and IPv6 at
          the same time</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>In conclusion, the world IPv6 day participation showed openSUSE to be quite ready for IPv6
      – and we will work on fixing the few problems we encountered.</para>
    <para>I’d like to mention two people especially and thank them for their hard work, great help
      and enthusiasm:</para>
    <para><emphasis role="italic">Christian Deckelmann</emphasis> (who provides us with the needed
      infrastructure, resources and knowledge) and <emphasis role="italic">Markus Rýckert</emphasis>
      (who handled all the configuration changes and patches that are needed on our servers).</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GFDL 1.2</ulink></para>
    <!--($ ld: 9.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>  
</sect1>
