<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 id="own" role="own">
  <title>Weekly News Special Corner</title>
  <abstract>
    <para>We are pleased to announce our 200th Issue of the openSUSE Weekly News. What happened all the time? Which people comes new to the team? Which people aren&apos;t present in the team?</para>
    <para>
      All these questions we want to answer in this special corner.
    </para>
  </abstract>
  <sect2 id="wnhistory" role="wnhistory">
    <title>History of the Weekly News</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>Brief history of openSUSE Weekly News</title>
      <para>It has been almost 4 years since openSUSE Weekly News Issue 1 was published. Here&apos;s a brief history of Weekly News.</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem><para>22 November 2007: The first editor in chief Francis Giannaros aka Apokryphos started to edit the <ulink url="http://old-en.opensuse.org/OpenSUSE_Weekly_News/1">first issue of Weekly News</ulink> and it was officially published on November 26th. Then, it was translated to German by Matthias Fehring aka Buschmann23.</para></listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Issue 4: Stephan Binner aka Beineri joined the Weekly News team.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Issue 15: Jan-Simon Möller aka Dl9pf joined the team.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Issue 24: A special section for &quot;LinuxTag&quot; was featuered.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Issue 40: Translated to Russian by Dinar Valeev aka k0da for the first time.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Issue 41: Translated to Japanese by Satoru Matsumoto aka HeliosReds for the first time. Afterwards, Weekly News were going to be translated to many languages (at the maximum, 14 languages were available).</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Issue 44: Sascha Manns aka saigkill (the current editor in chief) has joined the team.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Issue 49: The new section &quot;openSUSE Forums&quot; is created.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Issue 52: A special section &quot;Best of Newsletter 2008&quot; was featured.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem><para>13 February 2009: A <ulink url="http://old-en.opensuse.org/OpenSUSE_Weekly_News/FOSDEM2009">special Issue &quot;FOSDEM2009&quot;</ulink> was published.</para></listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Issue 69: Sascha Manns started Livestream/Podcast in the German Language based on Weekly News on RadioTux.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem><para>15 May 2009: A <ulink url="http://old-en.opensuse.org/OpenSUSE_Weekly_News/CommunityWeek2009">special Issue &quot;CommunityWeek2009&quot;</ulink> was published.</para></listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>11 June 2009: &quot;How are the openSUSE news?&quot; survey on openSUSE Forums.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Issue 86: Thomas Hofstätter aka Okuro joined the team and has been contributing entries for Events section.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>17 September 2009: Sascha Manns gave a talk session about Weekly News at openSUSE Conference 2009.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem><para>Issue 100: <ulink url="http://old-en.opensuse.org/OpenSUSE_Weekly_News/Dashboard/mail_greetings">Congratulations from Francis Giannaros and Bryen Yunashko</ulink> for the 100th anniversary issue.</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>Issue 118: From this issue on, HTML versions have been published <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/04/10/opensuse-weekly-news-issue-118-is-out-2/">on news.opensuse.org</ulink>.</para></listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Issue 150: Translated to Greek by Greek team. Gertjan Lettink aka Knurpht joined the team and took over contributing articles for Forums from Carl Fletcher aka Caf4926.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Issue 152: From this issue on, Weekly News have been completely edited in XML/DocBook format.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Issue 155: From this issue on, Weekly News have been also available in PDF format.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Issue 165: As compilation, Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported (CC BY-SA 3.0) License is adopted.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>Here in this article, we have just introduced some key editors/contributors for Weekly News. But there were many other contributors/translators who helped publishing Weekly News much. We want to take this opportunity to thank them for what they have done for Weekly News.</para>
<!--($ ld: 05.10.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2 id="wncongrats" role="wncongrats">
    <title>Congratulation Mails from others</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>Andreas Jaeger (Program Manager openSUSE)</title>
      <para>
        <programlisting>200 issues of the openSUSE weekly news - that means nearly 4 years of 
monitoring what&apos;s happening around openSUSE, writing nicely about it on tight 
schedule, translating it so that people have access in their native tongue to 
some information,... I&apos;m impressed and gratefull for your service to the 
openSUSE project.

Thanks,
Andreas</programlisting>
      </para>
<!-- ($ ld: 04.11.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>Jos Poortvliet (Community Manager openSUSE)</title>
      <screen>Congrats on the 200th release of OWN! Well before I joined openSUSE I 
already knew about OWN it is frequently posted or referenced around the 
web. And in the last year I often had OWN come to my rescue - if I'm too 
busy to keep up with what's going on, OWN helps to catch up quickly!

I know I am not alone in this, the tireless work of you, heliosred and 
everyone else who helps (especially the translators) is very valuable 
for openSUSE.

Thanks! </screen>
      <!--($ ld: 05.11.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>Stefan Werden (open-slx)</title>
      <screen>Congratulations, the 200th weekly news is out!  
I can remember the first start of the weekly news and now we have  number 200! A lot of
users are reading weekly news to stay tuned with  Linux. Weeky news is a fantastic resource to
get a clear overview and  what is happening in open source space. The good presentation makes
things easy to read and easy to understand.  I like to thank everybody in this project, founding members as well as  contributors
spending every week there free time to provide this great  service.  Of cause open-slx will continue sponsoring weekly news and insure any  contributor has a
lot of fun in presenting weekly news.  
Stefan Werden </screen>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
