<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="tipsandtricks">
  <title>Tips and Tricks</title>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Desktop Users</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.unixmen.com/linux-tutorials/1823-how-to-make-your-own-20th-century-fox-and-lionsgate-intro-with-blender-25-">Unixmen/M. Zinoune: How to make your own 20th Century Fox and LIONSGATE intro with Blender 2.5 in 5 min</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>This is an easy tutorial on how to make your own 20th Century Fox and&#160; LIONSGATE styled
        intro using Blender 2.5. It is very easy you just need to donwload the templates blender and
        follow the instructions, it shouldn&apos;t take more than 5-10 minutes to edit it.&#160; To do this,
        you need to have Blender 2.5 or above installed in your system, if you are an ubuntu or
        LinuxMint&#160; user, you can install the latest release of blender using PPA from<ulink url="http://www.unixmen.com/linux-tutorials/1714-blender-257-is-released-with-a-new-design-multiple-windows-support-and-more">&#160;this link</ulink>. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 23.7.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linux.com/learn/tutorials/470411:screencasting-stars-of-the-linux-world">Linux.com/Nathan Willis: Screencasting Stars of the Linux World</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Are you still taking screenshots? That is sooo last decade. Today if you want to
        showcase your application, your gaming skills, or even your astonishing new desktop
        wallpaper collection, you need a screen recorder (or screencasting tool) to capture
        full-motion video and audio of your desktop. You&apos;ll find several solid options, but which
        one works best for you depends a lot on the type of content you need to capture, and what
        you intend to do with it.For starters, the output produced by the tool varies considerably.
        Some alternatives give you a wide choice of video and audio codecs, others just one. But if
        that one (say, Flash) is the one you need, producing it directly is much quicker than having
        to save an intermediary file and crank it through a video editor. It also may be important
        to select just a portion of the screen rather than your whole display, or to choose a
        specific frame-rate (high for games, low for bandwidth-saving demos). Finally, there are
        always special features that vary between utilities, such as whether or not they can capture
        OpenGL content or be started remotely by script. (...)</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Editors Note:</emphasis> Both <ulink url="http://bit.ly/qoyFx6">recordMyDesktop</ulink> and <ulink url="http://bit.ly/p94swf">Istanbul</ulink> are
        available via OBS.</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 23.7.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Commandline/Script Newbies</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="https://scribblesandsnaps.wordpress.com/2011/07/25/quick-tip-a-simple-python-script-to-launch-digikam/">Scribbles and Snaps: Quick Tip: A Simple Python Script to Launch digiKam</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>I store all my photos on a Linux server and mount the remote directory containing all the photos on my local machine using sshfs (see <ulink url="http://scribblesandsnaps.wordpress.com/2011/03/13/manage-photos-from-multiple-digikam-installations/">Manage Photos from Multiple digiKam Installations</ulink>). This way, I can access my photos from multiple digiKam installations. This setup works like a charm, except for one thing: when I inadvertently launch digiKam before I mount the remote directory, the application doesn’t show photos from remote albums. What’s worse, after I mount the remote directory and restart digiKam, it takes the application a long time to rescan all remote albums. To fix this annoyance, I wrote a simple Python script: (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 29.7.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://rollingprogrammer.com/2011/07/25/finch-instant-message-from-the-shellcommand-line/">RollingProgrammer();: Finch: instant message from the shell / command line</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Here’s a little trivia for everyone out there: Did you know that Pidgin also makes a text-based version of their popular instant messaging client?</para>
      <para>The application is called Finch, and it feels exactly the same as its GUI based brother Pidgin but… you know… in a shell. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 29.7.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://linuxaria.com/article/chage-uses-to-control-your-users-on-linux?lang=en">Linuxaria: chage : control your users “age” on Linux</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>If you think that the operations about users are only: creation, deletion and change of the passwords you are in error, in the standard GNU/Linux system about authentication and authorization of users there are some interesting flags regarding the age of an account.</para>
      <para>These parameters are usually ignored, but can be very useful in particular situations, or to help enforce internal policies on the use of personal accounts.</para>
      <para>All these parameters are stored in /etc/shadow can be viewed and modified with the command chage (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 29.7.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Developers and Programmers</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.techradar.com/news/software/operating-systems/19-ways-to-do-your-bit-for-open-source-980764">techradar/Neil Bothwick:19 ways to do your bit for open source</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>It&apos;s undoubtedly good to give back to a community you take so much from.</para>
      <para>And in doing so, you can also help improve the software that you use every day, both for
        your benefit and for everyone else.</para>
      <para>Here are 19 ways you can help open source projects.</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 25.7.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://python4kids.wordpress.com/2011/07/18/tkinter-tinkering-graphical-user-interfaces/">Python4Kids/Brendan Scott: Tkinter tinkering (Graphical User Interfaces)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Man &#160;&#160; &#160;Shut up! (It goes quiet next door) That’s better.He walks to a side wall and
        hangs his club on a hook beneath big old-fashioned art-nouveau sign clearly labelled `The
        Burlington Wall-banger’. He goes across to bed and gets in. In the bed are a party of four
        Japanese businessmen in suits with lapel badges, two lady American tourists with rain hats
        and cameras, three other moustached English gentlemen in pyjamas, four Tour De France
        riders, three Swedish businessmen, and Winston Churchill.</para>
      <para>So far we have been dealing with a command line interface for working with our Python
        programs.&#160; While command lines are good for a lot of things, they’re usually pretty bad for
        interfacing with a general user of the program who doesn’t know how the various pieces
        work.&#160; What we are going to look at now is a different way of presenting the program to a
        user (and probably a way that you are more familiar with) – GUIs.&#160;&#160; GUI stands for
        “Graphical User Interface”. (...)</para>
<!--($ Id: 23.7.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://olex.openlogic.com/wazi/2011/tips-for-using-vim-as-an-ide/">Wazi/Juliet Kemp: Tips for using Vim as an IDE</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><ulink url="http://olex.openlogic.com/packages/vim">Vim</ulink>&#160;isn’t just a great
        editor; it’s also a hugely flexible, configurable, and extendable application. You can even
        set up Vim as an integrated development environment (IDE), giving you all the advantages of
        a dedicated text editor together with the ability to check syntax, jump between tags,
        autocomplete, and do all the other useful things you get from a modern IDE. These Vim tips
        and tricks will get you editing like a pro. (...)</para>
<!--($ Id: 23.7.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://net.tutsplus.com/tutorials/ruby/how-to-build-a-shortlink-app-with-ruby-and-redis/">net.tutsplus.com/Charlie Somerville: How to Build a Shortlink App with Ruby and Redis</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>In this tutorial, we’ll be building a quick shortlink web app with Ruby, the&#160;<ulink url="http://www.sinatrarb.com/">Sinatra</ulink>&#160;web framework, and the<ulink url="http://redis.io/">Redis</ulink>&#160;database. By the conclusion of this tutorial, you’ll
        end up with a dead simple, high performance shortlink webapp that’s super easy to scale.
        (...)</para>
<!--($ Id: 23.7.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For System Administrators</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.serverwatch.com/tutorials/article.php/3937741/Monitor-Progress-With-Pipe-Viewer.htm">ServerWatch/Joe Brockmeier: Monitor Progress With Pipe Viewer</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>One of the most frustrating things when doing system administration is having no idea how long a process will take to finish or how much progress it&apos;s made. To get a better look at what&apos;s going on, try the <ulink url="http://www.ivarch.com/programs/pv.shtml">Pipe Viewer</ulink> utility.</para>
      <para>Pipe Viewer, or just pv when you&apos;re invoking it at the command line or in scripts, is a utility for monitoring data flowing through a pipeline. It gives you an idea of how fast the data is moving through the pipeline, how long it&apos;s taken so far, and when it will be finished. It&apos;s the digital answer to the administrative question, &quot;are we there yet?&quot; (...)</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Editors Note:</emphasis>
        Pipe Viewer  (pv) packages for openSUSE are  <ulink url="http://software.opensuse.org/search?p=1&amp;baseproject=ALL&amp;q=pv">available from Contrib repo</ulink>.</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 29.7.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://beginlinux.com/desktop/opensuse/configuring-iscsi-and-adding-isns-servers">BeginLinux: Configuring iSCSI and adding iSNS Servers</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>In previous tutorials we&apos;ve learned SUSE has made life very easy for System Administrators having developed graphical tools to manage many system components including the iSCSI target. As with most things in life there is a price to pay for this ease: YaST only writes to the configuration files and the changes do not come into force until the service is restarted. Command Line knowledge lifts us out of troublesome pit and gives us full control of our systems. Additionally we will add in ISNS (Internet Storage Name Service) to locate ISCSI Targets on our network. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 29.7.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
