<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
  %myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="kernel">
  <title>Kernel Review</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/open/news/item/Real-time-patches-for-the-Linux-kernel-take-a-major-step-forward-1282492.html"
        >h-online/Chris von Eitzen/Real-time patches for the Linux kernel take a major step
        forward</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>Thomas Gleixner has released the first test version of a real-time (RT) Linux kernel based
      on a current release candidate of Linux kernel version 3.0; having been <ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/news/item/Linux-kernel-3-0-slightly-delayed-1282429.html"
        >slightly delayed</ulink>, version 3.0 is due to be <ulink
        url="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.rt.user/6861">released</ulink> any day now. With
      version 3.0-rc7-rt0, the developers have taken the biggest step towards a modern basis for
        the <ulink url="https://rt.wiki.kernel.org/index.php/Main_Page">RT kernel</ulink>, a kernel
      that is chiefly maintained by Gleixner and several other developers – the current stable
      kernel with real-time capabilities is still based on the Linux 2.6.33 series, which Greg
      Kroah-Hartman has <ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/Kernel-Log-Further-problems-with-UEFI-1281549.html"
        >continued to maintain</ulink> specifically for the RT developers. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 22.7.11 sm $) -->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="https://lkml.org/lkml/2011/7/21/455">Linus Torvalds: Linux 3.0
        release</ulink></title>
    <para>So there it is. Gone are the 2.6.&lt;bignum> days, and 3.0 is out.</para>
    <para>This obviously also opens the merge window for the next kernel, whichwill be 3.1. The
      stable team will take the third digit, so 3.0.1 willbe the first stable release based on
      3.0.</para>
    <para>As already mentioned several times, there are no special landmarkfeatures or
      incompatibilities related to the version number change,it's simply a way to drop an
      inconvenient numbering system in honor oftwenty years of Linux. In fact, the 3.0 merge window
      was calmer thanmost, and apart from some excitement from RCU I'd have called itreally smooth.
      Which is not to say that there may not be bugs, but ifanything, there are hopefully fewer than
      usual, rather than the normal".0" problems. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 23.7.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/What-s-new-in-Linux-3-0-1279552.html"
        >h-online/Thorsten Leemhuis: What's new in Linux 3.0</ulink></title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">The transition to the Linux kernel's 'third decade' sees numerous
        changes to the Btrfs filesystem. The kernel now includes all the major components needed to
        host guest systems under Xen and includes many new and revised drivers.</emphasis></para>
    <para>Linus Torvalds and his collaborators have taken just two months to <ulink
        url="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.kernel/1170070">complete</ulink> the latest kernel.
      The most notable change, however, is cosmetic rather than technical – the transition from
      version 2.6.39 to 3.0. This not been taken as a cue to insert major changes, however, and the
      new kernel is in fact a perfectly normal version increment, following the pattern set for the
      2.6 series.</para>
    <para>New features in Linux 3.0 include the addition of a storage backend for Xen, which means
      that the kernel now contains all the major components required to run as Dom0 – the merger of
      Xen support appeared tantalisingly close six years ago, but it has taken until now for it to
      actually happen. There have also been a number of changes to the Btrfs filesystem and to
      graphics drivers. Kernel developers have as ever also added several new drivers and have
      improved many existing drivers. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 23.7.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="https://plus.google.com/102150693225130002912/posts/2BXkWyrY4jH">Linus
        Torvalds: Linux 3.0 Delayed for Late Breaking Patch</ulink></title>
    <para>Why do we always find the subtle bugs just before a release?</para>
    <para>Looks like I won't be releasing 3.0 today, just because Hugh found this incredibly subtle
      pathname lookup bug. We have a patch, we understand the problem, and it looks
      ObviouslyCorrect(tm), but I don't think I want to release 3.0 just a couple of hours after
      applying it.</para>
    <para>Of course, the bug is so hard to see that Hugh needs weeks to reproduce it even with his
      stress test, so we could just ignore it and backport the fix later. But I really hate making
      releases with known issues even if it's almost certainly a "nobody will ever hit this in
      practice" issue</para>
    <para>.Oh well.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 23.7.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="https://lkml.org/lkml/2011/7/20/371">Linus Torvalds: Note on Linux 3.0 and
        the 3.1 merge window</ulink></title>
    <para>As everybody knows by now, not only did I do an -rc7 last week insteadof releasing 3.0
      (due to some worries about the RCU code), but I endedup also not doing the 3.0 on Monday
      because of a pathname lookup bugand then some _more_ RCU issues.</para>
    <para>Anyway, those should all be resolved and the fixes merged now, and I'mnot really all that
      nervous about the pathname lookup issue - I thinkthat got nailed, and the patch for that was
      literally just moving asingle line (and adding a comment).</para>
    <para>The RCU issues worries me a bit, but everything says it's all good,and the biggest issues
      were with the new RCU_BOOST feature that reallyneither defaults to on, nor is suggested right
      now. So I think we'reok, and I'm planning on doing 3.0 tomorrow. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 23.7.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://schaiba.wordpress.com/2011/07/23/kernel-weekly-news-23-07-2011/">Rares
        Aioanei: kernel weekly news – 23.07.2011</ulink></title>
    <para>Rares gives his weekly Kernel Review.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 23.7.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
