<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="community">
  <title>In the Community</title>
  <!--Put here things relevant to the openSUSE community maybe from * People of openSUSE or elections, votings 1 - 2 posts-->
  <sect2>
    <title>Postings from the Community</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://www.linuxjournal.com/content/opensuse-celebrate-114-virtual-dance-party"
          >LinuxJournal: Susan Linton: openSUSE to Celebrate 11.4 with Virtual Dance
        Party</ulink></title>
      <para>"Many large projects mark their significant releases with launch parties. Some become
        legend for their over-the-top festivities. Photos populate the share sites. Blogs are
        written for weeks following. But openSUSE has come up with a uniquely Gecko idea: a
        Secondlife.com virtual dance party. </para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="http://www.linuxjournal.com/files/linuxjournal.com/ufiles/imagecache/node-page/nodeimage/story/openSUSE11.4rc1_launchParty.png"
          />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>On February 3, Bruno Friedman <ulink
          url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/02/03/join-us-for-the-first-virtual-launch-party-opensuse-11-4/"
          >announced</ulink> the clever launch party. In his annoucement Friedman listed the three
        dates of March 9 10 &amp; 11 2011 at 16:00 UTC. For those in the US that translates to 11:00
        PM Eastern Time, 10:OO PM Central, or 8:00 PM Pacific. The location is described as
        Macedonia at 183,213,21 coordinates or search for the Geekos group and join. It's an all you
        can virtually eat, drink, and dance party. Of course there will be lots of pictures,
        installation movies, and discussions." (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 15.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://nowwhatthe.blogspot.com/2011/02/on-getting-and-giving-attention.html">Jos
          Poortvliet: On getting and giving attention</ulink></title>
      <para>"Dear openSUSE community, There is a lot going on in openSUSE. Some of those things are
        reasonably well known by now - Tumbleweed for example. Other things like the cross-desktop
        MIME handling Stanislav Brabec has been working on are not that public. But should be! Now
        that is where everyone can make a difference. If you're a developer but also if you're just
        interested in what is going on! Development of important things happens because people know
        about it and care about it. They know and care about it because there is communication done.
        The openSUSE marketing team and in particular those writing for news.opensuse.org see it as
        their task to help spread the word about things in openSUSE which are important and can use
        help. But our marketeers can't be everywhere - they don't always know what is going on. So
        they need help with that.</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2557/3704699851_687d439826_z.jpg"
            width="30%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">How? </emphasis></para>
      <para>Simple. If you are a developer working on something cool and new, let the openSUSE
        marketing team know. That doesn't mean you have to write a story - just ping one or more
        members of the team or mail the mailinglist or <email>news@opensuse.org</email>. They'll get
        back to you, ask you questions, write about your initiative. And if you're aware of
        something cool a developer has done or is doing in and for openSUSE but you haven't seen any
        writing about it, think about letting the marketing and news team know! Send links to mails
        or blogs where they can find some information or help them contact the developer(s).
        Obviously, if you can write a quick summary of what is going on and why it is cool - that is
        awesome. You don't have to write the article, the marketeers can do that for you, but any
        material you can give or point them to will help them do it! </para>
      <para>This way we can more easily give some of the cool new initiatives in openSUSE more
        attention. openSUSE is a bottom-up community, the initiatives by individual contributors
        make the difference - that also means we need to work a bit harder to get the word out on
        what is going on. Help us with that, please! </para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Linux Starter</emphasis></para>
      <para> On an slightly related note (getting the word out), the Dutch "Linux Starter" Magazine
        still is and will continue to be available from <ulink
          url="http://www.hubstore.nl/informatie.asp?LN=STLIN2010">this site</ulink>. Yes, you can
        finally order them now! Go ahead if you want to start with Linux and/or openSUSE, for about
        10 bucks you have an excellent source of information and a nice custom dutch openSUSE DVD!
        Spread the word on that too :D"</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 19.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>People of openSUSE</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>This Week: xyz</title>
      <para>Good Guy. Glows in the night.</para>
    </blockquote>
    </sect2> -->
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Welcome new openSUSE Members</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/fcrozat">Frederic Crozat (fcrozat)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Very active in the openSUSE GNOME Team and Bugzilla.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/helen-au">Helen South
        (helen-au)</ulink></title>
      <para>Helen works inside Marketing and the Editor Team of news.opensuse.org.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/dominian">Matt Hayes
        (dominian)</ulink></title>
      <para>Active in Bugzilla, Wiki and Mailinglists.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/tsotsos">Angelos Tzotsos
        (tsotsos)</ulink></title>
      <para>Active inside the Greek Community and Marketing.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/bekun">Kai-Uwe Behrmann
        (bekun)</ulink></title>
      <para>Kai-Uwe serves as Speaker, Boothman and Developer for the openSUSE Project.</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Events &amp; Meetings</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Past</title>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/03/24/opensuse-board-meeting/">February 09,
            2011 : openSUSE Board Meeting</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/05/13/%ef%bb%bfopensuse-kde-team-meeting/"
            >February 10, 2011 : openSUSE KDE Team meeting</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Upcoming</title>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/03/24/opensuse-board-meeting/">February 23,
            2011 : openSUSE Board Meeting</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <!-- ($ ld: 12.02.11 sm $) -->
    <para>You can find more informations on other events at: <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/category/events/">openSUSE News/Events</ulink>. - <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Ambassadors_events">Local Events</ulink></para>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>openSUSE for your Ears</title>
    <para>The openSUSE Weekly News are available as livestream or podcast in German. You can hear it
      or download it on <ulink url="http://blog.radiotux.de/podcast">Radiotux</ulink>. </para>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>From Ambassadors</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://opensuseambassadors.blogspot.com/2011/02/kde-release-party-in-larissa.html"
          >Greek openSUSE Ambassadors: KDE Release Party in Larissa</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Last week in Larissa LinuxTeam hosted a KDE Release Party for 4.6. The event was listed
        in the KDE promo's wiki page, hosted in the university and there was a presentation about
        the new technologies and renovations of KDE 4.6 in which a member of the Greek openSUSE
        community Giorgos Tsiapaliokas was one of the two main speakers, the other was Theo
        Chatzimichos from Gentoo Greek Community. Of course Ι was there along with Kostas Koudaras
        and Stathis Agrapidis (another active Greek community member) who came from Thessaloniki in
        order to attend the speech and spread the word about openSUSE 11.4. We also had set up a
        booth with stickers, flyers, openSUSE 11.4 Milestone 6 KDE live cds, openSUSE 11.3 dvds, my
        netbook with openSUSE 11.4 Milestone 6 and some KDE promo material (stickers and badges)
        from the KDE e.v. which by the way I want to thank them for it because they managed to send
        me the promo kit on time. We talked about the new technologies of openSUSE 11.4, met new
        people and had fun. After the event we went in a local tavern along with LinuxTeam members,
        ate local food, drunk some tsipouro (local drink) and continued our talk about communities
        and Linux in general. </para>
      <para>Some photos from the event. You can find more here.</para>
      <para>
        <table frame="none">
          <title>Photos</title>
          <tgroup cols="2">
            <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
            <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2"/>
            <thead>
              <row>
                <entry/>
                <entry/>
              </row>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry>
                  <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                      <imagedata
                        fileref="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-IUHTfghIJPo/TV61ARRz4aI/AAAAAAAAAE4/0OGPbrzRGdY/s1600/171751_1756198139059_1062123936_32043818_5899666_o.jpg"
                        width="60%"/>
                    </imageobject>
                  </mediaobject>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                      <imagedata
                        fileref="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-t6Up-VwKOG0/TV608uwZJuI/AAAAAAAAAEw/1h0cp_1aVMo/s1600/DSC01443.jpg"
                        width="60%"/>
                    </imageobject>
                  </mediaobject>
                </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry>
                  <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                      <imagedata
                        fileref="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-QI1FJk394co/TV601RhkHGI/AAAAAAAAAEo/bEqt3tUoLsY/s1600/DSC00822.jpg"
                        width="60%"/>
                    </imageobject>
                  </mediaobject>
                </entry>
                <entry/>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table>
      </para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Communication</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/">The Mailinglists</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org">The openSUSE Forums</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Contributors</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://users.opensuse.org">The User Directory</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
