<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
<!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.attachmate.com/Press/PressReleases/attachmate-group-completes-aquisition-of-novell.htm">The Attachmate Group Completes Acquisition of Novell</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">HOUSTON – April 27, 2011</emphasis> – <ulink url="http://www.attachmategroup.com/">The Attachmate Group</ulink> today announced the completion of the acquisition of Novell, Inc., a leader in intelligent workload management, under the terms of the definitive agreement <ulink url="http://www.attachmategroup.com/news/attachmate-corporation-to-acquire-novell-inc.html">disclosed</ulink> on November 22, 2010. Novell will now operate as two separate business units under the Novell® and SUSE® brand names and join Attachmate® and NetIQ® as holdings of The Attachmate Group.

</para>
      <para>The addition of Novell furthers the mission of The Attachmate Group and its ability to support customers’ strategic and tactical business requirements through innovative solutions, quality products, and exceptional service. The Attachmate Group product families now include complementary solutions that range across IT operations management; open source; end user computing and collaboration; host connectivity and legacy modernization; security, identity and compliance management; virtualization and cloud computing; and more. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 30.4.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://futureofopensource.drupalgardens.com/2011-future-open-source-survey">5th Annual North Bridge Future of Open Source Survey 2011</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Who are the top 3 up-and-coming commercial open source software companies?

</para>
      <para>Take 5 minutes to take the survey, make your vote count, answer question 15.

</para>
      <para>Complete the survey &amp; you can register for OSBC with a 20% discount! (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 30.4.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxjournal.com/article/10935">LinuxJournal/Ibrahim Haddad: Run with
          MeeGo</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">What's new in 1.1?</emphasis>
      </para>
      <para>The MeeGo Project has had multiple releases and has progressed significantly since its
        announcement in February 2010. This article provides an overview of the MeeGo Project for
        newcomers, a review of the benefits MeeGo provides to the players in the mobile ecosystem,
        and discusses the features in the latest MeeGo 1.1 release, announced October 28, 2010.  </para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Introduction to MeeGo </emphasis></para>
      <para>MeeGo is an open, collaborative project between the project founders (Nokia and Intel),
        the Open Source community and various commercial and noncommercial partners with the goals
        of accelerating the adoption of Linux on a magnitude of client devices and enriching the
        technical Linux platform as the platform of choice for mobile computing devices.
        (...)</para>
      <!--($ ld: 1.5.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://blog.martin-graesslin.com/blog/2011/05/things-i-want-to-see-in-kwin/"
          >Martin Grässlin: What Would Be A Win For KWin In KDE</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Now with the GSoC application timeline ended, I feel like blogging about some more ideas
        what I want to see in KWin in our next releases, but are not enough for a GSoC. Nevertheless
        most of it is in the scope that it can also be handled by new developers. But some parts
        have to be done by KWin/Plasma developers. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 2.5.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.dedoimedo.com/computers/trinity-kde.html">Unixmen/Anuradha Shukla: When will Linux games become more mainstream?</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Developers are quite often gamers at heart. Until they get to core structure, there is
        no respite. Delving deep into popular games and rebuilding them are quite often the reason
        developers go on to develop the next generation of games. Linux has had quite a challenging
        history of games and their development. These are notably due to technical and practical
        reasons. While sometimes the philosophy of Open source have been the hurdle for successful
        games development.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Linux and lack of technical framework</emphasis></para>
      <para>Technically the lack of GPU drivers for Linux-based graphic cards, like in
        high-performing as proprietary software and the never resolving patents do put a large
        hurdle-infested road map for Linux games. Experts believe the continued failure to include
          <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/S3_Texture_Compression">S3TC</ulink> for open
        source OpenGL drivers as most are patent pending is creating a pseudo-scenario where distros
        are being released on the assumption that the drivers are already available. Distros without
        supporting graphic card drivers are as improper to have as a web browser without
        .jpg.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Linux and lack of revenue generation from games</emphasis></para>
      <para>The main belief for laxity in Linux games is that open source gaming sponsors find there
        is a lack of revenue generation as most is free software and most believe in
        doing-it-yourself philosophy. The limitation in specialized proprietary game-ware available
        currently, is that they become so niche in their genre that gamers are finding it difficult
        to port games across platforms.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Linux overworked by licenses?</emphasis></para>
      <para>Linux Gamers have a choice between choosing limited digitally licensed games that allow
        games to be installed on several systems and open source fee games. But again, the buck
        stops why are they not as powerful or as overwhelming as MMORG games and their ilk, given
        that Linux offers such fantastic scope for similar gaming ecosystems. Grapple is one of the
        free software projects, which is bundled with the Linux Game Publishing. It offers
        multiplayer opportunities and applications development.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Trend towards Linux game change </emphasis></para>
      <para>Analysts are now pinning down on new trends of platform confining proprietary games.
        Purist gamers believe cross-platform gaming and Linux with its high degree of cross platform
        compatibility are beginning to look towards Linux for better gaming solutions.</para>
      <para>The dichotomy in Linux games seems to have been bridged somewhat by the availability of
          <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Humble_Indie_Bundle">Humble Indie Bundles</ulink>
        a non-dependent video gaming line by <ulink url="http://www.wolfire.com/">Wolfire Games</ulink>, which are multi-platform, non-DRM and compatible with Windows, OS X as well
        as Linux. The first bundle released in the second quarter of May 2010, saw the likes of
        World of Goo, Lugaru, Penumbra, Gish and Samorost 2 as an afterthought. As the developers
        committed to offer these under open source if sales went beyond $1 million, the 1.25 million
        sales led to these games being available under the GPL license. Revenge of the Titans was
        released post better sales in Dec 2010.</para>
      <para>Despite <ulink url="http://www.worldofgoo.com/">World of Goo’s</ulink> success, open
        source yet remains a high-risk option for games owners. Humble Indie Bundle has proved a
        successful model and will hopefully be the harbinger of greater, more enjoyable games on the
        open source platform.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/nl/">CC-BY-NC-ND</ulink></para>
<!-- ($ ld: 29.4.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxaria.com/article/10-easter-eggs-in-linux?lang=en">Linuxaria: 10 Easter Eggs in Linux</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Happy easter to all, what’s better than celebrate this holiday taking a look at what have hidden the programmers in our software ?
A virtual Easter egg is an intentional hidden message, in-joke or feature in a work such as a computer program, web page, video game, movie, book or crossword. The term was coined—according to Warren Robinett—by Atari after they were pointed to the secret message left by Robinett in the game Adventure. (...)</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Editors Note</emphasis>: If you are an openSUSE user, try &apos;zypper moo&apos; on your console. ;-)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 30.4.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://linuxlibrary.org/index.php/distributions/opensuse-11-4-gnome-review/">Linux Library/thinkinhurtz: OpenSUSE 11.4 Gnome Review</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Here is another great all purpose Linux distribution with lots of the newest software only a few clicks away. Although things don’t appear to have changed much in recent years there are still some great improvements under the hood. OpenSUSE is known as a reliable distribution with a diverse selection of options making it another great choice for desktops and servers alike. Lighter desktop editions of OpenSUSE might be a better for choice for laptops however. I have already covered OpenSUSE 11.4 KDE for those who are interested, here I will focus on the OpenSUSE Gnome desktop. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 30.4.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/The-naming-of-parts-Time-for-Linux-Inside-1235154.html"
          >Linux.com/Glyn Moody: The naming of parts: Time for <quote>Linux
        Inside</quote>?</ulink></title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Names matter in free software. Just think of the number of
          electrons that have been spilt arguing over whether it's “Linux” or “GNU/Linux”.
        </emphasis></para>
      <para>The naming of parts came up when I interviewed Linus back in 1996. I had asked him about
        his relations with Richard Stallman, and this is what Linus said:</para>
      <para>I<emphasis role="italic">'ve had some, not very much. At first he wasn't too interested,
          because Linux was so PC-centric – just two years ago, it didn't run on anything else. And
          I suspect Richard really dislikes PCs. So he wasn't really interested in that sense.
          Lately, when it's become obvious how portable it is and how well it works on other
          architectures too, I think Richard in that sense looks at Linux in a different light.
        </emphasis></para>
      <para><emphasis role="italic">One problem we've had, well, problem, kind of clash of
          personalities, is that Linux has gotten so much press and GNU has gotten so little. So for
          Richard, he's not pragmatic, he really has this idealistic world-view, he'd really like
          the system to be called GNU/Linux or something like this. Personally I don't think GNU
          Linux flies as a name, it should be catchy.</emphasis></para>
      <para>But is “Linux” catchy? The fact that few people have heard of it outside the rather
        specialised world of free software suggests not. Indeed, far more people have probably come
        across “Ubuntu”, which has taken on the role of the public face of GNU/Linux to a certain
        extent. That's good, in the sense that it has done valuable work promoting free software to
        the general public; but it's also unfortunate in that it has pushed the “Linux” name even
        further into the background. (...)</para>
      <!--($ ld: 30.4.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.techrepublic.com/blog/opensource/introduction-to-selinux-dont-let-complexity-scare-you-off/2447">Techrepublic/Vincent Danen: Introduction to SELinux: Don&apos;t let complexity scare you off</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>akeaway: Vincent Danen acknowledges that some of the complexity of SELinux is
        intimidating, but if you spend some time with it, the payoff is heightened security and
        better control of your system.</para>
      <para>Most people who know Linux have at least heard about SELinux. SELinux, or
        Security-Enhanced Linux, was originally developed primarily by the NSA (U.S. National
        Security Agency), as an implementation of the Flask operating system security architecture.
        Flask implements MAC (Mandatory Access Control), a means of designating what processes have
        access to what resources (be they network ports, files, and so on). A lot of work has been
        done to make SELinux as easy to use as possible, although at first glance it does look
        hideously complex.</para>
      <para>Since 2003, SELinux has been integrated into the mainline Linux kernel, and is fully
        supported in distributions such as Red Hat Enterprise Linux, Fedora, CentOS, Debian
        (disabled by default), Ubuntu, openSUSE, Hardened Gentoo, and others. On Red Hat Enterprise
        Linux and Fedora, SELinux is enabled at installation.</para>
      <!-- ($ Id: 27.4.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
<!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.petur.eu/blog/?p=349">Petur.eu: Linux can be hacked with an USB device</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>I have to admit, over the years I haven’t given openSUSE enough love or credit for being
        the outstanding Linux distribution is it. With that said, I wanted to give some attention to
        the latest release coming out of the openSUSE project. And, since the default desktop for
        openSUSE 11.4 is KDE, I will be giving a little extra attention to the KDE desktop. Since
        both might well gain some serious ground, when Ubuntu 11.04 is released, it will be nice for
        users to not only know of its existence, but to also know that openSUSE 11.4 is, in fact, a
        solid distribution worth giving a look. (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> --><!--<sect2>
  <title>LOL</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://xkcd.com/874/">XKCD: Time Management</ulink>
    </title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/time_management.png" width="50%"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.5/">CC-BY-NC</ulink></para>
  </blockquote>
</sect2>--></sect1>
