<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1>
  <title>Board Election 2010</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://nmarques.digitalwhores.net/2010/10/16/to-nuremberg/">Sebastian 'sebas'
        Kügler: Running for the openSUSE Board.</ulink></title>
    <para>Following up on the call for candidates, I’d like to let you know that I’m intending to
      run for the openSUSE Board. </para>
    <para>In my dayjob, I am responsible for user experience at open-slx, and will be able to invest
      time on a regular basis into participating in the openSUSE board. I have a degree in business
      science, which gives me some formal insight into organisational processes, this has helped my
      work for the KDE e.V. in the past, and it will surely be benefitial for openSUSE. I am 34
      years old, and live in Nijmegen, in the east of the Netherlands. </para>
    <para>I have more than 4 years of experience in administering a Free software project (I’m
      member of the KDE e.V. board since 2006), and during this period have helped turning the KDE
      e.V. into an effective community representation and supporting organisation, which in many
      ways acts as a role model to other, similar organisations. The Geeko in me is about 9 years
      old, it started with openSUSE 7.2, which got me hooked on Linux. After a period of trying all
      kinds of Linuxen, I’m firmly back to openSUSE for about two years now. </para>
    <para>openSUSE represents to me a technically excellent product with a friendly, helpful and
      skilled community around it that is failing to realise its potential, and in many ways is
      searching for orientation and a clear mission. Aside from organisational topics, this process
      I’d like to facilitate. </para>
    <para>My platform for the elections is to help set up the openSUSE e.V. (or rather a legal
      representation of the community, as outlined in the current plans), and to help the community
      through the process of becoming more independent from Novell, which in my opinion is important
      for the growth and sustainability of openSUSE as product and community. I’m a Free software
      dude by heart, and the principle and ethics of the Free software community will be what drives
      my decisions as executive. My experience as "cat-herder" will be beneficial in the same
      way.</para>
    <para>I do realise that my involvement in the openSUSE community has been fairly transparant,
      following things from the sideline, stepping in actively here and there, and certainly far
      from taking on any role as rock-star. I am planning to further ramp up my profile, since that
      a) will make the members’ decision during the elections a lot easier, and b) it improves
      accessibility and visibility of the TOTRoS (The Organisation That Represents openSUSE). </para>
    <para>This email is just to let you know in advance that I’m intending to run for the board. As
      I /also/ intend to go on vacation on Friday, I might appear unresponsive until ~christmas.
      Still, I opted for letting everybody know early on that I’m intending to run (rather than
      sending my note of intent to run after christmas), as planning will likely make the work of
      the election committee a bit easier. Surely, if you’ve questions already, feel free to ask. I
      will, after returning from vacation be more outgoing about my involvement with openSUSE and my
      ideas and plans for the openSUSE board. Thanks for your attention, and your support.</para>
  </blockquote>

  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://opensuse.terrorpup.net/?p=176">Chuck 'terrorpup' Payne: Throwing my
        name as a candidate for board of openSUSE</ulink></title>
    <para>I like to throw my name in as a candidate for board of openSUSE. For the past two years I
      have been helping out as Ambassador, but I have been a SUSE user since 5.3. I love my work
      with openSUSE, and I want to do more. I think my experince as System Administrator, End User,
      Mentor, and Ambassador, plus years of experience would be a big plus to board and to the
      community. </para>
    <para>I started out with Linux in 96′ as an end, tried of Mac OS, and fearing that it would
      died. This was before the return of Steve Jobs. Start with Slackware 96 then move to Red Hat
      and Turbo Linux, then moving to S.u.S.E and never leaving it. </para>
    <para>I have worked in the IT field as System Administrator since 98. My first job, I was able
      to get S.u.S.E 6.2 in to replace Red Hat 6.0. Personally I have used it since 5.3 as server.
      It was until openSUSE 10.2 that I started using as a Desktop replacement at work for daily to
      daily, replacing Windows XP and Macintosh OS X OS’es. I can be honest, I still use Mac OS for
      some desktop publishing, but I use my openSUSE desktop for the other 90%. </para>
    <para>When the call came for people to become Ambassador back in 2008, I jumped at the chance to
      give back to openSUSE in return for everything it has giving to me. I have been to three linux
      fest. Give a couple of number of talks to local user group. I have even wrote for a Polish
      Linux this summer called Linux Identity. I have even done a video for the OSC, which was the
      best but did put some faces to aliases. I am working on other projects that once are done I
      will show the community. </para>
    <para>The other thing I am doing currently for openSUSE is I help with the Facebook page. Trying
      to post links and events. And I have even set up a twitter account for the openSUSE Ambassador
      that I hope in the furture and help get out their great work to community and others. </para>
    <para>I am currently rebuilding the Georgia openSUSE User Group. I am active in ALE. And love to
      go to Linux Fest and help spread the word about openSUSE and open source software to the
      masses. </para>
    <para>My daily-to-daily life, I am System Administrator for a start company called Vocalocity
      that does a lot with SIP/Telecommunications in their NOC team. Before that I worked at Travel
      Channel Media. I am married. I am very much international. I know that a lot of people don’ t
      think that of American. But I have lived in Japan for three and half years and taught English
      Communications. My wife is Turkish. I do travel from here to there no as much as I would like.
      I have a six year son that know I love Linux and every time he see a penguin points out that,
      “There that software you work with Daddy”. I also have a black cat that loves to sit in my lap
      while I am computer working. I am a bit old I think than most, I am 43 but with that I bring a
      lot of experience to the table, one not being a developer, but as a end user, a system
      administrator. Which covers both every day-to-day users and business. </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-project/2010-12/msg00034.html">Kostas
        'warlordfff' Koudaras: Board Member Application</ulink></title>
    <para>Hello world I would like you to know that I want to run as a candidate for the board of
      openSUSE. I am a seasonal forest firefighter in my 'day' job, so as you can understand,
      contributing for the common good is all I do in my life. </para>
    <para>I am into FOSS for a couple of years now but I am a man of action so I do most of the
      things I plan and do not stay in plans.I am currently the event manager of Association of
      Greek Users and Friends of FS / OSS (GREEKLUG) and I was responsible for organizing the host
      and speech of Richard Stallman here in Thessaloniki, which was a huge success. I spend four
      days with him and I learned many things about the meaning of Free Software, among other
      things, and got deeply effected and motivated by his words. </para>
    <para>I started working with openSUSE almost a year ago and I became ambassador on that summer.
      Since I became ambassador I made quite a few things about it, as I said a man of action. Me
      along with Stathis 'Diamond_gr' Iosifidis organized the Greek openSUSE community from scratch.
      We re-activated the Greek IRC channel which was almost dead. We started the <ulink
        url="http://amb.opensuse.gr">http://amb.opensuse.gr</ulink> so that the world can see our
      actions as ambassadors. We were the openSUSE team at the 75th International Trade Fair of
      Thessaloniki. We made a call for all Greek Geekos to gather and for a community, although at
      that time (a few months ago) almost every 'expert' told us that it would end up a great
      failure, we never stopped fighting and finally we prove them wrong. We recently started
      translating the openSUSE Weekly news and I am responsible for gathering and checking the
      translation. We started re-organize and translating the Greek wiki. We went to Athens were we
      actually met suseRocks and spoke with him about several matters about the community and the
      project.I went to several city’s all over Greece in order to meet in person people of the
      Greek community because I strongly believe that face to face communication builds actual trust
      and I do whatever is possible to prove people that I truly deserve their trust. Greek
      ambassador team trusted me to be the one communicating the board if needed in order to
      separate jobs inside the Greek community. I participated in several innovating events for
      openSUSE like the Xariseto Free festival. I represented openSUSE to an event at primary school
      in Thessaloniki for celebrating Software Freedom Day 2010. </para>
    <para>Beyond the Greek community I participate actively in the marketing and the ambassador
      teams and I am trying to do the same at other teams too. Andreas Jaeger recently trusted me to
      be the one of three at the Ambassador Welcome Team. I probably forgot some of the things I do
      but the general idea about me as a person and also my moto for my campaign is 'Planning is
      good, but acting is better'. I totally believe in team working and I think that I co-operate
      great with others. I am a Hacker in life more than I am a hacker in programming,in fact I
      don't know almost no programming at all nor I am good at solving technically nature problems.
      I tend to like my disadvantages and use them as actual advantages. I think outside of the box
      and try to think with as much playful cleverness as I can get. I believe deeply in evolution
      and I am not afraid to bleed my ego for evolution to come. I don't stare at targets, I hit
      them till I get them and I never give up. </para>
    <para>If you read the whole text above I truly thank you,if not I can understand you I hope for
      your support </para>
  </blockquote>

  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://nowwhatthe.blogspot.com/2010/12/opensuse-board-elections.html">Jos
        Poortvliet: openSUSE Board elections</ulink></title>
    <para>Awesomeness. I just heard that already 3 people stepped up for the 2010 openSUSE Board
      elections. And Sascha posted the announcement only yesterday! </para>
    <para>Really, this is something that shows how openSUSE is a healthy community. We have plenty
      of people who are able and willing to do this - which is really great. Thanks to those who
      stepped up - there are only 2 positions, but even the act of stepping forward and saying
      you're willing to do this is very important! </para>
    <para>The openSUSE Board work is very important and becoming more so. Currently work is being
      done on setting up an openSUSE Foundation - and the board plays a crucial role there. We need
      people with some experience and willingness to work hard on this, there is a lot of work. If
      you fit that bill - apply!</para>
  </blockquote>
  <!-- More entries here... -->
</sect1>
