<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/21/opensuse-11-4-still-going-strong/"
        >Andreas Jaeger: openSUSE Release versioning – Poll on last three options</ulink></title>
    <para>The poll on SurveyMonkey on how to version the openSUSE distribution release is now
      closed, you can see the results <ulink
        url="http://www.surveymonkey.com/sr.aspx?sm=ZMyUjEimqUeLGFeX8Kmq_2baNaoqX9TRhoTN0KA_2fPlQxQ_3d"
        >here</ulink>. The winner is the “old school” (like currently but only counting the right
      number until 3), followed by “Fedora style” (just integers) and “Ubuntu style” (2 digits year
      “.” 2 digits month).</para>
    <para>The openSUSE members only poll is now live on <ulink
        url="https://connect.opensuse.org/pg/polls/read/a_jaeger/12979/opensuse-release-versioning"
        >connect.opensuse.org</ulink> until April 04, 2011. Please <ulink
        url="https://connect.opensuse.org/pg/polls/read/a_jaeger/12979/opensuse-release-versioning"
        >select</ulink> your favorite option!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GFDL 1.2</ulink></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 28.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/28/review-opensuse-11-4-and-the-much-improved-xfce-4-8/"
        >Review – openSUSE 11.4 and the much improved XFCE 4.8</ulink></title>
    <para>Just a few months ago, the XFCE project announcedý<ulink
        url="http://www.xfce.org/about/news/?post=1295136000">XFCE 4.8</ulink>,ýthe result of over 2
      years of hard work. This desktop, one of the four official desktops of <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/10/opensuse-11-4/">openSUSE 11.4</ulink>, brings many
      new features. If you’re not having fun in the desktops provided by KDE or GNOME you should
      have a close look at XFCE (or the lightweight LXDE). To show you how it’s done, I checked out
      XFCE and wrote about my experience.</para>
    <figure id="xfce">
      <title>The default XFCE desktop</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/desktop-300x168.png"/>
        </imageobject>        
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Testing XFCE 4.8 on openSUSE 11.4</emphasis></para>
    <para>To test XFCE <xref linkend="xfce"/> I went into <ulink url="http://susestudio.com">SUSE Studio</ulink> and
      created an XFCE 4.8 image. After some clicking around (slimming a standard GNOME down to XFCE)
      I had built a hard disk image. If you do this yourself, notice that by default, SUSE Studio
      does not install ‘recommended’ packages from patterns. This can be enabled – and you surely
      should do that if you want a decent XFCE!</para>
    <para>The ability to just write an image to an usb disk and have it resize itself to the size of
      the whole stick at first boot is awesome. You can just install software and in general won’t
      notice you work on an USB stick! That is truly a portable OS… (...)</para>    
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">FDL 1.2</ulink></para>
    <!--($ ld: 28.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/25/linux-foundation-20th-anniversary-of-linux-campaign-and-video-contest/">Linux Foundation 20th Anniversary of Linux Campaign and Video Contest</ulink></title>
    <para>It’s the 20th Anniversary of Linux in August and the Linux Foundation is kicking off
      celebrations at <ulink url="http://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/collaboration-summit">The
        Collaboration Summit</ulink> which takes place April 6-8, 2011 at the Hotel Kabuki in San
      Francisco. A highlight of the campaign is the annual Video Contest, which this year focuses on
      the 20 year celebration and will be judged by Linux Torvalds himself.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/vintage-8mm-camera-242x300.jpg"
          width="10%" align="right"/>
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <para>The Linux Foundation has invited members and the community to create their own 20th
      anniversary videos in advance, which will be featured on the announcement date of April 6.
      Videos submitted early enough to be available during the first days of the contest will
      receive additional promotion by The Linux Foundation.</para>
    <para>This is a fantastic opportunity for video makers in the openSUSE community to get some
      visibility for their work and their favorite distribution! (Not to mention showing off how
      easy it is to make awesome videos with openSUSE.) So get started right away, and watch this
      space for details on how to submit your video.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">FDL 1.2</ulink></para>
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
