<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://mschlander.wordpress.com/2011/03/12/opensuse-11-4-has-been-released/"
        >OMG! SUSE! team: On release day, it is like a big dump truck</ulink></title>
    <para>Shortly after the initial release of openSUSE 11.4, I posted some <ulink
        url="http://omgsuse.com/content/rapidly-downloading-opensuse-114-bittorrent">giant
        BitTorrent links</ulink> to speed up your downloading of openSUSE. Now that the initial
      flood of downloads has come and gone, I wanted to report back with some statistics shared by
      openSUSE Contributor <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2008/03/01/people-of-opensuse-marcus-rueckert/">Marcus
        Rueckert</ulink>.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">Note</emphasis></emphasis>: These numbers
      are for BitTorrent downloads only.</para>
    <para>As of last Thursday (March 17th), the numbers broke down as follows:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Full DVD images downloaded: <emphasis role="bold">8228</emphasis></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Live CD images downloaded: <emphasis role="bold">4009</emphasis></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>If you're not terrifically familiar with the way that BitTorrent works, all users are
      constantly sharing data with one another but users fall into two buckets:
        <quote>leechers</quote> and <quote>seeders</quote>. The <quote>leechers</quote> are users
      who don't <emphasis role="italic">yet</emphasis> have the complete file, while the
        <quote>seeders</quote> have fully completed their download and are <emphasis role="bold"
        >only</emphasis> uploading to the other users. In short, having a lot of seeders means you
      have a good healthy torrent and downloads for new folks will be <emphasis role="italic"
        >fast</emphasis>.</para>
    <para>As of last Thursday, both the 32-bit and the 64-bit DVD images had over <emphasis
        role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">one thousand seeders</emphasis></emphasis>, 20% more
      seeders than leechers too! That is incredibly awesome!</para>
    <para>Marcus went on to say:</para>
    <para><quote>I tested on friday morning and peaked at 11.2MB/s download speed for torrent which
        is almost max speed of my line.</quote></para>
    <para>This means if you download the DVD image <emphasis role="italic">right now</emphasis>, you
      are likely going download openSUSE as fast as technically possible!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">CC-BY-SA</ulink></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 21.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/03/13/opensuse-11-4-how-it-goes-in-portugal/">OMG!
        SUSE! team: Search openSUSE, powered by Google</ulink></title>
    <para>Community member Brandon Philips introduced <emphasis role="bold"><ulink
          url="http://search.opensuse.org">search.opensuse.org</ulink></emphasis> to the world on
      the opensuse-project<ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Mailing_lists">mailing
        list</ulink>. The site is a simple, fast Google-powered search engine for openSUSE.org, the
        <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/">forums</ulink>, the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org">wiki</ulink> and the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Mailing_lists">mailing lists</ulink>.</para>
    <para>If you're interested in checking out the code behind <ulink
        url="http://search.opensuse.org">search.opensuse.org</ulink>, head on over to the <ulink
        url="http://gitorious.org/search-opensuse-org/search-opensuse-org">repository on
        Gitorious.org</ulink>.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://cdn.omgsuse.com/omg/images/susesearch_crushed.png" width="50%"/>
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">CC-BY-SA</ulink></para>
    <!--($ ld: 22.3.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://omgsuse.com/content/suse-studio-jumps-114-bandwagon">OMG!SUSE! team:
        SUSE Studio jumps on the 11.4 bandwagon</ulink></title>
    <para>With the release of <ulink
        url="http://omgsuse.com/content/tenth-day-opensuse-114-changed-everything">openSUSE
        11.4</ulink>, I would like to start talking more and more about <ulink
        url="http://susestudio.com">SUSE Studio</ulink>. While SUSE Studio might not be a terribly
      useful tool for the average end-user, for power-users and developers it is quite an impressive
      piece of technology, built on top of openSUSE and <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:KIWI">KIWI</ulink>.</para>
    <para>For developers, imagine creating an image of the <emphasis role="italic">ideal</emphasis>
      test machine, complete with repositories from the <ulink url="http://build.opensuse.org"
        >openSUSE Build Service</ulink> already enabled and all the necessary dependencies already
      installed. SUSE Studio <emphasis role="bold">does that</emphasis>.</para>
    <para>For power-users, imagine having a USB stick or a Live CD with your completely
      personalized, custom version of openSUSE. All set up and ready to go, whenever you need it.
      SUSE Studio does that.</para>
    <para>With the initial release of 11.4, <ulink
        url="http://blog.susestudio.com/2011/03/opensuse-114-support.html">SUSE Studio announced
        support for 11.4 appliances</ulink>. Which means you could create a custom openSUSE 11.4
      appliance <emphasis role="italic">while</emphasis> your <ulink
        url="http://omgsuse.com/content/rapidly-downloading-opensuse-114-bittorrent">ISO was
        downloading off BitTorrent</ulink>.</para>
    <para>Now the team has gone a step further, allowing you to <ulink
        url="http://blog.susestudio.com/2011/03/upgrade-your-older-appliances-to.html">upgrade
        existing 11.3 appliances to openSUSE 11.4</ulink>, with a single button click on <ulink
        url="http://susestudio.com">SUSEStudio.com</ulink>. <emphasis role="italic">See
        below:</emphasis></para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://cdn.omgsuse.com/omg/images/susestudio_upgrade.png" width="50%"/>
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <para>(In case you're wondering, the SUSE Studio mascot is named "Dister" and he's a robot. A
      friendly robot, with three friendly fingers.)</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">CC-BY-SA</ulink></para>
    <!--($ ld: 22.3.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://omgsuse.com/content/poll-are-you-using-114-yet">OMG!SUSE! team: Poll:
        Are you using 11.4 yet?</ulink></title>
    <para>It's been a little over a week since <ulink
        url="http://omgsuse.com/content/tenth-day-opensuse-114-changed-everything">openSUSE
        11.4</ulink> was released out into the wild. As with any release of any single piece or
      collection of software, there will of course be a few <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Most_annoying_bugs_11.4">pretty annoying bugs</ulink>,
      but have they been enough to hold you back from trying out 11.4?</para>
    <para>Have you taken the plunge, still cautious?</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">We want to know!</emphasis></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">CC-BY-SA</ulink></para>
    <!--($ ld: 23.3.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://opensuse.terrorpup.net/?p=246">Chuck Payne: Time to start writing again</ulink></title>
    <para>I know since the elections it’s been very quite here. I been on the openSUSE Wave that’s
      calming down a bit, which is sad, because it been a wonderful ride. It fact lately I feel I am
      on the downward ebb of Karma. </para>
    <para>The wave started getting ready for Hackfest/SCALE which took place in L.A. I got to work
      with a great group of people. Very long hard days, but we made a very big splash at SCALE.
      Where I got to do a bit of training openSUSE Day, and thanks to Alan Clark, got to help give a
      talk at SCALE. </para>
    <para>Coming back from that week, I got sick but couldn’t slow down because of the release of
      openSUSE 11.4 and working on a Poster, I assume for Linux Magazine in UK. Both were very
      import. The poster looks great because of Carlos awesome background and the release when
      great. (...)</para>
    <para><!--($ ld: 15.3.11 sm $)--></para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://e-tote-kala.blogspot.com/2011/03/attachmate-supportive-friend-of.html">Kostas Koudaras: Attachmate - A supportive friend of the openSUSE Project</ulink></title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-RHd1mQJWS0s/TX5b1sDf6pI/AAAAAAAAA8Q/D4kH-fD9cWo/s1600/cip_attachmate-sold.gif"
          align="center"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Today, Jeff Hawn the Chairman and CEO of <ulink url="http://www.attachmate.com/"
        >Attachmate</ulink> made an announcement <ulink
        url="http://www.attachmate.com/Press/PressReleases/congratulations-openSUSE-project.htm"
        >congratulating the openSUSE community on the release of openSUSE 11.4</ulink>. It is the
      second press release of <ulink url="http://www.attachmate.com/">Attachmate</ulink> after the
        '<ulink url="http://www.attachmate.com/Press/PressReleases/nov-22-2010-SUSE.htm">Attachmate
        Corporation Statement on openSUSE project</ulink>' and it shows the intentions of
      Attachmate's people to support the openSUSE project and community and all together to achieve
      great things in the Future. -- Kostas Koudaras</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">CC-BY-SA </ulink></para>
    <!--($ ld: 15.3.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://nowwhatthe.blogspot.com/2011/03/be-proud-of-yourself-geekos.html">Jos Poortvliet: Be proud of yourself, Geekos!</ulink></title>
    <para>Right now I'm enjoying the post-release stress. Going back and catching up with what was
      delayed due to the release being priority and all... And enjoying huge discussions on
      Identi.ca like <ulink url="http://identi.ca/conversation/65860477#notice-66972122">this
        one</ulink> ;-)</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-5cGzCcRPd18/TX7ZH6urREI/AAAAAAAABbc/5dbpQYZiR0A/s200/11.4_NET_installer-boot.png"
          align="right"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Me proud of the Geeko!</emphasis></para>
    <para>The article which went out on Friday made me very proud - <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/12/opensuse-11-4-made-a-splash/">openSUSE 11.4 made a
        splash</ulink>. The title is really correct - we're gathering info on reviews etc on <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/In_the_press">this page</ulink> but it is extremely incomplete -
      there are so many reviews, articles, <ulink url="http://twitter.com/#!/search/opensuse"
        >tweets</ulink>, <ulink url="http://bit.ly/e3IAHc">dents</ulink>, <ulink
        url="http://www.facebook.com/#!/pages/openSUSE/45393742283">facebook</ulink> comments,
        <ulink url="http://bit.ly/fPsJaZ">video's on youtube</ulink> - it is really great! And well
      over <emphasis role="bold">100.000 downloads in 24 hours</emphasis>, almost twice what we did
      for 11.3 - awesome. openSUSE has its momentum back, that's clear. We already wrote that <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/01/03/opensuse-finished-2010-big/">in this "end of 2010"
        article</ulink>, and the subsequent Bretzn and Appstore sprints, the marketing sprint and
      all the cool stuff that is going on makes me quite certain about this: the openSUSE conference
      2010 was a real turning point for openSUSE. The Geeko's back in the game!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Did we leave?</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>The question that might come up is - did the Geeko ever leave? I had a look at <ulink
        url="http://opensuse.org/statistics">some statistics</ulink> on our user base.<emphasis
        role="bold"> openSUSE has 7-8 million users</emphasis>, that's significant! And,
      interestingly enough, between 30-50% more than Fedora. Ubuntu has no statistics online but
      once made some noise about numbers - talking somewhere between 6 and 8.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">So be a proud Geeko! </emphasis></para>
    <para>Now all these numbers have some uncertainty associated with them, nothing is sure. Yet the
      numbers of Fedora and openSUSE at least are measured in the same way, so likely you can at
      least compare them roughly. And I bet Ubuntu has similar statisics on which they based their
      number - with the usual exaggeration. So even though the numbers aren't entirely clear, it is
      interesting to see openSUSE ain't exactly insignificant as many seem to believe... Not only do
      we have amazing technology like <ulink url="http://build.opensuse.org/">OBS</ulink> and <ulink
        url="http://susestudio.com/">Studio</ulink> but we also have a HUGE user base whom we serve
      with <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/10/opensuse-11-4/">a pretty awesome
        distro</ulink>! So, Geeko's, in the communication and marketing department - maybe openSUSE
      is not well known for that. But we're a leading distro when it comes to what matters - users
      and technology. Be proud!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">CC-BY-SA</ulink>
    </para>
    <!--($ ld: 15.3.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/03/16/first-survey-on-opensuse-version-naming-is-open-now/">Andreas Jaeger: First Survey on openSUSE Version naming is open now</ulink></title>
    <para>Following my last blog post on “<ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/03/11/how-to-name-the-distribution-releases/">how to
        name the distribution release</ulink>“, I’ve opened up a public <ulink
        url="http://www.surveymonkey.com/s/ZYC5PYZ">survey</ulink> and look forward to your votes.
      There is also a good discussion going on on the <ulink
        url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-project/2011-03/msg00262.html">opensuse-project
        mailing list</ulink>. </para>
    <para>This is the first iteration. Coolo and myself discussed to use a second survey with the
      group of winners on <ulink url="http://connect.opensuse.org"
      >connect.opensuse.org</ulink>.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 16.3.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/03/17/opensuse-and-kraft-on-clt/">Klaas Freitag: openSUSE and Kraft on CLT</ulink></title>
    <para>First some news about my KDE project <ulink url="http://volle-kraft-voraus.de/"
        >Kraft</ulink>: </para>
    <para>A review was posted on <ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/03/17/opensuse-and-kraft-on-clt/Technewsworld.com"
        >Technewsworld.com</ulink> with title <ulink url="http://bit.ly/f40Pux">Kraft: A No-Nonsense
        Office Assistant That Gets Straight to Work</ulink>. Nice title, and also the bottomline of
      the whole article. Good to read, however I am wondering why the author tested Kraft version
      0.32 instead the current one 0.40 which is out already for ten month. Are there *still* 0.32
      packages around in the Ubuntu-World? On the <ulink
        url="http://volle-kraft-voraus.de/Main/Download">download page</ulink> on Kraft’s website,
      there are good Ubuntu packages linked thanks to Rohan Garg. </para>
    <para>The only remark in the review was that the list of document types should be editable. It
      is since 0.40 :-) Anyway, thanks for considering Kraft for a review. </para>
    <para>On next weekend I will be in Chemnitz on the <ulink
        url="http://chemnitzer.linux-tage.de/2011/">Chemnitzer Linux Tage</ulink>. I will give a
      talk titled <ulink url="http://chemnitzer.linux-tage.de/2011/vortraege/800">Linux im Büro von
        Kleinunternehmen</ulink> (Linux in the small enterprise). Beside other interesting things I
      will present Kraft of course. It will be a talk for people who are new to Linux but try to get
      their work done with Linux. I am looking forward as I enjoy these solution focused topics. If
      you are interested, show up and we talk about Kraft. And, yes, a new release of Kraft is also
      on the way, it can’t take too long any more. </para>
    <para>The <ulink url="http://www.opensuse.org/">openSUSE Project</ulink> will have a booth as
      well and I probably will be around there for the rest of the time together with friends from
      the project. We will tell you about our cool project, explain how you can participate and show
      the brand new <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/10/opensuse-11-4/">openSUSE 11.4
        release</ulink>. It is a nice one. and we think you will like it. I hope to see you there
      :-) </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">FDL 1.2</ulink>
    </para>
    <!--($ ld: 17.3.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.linuxuser.co.uk/reviews/opensuse-11-4-review-kde-4-6-and-tumbleweed-shine/">Linux User &amp; Developer/Koen Vervloesem: openSUSE 11.4 review – KDE 4.6 and Tumbleweed shine</ulink></title>
    <para>Do you want to run the newest software like KDE 4.6 and LibreOffice 3.3? OpenSUSE 11.4 has
      it all on offer, and if you’re really impatient there’s even a rolling updates repository in
      the form of Tumbleweed. Koen Vervloesem investigates… (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 18.3.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.digitalflow.de/blog/2011/03/opensuse-11-4/">Thomas Schmidt: openSUSE 11.4</ulink></title>
    <para>After 8 months of work openSUSE 11.4 has been <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/10/opensuse-11-4/">released</ulink> last week! This
      has been celebrated with <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/10/opensuse-11-4/"
        >release parties</ulink> all around the world. As usual, the new release comes with the
      latest <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/10/opensuse-11-4/">kernel</ulink>, <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/07/opensuse-11-4-will-be-first-to-roll-out-with-libreoffice/"
        >LibreOffice</ulink>, <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/03/gnome-on-opensuse-11-4/">Gnome</ulink> and <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/02/opensuse-11-4-and-kde-2/">KDE</ulink>
      packages.</para>
    <para>In Nuremberg, we celebrated the release with a party at the Artefakt bar, and had the
      fabulous <ulink url="http://on.fb.me/g2Ux2X">Ukulele Insanity</ulink> playing live.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5259/5532944943_f725cf95d3_m.jpg"
          width="20%" align="right"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Althogh the release is considered a very good one by many <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/In_the_press">press and user reviews</ulink>, I had some small
      problems after upgrading to it and want to share with you how I solved those: (...)</para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://anditosan.blogspot.com/2011/03/opensuse-release-party-provo-ut.html">Andres Silva: openSUSE Release Party - Provo, UT</ulink></title>
    <para>The openSUSE release party was a lot of fun and I was very happy to be there one more
      time. The Novell facility in Provo, UT is pretty big and had plenty of room to accommodate the
      few of us that attended. I met a few personalities as well, most of them participants of the
      SLED version of openSUSE sponsored by Novell. I also had the chance to talk to some of the
      guys there about what they did as part of the project and felt like my contributions to the
      project seem to be so much smaller than theirs. People working for XEN, the package manager,
      Yast and others have put a lot of effort into making openSUSE a great distribution. </para>
    <para>I am happy for their achievement and their contribution as well. openSUSE would not be my
      favorite distribution if it wasn't for much of the work that these people do. So a big THANK
      YOU to all of them. They also had pizza, a few goodies and 2 big screens. That did it for me.
      I was happy to see openSUSE handling big screens like that. Although with gnome 3 and the
      resolution, there were some glitches. </para>
    <para>Anyway, I promised some pics and here they are. They are not the greatest quality, I used
      my Palm Pre to take the shots and the lighting was not that great for this tiny phone.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">CC-BY-SA</ulink></para>
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
