<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
<!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->  <important>
    <para>The Articles inside this Section are in full. If you are already knowing the stuff in
      news.opensuse.org, then you can skip this section through using the TOC.</para>
  </important>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/07/22/a-new-milestone-on-the-cloud-opensuse-releases-milestone-3/"
        >A new milestone on the cloud: openSUSE releases milestone 3</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>Just a few days ago the third of six milestones on the road ftoopenSUSE 12.1 has been
        made <ulink url="http://software.opensuse.org/developer/en">available</ulink> for testing
      before it goes to final release November 11th, 2011.  (Yes, 11-11-11!)</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Main changes on this milestone</emphasis></para>
    <para>The third milestone has a huge number of changes and improvements on top of the latest
      openSUSE release. And many packages have been updated or upgraded. You can check the latest
      package versions on <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/index.php?title=openSUSE:Factory_versions&amp;diff=cur&amp;oldid=40501"
        >this page</ulink>. What are the major changes?<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Firefox 5</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>MozillaThunderbird 5.0</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>aaa_base 12.1</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Kernel 3.0 rc7</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Python3   3.2</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Sysstat 10.0.1</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>LibreOffice 3.3.3.1</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Tomboy 1.7.1</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Tracker 0.11.0</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>many smaller updates to KDE and GNOME applications and desktops</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Systemd needs your feedback</emphasis></para>
    <para>The team welcomes help and bugreports as we prepare for the first release of openSUSE to
      use systemd.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Hands on to help out easier than ever!</emphasis></para>
    <para>Your input at this early development stage is a great opportunity to collaborate in making
      the final release into the polished work we always prosecute for. openSUSE 12.1 Milestone 3
      has a <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Most_annoying_bugs_12.1_dev">list of most
        annoying bugs here</ulink>, please add issues you find and help fix them. As Will Stephenson
        has <ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/05/16/have-you-burped-yet-today/">already
        blogged</ulink>, fixing an issue is a matter of<emphasis role="bold">BURP</emphasis>ing
        on <ulink url="http://build.opensuse.org/">build.opensuse.org</ulink>! Find a how-to <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Build_Service_Collaboration#Example_with_web_interface"
        >here</ulink>.</para>
    <para>So go and see for yourself what the next version of openSUSE has in store for you at
        our <ulink url="http://software.opensuse.org/developer">download center</ulink>.</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 22.7.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/07/22/last-call-for-opensuse-conference-papers/"
        >Last Call for openSUSE Conference Papers!</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>With the days closing in on us before the next great openSUSE Conference in Nuremberg,
      Germany 11-14 September, 2011, we’re seeing a lot of awesome papers being submitted to the
      Conference Program Committee.  But there’s still time for you to submit that awesome session
      you’ve dreamed of. The deadline to <ulink
        url="http://conference.opensuse.org/indico//conferenceDisplay.py?confId=2">submit your
        paper</ulink>is <ulink
        url="http://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?day=25&amp;month=7&amp;year=2011&amp;hour=0&amp;min=0&amp;sec=0&amp;p1=0"
        >midnight July 25th</ulink>.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">What We Are Looking For:</emphasis></para>
    <para>This year’s Conference theme is RWX³.  That means its an open conference in which we all
      get to roll up our sleeves and get involved!  We’re looking for that great session that talks
      about FOSS projects, openSUSE Community growth, and  workshops that empower our users and
      contributors to do more awesome stuff.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Types of Sessions you can apply for</emphasis><itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Presentation</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink
              url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/14/opensuse-conference-and-rw-sessions-the-bof/"
              >Birds of a Feather (BoF)</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink
              url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/07/13/opensuse-and-rw-sessions-the-workshop/"
              >Workshops</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Hacksessions</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>As you can see, the possibilities are endless.  And this year’s conference, which is
      always free, is extra special because we’ll be moving to our new location, Zentrifuge, and
      co-hosting with the SUSE Labs Conerence.  That’s two for the price of one and one is
      FREE!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">What’s Next</emphasis><itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Submit your proposal <ulink
              url="http://conference.opensuse.org/indico//conferenceDisplay.py?confId=2"
              >here</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>The Program Committee will be reviewing all submissions and making their votes
            before August 1.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>After August 5, we will announce the accepted proposals and contact you with the
            status of your proposal.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>Remember, the deadline is this <emphasis role="bold">Sunday, July 24th</emphasis>!</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 23.7.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/07/14/opensuse-conference-registration-open/"
        >openSUSE Conference registration open!</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>The organization team is excited to announce the registration for the openSUSE Conference,
      from September 11 to 14 in Nürnberg, is now open. Head over to cur registration form and
      register to help us plan for a great event.</para>
    <para>It is time to start preparing your trip to Nuremberg!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Preparations</emphasis></para>
    <para>Two months from now the openSUSE and SUSE Labs Conference will kick off in Nuremberg,
      Germany. That means, as flights don’t get cheaper, you have to start planning! Ask your boss
      for some days off, start telling your professor you won’t be there from September 11-14. Start
      looking for a reasonable flight or train fare, <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Conference_hotels">book a hotel</ulink>and then you’re
      ready to <ulink
        url="http://conference.opensuse.org/indico/confRegistrationFormDisplay.py?confId=2">register
        for the conference</ulink>. Of course, be sure you have <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/07/14/opensuse-conference-registration-open/news.opensuse.org/2011/05/16/opensuse-conference-2011-to-be-creative-and-open/"
        >submitted a session</ulink> if you want to give a talk, organize a BoF (team meeting), lead
      a hack session or give a workshop.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Hotel</emphasis></para>
    <para>The openSUSE conference team has made <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Conference_hotels">a list of hotels</ulink> where you
      can book your stay for the duration of the conference. It is recommended to use these hotels
      as they will not only have fellow geekos in them but are also reasonably priced (special
      conference prices!) and not too far from our location, <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Conference_Location_Zentrifuge"
      >Zentrifuge</ulink>.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Travel Support</emphasis></para>
    <para>For some of you, the trip to Nuremberg is financially not easy. You might be a student, or
      have to fly in all the way from India. We know that very well and it is the main reason why
        we <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/08/opensuse-conference-looking-for-sponsors/">are
        looking very hard for sponsors</ulink>! Within a week, you can count on an announcement of
      the what and how of travel subsidy, but rest assured that we will do everything we can to
      ensure our community members from far away or on low budget are also able to come and join
      us!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Visa</emphasis></para>
    <para>Another important thing to think of in time is access to Europe/Germany. We have a
      standard invitation letter you can get from us on request. For that, send a mail with some
      personal details (who you are, what you do for openSUSE, what you will do at the conf, that
      stuff) to <ulink url="mailto:opensuse-conference@opensuse.org"
        >opensuse-conference@opensuse.org</ulink> and the team will send you one.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Registration</emphasis></para>
    <para>Registering makes sure there’s a badge for you at the conference, you won’t have to wait
      in line for us to create one for you on the spot. It’ll also make sure you are able to go on
      the wifi and we have a place for you at the party. And of course it allows us to plan better
      so it matters a lot that you register as soon as possible if you intend to come!</para>
    <para>Please note that for the registration, you don’t have to create an account. And you will
      have to book a hotel yourself, see <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Conference_hotels">this page</ulink>!</para>
    <para>Last but not least, there is an option between <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Professional_conf_ticket">two different
      tickets</ulink>. Entrance is free for all but those who want to support the conference and can
      afford it can buy a professional ticket. For $350 or €250 you get, besides access to the
      conference, a networking dinner with the speakers and other professional ticket holders as
      well as a session with SUSE Product Management.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Helping out</emphasis></para>
    <para>Meanwhile, the conference team is welcomes all the help it can get! If you want to get
      involved and help us make the openSUSE conference the best ever, please subscribe to the team
          mailinglist: <email><ulink url="mailto:opensuse-conference+subscribe@opensuse.org"
          >opensuse-conference@opensuse.org</ulink></email> and checkout the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Conference_Planning_2011">planning page</ulink>.</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 15.7.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
</sect1>
