<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="forums">
  <title>openSUSE Forums: an overview of functionality</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/content/">Articles</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>
      The title covers it. We already had our FAQ, New User HOWTO FAQ and some other subforums with limited posting access for members, to collect and present general information on openSUSE installation and usage, graphic card drivers etc. Now we have the option to promote these to Article. Check it out, the first ones are there, categorized and all.
    </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/forum.php">Forum</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>
      This is the former landing page of http://forums.opensuse.org. An overview of the international forums, and the language specific subforums -we currently serve Nederlands (Dutch), Français (French), Deutsch (German), Ελληνικό (Greek), Magyar (Hungarian), 日本語 (Japanese), Portuguese (Portuguese), Pусский (Russian) under the big openSUSE Forums umbrella, plus links to the עִברִית (Hebrew) and Español (Spanish) ones. Other languages are under contstruction, awaiting setup etc.
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/blogs/">Blogs</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>
      Another new piece of functionality is the Blogs section. A couple of entries have already been made, the Forums Team is still discussing to whom it will be open to post. Team member @malcolmlewis is presenting a package-of-the-day as a structural entry. others are still searching for a good modus to post in a blog style. 
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
    <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/search.php?do=getnew&contenttype=vBForum_Post">New</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>
      This one was already there before the new items. It gives the regular visitor a list of recent threads and posts, from the international as well as the language specific subforums. A very nice tool, for those members who want to help out.

Remember: any issue, problem you may meet using openSUSE has probably hit others too. Always check the forums to see if a solution for the issue, problem, is not already available. Enjoy the forums like you enjoy your distro
      </para>
<!-- ($ ld: 09.06.2011 gl $) -->  </blockquote>
</sect1>
