<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/02/16/open-bugs-day-on-sunday-the-20th-of-february/"
        >Open-Bugs-Day on Sunday the 20th of February</ulink></title>
    <para>As you all know, we’re closing in on the Final Release of openSUSE 11.4…</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://countdown.opensuse.org/11.4/small.en.png"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>and so in this last window for bug-fixing we need your help! The <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Testing_meeting">testing team</ulink> is looking for
      volunteers to help with bugs in <ulink url="http://bugzilla.novell.com/">bugzilla</ulink> on
      the Open-Bugs-Day at Sunday the 20th of February. Participants are going through the bugs that
      currently exist for 11.4 in bugzilla, close what is fixed and confirm what still needs some
      work. It’s all part of a final push for a great 11.4 release, with us clearing out what is
      fixed, the developers can focus their energies on fixing bugs instead of clicking around in
      bugzilla! We will meet, hang out and coordinate during the Open-Bugs-Day in the IRC channel
        <ulink url="irc://irc.freenode.net/opensuse-testing">#opensuse-testing</ulink> on the <ulink
        url="http://freenode.net/">Freenode</ulink> network and anyone using openSUSE is welcome to
      help. Read on to learn more about how you can make a difference.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">How to participate </emphasis></para>
    <para>You only need the following to participate: <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>An installation of openSUSE 11.4 RC1 or openSUSE Factory so you can verify things.
            It’s of course okay to run it in a virtual machine</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>An IRC client to interact with the other participants</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Good mood :-)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>If you don’t know how to triage bugs the organizers will give you a list of bugs that you
      can work on and you can double-check with other participants that your changes are okay. If
      you do know how to triage bugs you can of course just go ahead and do it!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Workflow</emphasis></para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/t-shirt1-e1297864943503-300x300.png"
        />
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>The workflow is as follows <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Search bugzilla for open bugs in obsolete releases (<ulink
              url="http://bit.ly/gflb6r">11.4-MS1-5</ulink> or <ulink url="http://bit.ly/hebmX1"
              >11.4-Factory</ulink>)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Try to reproduce the issue on the 11.4 RC1<orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>If the issue still occurs, update the bug to current version</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>If you know the issue was fixed, set the bug to RESOLVED+FIXED</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>If you have the feeling that the issue is fixed, set the bug to
                  RESOLVED+NORESPONSE</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Go to 1</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">No pain without gain!</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>The ten most active contributors that help us to clean up bugzilla and make openSUSE 11.4
      a big success will receive a nice thank you package with an openSUSE t-shirt and other
      goodies.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 17.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
