<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1>
  <title>openSUSE Conference 2011</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/09/05/sponsors-present-at-opensuse-conference-2011/">Jos
        Poortvlieet: Sponsors present at openSUSE Conference 2011</ulink></title>
    <para>The <ulink url="http://conference.opensuse.org">openSUSE Conference 2011</ulink> team is
      happy to announce the partners for this year’s conference. Aside from sponsoring, there are
      contributions in terms of sessions, media coverage and network bandwidth. Let’s look at what
      our sponsors contribute, what sessions they’ll present and thank them for their support!
      (...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 6.09.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://blog.jospoortvliet.com/2011/09/bretzn-at-osc.html">Jos Poortvlieet:
        Bretzn at oSC </ulink></title>
    <para>So there is the <ulink url="http://www.socialdesktop.org/bretzn/">cool Bretzn
        project</ulink> which was about creating a plugin for IDE's to compile and publish code via
      the <ulink url="http://openbuildservice.org">Open Build Service</ulink> and the <ulink
        url="http://www.freedesktop.org/wiki/Specifications/open-collaboration-services">Open
        Collaboration Services</ulink> and then letting the user install, rate and comment on apps
      via a desktop client. (...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 06.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://oyranos-cms.blogspot.com/2011/09/oyranos-rwx.html">Kai-Uwe Behrmann:
        Oyranos @ rwx³</ulink></title>
    <para>We will meet there and can discuss ICC colour management for the openSUSE distribution,
      KDE and Qt. </para>
    <para>Sebastian Oliva will be there too. I hope we can hack together a Oyranos connection to his
      newly created ICC DB. The ICC DB project, done during GSoC 2011, shall be used to search for
      ICC profiles by terms of colour device configurations. This means a printer can obtain a
      fitting ICC profile for a special driver without the need to have all the canned profiles
      packaged. Independent vendors can easily upload their ICC data and get their optimised profile
      selected automatically - if all works. Sebastian and Joseph Simon have done fair bits to get
      there in a clean way, without hacking the whole system. (...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 06.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
