<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 id="distro" role="distro">
  <title>openSUSE 12.1: All Green!</title>
  <abstract>
    <para>This Special Corner is about Postings about openSUSE 12.1 into the Community and the
      Press.</para>
  </abstract>
  <sect2 id="distro-community" role="distro-community">
    <title>Community Articles</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://sellingfreesoftwareforaliving.blogspot.com/2011/11/opensuse-121-gets-positive-review-on.html">Han Wen Kam: openSUSE 12.1 gets positive review on LAS</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Nice and positive review of openSUSE 12.1 on the Linux Action Show on 20th Nov 2011. The
        YouTube video is embedded below... you may fast-forward to 30:10 where they finally got down
        to the review of openSUSE 12.1. </para>
      <para>Most interesting (the best) comment on that YouTube page was from Jos Poortvliet (our
        openSUSE Community Manager), &quot;VERY nice review guys! Fun to see how opinions on openSUSE﻿
        have changed in the last year - from &apos;meh, yeah, is that distro still alive?&apos; to the
        awesomeness now :D If you ever wanna talk about it with me - I&apos;d be happy to be on the
        show...&quot; </para>
      <para>As with most things in life, its all about perception and goodwill. openSUSE 12.1 is
        polished and enjoyable but a number of the great features mentioned, including <ulink url="http://susestudio.com/">SUSE Studio</ulink> and <ulink url="https://build.opensuse.org/">openSUSE Build Service</ulink>, have been around for a
        while... anyway, I&apos;m just happy &amp; enjoying the goodwill towards openSUSE. :)</para>
<!--($ ld: 26.11.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2 id="distro-press" role="distro-press">
    <title>In the Press</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://desktoplinuxreviews.com/2011/11/26/opensuse-12-1-kde/">Desktop Linux Reviews/Jim Lynch: openSUSE 12.1 KDE</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>openSUSE is one of the most popular desktop distros available. This time around it’s version 12.1 that has been released. If you aren’t familiar with openSUSE then you should know that it comes in KDE, GNOME, Xfce and LXDE versions. For this review I’ve picked the KDE version of openSUSE 12.1. I may do a quick look at the GNOME version on <ulink url="http://eyeonlinux.com/">Eye On Linux</ulink> later though.</para>
      <para>Speaking of the GNOME version of openSUSE 12.1, I took a quick peek at it to see if the openSUSE had made any significant changes to the dreadful GNOME 3 desktop. Unfortunately, they didn’t though they should have. The Linux Mint developers did a good job on altering the GNOME 3.2 desktop to make it usable; I had hoped the openSUSE developers would do the same. Alas, perhaps they will in the next release. The lack of GNOME 3 tweaks is one of the reasons why I decided to review the KDE version instead.</para>
      <para>Okay, enough babble about GNOME. Let’s get on with this review of openSUSE 12.1 KDE. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 01.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://dasublogbyprashanth.blogspot.com/2011/11/review-opensuse-121-gnome-kde.html">Das U-Blog/Prashanth: Review: openSUSE 12.1 GNOME + KDE</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>It&apos;s November again, so what does that mean? It means there&apos;s another new release of openSUSE, and I&apos;m reviewing it.</para>
      <para>openSUSE doesn&apos;t really need much of an introduction here. There are a few new things with this release, though. The first is that GNOME 3 has become an official part of openSUSE; this is not surprising considering that openSUSE and Fedora were the only distributions who provided vanilla live CD previews of GNOME 3 before its official release. The second is that the release numbering and schedule have changed. Now, there will be releases in November, July, and March, and they will respectively have decimal numbers &quot;.1&quot;, &quot;.2&quot;, and &quot;.3&quot; before the number before the decimal point gets incremented by one with the next November release. This means that there will be no more &quot;.0&quot; or &quot;.4&quot; releases, and that the jump from, for example, version 13.1 to 13.2 will be just as significant as the jump from version 12.3 to 13.1. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 01.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.mylinuxrig.com/post/13403783266/a-review-of-gnome-3-and-opensuse-12-1">My Linux Rig: A Review of GNOME 3 and OpenSUSE 12.1</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>I was curious to try out OpenSUSE 12.1 not just because the buzz on it is that it’s a great release, but also because it presented a chance to kick the tires on GNOME 3, which I still hadn’t worked with.</para>
      <para>I tested it on my ThinkPad T43 (on the actual machine and not in a virtual one) and it installed with no problems. Everything worked perfectly out of the box (as a side note, <ulink url="http://www.tuxradar.com/content/podcast-season-3-episode-22">on a recent edition of the Tux Radar podcast</ulink>, host Jonathan Roberts credited improvements in the Linux kernel in making non-Ubuntu distributions competitive hardware-wise; where Ubuntu found early success getting hardware to work, now the kernel itself seems to handle a lot of that heavy lifting for distributions).</para>
      <para>OpenSUSE with GNOME 3 looked great. Everything worked. Everything felt fast, even on an older machine with 2GB RAM. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 01.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.muktware.com/articles/3036">Muktware/Swapnil Bhartiya: OpenSUSE KDE 12.1 Review: I Take My Words Back</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>openSUSE 12.1 is the best openSUSE ever as far as I can tell -- whether it be Gnome 3 or KDE. Interestingly, openSUSE is the major contributor to the Gnome project, yet its KDE implementation is considered to be the finest integrations.</para>
      <para>Being an Ubuntu user (and apt-get fan), I never flirted with openSUSE much. I did try it every time a new version comes out, but from a home user&apos;s point of view it was more work than Ubuntu and the pay off wasn&apos;t that much so I stayed away from it.  But everything has changed with version 12.1. It is much more stable (compared to Ubuntu 11.10) and useful for me.</para>
      <para>I love Gnome 3 (thanks to the shell-extensions), yet I needed something for those who are not comfortable with Gnome 3 Shell and want a windows like environment.  KDE always fascinated me and I thought of giving KDE a try on openSUSE.</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 01.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
