<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/05/14/atiamd-fglrx-8-850-catalyst-11-5-available-for-opensuse-11-2-11-3-11-4-factory/"
        >Bruno Friedmann: ATI/AMD fglrx 8.850 Catalyst 11.5 available for openSUSE 11.2, 11.3, 11.4,
        Factory</ulink></title>
    <para>Please refer to my <ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/?p=6680">previous
        article</ulink> where all the installation procedure is explained. </para>
    <para>At least after a wrong 11.4 version, and a first buggy 11.5 catalyst version, the new one
      is finally build and ready to install from the repo. Like for 11.3 I’ve clean up all previous
      version which are not xpic, so everybody can easily know which drivers he has to install. I’ve
      resigned all rpm with my key. And the tests made show them working. </para>
    <para>Warning </para>
    <para>Some instabilities have been reported. In case of crash like no keyboard, mouse, and
      blackscreen on reboot. Try to shutdown properly your computer with the shutdown poweroff
      button. On reboot, just add 3 at the end of grub line to restart in console mode. Then with
      yast or zypper you can always try the previous version. </para>
    <para>All credits to Sebastian Siebert (freespacer) : <ulink url="http://bit.ly/l6Ddyc">11.5
        article</ulink> (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 16.5.11 sm $)-->    
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://people.gnome.org/~michael/blog/2011-05-09-libreoffice-fud.html"
        >Michael Meeks: LibreOffice is the future of Free Software Office suites</ulink></title>
    <para>This is of course my view, and I hope yours, but naturally it is worth presenting at least
      some rational and working for this conclusion. Unfortunately, there are <emphasis role="bold"
        >so</emphasis> many reasons why TDF and LibreOffice are done right, that I can't list them
      all in linear time. However, I'll try to address some of the major ones recently raised by
      congenital worriers. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">LibreOffice is vendor neutral</emphasis></para>
    <para>LibreOffice does not belong to any single vendor, neither is it a single vendor's product.
      To characterise it that way is just silly. We have full-time developers from Novell, RedHat,
      Canonical and Lanedo working currently, with many key volunteer contributors, and
      contributions from other companies and distributions eg. CodeThink's Unity integration work,
      or the many Google Summer of Code students we've enjoyed working with. No-one is excluded from
      our governance - oh, except over-dominant corporations, there are strict limits in our <ulink
        url="http://wiki.documentfoundation.org/CommunityBylaws">bylaws</ulink> on the proportion of
      representation (one third) that any single company can have in any of our key institutions.
      Elections will be by a fair method (Single Transferable Vote), and be participated in by all
      significant contributors equally. The contrast with the mess of ridiculously gerrymandered
      governance, with layers of stacked privilege given to a single corporation in a previous
      project is quite stark. </para>
    <para>SUSE is the largest corporate contributor to TDF, though we are small compared to our huge
      group of motivated volunteers. My aim is to ensure that no vendor dominates (including SUSE):
      and that there is room for all contributors. Looking at our structures: the Steering
      Committee, Membership Committee, and the Engineering Steering Committee, we seem to be doing
      well there. </para>
    <para>Of course, having vendor neutrality around open standards is also good, but this is
      someone else's fight. I'm interested in the best result Free Software implementation possible,
      with a fun community to stand behind it, rather than the different good of enabling
      competition between implementations. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 10.5.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
