<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://vavai.net/2011/11/suse-linux-enterprise-server-11-sp1-minimal-server-appliance/"
        >Masim Sugianto: SUSE Linux Enterprise Server 11 SP1 Minimal Server
      Appliance</ulink></title>
    <para>I’m currently working as an IT system integrator on a <ulink
        url="http://www.excellent.co.id">small company</ulink> based on Bekasi, a small town near
      Jakarta Indonesia. The company founded by me and my young brother and covering on various jobs
      regarding server setting, implementation, maintenance and workshop/training.</para>
    <para>At first, installing server is an interesting jobs but after similar works on some client,
      I feel bored with the process, ie :<orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Virtualization Server (VMWare, KVM, OpenVZ, Xen, etc) Installation</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Server OS installation</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Application Installation</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Customizing the configuration</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist></para>
    <para>I think I could reduce the time for processing the above task by making an appliance using
      SUSE Studio. An appliance will contains my default server setup and all of packages required
      by application. The results are <ulink
        url="http://susestudio.com/a/veav1Y/minimal-server-appliance"><emphasis role="bold">Minimal
          Server Appliance</emphasis></ulink>. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 3.12.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://kohei.us/2011/11/30/performance-improvement-in-opening-ods/">Kohei Yoshida:
        Performance improvement in opening ODS documents</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>I have great news to share with you. Calc’s ODS import filter in 3.5 should be
      substantially faster when you have documents with a large number of named ranges. Read on if
      you want to know more details.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">What happened?</emphasis></para>
    <para>Laurent Godard, Markus Mohrhard, and myself have been working pretty hard in the past
      month to bring the performance of ODS import filter to a reasonable level, especially with
      documents containing a large number of named ranges.Here is the background. Laurent uses
      LibreOffice as a platform for his professional extension, which makes heavy use of named
      ranges. It programmatically generates ODS documents and inserts hundred’s or thousand’s of
      named ranges as intermediary storage to further process the data. The problem was, however,
      our import performance with that kind of documents was so suboptimal that this process was
      taking a prohibitively long time. In order for his extension to perform optimally, our ODS
      import filter needed to be optimized, and optimized heavily. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 03.12.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://e-tote-kala.blogspot.com/2011/12/dot-in-map.html">Kostas Koudaras: A dot in
        the map</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>I don't ever remembering suggesting a site but to be honest I rarely fall into sites that
      not many people know and worth mentioning, also most of the times I do, I am a bit bored on
      blog about it so I eventually never do ;-) Today though it's different, I am taking a break
      from a presentation it was supposed to be ready...Well...Yesterday, but I am still looking for
      the right kittens photos to complete this presentation(...don't ask...). Anyway normally I
      would just watch a movie or something but I am a bit in a mood to blog and latelly I had too
      much on my plate and had no time to do it, so here I am. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 03.12.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
</sect1>
