<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 id="distro" role="distro">
  <title>openSUSE 12.1: All Green!</title>
  <abstract>
    <para>This Special Corner is about Postings about openSUSE 12.1 into the Community and the
      Press.</para>
  </abstract>
  <sect2 id="distro-community" role="distro-community">
    <title>Community Articles</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://sellingfreesoftwareforaliving.blogspot.com/2011/11/opensuse-121-gets-positive-review-on.html"
          >Han Wen Kam: openSUSE 12.1 gets positive review on LAS</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Nice and positive review of openSUSE 12.1 on the Linux Action Show on 20th Nov 2011. The
        YouTube video is embedded below... you may fast-forward to 30:10 where they finally got down
        to the review of openSUSE 12.1. </para>
      <para>Most interesting (the best) comment on that YouTube page was from Jos Poortvliet (our
        openSUSE Community Manager), "VERY nice review guys! Fun to see how opinions on openSUSE﻿
        have changed in the last year - from 'meh, yeah, is that distro still alive?' to the
        awesomeness now :D If you ever wanna talk about it with me - I'd be happy to be on the
        show..." </para>
      <para>As with most things in life, its all about perception and goodwill. openSUSE 12.1 is
        polished and enjoyable but a number of the great features mentioned, including <ulink
          url="http://susestudio.com/">SUSE Studio</ulink> and <ulink
          url="https://build.opensuse.org/">openSUSE Build Service</ulink>, have been around for a
        while... anyway, I'm just happy &amp; enjoying the goodwill towards openSUSE. :)</para>
      <!--($ ld: 26.11.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2 id="distro-press" role="distro-press">
    <title>In the Press</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.pcworld.com/businesscenter/article/244005/try_opensuse_linux_121_for_stability_and_flexibility.html"
          >PCWorld/Katherine Noyes: Try OpenSUSE Linux 12.1 for Stability and Flexibility</ulink>
      </title>
      <para id="first_paragraph">Major updates have been coming fast and furious in the world of
        Linux distributions this fall, and this week is no exception. Now joining the ranks of
          <ulink
          url="http://www.pcworld.com/businesscenter/article/241831/ubuntu_1110_oneiric_ocelot_bounds_onto_stage.html"
          >Ubuntu 11.10</ulink>, <ulink
          url="http://www.pcworld.com/businesscenter/article/243189/six_good_reasons_to_try_fedora_16.html"
          >Fedora 16</ulink> and many others is OpenSUSE 12.1, which on Wednesday made its
        debut.</para>
      <para>OpenSUSE is currently the fourth most popular <ulink
          url="http://www.pcworld.com/businesscenter/article/204767/a_guide_to_todays_top_10_linux_distributions.html"
          >Linux distribution</ulink> on DistroWatch, behind just <ulink
          url="http://www.pcworld.com/businesscenter/article/243793/get_an_early_taste_of_linux_mint_12.html"
          >Mint</ulink>, Ubuntu and Fedora. I last wrote about OpenSUSE back in March, shortly after
        its last major version, 11.4, arrived on the scene. As I <ulink
          url="http://www.pcworld.com/businesscenter/article/222065/5_reasons_to_try_opensuse_114.html"
          >noted then</ulink>, the free and open-source operating system offers a lot of compelling
        features to explain its popularity, including stability, power and ease of use.</para>
      <para>With this new release, however, OpenSUSE brings even more to the table -- not to mention
        a new numbering scheme, which is why it's now 12.1. Ready for a look? Here's a small
        sampling of what OpenSUSE 12.1 has to offer. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 22.11.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.howtoforge.com/the-perfect-desktop-opensuse-12.1-gnome"
          >Howrtoforge/Falko Thimme: The Perfect Desktop - OpenSUSE 12.1 (GNOME)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>This tutorial shows how you can set up an <ulink url="http://www.opensuse.org/">OpenSUSE
          12.1</ulink> desktop that is a full-fledged replacement for a Windows desktop, i.e. that
        has all the software that people need to do the things they do on their Windows desktops.
        The advantages are clear: you get a secure system without DRM restrictions that works even
        on old hardware, and the best thing is: all software comes free of charge.</para>
      <para>I want to say first that this is not the only way of setting up such a system. There are
        many ways of achieving this goal but this is the way I take. I do not issue any guarantee
        that this will work for you! (...)</para>
      <!--($ ld: 23.11.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.linuxuser.co.uk/reviews/opensuse-12-1-review-new-heights-of-high-tech/"
          >Linux User &amp; Developer/Koen Vervloesem: openSUSE 12.1 review – new heights of high
          tech </ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">We were never really excited about openSUSE, but 12.1 is well
          positioned to change this: it adds some state-of-the-art technology to the highly polished
          desktop openSUSE is known for… </emphasis></para>
      <para>OpenSUSE 12.1, you say? Did we miss 12.0 then? No, this is the first release in the
        distribution’s slightly altered release numbering: from now on openSUSE will not have a .0
        release but only .1, .2 and .3 releases. Because the distribution is following an
        eight-month release cycle, from now on the November release will always be the .1 release,
        the July release the .2 and the March release the .3. (...)</para>
      <!--($ ld: 23.11.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
