<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.oyranos.org/2011/11/colour-management-in-opensuse-12-1/">Kai-Uwe
        Behrmann: Colour Management in openSUSE-12.1</ulink></title>
    <para>The <ulink url="http://www.oyranos.org/">Oyranos Colour Management System</ulink> will be
      in the upcoming <ulink url="http://www.opensuse.org/">openSUSE</ulink>-12.1 release. With the
      new library users can configure their ICC profiles and settings in one central place. It
      brings as well a set of command line tools like <emphasis role="italic"
        >oyranos-policy</emphasis> for handling policy configuration files and <emphasis
        role="italic">oyranos-profiles</emphasis> for installation of ICC profiles. KDE users can
      install the <emphasis role="italic">KolorManager</emphasis> package. This Oyranos front end
      adds a system settings control panel for individual settings adaption. But most systems will
      run fine with Oyranos defaults. (...)</para>
    <para><inlinegraphic fileref="http://www.oyranos.org/images/KolorManager-oS12.1_arrow.png"
        width="40%"/></para>
    <!--($ ld: 10.11.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://jaegerandi.blogspot.com/2011/11/opensuse-121-on-road-to-goldmaster-and.html"
        >Andreas Jaeger: openSUSE 12.1 on the road to Goldmaster - and one bug more
      fixed</ulink></title>
    <para>Several people have reported in the past that during installation the system hangs
      "forever" (see bug bnc#722858) starting udev. The problem was that this did not appear
      reproduceable. It appeared once on my machine and when I brought the machine to Steffen to
      help debugging, I couldn't reproduce it. After some more tries, it was reproduceable but not
      everytime. Steffen initially thought it was a kernel race with module loading and thus we
      added "maxcpus=1" to the kernel command line. This made the bug less likely but it still
      happened. But now Christian, Coolo and myself had each a machine for reproduction and figured
      out that udevadm was waiting for some events and timing out after 10 minutes as that was the
      timeout in the installation system. So, one idea was to use the normal 30s as timeout so that
      fewer people noticed. In the end Coolo found the culprit: A bug in udev that got fixed in
      upstream udev a month ago that we got with a udev update a couple of months ago. Coolo fixed
      this with a new udev package that has been updated for 12.1 now. So, these hangs might have
      not only happened during installation but also at normal booting and I'm glad that Coolo
      decided to hunt down this bug. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 10.11.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://blog.jospoortvliet.com/2011/11/121-closing-in.html">Jos Poortvliet:
        12.1 closing in!</ulink></title>
    <para>We're about to put the finishing touches on openSUSE 12.1 and the amount of activity in
      the <ulink url="http://blog.jospoortvliet.com/2011/11/en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:IRC_list"
        >openSUSE IRC channels</ulink> is impressive. I see people working 12-14-16 hours a day,
      fixing the last issues, writing release notes, and in short getting this release ready for our
      users. Respect! I myself have upgraded my laptop to openSUSE 12.1 RC2 now and I got to see the
      new Plasma Desktop. Overall, the difference between Tumbleweed and 12.1 are minimal. As
      expected, considering <ulink url="http://opensuse.org/Tumbleweed">Tumbleweed</ulink>
      (openSUSE's cool rolling release repository) was a hair away from 12.1, the biggest
      differences are probably artwork and of course Plasma 4.7 instead of 4.6...</para>
    <!--($ ld: 10.11.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
