<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <important>
    <para>The Articles inside this Section are in full. If you are already knowing the stuff in
      news.opensuse.org, then you can skip this section through using the TOC.</para>
  </important>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/08/01/volunteers-needed-conference/">Volunteers
        needed for the conference</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>As you know, the third international <ulink url="http://conference.opensuse.org/">openSUSE
        Conference</ulink> is happening in a couple of weeks from now, you already should be <ulink
        url="http://conference.opensuse.org/indico//confRegistrationFormDisplay.py/display?confId=2"
        >registered</ulink>! For the organization team this means that we are really picking up pace
      now and start to feel dizzy. One of the reasons for that is that we are short on helping
      hands. We especially miss <emphasis role="italic">“boots on the ground</emphasis>“, <emphasis
        role="bold">we need your help!</emphasis></para>
    <para>Being a boot on the ground means we need people to help us at the conference in September.
      There is no special knowledge about the location or other details needed. So far we have 5
      tasks where we desperately need people to help out. Venue setup, Registration Desk, Session
      Chairs and the Snack Bar. Read on to learn how you can contribute to the success of the
      conference.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold"><ulink
          url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Conference_volunteers#Venue_Setup">Venue
          Setup</ulink></emphasis></para>
    <para>The Zentrifuge is not an event location in the classical sense so we have to do a lot of
      setup tasks the days before the conference starts. For instance we need to make sure that the
      seminar rooms have enough chairs, multisockets and a working projector. We also need to setup
      the lounge with sofas, equip the Beergarden with tables, distribute waste bins and so on and
      so on. Most of this we will need to do on Friday/Saturday before the conference and it’s a lot
      of physical labor. If you can help with this please lets us know on the volunteers page or let
      us know at opensuse-conference@opensuse.org.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold"><ulink url="">The Registration Desk</ulink></emphasis></para>
    <para>At the conference, every morning from 9:00 to 10:30, we will have a registration desk. It
      will handle the registration of new visitors,  distribution of info materials and answering of
      general questions and such. We need two people per day to man this desk during the conference.
      On Sunday, as it’s the first day, it better be three! If you can help with this please lets us
      know on the volunteers page or let us know at opensuse-conference@opensuse.org.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold"><ulink
          url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Conference_volunteers#Session_Chair">Session
          Chair</ulink></emphasis></para>
    <para>We have two floors in the Zentrifuge and both have a main room and some smaller rooms for
      workshops and birds of a feather sessions. For both floors we need two people per day to be a
      chair for the sessions that will take place. Being a chair means that you introduce the next
      presenter, make sure the sessions stick to the schedule and answer all questions speakers
      might have. This task takes a bit of experience as speaker/moderator to make the
      introductions, a wristwatch and, ideally, some technical knowledge with projectors/laptops. If
      you can help with this please lets us know on the volunteers page or drop us a mail
      at opensuse-conference@opensuse.org.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold"><ulink
          url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Conference_volunteers#The_Bar">The Snack
        Bar</ulink></emphasis></para>
    <para>This year we will run our own snack bar at the venue. The organization team has already
      seen to that foods and drinks are available and that we have a fully equipped snack bar
      ready.  Now we need people that help us to man the snack bar to sell, sell, sell. You would
      need to sell snacks and drinks, make sure that we don’t run out and count the moneys! If you
      can help with this please lets us know on the volunteers page or drop us a mail
      atopensuse-conference@opensuse.org.</para>
    <para><ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Conference_volunteers#Evening_Manager_and_Lock_Service"
          ><emphasis role="bold">Evening Manager and Lock Service</emphasis></ulink></para>
    <para>One nice side effect of the Zentrifuge not being a classical event location is that we
      will have very long opening hours. People can continue to collaborate and don’t have to leave
      the place until 23:00. But this also means that we have to have at least one person per day
      that makes sure it doesn’t get to wild and that closes everything in the night. If you can
      help with this please lets us know on the volunteers page or drop us a mail
      at opensuse-conference@opensuse.org.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Other tasks</emphasis></para>
    <para>The team held couple of meetings which resulted in a nice list of stuff to do, like
      organizing hardware for the venue, ordering internet, food and drinks and so on. If you rather
      want to help with this, you’re more than welcome to contribute to the conferences success! A
      good start is to subscribe to our mailing list and participate in our meetings.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Thanks a lot in advance!</emphasis></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 2.8.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/08/01/are-you-ready/">Are you ready for RWX³
        ?</ulink></title>
    <para>Less than 50 days left before the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Conference"
        >3rd openSUSE conference</ulink> starts. A lot of people are working hard for this to be
      another successful gathering. Are you <ulink
        url="http://conference.opensuse.org/indico//confRegistrationFormDisplay.py/display?confId=2"
        >registered</ulink> yet? If you are still undecided, and looking for a reason why you should
      come, let me tell you this:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>You will miss many interesting talks, you’ve heard the little birds sing that kernel
            star Greg KH will keynote at oSC…</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>More awesome keynote speakers and sessions are going to be announced in the next
            week or so, STAY TUNED!</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>You will miss one of the greatest FOSS events in the world.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>You will miss a chance to meet other fellow Lizards from all over the world in
            person.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>You will miss the chance to meet people from other projects like <ulink
              url="http://www.kde.org/">KDE</ulink>, <ulink url="http://www.gnome.org/"
              >GNOME</ulink> and <ulink url="http://www.libreoffice.org/"
            >LibreOffice</ulink>.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Imagine the interesting talks you will have in the halls of the conference, if you
            won’t come you will miss those too.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>You will miss to visit Nuremberg, one of the most beautiful and historical cities on
            Europe.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>You will miss tons of group-hugs.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>You will lose the chance to kick people that annoy you on IRC and on Mailing
            lists.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>You will miss the chance of drinking lots of openSUSE-branded beers and eating tons
            of Wurst having a good excuse, you will be in Germany after all so it’s your ‘duty’ to
            do that.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>If you want to come, but money is a problem then you can apply for assistance through
        the <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/08/01/2011/07/23/travel-sponsorship-program/"
        >Conference travel sponsorship program</ulink>. People of openSUSE ‘are willing to help you,
      as much as possible.</para>
    <para>The conference will take place in <ulink url="http://www.zentrifuge-nuernberg.de/"
        >Zentrifuge</ulink> which is a very interesting place to be. <ulink
        url="http://www.zentrifuge-nuernberg.de/">Zentrifuge</ulink> has an exhibition and event
      hall on the former grounds of a company called AEG. The hall is used to host art exhibitions
      of local and international artists and workshops. It is managed by a foundation that helps
      network the art world. The people there are very excited about the idea of hosting our
      conference so you can count on having a great time there during the conference.</para>
    <para>Oliver Fecher visited Zentrifuge Venue and took a few shoots of the place that will host
      the Conference. Take a closer look at the photos and imagine you and your favorite FOSS people
      having endless talks there.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 2.8.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/08/04/and-they-keep-rocking%E2%80%A6/">And they
        keep rocking…</ulink></title>
    <para>Over the last few months the openSUSE ambassadors have continued to visit conferences
      around the world. Since our <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/05/06/opensuse-ambassadors-are-rocking-all-over-the-world/"
        >previous report</ulink> beginning of May, several big events have happened and we’ll treat
      you on a report on some of those.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Already covered in blogs</emphasis></para>
    <para>Let’s start with a few quick links to reports which are already online and probably read
      by some of you. There is for example the huge splash Greece ambassadors made at <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/05/27/fosscomm-2011/">Fosscomm 2011</ulink> which took
      place on May 7 and 8 in Greece. With 8 presentations as well as a similar number of lightning
      talks and a workshop on OBS openSUSE ruled the conference. The team co-hosted the GNOME
      community in their booth as well as the Enlightenment project and a few others, showing the
      open and collaborative spirit of openSUSE! Last but not least, they organized a late 11.4
      release party which ended up having Red Hat, Ubuntu, Slackware, FreeBSD and many other
      visitors joining the party!</para>
    <para>The Greek team also organized a <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/20/opensuse-summer-camp-greece-2011/">summer
        camp</ulink> from which you can see pictures in their <ulink
        url="http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=153638841330360">facebook group</ulink>. Rest
      assured we’ll make them work harder after they so clearly spend a lot of time drinking and
      hanging in the sun…</para>
    <para>Most interestingly, the Greek team went to <ulink
        url="http://zoumpis.wordpress.com/2011/05/20/participation-of-opensuse-greek-community-in-xariseto-gr-bazaar-may-14-2011-report/"
        >the Xariseto.gr bazaar</ulink>. In Thanasis’ words: Xariseto is a festival where people
      meet and donate their personal belongings which they don’t use any more. So as a Linux and
      openSUSE community we thought that participating in these kind of festivals is really
      interesting.</para>
    <para>The result was people from 7 to 70 years old learning about openSUSE… The team also went
      to the <ulink
        url="http://opensuseambassadors.blogspot.com/2011/06/report-from-ellak-conference.html"
        >EL/LAK conference in Thessaloniki</ulink>.</para>
    <para>And as was quite visible on <ulink url="http://planet.opensuse.org/">planet
        openSUSE</ulink>, we <ulink url="http://michal.hrusecky.net/2011/05/linuxtag-2011/"
        >had</ulink> <ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/05/16/wine-on-linuxtag-2011/">a
        presence</ulink> <ulink
        url="http://mvidner.blogspot.com/2011/05/linuxtag-2011-pictures.html">at</ulink> <ulink
        url="http://blog.jospoortvliet.com/2011/05/linuxtag-2011.html">LinuxTag</ulink> <ulink
        url="http://www.digitalflow.de/blog/2011/05/linuxtag-2011-in-berlin/">in</ulink> <ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/05/16/opensuse-on-the-linuxtag-2011/"
      >Berlin</ulink>.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">More reports</emphasis></para>
    <para>While not all openSUSE ambassadors have the time to send in event reports, we are always
      happy to read the ones we get. Below a few of them.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Chile, FLISoL</emphasis></para>
    <para>At the end of April, Ricardo Varas Santana attended the FLISoL event in Chile, which has
      about 1000 visitors. He gave a talk titled <emphasis role="italic">“openSUSE, Linux in Green
        and for all”</emphasis>, talking about what openSUSE is, how to get involved as well as what
      technologies we have. About 400 DVD’s were handed out as well!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">USA</emphasis></para>
    <para>Orv Beach participated in the Southwest Computer Conference where he presented openSUSE to
      an eager crowd. He gave out Tuxes and Geeko’s as well as 160 DVD’s and flyers to the visitors,
      mostly members from Computer Clubs around the USA.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Taiwan</emphasis></para>
    <para>Max “Sakana” from Taiwan wrote us three reports in one. First of all, he as well as
      several other openSUSE ambassadors was at GNOME.Asia 2011, where the GNOME 3 LiveDVD’s (based
      on openSUSE) were handed out. Pictures can be found in the<ulink
        url="http://www.flickr.com/groups/opensuse/pool/page2/">openSUSE flickr pool</ulink>. But
      Max and the Taiwan team did more. Max teaches students openSUSE at the <ulink
        url="http://english.mcut.edu.tw/onweb.jsp?webno=3333333330">Ming Chi University of
        Technology</ulink>, where openSUSE is quite popular. Moreover, there were two seminars at
      two different colleges, the <ulink url="http://webov.ltu.edu.tw/Eng_Ltu/">Ling Tung
        University</ulink> and the <ulink url="http://www.nfu.edu.tw/main.php">National Formosa
        University</ulink> about <ulink url="http://susestudio.com/">SUSE Studio</ulink> and Nagios
      with openSUSE. openSUSE DVD’s were handed out and according to Max, openSUSE did very
      well!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Great Britain</emphasis></para>
    <para>Stuart Tanner went to the RedRat Computer Market in Sheffield. He was the only linux
      person in the room and brought a large 42″ FullHD TV to demo it. He tried to lure
      amateur-photographers into Free Software, aweing them with ShowFoto, DigiKam and similar
      tools</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Netherlands</emphasis></para>
    <para>Your humble writer has also done his small share the last months, showing up at a computer
      event in the Netherlands. A team of 4 manned a booth, held 2 presentations, handed out a few
      hundred DVD’s as well as posters and in general showed openSUSE rocks also in NL!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">more work</emphasis></para>
    <para>First of all, the above are just a few of the events we know about. For example, in
      Brazil, openSUSE was present on FISL, the Porto Alegre event with over 8000 visitors. We’re
      eagerly awaiting the event report! More events happened, more will come. But this is not the
      only thing openSUSE ambassadors do!</para>
    <para>Take the incredible Baltasar Ortega who has been covering openSUSE and KDE
        technology <ulink url="http://kdeblog.com/">in his blog</ulink> for years! If you can read
      Spanish, be sure to bookmark his blog. He will point you to<ulink
        url="http://www.kdeblog.com/como-grabar-tu-live-usb-con-imagewriter.html">gems like the
        Studio Imagewriter</ulink> or share <ulink
        url="http://www.kdeblog.com/kde-tutorials-7-y-8-cambiando-las-fuentes-y-uso-basico-de-dolphin.html"
        >wonderful tutorials like these</ulink>. Max wrote an article about <emphasis role="italic"
        >“openSUSE and Hadoop”</emphasis> the May edition of the Hongkong Chinese/Taiwanese <ulink
        url="http://www.linuxpilot.com/issue/102">Linux Pilot Magazine</ulink>.</para>
    <para>And did you notice our Greek team <ulink
        url="http://opensuseambassadors.blogspot.com/2011/07/greek-opensuse-community-translation-of_15.html"
        >translates the awesome Weekly News in Greece</ulink>?</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Value</emphasis></para>
    <para>The work these ambassadors do for openSUSE is incredibly valuable and should not be under
      estimated. Christos Bountalis, working on <ulink
        url="http://cbounta.wordpress.com/2011/05/07/gsoc-2011tool-for-merging-configuration-files/"
        >fillup-ng</ulink> in openSUSE, joined after meeting the Greek openSUSE ambassadors at an
      event, remarking <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/23/people-of-opensuse-christos-bountalis/">in his
        interview</ulink>, when asked why he joined openSUSE: I have found many nice and interesting
      peopleAnd indeed. People are what makes the difference between a good and a great Free
      Software project. And our Ambassadors are often the first people outsiders see!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Thanks!</emphasis></para>
    <para>So we’d like to thank our ambassadors for their awesome work, and invite anyone to <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Ambassadors">join their ranks</ulink>!</para>
    <para>You can also help in other ways. For example, if you are an openSUSE developer or follow
      development closely, add a glimpse of what is coming to the wiki. Or if you know a bit about
      openSUSE, add and improve our talking points! We also can always use artwork, help with
      writing and many other things. Feel free to contact the openSUSE marketing team
      on opensuse-marketing@opensuse.org and offer to help out!</para>
    <!--($ ld: 5.8.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
