<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="tipsandtricks">
  <title>Tips and Tricks</title>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Desktop Users</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="nbprashanth.wordpress.com/2011/10/01/customizing-gnome3/">N.B.Prashanth: Customizing GNOME3</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>GNOME3 and the GNOME Shell are no doubt, major improvements. They bring in usability and
        quite a bit of eye candy (in a different way compared to compiz) while at the same time, a
        few features went missing in 3.0 release – like Emblems, for instance. Nevertheless, GNOME3
        is a great release and has been extremely stable so far (Yes, i have been using it since
        it’s release in April.). </para>
      <para>One major complaint that I hear from people is that GNOME3 is not as easy to customize
        as 2.x. A lot of people seem to think that they are “stuck” with the blue-black theme that
        comes by default. Ofcourse this is not the case. In this post, I ll explain a few ways in
        which we can customize GNOME3 and the GNOME Shell. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 02.10.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://linuxaria.com/recensioni/4-programs-to-update-your-blog-from-linux?lang=en">Linuxaria: 4 programs to update your Blog from Linux</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Sometimes it’s useful to work offline, and once the article it’s finished publish it on your Blog.
yes you can do it with an html editor, or also with a simple text editor like Vi or Emacs, but there are specialized programs that can ease your work of publishing and management of your online Blog.</para>
      <para>So we’ll take a look at Scribefire, BloGTK, Blogilo and Qumana. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 8.10.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Commandline/Script Newbies</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://olex.openlogic.com/wazi/2011/how-to-find-anything-under-linux/">Wazi/Carla Schroder: How to Find Anything Under Linux</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The Linux find, grep, and awk commands are amazing power tools for fine-grained file searches, and for finding things inside files. With them you can find the largest and newest files on a system, fine-tune search parameters, search for text inside files, and perform some slick user management tricks. (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
<!-- ($ Id: 8.10.11 sat $)-->  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Developers and Programmers</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.thegeekstuff.com/2011/10/c-program-to-an-executable/">The Geek Stuff/Himanshu Arora: Journey of a C Program to Linux Executable in 4 Stages</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>You write a C program, use gcc to compile it, and you get an executable. It is pretty simple. Right?</para>
      <para>Have you ever wondered what happens during the compilation process and how the C program gets converted to an executable?</para>
      <para>There are four main stages through which a source code passes in order to finally become an executable. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 8.10.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For System Administrators</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxjournal.com/content/playterm-platform-gurus">IBM Developer Works/Tracy Bost: Learn Linux, 302 (Mixed environments): Internationalization</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>If you work in a mixed environment in which non-English characters are used, you need to
        understand character codes and code pages as they relate to your locale. You also need to
        understand Linux and Windows environments differ when interpreting name spaces. Although
        Samba supports internationalization, if you work with older Windows clients , Samba 2.x
        versions, or otherwise need to use a specific character set other than Unicode, you&apos;ll need
        to do a bit of configuration tuning. Depending upon the environment&apos;s locale in use,
        building and patching conversion libraries may also be necessary. In this article, learn how
        to handle internationalization in your Linux environment. (...)</para>
<!--($ Id: 05.10.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.ibm.com/developerworks/linux/library/l-lpic3-312-5/index.html?ca=drs-">ZDNET/Steven J. Vaughan-Nichols: How to lock down Linux</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Linux is, by design, a very secure operating system, but so what? You can have the best
        security system in the world on your house, but if you leave your front-door open anyone can
        still walk in. Even people who know better, like Linux kernel developers, blow it sometimes.
        That’s what happened to the <ulink url="http://www.linuxfoundation.org">Linux Foundation</ulink>’s constellation of sites. <ulink url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/some-linux-foundation-crack-attack-details-emerge/9535">Multiple important Linux sites were down for weeks</ulink> and as of October 3rd, <ulink url="http://http://kernel.org">kernel.org</ulink> is still down. This doesn’t have to
        happen to you. Here are a few simple suggestions from me, and some more advanced ones from
          <ulink url="http://www.kroah.com/log/">Greg Kroah-Hartman</ulink>, one of Linux’s lead
        developers. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 05.10.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
