<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 id="own" role="own">
  <title>openSUSE 12.1: All Green!</title>
  <abstract>
    <para>This Special Corner is about Postings about openSUSE 12.1 into the Community and the
      Press.</para>
  </abstract>
  <sect2 id="wnhistory" role="wnhistory">
    <title>Community Articles</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/11/16/opensuse-12-1-all-green/">openSUSE 12.1: All Green!</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>It is November 16, 2011 and our mirrors have synced. Time to present to you: openSUSE
        12.1! This release represents more than eight months of work by our international community
        and brings you the best Free Software has to offer. Awesome improvements include the latest
        GNOME 3.2 desktop as well as the newest from KDE, XFCE and LXDE; your ownCloud made easy
        with mirall; Snapper-shots of your file system; and much, much more. (...)</para>
      <para><inlinegraphic fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/12.1_Installer-boot1-300x225.png"/></para>
<!--($ ld: 17.11.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://masterpatricko.blogspot.com/2011/11/opensuse-121-released-spread-word.html">Tejas Guruswamy: openSUSE 12.1 released - spread the word!</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Congratulations to everyone who has worked hard on openSUSE 12.1 for another successful
        release. Can&apos;t wait to get it running.</para>
      <para>In the meantime, spread the word!</para>
      <para>Stories are
        appearing on <ulink url="http://slashdot.org/submission/1851340/opensuse-121-released">Slashdot</ulink> and <ulink url="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=3243673">HackerNews</ulink>. Upvote, comment, discuss! Suggest to the websites and
        magazines you read to run a review. Zonker over at Linux.com has already written an <ulink url="https://www.linux.com/learn/tutorials/510731-opensuse-121-arrives-whats-new-and-what-happened-to-120">intro to 12.1 piece</ulink>. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 17.11.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://mschlander.wordpress.com/2011/11/16/opensuse-12-1-released/">Martin Schlander: openSUSE 12.1 released</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>You can read about all the goodies in the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Product_highlights">product highlights</ulink> and <ulink url="http://software.opensuse.org/">download it</ulink>.</para>
      <para>As always there are some pain points you should be aware of too:<itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>KDEPIM (Kontact, KMail, KOrganizer etc.) of KDE SC 4.7 is now fully ported to
              using Akonadi and you should expect some problems and probably do some testing before
              you upgrade/migrate your production machines.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Touchpad tapping is disabled by default. To enable it, make sure synaptiks is
              installed and go to systemsettings =&gt; Input Devices =&gt; Touchpad and enable
              tapping.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>The new default init system systemd might cause you some grief.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Sun/Oracle Java is no longer included in the distro because of a license change.
              If OpenJDK is not working for you, you’ll have to get Oracle Java from
              Oracle.com.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
<!--($ ld: 17.11.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2 id="wncongrats" role="wncongrats">
    <title>In the Press</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.theregister.co.uk/2011/11/17/opensuse_cloud_virtual/">The Register/Iain Thomson: New openSUSE heads for cloud, virtual markets</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The openSUSE Project has shipped its <ulink url="http://software.opensuse.org/121/en">12.1 build</ulink>, with enhanced cloud and virtualization integration tools. It&apos;s also
        the first distro to ship with support for Google’s Go language.</para>
      <para>From the look of the new build, Attachmate has kept <ulink url="http://www.theregister.co.uk/2010/11/23/attachmate_opensuse_safe/">its promise</ulink> to carry on supporting openSUSE after its <ulink url="http://www.theregister.co.uk/2011/04/28/farewell_novell/">$2.2bn deal to buy Novell</ulink>. The new code, in line with <ulink url="http://www.theregister.co.uk/2011/10/17/opensuse_12_point_1_review/">the beta <emphasis role="italic">El Reg</emphasis> examined last month</ulink>, is built around
        kernel 3.1 and contains the latest software, including Firefox 7, Thunderbird 7, LibreOffice
        3.4.3, and GIMP. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 17.11.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.osnews.com/story/25341/openSUSE_12_1_Released">OSNews/Thom Holwerda: openSUSE 12.1 Released</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>And another popular Linux distribution pushes a new release out the door. This time
        around, it&apos;s openSUSE, as they <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Product_highlights">just released version 12.1</ulink>. Other than the usual latest and greatest version of all the
        open source desktops and associated tools, there&apos;s a few other interesting tidbits in this
        release as well. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 17.11.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/open/news/item/openSUSE-12-1-arrives-with-systemd-and-Btrfs-1380033.html">h-online/Chris von Eitzen: openSUSE 12.1 arrives with systemd and Btrfs</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Following two release candidates and <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/news/item/openSUSE-12-1-running-late-1362984.html">a slight delay</ulink>, the <ulink url="http://www.opensuse.org/en/">openSUSE</ulink> project has
        published version 12.1 of its Linux distribution. The major update to the openSUSE operating
        system introduces a number of platform changes and new features. Based on the <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/What-s-new-in-Linux-3-1-1347364.html">3.1 Linux kernel</ulink>, openSUSE 12.1 offers a choice of the <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/First-Look-GNOME-3-2-1350917.html">GNOME 3.2</ulink> or the <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/news/item/KDE-SC-4-7-released-1286972.html">KDE 4.7</ulink>
        desktop environments and is the first distribution to ship with <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Color_management">colour management</ulink> tools for
        both. Users looking for a minimal, lightweight desktop can alternatively select from either
        Xfce or LXDE desktops which, according to the developers, haven&apos;t seen any major feature
        updates since the last openSUSE release. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 17.11.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.desktoplinux.com/news/NS4968533300.html?kc=rss">DesktopLinux: OpenSUSE 12.1 ships with GNOME 3.2, SystemD, Snapper, Go tools</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The OpenSUSE project released OpenSUSE 12.1, featuring Linux 3.1, GNOME 3.2, KDE 4.7,
        plus support for KDE&apos;s &quot;OwnCloud&quot; cloud platform. OpenSUSE 12.1 introduces the SystemD
        configuration utility and Google&apos;s Go programming language, and integrates a Btrfs-based
        &quot;Snapper&quot; tool for rolling back system updates and configuration changes.The first <ulink url="http://www.desktoplinux.com/news/NS5890234816.html">
          <emphasis role="underline">beta of OpenSUSE 12.1</emphasis>
        </ulink> was released in early October, revealing the
        distro&apos;s switch to GNOME 3.2. The desktop upgrades GNOME 3.0, which shipped as a preview
        version in <ulink url="http://www.desktoplinux.com/news/NS3982709075.html">
          <emphasis role="underline">OpenSUSE 11.4</emphasis>
        </ulink> in March.OpenSUSE 12.1 also supplies
        the long-time GNOME desktop competitor KDE 4.7, as well as Xfce and LXDE. The distro is
        touted for being the &quot;first major Linux distribution&quot; to ship both GNOME and KDE with color
        management tools. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 17.11.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="https://www.linux.com/learn/tutorials/510731-opensuse-121-arrives-whats-new-and-what-happened-to-120">Linux.com/Joe &apos;Zonker&apos; Brockmeier: openSUSE 12.1 Arrives: What&apos;s New and What Happened to 12.0?</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The openSUSE Project has released openSUSE 12.1, eight months after 11.4 and the first release since SUSE officially became a subsidiary of Attachmate. With 12.1, openSUSE brings major improvements to openSUSE tools and users&apos; favorite components like GNOME, KDE, LibreOffice, and DigiKam. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 18.11.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/opensuses-new-linux-distribution-is-for-the-clouds/9908">ZDNet/Steven J. Vaughan-Nichols: OpenSUSE&apos;s new Linux distribution is for the clouds</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>When <ulink url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/novell-deals-done/8755">Novell was bought by Attachmate</ulink>, people <ulink url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/where-novell-suse-linux-goes-from-here/8951">wondered if Novell/SUSE’s community Linux distribution, openSUSE, would even survive</ulink>. Now, we know, <ulink url="http://www.opensuse.org/en">openSUSE</ulink> lives.</para>
      <para>The openSUSE Project has released the <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/11/16/opensuse-12-1-all-green">latest version of its popular Linux distribution openSUSE 12.1</ulink>. In a statement, Jos Poortvliet, openSUSE community manager for <ulink url="http://www.suse.com/">SUSE</ulink>, said, “OpenSUSE 12.1 represents more than eight months of worldwide effort to create one of the industry’s best Linux distributions. The openSUSE distribution and its thousands of open source applications are the result of contributions from individual testers, writers, translators, usability experts, artists, ambassadors, packagers and developers having a lot of fun working together to create a uniquely powerful set of tools and capabilities.”</para>
      <para>So what does that mean? Well, among other things even more so than <ulink url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/ubuntu-linux-heads-to-the-clouds/9722">Ubuntu</ulink>, openSUSE is embracing the cloud. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 18.11.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.networkworld.com/community/blog/new-opensuse-adds-features-for-cloud-servers-desktops">Network World/Julie Bort: OpenSUSE 12.1 bulks up on features for cloud, servers, desktops</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The OpenSUSE project has released its next stable version, a.k.a <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/12.1">OpenSUSE 12.1</ulink>. It includes the Linux kernel 3.1, tons of enhancements for use with public and private clouds and the cool new Tumbleweed tool, a project conceived by SUSE kernel engineer Greg Kroah-Hartman.</para>
      <para>openSUSE includes a feature called &quot;ownCloud,&quot; which is a filesharing alternative to services like DropBox. ownCloud has two downsides: it takes some skills to implement it and it doesn&apos;t keep the files persistently on your computer to access them offline. openSUSE solves that with its new mirall tool which eases deployment of ownCloud and creates a local folder in which it synchronized local and cloud files. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 18.11.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://techcrunch.com/2011/11/16/opensuse-12-1-released/">TechCrunch/Scott Merrill: openSUSE 12.1 Released</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><ulink url="http://www.opensuse.org/en/">openSUSE</ulink>, the community developed Linux distribution sponsored by SUSE, has released version 12.1 today. At first glance, openSUSE 12.1 is pretty much in line with recent releases from Fedora and Ubuntu: GNOME 3.2, <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Systemd">systemd</ulink>, etc. But a closer look starts to reveal some real divergence between the various Linux offerings today. For example, while Fedora 16 allows you to choose <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Btrfs">btrfs</ulink> for your filesystem, openSUSE 12.1 uses btrfs by default. There’s a number of other interesting advancements packed in this release, too. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 18.11.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.serverwatch.com/server-news/opensuse-12.1-gets-snappy-release.html">ServerWatch/Sean Michael Kerner: OpenSUSE 12.1 Gets Snappy Release</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The openSUSE Linux distribution is out with a new release today, providing users with new desktop, cloud and backup features.</para>
      <para>One of the key new features in the openSUSE 12.1 release is the Snapper tool that helps users to take full advantage of the Btrfs filesystem.</para>
      <para>&quot;Btrfs adds the ability to do rollbacks on file changes,&quot; openSUSE Board Chairman, Alan Clark told InternetNews.com. &quot;So if someone accidentally deletes a file, I can use Snapper to rollback and recover that file.&quot; (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 18.11.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.muktware.com/bitsnbytes/2956">Muktware/Neil Richards: openSuse 12.1 Released, Comes With OwnCloud</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The openSuse team has announced the release of version 12.1.  I have been playing with the RC for a while and found it exremely stable. We are working on a review of openSuse 12.1 and will be publishing it soon. Keep an eye on our Google Plus page for the review.</para>
      <para>openSUSE 12.1 comes with the new GNOME Shell 3.2. Notifications are much nicer, you can now configure your online accounts in one place and Shell handles multiple-screen setups better. Among the features is color management, something GNOME shares with KDE where openSUSE is the first to integrate the Oyranos color management system. Also new from KDE is Apper, an easier-to-use PackageKit front end. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 18.11.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxfordevices.com/c/a/News/OpenSUSE-121/">LinuxDevices.com/Eric Brown: OpenSUSE 12.1 ships with GNOME 3.2, SystemD, Snapper, Go tools</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">The OpenSUSE project released version 12.1 of its enterprise-focused Linux distribution, featuring Linux 3.1, GNOME 3.2 and support for KDE&apos;s &quot;OwnCloud&quot; cloud platform. OpenSUSE 12.1 introduces the SystemD configuration utility and Google&apos;s Go programming language, and further integrates the Btrfs file-system with a &quot;Snapper&quot; tool for rolling back system updates and configuration changes.</emphasis></para>
      <para>A bare-bones <ulink url="http://www.linuxfordevices.com/c/a/News/Fedora-16-beta-and-OpenSUSE-121-beta/">beta of OpenSUSE 12.1</ulink> was released in early October, with the primary purpose of giving OpenSUSE developers a chance to get better acquainted with GNOME 3.2. According to the community project -- which is closely backed by <ulink url="http://www.linuxfordevices.com/c/a/News/SUSE-and-Xamarin-announce-broad-Mono-partnership/">Attachmate and its new SUSE</ulink> (formerly Novell) business unit as an upstream contributor to SUSE Linux -- GNOME 3.2 is a major improvement over the controversial GNOME 3.0. (The latter shipped as a preview version in the previous <ulink url="http://www.linuxfordevices.com/c/a/News/OpenSUSE-114/">OpenSUSE 11.4</ulink> release in March.) (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 18.11.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.muktware.com/articles/2962">Muktware/Swapnil Bhartiya: openSuse 12.1 Review: An Elite OS</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>This is the favorite time of the year, it&apos;s like Christmas for a GNU/Linux user. This is the time of the year when most Linux distros release their latest versions. We have already played with Ubuntu 11.10, Fedora 16 and today openSUSE 12.1 arrived. I have been casually using openSUSE 12.1 (RC) for a while and am quite comfortable with it -- a compliment as its coming from a long-time Ubuntu user. If I look at my pattern I have been switching between Ubuntu 11.10, Fedora 16 and openSUSE 12.1 quite a lot recently. My Google + page is full of my experiences with these three OSes.</para>
      <para>I never was an openSUSE user. I completely shifted to Linux at the same time when Novell signed that infamous deal with Microsoft which tried to &apos;validate&apos; Windows maker&apos;s base-less and false claims that Linux infringes upon its patents. I distanced myself from openSUSE after that deal. Now, with Novell gone and Microsoft shifting focus to Android (Barnes &amp; Nobel just exposed that Microsoft&apos;s Android claims were bogus) openSUSE appears to be back as the community driven project, and I am back too. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 19.11.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.unixmen.com/linux-tutorials/linux-distributions/suse/1978-opensuse-121-has-been-released-screenshots-tour">Unixmen/M. Zinoune: Opensuse 12.1 has been released! Screenshots tour</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/11/16/opensuse-12-1-all-green/">Opensuse 12.1</ulink> has been released! This release bring awesome improvements include the latest GNOME 3.2 desktop as well as the newest from KDE, Xfce and LXDE; your own Cloud made easy with mirall; Snapper-shots of your file system. openSUSE 12.1 comes with the new GNOME Shell 3.2. We presented you with a taste of GNOME Shell on openSUSE 11.4; since then, many bugs have been squashed and numerous small improvements have made life on the Shell more comfortable. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 19.11.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
