<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
  <!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.novell.com/news/press/2011/2/novell-makes-it-easier-to-run-business-critical-linux-workloads-on-hp-proliant-and-bladesystem-servers-.html"
          >Novell Makes it Easier to Run Business-Critical Linux Workloads on HP ProLiant and
          BladeSystem Servers</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Novell today announced it has made it easier and more affordable for customers to run
        business-critical applications in a Linux* environment on HP ProLiant* and BladeSystem*
        servers. Available immediately, Novell has bundled <ulink
          url="http://www.novell.com/products/highavailability/">SUSE® Linux Enterprise High
          Availability (HA) Extension</ulink> for no additional cost with select SUSE Linux
        Enterprise Server subscriptions sold through HP and authorized resellers for a limited time.
        (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 10.2.11 sat $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://lwn.net/Articles/426842/">The Ada Initiative launches</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Ada Initiative launches to promote women in open technology and culture </para>
      <para>Open source activists Valerie Aurora and Mary Gardiner announce the launch today of the
        Ada Initiative (http://adainitiative.org/), a non-profit organization to promote
        women&apos;s participation in open technology and culture. </para>
      <para>Open technology and culture, including open source software, open content, and related
        communities, suffer from a dearth of women at all levels. &quot;Open technology and culture
        are shaping our future and must reflect all people. Involving more women in the creation of
        our future is a critical step in building a healthy Internet world,&quot; says Mitchell
        Baker, chair of the Mozilla Foundation. The Ada Initiative will concentrate on focused,
        direct action programs, including recruitment and training for women, education for
        community members, and working with companies and projects to improve their outreach to
        women. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 10.2.11 sat $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://camp.kde.org/">Welcome to Camp KDE 2011!</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The 3rd annual Camp KDE will be held on the 4th and 5th of April, 2011 in San Francisco,
        California at <ulink url="http://www.jdvhotels.com/hotels/kabuki">Hotel Kabuki</ulink>. Held
        annually in the United States, Camp KDE provides a regional opportunity for KDE contributors
        and enthusiasts to gather, learn about the latest KDE happenings and share their
        experiences. The event will feature in-depth talks by core KDE developers. </para>
      <para>This year Camp KDE is co-located with the <ulink
          url="http://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/collaboration-summit">Linux Foundation
          Collaboration Summit</ulink>, which takes place April 6-8, 2011. Co-location with the
        Collaboration Summit will allow Camp KDE attendees a unique opportunity to learn from and
        share their experiences with members of many other successful Free and Open Source software
        projects and companies. All Camp KDE attendees are invited to attend the Collaboration
        Summit. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 10.2.11 sat $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.computerworlduk.com/news/open-source/3260727/london-stock-exchange-in-historic-linux-go-live/"
          >Computerworld/Leo King: London Stock Exchange in historic Linux go-live</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>"UPDATED The London Stock Exchange has successfully set into live trading a new matching
        engine based on Novell SUSE Linux technology, following successful last-step setup
        procedures on Saturday. </para>
      <para>The move has been billed as one of the LSE's most significant technological developments
        since the increasing prevalence of electronic trading led to the closure of the traditional
        exchange floor in 1986. LSE chief executive Xavier Rolet has insisted that the exchange,
        once a monopoly, will deliver record speed and stable trading in order to fight back against
        the fast erosion of its dominant marketshare by specialist electronic rivals.</para>
      <para><quote>The London Stock Exchange Group is pleased to confirm that Millennium Exchange is
          now operational," the LSE said in a statement to clients ahead of the main market trading
          opening on Monday. "We would like to thank all clients for their support during this
          migration.</quote>" (...)</para>
      <!--($ ld: 15.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.techrepublic.com/blog/10things/10-ways-to-e-publish-with-linux/2293"
          >TechRepublic/Jack Wallen: 10 ways to e-publish with Linux</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>"As a writer, I always am looking at new and better ways to get my words to the public.
        And since I write fiction as well as technology pieces, it’s in my best interest to know how
        to get my books into the hands of readers. In today’s market, the publishing industry is in
        a serious swing away from the traditional routes. With the major improvements in e-readers,
        more and more users are migrating away from the old standard hardcover/paperback books to
        digital formats. This has been a boon for new writers. With the ability to easily
        self-publish for various e-readers, it no longer requires an agent or a publisher to see
        your brilliance. </para>
      <para>But does that mean everyone should be submitting their books? Well, if everyone can
        properly format, design, and create -yes. If not, no. For those with the necessary skills,
        it is important to have the right tools and/or procedures for getting your books into the
        Amazon, Barnes &amp; Noble’s, and Apple systems. Linux can help you do that. Let’s take a
        look at 10 Linux tools that can help your get your book into the market." (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 15.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://asiajin.com/blog/2011/02/08/facebook-japan-takes-hard-line-banning-pseudo-names-and-requires-id/"
          >Asiajin/Akky Akimoto: Facebook Japan Takes Hard Line, Banning Pseudo Names And Requires
          ID</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Today February 8, some Japanese web users who are influential in tech communities like
        Hatena and Twitter, started reporting they were locked out from Facebook. After trying to
        log in, they were taken to the form, which title is “Complaints against a ban of your
        account, identity demanded”. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 10.2.11 sat $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linux.com/learn/tutorials/403466-review-hands-on-libreoffice-33"
          >techhacking.com/Lev: LibreOffice-The Future of Office in Linux</ulink>
      </title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://techhacking.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/libologo.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>"<ulink url="http://www.libreoffice.org/">LibreOffice 3.3</ulink> was released a few
        weeks ago and this marks a very important milestone in the Open Source Office environment.
        In my previous post I talked in detail about OpenOffice.org but completely forgot to mention
        LibreOffice and all of the exciting things that are happening at The Document
        Foundation.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">The Big Bang of Open Source</emphasis>
      </para>
      <para>In September of 2010 many of the top developers of Open Office parted ways from Oracle
        and the Open Office project. They went on to form the <ulink
          url="http://documentfoundation.org/">Document Foundation</ulink>. </para>
      <para><quote>Our mission is to facilitate the evolution of the OpenOffice.org Community into a
          new open, independent, and meritocratic organizational structure within the next few
          months. An independent Foundation is a better match to the values of our contributors,
          users, and supporters, and will enable a more effective, efficient, transparent, and
          inclusive Community. We will protect past investments by building on the solid
          achievements of our first decade, encourage wide participation in the Community, and
          co-ordinate activity across the Community.</quote></para>
      <para>This split from Oracle was in a sense a revolution. OpenOffice.org used to be sponsored
        by Sun Micro systems. After Sun was bought out by Oracle there were rumors and fears that
        OpenOffice.org would go the way of OpenSolaris which lost support from Oracle. The Document
        Foundation initially hoped to keep Oracle and have a strong working relationship, but Oracle
        decided not to support LibreOffice and the rest is (or will be?) history." (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 13.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.tildehash.com/?article=interview-with-richard-stallman-2011"
          >techhacking.com/Lev: Useful Open Source Software #2: GIMP</ulink>
      </title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://techhacking.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/gimp-splash-2.4.png"
            width="10%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>"<ulink url="http://www.gimp.org/">GIMP</ulink> (GNU Image Manipulation Program) is a
        very powerful piece of image editing software that is comparable to Photoshop. It is free to
        use, and offers you many of the same basic to advanced image editing capabilities as
        Photoshop without the hefty price tag. It is available on Mac, Windows, and Linux. </para>
      <para>GIMP is now at version 2.6 and has come a long way since its humble beginnings. It
        started off as a small project designed to create a Photoshop-like program in the Linux
        environment and since 1995 has exploded into a very powerful graphic design system. It is
        one of my favorite pieces of open source software and I am constantly amazed by the amazing
        capabilities of this program. </para>
      <para>The program has many features that computer graphics designers will find useful, but at
        the same time beginners may be intimidated by the amount of options that are available. When
        first run, you are met with several screens, tons of menus, and tons of options. If you are
        new to graphic design it may be very intimidating and overwhelming. Luckily there is a lot
        of documentation on how to effectively use GIMP. There are free <ulink
          url="http://www.gimp.org/tutorials/">tutorials</ulink> for all ranges of expertise
        available on the GIMP.org website. There are also a lot of books that have been published
        about <ulink url="http://amzn.to/e3xQ0k">GIMP, the newest being GIMP 2.6 for Photographers:
          Image Editing with Open Source Software</ulink> by Klaus Goelker." (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 13.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.unixmen.com/gaming-on-linux/1131-19-awesome-opensource-games-for-linux-"
          >techhacking.com/Lev: Useful Open Source Software #3: FreeMind</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>"<ulink url="http://freemind.sourceforge.net/wiki/index.php/Main_Page">Freemind</ulink>
        is a free mind mapping program which has some amazing functionality and a variety of uses. A
        mind map is nothing more than what people have done for years with a pencil and pad of paper
        – Brain Storm. You start with a main idea, then you expand it with branches of related
        concepts, then you expand those concepts with specific details. Before you know it, you have
        just cured cancer, invented the first car that runs on water, or successfully taken over the
        world. </para>
      <para>The best part about Freemind, is that unlike a pad and paper you are able to insert
        images, objects, links, files, and pretty much anything that you desire into your mind map
        which allows you to have one place to organize all of your thoughts. Mind maps are an
        alternative way to study, take notes, organize your ideas, make decisions, and solve
        problems. I have been using it for about a year in school. Personally, I am in love with it.
        I used to take vigorous notes in classic format. But I found myself getting lost, confused,
        and unable to really feel a sense of organization in my notes. Freemind allows you to have
        all of your information on a single page. You can expand and reduce the categories as you
        see fit to first learn major concepts, and then specific details." (...)</para>
      <!--($ ld: 8.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxjournal.com/content/cups-and-sun">Linux Journal/Johan Thelin:
          CUPS and Sun</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>I recently spent some time getting one of my long term projects built. For quite some
        time I&apos;ve had an old desktop computer serve as my printer server. As this machine is
        kind of loud, I&apos;ve turned it off when not using it. This led to some client machines
        not appreciating the printer becoming available at the wrong time.</para>
      <para>In my posession I also had an old mini-itx board with passive cooling (large heat sinks)
        and a pair of sun portable scsi hdd cases. Incidentally, the latter fit into the former. The
        plan for a new print server was born. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 10.2.11 sat $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://genek.net/wordpress/">Adventures in Linux: Software Review: The KDE 4.6
          Desktop Environment</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Author’s note: </emphasis></para>
      <para>most of the screenshots contained herein were taken from the KDE release announcement.
        Thanks to KDE for making these pics available for re-use. </para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Ancient History: </emphasis></para>
      <para>It’s been three years, and it’s still hard to put the KDE 4.0 debacle behind me. I was
        running KDE 3.5 on Debian stable happy as a clam, and then one fine day in January of 2008
        the KDE folks dumped their brand-new, completely re-vamped desktop environment into our
        laps. I couldn’t get it for Debian so I installed another distro just to check it out… and
        used it for less than 24 hours. I could see what they were trying to do, and there were some
        good ideas there, but the implementation was so unbelievably bad that I missed out on the
        next two releases altogether. I didn’t try KDE 4.x again until January of last year, when I
        installed Debian testing with the KDE 4.3 desktop. It was great! Since then KDE has gone
        from strength to strength. KDE 4.4 was mature and stable, and KDE 4.5 added polish and
        finesse. KDE 4.6, released a little over a week ago, ups the ante once again. (...)</para>
      <!--($ ld: 10.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://blog.qt.nokia.com/2011/02/12/nokia-new-strategic-direction-what-is-the-future-for-qt/"
          >QTBlog/Daniel Kihlberg: Nokia new strategic direction. What is the future for
        Qt?</ulink></title>
      <para>Wow, what a day… Nokia outlined its new platform strategy for smartphones, with Windows
        Phones as it primary smartphone platform in a proposed partnership with Microsoft… and
        Microsoft’s tools would be used for Nokia Windows Phone application development … and guess
        what, it has raised a lot of questions in the Qt community. </para>
      <para>So the question is, what is the future for Qt? </para>
      <para>Qt will continue to play an important role in Nokia. Consider the following:<itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>The retention of Nokia’s 200 million Symbian-users is vital and Nokia has targeted
              sales of 150 million more Symbian-devices in years to come. To achieve that Nokia
              needs to continue the modernization of Symbian in Qt – to keep existing consumers
              engaged and to attract new customers, either upgrading from existing Symbian devices
              to Qt enabled devices or entirely new to Nokia.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Nokia also announced it will ship its first MeeGo-related device in 2011, which
              will rely on the Qt ecosystem – and then will continue with MeeGo as an open source
              project for future disruption. Nokia can’t afford to be behind the next disruption
              again and Qt can play an important role in making sure it isn’t.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>With Qt Quick and Qt SDK 1.1 releases in the coming months we are expecting the Qt
              developer community to continue to grow – adding to the 400.000 developers using Qt
              today. Qt is developed together with the community and we expect the pace of
              innovation to increase even further as the community grows.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>We in Nokia are one of tens of thousands of companies in multiple industries
              actively using and contributing to Qt, making Qt relevant for both mobile, desktop and
              other embedded developers</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Qt expansion: We have continued to hire Qt developers and we will continue to
              improve and expand Qt in the future. Qt is great at delivering innovation; we have
              been doing that for 15 years. With the upcoming release of Qt Quick, we will reach out
              to new users and make it even easier to create great apps and UIs for many platforms
              including Symbian and MeeGo.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>The new Qt SDK 1.1 technology preview. We now offer only one SDK for both desktop
              and mobile developers, which makes it easier to target more platforms by using just
              one SDK.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Qt everywhere. Qt continues to make vast inroads into especially low end Linux
              devices and distro’s. Qt also continues to provide a platform for others to innovate
              and differentiate upon. For example Dreamworks switching all their internal animation
              tools to Qt and making cool movies like “MegaMind” and “How to Train Your
              Dragon”.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
      <para>Qt is increasingly popular. During 2010, we had 1.5+ million downloads at qt.nokia.com
        (alone) – twice as much as during 2009 – and with the up-coming innovation and additional
        investments in Qt combined with the introduction of open governance, I believe Qt will be
        used more than ever before.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 10.2.11 sat $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.net-security.org/secworld.php?id=10544">HELP NET SECURITY: USB
          autorun attacks against Linux</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Many people think that Linux is immune to the type of Autorun attacks that have plagued
        Windows systems with malware over the years. However, there have been many advances in the
        usability of Linux as a desktop OS - including the addition of features that can allow
        Autorun attacks.</para>
      <para>This Shmoocon presentation by Jon Larimer from IBM X-Force starts off with a definition
        of autorun vulnerabilities and some examples from Windows, then jumps straight into the
        Linux side of things. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 10.2.11 sat $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>LOL</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://e-tote-kala.blogspot.com/2011/01/first-joke-of-year-if-operating-systems.html"
          >Kostas Koudaras: First Joke of the year: If Operating Systems Ran The Airlines</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The first joke of the year :-) </para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
</sect1>
