<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="updates">
  <title>New/Updated Applications @ openSUSE</title>
  <!--* Gnome
* KDE
* XYZ 

Version should be available at packman or software.opensuse.org/search max. 4 posts. -->
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://psankar.blogspot.com/2011/01/introducing-sqlite-commander-curses.html"
        >Sankar P: Introducing Sqlite-Commander - Curses Client for your SQLite
      Database</ulink></title>
    <para>I am happy to introduce to you, my recent nighttime hack "Sqlite-Commander - <ulink
        url="https://github.com/curiosity/sqlite-commander">A Curses client for your SQLite
        Database</ulink>".</para>
    <para>While I was working in a project involving sqlite, I wanted to check the contents of a
      sqlite database. The command line sqlite client involves too much of typing for viewing
      records. The sqlite viewers that I found were not very keyboard friendly. There was a firefox
      extension which looked good but I felt it is too clumsy to launch that application. Also, I
      wanted a tool that will read SQLite tables over ssh without requiring much bandwidth. I could
      not find any CUI client for SQLite and I felt it may be useful to write one, atleast for my
      satisfying my needs. So, here we have Sqlite-Commander. The name is inspired from an awesome
      piece of software Midnight-Commander written by Miguel De Icaza.</para>
    <figure id="fig.sqlite">
      <title>Screenshot</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata width="50%"
            fileref="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_G_VBnbGWMzs/TSBaaaJW18I/AAAAAAAAEWQ/v9HLv-7nHMk/s1600/sqlite-commander.png"
            align="center"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Features</emphasis></para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Shows the list of tables in the left pane.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Allows you to navigate the list of tables using arrow keys.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Shows the first 30 records for the selected table in the right pane</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Non-printable columns are shown with a ???</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Maximum of 30 characters are displayed per column. Column data exceeding this length
          are shown with <quote>...</quote></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">TODO</emphasis></para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>It is not a full-fledged SQLite client with rich features. It is like an enriched
          version of cat for working with sqlite. I don't intend to make a release, as I am not sure
          if this will be useful for anyone other than people who work with SQLite and can use only
          a terminal/ssh. If there are enough users, I will enhance and make it a full-fledged
          product. So drop me a mail if you are interested in this project.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>It should be fairly straight-forward to implement connectivity to any database (MySQL,
          Oracle, etc.) such that we can have a generic SQL NCurses client. It will be a good
          exercise for someone who wants to know C#.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Add a scroll bar and show more than 30 columns. Should be moderate/easy to
          implement.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Add a dialog box to execute any random SQL statement. Should be fairly trivial to
          implement.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Create Events such that pressing Enter on the records list will pass the currently
          selected record to a custom script/command. Useful ?</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Copy selections of records to clipboard. Easy to implement.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Handle tablenames with special characters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Thanks</emphasis></para>
    <para>Credits are due for the awesome mono-ncurses interface authors (Miguel and Co.) If you are
      looking to writing some terminal application I can heartily recommend that mono-ncurses is the
      best library you will ever get. Before beginning this application, I evaluated a few options
      (like Python etc.) and nothing comes close to being as easy to use as <ulink
        url="http://www.mono-project.com/MonoCurses">mono-ncurses</ulink>. Also, special thanks to
      VIM and git, two of the most productive tools ever invented. </para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 3.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://dev-loki.blogspot.com/2011/01/mplayer-and-smplayer-update.html">Pascal
        Bleser: MPlayer and smplayer update</ulink></title>
    <para>I've just updated the <ulink url="http://packman.links2linux.org/package/MPlayer"
          ><emphasis role="bold">MPlayer</emphasis></ulink> and <ulink
        url="http://packman.links2linux.org/package/smplayer"><emphasis role="bold"
          >smplayer</emphasis></ulink> in the <ulink url="http://packman.links2linux.org">Packman
        repository</ulink> to their latest respective development revisions. </para>
    <para>I also enabled <ulink url="http://packman.links2linux.org/package/rtmpdump"><emphasis
          role="bold">rtmpdump</emphasis></ulink>, <ulink
        url="http://packman.links2linux.org/package/mpg123"><emphasis role="bold"
        >mpg123</emphasis></ulink> and mpcdec support. <emphasis role="bold">MPlayer</emphasis>
      changed the way it handles <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Closed_captioning">closed
        captions</ulink> in a recent revision, as it now takes an option to the <emphasis
        role="bold">-subcc</emphasis> parameter to select which channel to use. </para>
    <para>Because of that, I also had to update the (brilliant) smplayer GUI frontend for <emphasis
        role="bold">mplayer</emphasis> in order to support that change. </para>
    <para>Needless to say, if you encounter any issue, please report it by email to packman with the
      domain <emphasis role="bold">links2linux.de</emphasis></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 3.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://tittiatcoke.wordpress.com/2011/01/04/opensuse-kdeunstablesc-repo-becomes-trunk-again/"
        >Raymond Wooninck: openSUSE KDE:Unstable:SC repo becomes Trunk again !</ulink></title>
    <para>A little warning to those that have switched over to the KDE:Unstable:SC repo. The target
      is that either tonight or tomorrow a new Trunk snapshot will be loaded in this repo. That
      would mean that the Unstable becomes unstable again.</para>
    <para>I have already been building a number of snapshots based on the opened KDE 4.7 trunk and
      have to admit that things are still looking very stable and even kdebindings is compiling well
      :-) But this might of course change from the moment that KDE 4.6 has been released and the
      focus shifts to the newer 4.7 release. </para>
    <para>I will keep you posted on the developments around this repository, but this would be the
      moment to switch over to KDE:Distro:Factory if you want to get the RC1, RC2 and KDE 4.6 final
      version for your openSUSE system. Currently it contains RC1, but this would change in the next
      few days once RC2 is released. </para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 5.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://www.lenzg.net/archives/332-Updated-Drupal-7-appliances-to-version-7.0-final.html"
        >LenZ Grimmer: Updated Drupal 7 appliances to version 7.0 final</ulink></title>
    <para>Congratulations to the Drupal community for getting <ulink
        url="http://drupal.org/drupal-7.0">version 7.0</ulink>
      <ulink url="http://drupal.org/drupal-7-released">released</ulink>! This is a major mile stone
      and an excellent reason to <ulink url="http://www.drupal7releaseparty.org/">celebrate</ulink>!
      If you want to give Drupal 7 a try without having to install anything, I've now updated my
      Drupal 7 appliances on <ulink url="http://susestudio.com/">SuSE Studio</ulink> to the latest
      release. The appliance is based on <ulink url="http://software.opensuse.org/113/en">openSUSE
        Linux 11.3</ulink> and is available in two variants:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>A <ulink url="http://susegallery.com/a/Byn5dM/drupal-7-testdrive">text-mode</ulink>
            only appliance to which you connect using your local web browser via the network.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>A <ulink url="http://susegallery.com/a/Byn5dM/drupal-7-testdrive-gui">GUI
              version</ulink> that starts up the Firefox browser in a minimalistic GNOME desktop to
            perform the installation locally. Remote network access is available, too.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>The database backend is phpMyAdmin has been added to support web-based administration of
      the MySQL server. You can access it via http://localhost/phpMyAdmin/. I also added <ulink
        url="http://drush.ws/">drush</ulink>, the Drupal command line shell and scripting interface
      and some additional packages (yast2-http-server, bind-utils, php5-ctype, patch). I also bumped
      up the appliance's version number to 7.0.0, to match the version number of Drupal included. </para>
    <para>The appliance is available in various formats:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>A live raw disk image, ready to be written to an USB stick or flash drive</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>A live ISO image, to be burned on a CD or used in a virtual machine</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>A hard disk image, to be dumped on a hard disk drive</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Various virtual disk formats, e.g. OVF, VMWare/VirtualBox/KVM and Xen</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>Please see the installation instructions provided on the download pages for details on how
      to use the various image formats. </para>
    <para>So congratulations to the Drupal developer community for reaching this goal and thanks to
      SuSE/Novell/Attachmate for providing the infrastructure for creating such appliances. I also
      would like to especially thank <ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/author/rbos/">Richard
      Bos</ulink> for the testing and many suggestions for improvement of these appliances!</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 5.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <itemizedlist>
    <title>You can find other interesting Packages at:</title>
    <listitem>
      <para><ulink url="http://packman.links2linux.de/rdf/packman_en.rdf">Packman</ulink></para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para><ulink url="https://hermes.opensuse.org/feeds/66367.rdf">openSUSE Build
        Service</ulink></para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</sect1>
