<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="tipsandtricks">
  <title>Tips and Tricks</title>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Desktop Users</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.howtoforge.com/the-perfect-desktop-opensuse-11.4-gnome">HowtoForge/Falko Timme: The Perfect Desktop - OpenSUSE 11.4 (GNOME) </ulink>
      </title>
      <para>This tutorial shows how you can set up an <ulink url="http://www.opensuse.org/">OpenSUSE 11.4</ulink> desktop that is a full-fledged replacement for a Windows desktop, i.e. that
        has all the software that people need to do the things they do on their Windows desktops.
        The advantages are clear: you get a secure system without DRM restrictions that works even
        on old hardware, and the best thing is: all software comes free of charge.</para>
      <para>I want to say first that this is not the only way of setting up such a system. There are
        many ways of achieving this goal but this is the way I take. I do not issue any guarantee
        that this will work for you! (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 3.5.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.packtpub.com/article/scribus-importing-images">Packt Publishing/Cedric Gemy: Scribus: Importing Images</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Importing and exporting:</emphasis></para>
      <para>The concepts

To begin with, remember that there are two kinds of graphics you can add to your layout. You can have photos, generally taken from a digital camera, downloaded, or bought on some website. Photos will generally be stored in JPEG files, but you can also find PNG, TIFF, or many other file formats. The second kind of graphics is vector drawings such as logos and maps. They are computer-made drawings and are stored as EPS or SVG files. You will certainly need to work with both in most of your documents. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 8.4.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Commandline/Script Newbies</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.unixmen.com/linux-commands/1602-watch-al-jazeera-live-with-one-command">Unixmen/M. Zinoune (Zinovsky): Watch Al Jazeera Live in Linux with one command</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>If you are a fun of Aljazeera News channel, this is a nice command that allow you to
        watch Al Jazeera live in your Linux desktop. I tested the command and is working like a
        charm.</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://cdn.unixmen.com/images/stories/thumbnails/images-stories-videos-aljazeera1-400x225.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>First check if you have rtmpdump installed, if not install it using the command
        :<screen>sudo apt-get install rtmpdump</screen></para>
      <para>Now to start watching Aljazeera live, open terminal and enter the following
        command</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">To use Mplayer :</emphasis><programlisting><emphasis role="bold">$ rtmpdump -v -r rtmp://livestfslivefs.fplive.net/livestfslive-live/ -y \\ &quot;aljazeera_en_veryhigh&quot; -a &quot;aljazeeraflashlive-live&quot; -o -| mplayer -</emphasis></programlisting></para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">To use VLC player:</emphasis><screen>$<emphasis role="bold"> rtmpdump -v -r rtmp://livestfslivefs.fplive.net/livestfslive-live/ \\ -y &quot;aljazeera_en_veryhigh&quot; -a &quot;aljazeeraflashlive-live&quot; -o -| vlc -</emphasis>
          </screen></para>
      <para>Enjoy :)</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Editors Note:</emphasis> For openSUSE you should install via:
          <emphasis role="italic">zypper in rtmpdump</emphasis> instead of sudo apt-get</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 30.3.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Developers and Programmers</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://dominique.leuenberger.net/blog/?p=178">Dominique Leuenberger: how to fix brp and rpmlint warnings – today:I: Program causes undefined operation(likely same variable used twice and post/pre incremented in the same expression)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>It seems the planned series sort of finds an audience, which in turn of course is
        motivational to keep on writing it. Today, we’ll have a look at this Informational message
        in BRP
        checks:<screen>I: Program causes undefined operation
 (likely same variable used twice and post/pre incremented in the same expression).
 e.g. x = x++; Split it in two operations.</screen></para>
      <para>This is currently informational only and is not failing the build, but you might want to
        address them together with upstream. </para>
      <para>I assume you do know what “a++” means in C (otherwise, you should start reading
        C-books), so we just try to reproduce this error in a simple c test
        case:<screen>#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;
 
int main() {
 int i=5;
 i = i++ * ++i;
 printf(&quot;The current value of i is %d\n&quot;, i);
 return 0;
 }</screen></para>
      <para>When building this using gcc -Wall test.c, we get this compiler warning (which in turn
        is what brp translates to the information we’re discussing
        here)<screen>&gt; gcc -Wall test2.c
 test.c: In function ‘main’:
 test.c:5:5: warning: operation on ‘i’ may be undefined</screen></para>
      <para>So, let’s first see for ourselves what we would expect this to be? Hmm.. already for us,
        this looks not logic (and I surely hope nobody would write this code). Let’s just see what
        starting this executable gives shall we?<screen>The current value of i is 37</screen></para>
      <para>Now, is this surprising? We multiplied, assigned it to i and as a result we get a prime
        number? By closely analyzing the line you will likely understand what the compiler did. But
        was this expected? If this is actually what the programmer intended, the code should just be
        rewritten to be more logical, like:<screen>i = (i+1) ^2 + 1;</screen></para>
      <para>This is understandable for all of us and does not yield the surprise of what is going
        on.</para>
      <para>And that is actually all this warning is about: it requests the programmer to write code
        that can be understood and does not depend on what the compiler interprets. It might even
        very well be that the different optimization levels or the usage of different compilers
        might end up in different results.</para>
      <para>If you want to read some more about this topic, I suggest to have a look at:<itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sequence_point">Wikipedia</ulink></para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink url="http://publications.gbdirect.co.uk/c_book/chapter8/sequence_points.html">http://publications.gbdirect.co.uk/c_book/chapter8/sequence_points.html</ulink></para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
<!-- ($ Id: 28.3.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For System Administrators</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.howtoforge.com/installing-apache2-with-php5-and-mysql-support-on-opensuse-11.4-lamp">HowtoForge/Falko Timme: Installing Apache2 With PHP5 And MySQL Support On OpenSUSE 11.4 (LAMP)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>LAMP is short for <emphasis role="bold">L</emphasis>inux, <emphasis role="bold">A</emphasis>pache, <emphasis role="bold">M</emphasis>ySQL, <emphasis role="bold">P</emphasis>HP. This tutorial shows how you can install an Apache2 webserver on an OpenSUSE 11.4 server with PHP5 support (mod_php) and MySQL support. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 8.4.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.novell.com/communities/node/12703/howto-openldap-24x-replication-sles11sp1">Novell Cool Solutions/fpernet: HOWTO: OpenLDAP 2.4.x Replication on SLES11 SP1</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Introduction</emphasis></para>
      <para>YaST has a module for the server and the client part of OpenLDAP (plus a very basic LDAP browser / editor).

</para>
      <para>On SLES11 we had the following problems regarding the use of the YaST module and OpenLDAP server configuration:

    </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Database version only to store the configuratio (cn=config).</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>No way to set up any replication method or mode using this module.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>OpenLDAP modules available build in the SLAPD binary.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>Then your choices in this SLES11 version:

    </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Use the configuration file /etc/openldap/slapd.conf but in this case, forget YaST for ever.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Use YaST to set up a basic OpenLDAP server then use an external tool to set up the rest.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>If use of YaST only is mandatory, forget the replication.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>An RFE (Request For Enhancements) was created at this time, to be able to set up replication from the YaST module, on SLES11 SP1. They did it! So, let’s check how it works.

</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Note</emphasis>: On SLES11 or SLES11 SP1, by playing with /etc/sysconfig/opendlap, you can use the configuration file (/etc/openldap/slapd.conf) to configure OpenLDAP server but in this case do not use YaST anymore. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 8.4.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
