<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="forums">
  <title>openSUSE Forums</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/applications/464824-how-prevent-system-over-writes-customized-etc-sysconfig-files.html">How to prevent system-(over)writes to customized /etc/sysconfig/* files?</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>
      The title is clear, this thread means to find a solution for overwriting of modified system config files during an update. Of course there are the dirty tricks, like making the files concerned read-only etc., but that's not the way it should be done; forget one, and you may find yourself in a mess. IMHO the best suggestion is not to change these files at all, but add new ones that already are called from the existing ones, Still a very interesting thread for those of us that use modified default configurations for system services like, for example, a webserver.
    </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
    <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/other-forums/looking-something-other-than-support/465296-re-opensuse-corporate-server.html">openSUSE as a corporate server</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>
      Question in this thread is whether this can be done: using openSUSE as a corporate server. Of course there's the suggestion to use SUSE Linux Enterprise Server, but personally I have no hesitations to reply with a full "yes' and add that openSUSE can be used for the desktops connecting to the server as well. Read on, if you're interested in moving to an openSUSE based network for your company or organization. 
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
    <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/hardware/465251-opensuse-11-4-njytouch-touch-screen-problems.html">openSUSE 11.4 and njytouch touch screen - Problems</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>
      Today's world of computing is changing. Not only do we interact with social networks from our desktops, the way we control our actions changes as well. A good example is the touch screen for desktops/laptops as an input method. Not new -they've been out there for a couple of years already-, but these screens used to be quite expensive. With that changing, touch screens will become more common. Do they work on linux? They should, but here's a thread where original poster has difficulties in getting it to work properly. 
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      openSUSE Language specific subforums:
    </title>
    <para>We now host the following language specific subforums under the umbrella of the openSUSE Forums:
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/">Main forums, english</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/ae-ae-chinese/">中文(Chinese)</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/nederlands-dutch/">Nederlands (Dutch)</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/frana-ais-french/">Français (French)</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/deutsch-german/">Deutsch (German)</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/greek/">Ελληνικό (Greek)</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/magyar-hungarian/">Magyar (Hungarian)</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/japanese/">日本語 (Japanese)</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/portuguese/">Portuguese</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/p-russian/">Pусский (Russian)</ulink>
      </para>
<!-- ($ ld: 01.09.2011 gl $) -->  </blockquote>
</sect1>
