<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 id="gsoc" role="gsoc">
  <title>Google Summer of Code</title>
  <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
      <imagedata width="20%" align="center" fileref="http://michal.hrusecky.net/wp-content/uploads/GSoC2011_300x200.png"/>
    </imageobject>
  </mediaobject>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://sysbytes.wordpress.com/2011/08/07/sax3-monitor-module-completed/">Manu
        Gupta: SaX3 – Monitor Module completed</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>As part of GSoC Project, I am working on SaX3 and I have completed the monitor
      module.</para>
    <para>You can get the latest repo from my home repository<ulink
        url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/home:/manugupt1/"
        >http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/home:/manugupt1/</ulink></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Please test it thoroughly,and let me know if common troubleshooting
        use cases for a single monitor is supported. If there is anything missing let me know.
        Xinerama is not supported</emphasis></para>
    <para>For both factory and 11.4.</para>
    <para>Next up is touchpad, which I will finish by this thursday. And will begin pencil downs the
      following week onwards.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 8.8.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/08/08/gsoc-osc-code-cleanup-summary-of-week-11/"
        >Marcus Hüwe: osc code cleanup – summary of week 11</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>Here’s a small summary of the 11th (coding) week. This week I spent most of my time with
      working on the wc code.</para>
    <para>DONE:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>project wc: added commit and update methods</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>lots of wc code refactoring</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>TODO:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>project wc: commit only specific files for a package instead of the complete package
            (the package wc class already supports this) (use case: osc ci pkg1/file pkg1/foo
            pkg2/bar pkg3)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>convert old working copies to the new format</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>package wc: update: add support to specify stuff like “expand”, “linkrev”
            etc.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>project wc: add a revert method (to restore a package wc with state ‘!’)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>project/package wc: support diff</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>package wc: implement a pull method (does the same as “osc pull”)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
<!-- ($ ld: 8.8.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://obsforandroid.wordpress.com/2011/08/08/sorting-elements-with-jquery-mobile-controlgroup-buttons-vs-radio-buttons/"
        >Justine Leng: Sorting elements with jQuery Mobile: controlgroup buttons vs. radio
        buttons</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>After implementing a prototype for sorting functions in Requests, I needed to refine the
      UI and get the sorting buttons to work correctly with jQuery Mobile. The problem was when I
      clicked on a button to re-order the list of requests, the action would complete properly, but
      the selected button would not be highlighted.</para>
    <para>This is the ideal view I would like to have:</para>
    <para><inlinegraphic fileref="http://obsforandroid.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/prototype.png"
        width="20%"/></para>
<!-- ($ ld: 08.08.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://redache.wordpress.com/2011/08/06/entomologist-ui-changes-weekly-report-11/"
        >David Williams: Entomologist UI Changes – Weekly report #11</ulink></title>
    <para>This week has involved trying to get the UI in place for ToDo List
      exporting/configuration. The work should now be finished and I’ve begun trying to implement
      Remember the Milk exporting which is made a bit complicated by how they accept API requests
      but I hope to have this finished as soon as possible. I don’t really have that much to talk
      about this week as nothing huge has changed but I will keep working on integrating the
      services.</para>
    <para>What I hope to achieve is Google Calendar, Remember The Milk and WebDAV server integration
      by the Soft Pencils Down Date, which I believe is the 19th of August. I think it’s perfectly
      achievable to get these features to a finished state by then and I’ll continue working on
      having them integrated. As I’ve previously mentioned I would like to use the final week as a
      time to merge and test everything to try and uncover any bugs I’ve missed whilst adding these
      features.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 06.08.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
