<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1>
  <title>openSUSE Conference 2010</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/08/17/opensuse-conference-2011-schedule-available/"
        >Klaas Freitag: openSUSE Conference 2011 Schedule Available</ulink></title>
    <para>ts quite some work to get to a reasonable schedule for a FOSS conference done. You want a
      balanced program with topics where all visitors can find their interests in. Moreover the
      level of the talks must be taken care of as well as there should be gravitation centers for
      key topics within the community. As you usually also seek out for new community members with a
      conference, some topics which attract new people are also a very good idea. And all that needs
      to be sorted between rooms with different sizes, the times people can be around, the tracks
      you think are useful on the event and such. Quite some parameters to take into account. </para>
    <para>That said, I am very happy that we could issue the <ulink
        url="http://conference.opensuse.org/timetable">schedule</ulink> for the <ulink
        url="http://conference.opensuse.org">openSUSE Conference 2011</ulink> today.</para>
    <para>For conference organization there is tooling. Or should I say: Should be? Given the huge
      amount of FOSS conferences around, the number of free alternatives of conference organization
      systems is fairly small. We decided to go again with <ulink url="http://indico-software.org/"
        >Indico</ulink>, a python based system developed by <ulink
        url="http://public.web.cern.ch/public/">CERN</ulink>. It provides support for the whole
      conference life cycle such as the call for abstracts, the internal judging process, the
      scheduling and such. With nice help from the developers we got it running smoothly and
      integrated. Sometimes the interface is not really straightforward, but finally its a very
      feature rich yet flexible tool that feels like it has managed some large (CERN) conferences
      already.(...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 18.8.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>

  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://michal.hrusecky.net/2011/08/opensuse-conference-2011-sax3/">Michal
        Hrušecký: openSUSE Conference 2011 – SaX3</ulink></title>
    <para>Yet another advertisement for openSUSE Conference 2011. Something I’ll be participating in
      as well. But this time, all the glory belongs to <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/07/05/people-of-opensuse-manu-gupta/">Manu Gupta</ulink>.
      I’ll be just helping out. We will have together presentation about SaX3. Have you already
      heard about SaX3? If not,continue reading.</para>
    <para>SaX2 was X configuration tool. It was using xorg.conf file and it allowed people to set
      various X properties in GUI. It was a user friendly way how to set up Xorg. But X developers
      made automatic configuration much better and xorg.conf file obsolete. They replaced it with
      something much better – configuration directory xorg.conf.d. You can place just snippets of
      original xorg.conf file in there to override some properties. It’s much better,
      butýunfortunatelyýit also made SaX2 obsolete. And even though automatic configuration is
      great, there still people that want to tweak just a few details. These people missed SaX2. One
      of the GSoC projects was to create SaX3 that will be aware of xorg.conf.d directory, respect
      it and would create just the necessary snippets. So your X configuration will stay as simple
      as possible, but you’ll also have possibility to configure it easily from GUI.</para>
    <para>Manu started working on this project. He had to learn a lot of new things, but he put a
      lot of effort into that and in the end, there is completely new SaX3. It uses <ulink
        url="http://sourceforge.net/projects/libyui/">libyui</ulink>ýfor GUI toolkits abstraction.
      It is able to run as Qt, GTK or even ncurses application. It uses <ulink
        url="http://augeas.net/">Augeas</ulink> to parse xorg.conf.d files and during the summer
      even the Augeas Xorg lens was improved to support things that were needed. During the SaX3
      talk, you will learn, what SaX3 can do for you, how it works and also a little bit about
      interesting technologies beneath.</para>
    <para>If you are eager to see, what it already can do, you can check <ulink
        url="http://sysbytes.wordpress.com/tag/sax/">Manu’s blog about SaX3</ulink> and especially
        <ulink url="http://sysbytes.wordpress.com/2011/07/08/sax3-get-your-hands-dirt/">Get your
        hand dirty post</ulink></para>
    <!--($ ld: 19.8.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>

  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/10/18/the-third-opensuse-conference-keynote/"
        >The third openSUSE Conference Keynote</ulink></title>
    <para>This Wednesday the 2nd openSUSE Conference 2010 opens its
      doors and we are very happy to announce the third keynote
      today.</para>
    <para>The Desktop and the Cloud – Thoughts about Freedom on Thursday
      morning at 9:30 am. How relevant is the desktop in a world where
      computing is happening in the cloud?</para>
    <para>The motto for our conference is one of the basic ideas of
      openSUSE: Collaboration across borders. This is why we are
      especially proud to have this subject addressed in a keynote by
      two key people from the free desktop world: Cornelius Schumacher,
      president of KDE e.V., and Vincent Untz, former president of the
      GNOME Foundation. (...)</para>
  </blockquote>
  <!-- More entries here... -->
</sect1>
