<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
<!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.samba.org/samba/news/releases/3.6.0.html">Samba Team Releases Version 3.6</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The Samba Team is proud to announce the release of Samba 3.6, a major new release of the award-winning Free Software file, print and authentication server suite for Microsoft Windows® clients.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">The First Free Software SMB2 Server</emphasis></para>
      <para>Samba 3.6 includes the first Free Software implementation of Microsoft&apos;s new SMB2 file serving protocol. SMB2 within Samba is implemented with a brand new asynchronous server architecture, allowing Samba to display the performance enhancements SMB2 brings to Microsoft networking technology.</para>
      <para>Samba&apos;s new SMB2 server has been tested by major vendors and has been able to double the performance of some network applications when run in conjunction with Microsoft Windows 7® clients. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 12.8.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
<!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://dot.kde.org/2011/07/23/social-events-desktop-summit">Social Events at the Desktop Summit</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>We are pleased to announce the Desktop Summit social events, bringing even more excitement and fun to the Conference program. The social events vary from sports to parties, and will take place throughout the week in different locations in Berlin. They will provide opportunities for attendees to get together informally while enjoying foods and drinks provided by our sponsors—Intel, Collabora, SUSE, Igalia and corporate partner, c-base. (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>-->  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.itworld.com/mobile-wireless/191083/kde-50-roadmap-announced">ITworld/Brian Proffitt: KDE 5.0 roadmap announced</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The KDE desktop is about to take a major step forward, with the announcement today of
        the roadmap for KDE Frameworks 5.0.</para>
      <para>Most eyes in the Linux desktop world are on the Berlin Desktop Summit this week, as
        members of the GNOME and KDE camps come together for a joint technical conference running
        from August 6-12 at Humboldt University in Berlin. Currently, KDE seems to be making the
        most strides in the joint event, with the surprise announcement of the KDE 5.0 roadmap,
        which was revealed by KDE developer Aaron Seigo in his blog Sunday.</para>
      <para>According to Seigo, the new KDE Frameworks roadmap, which will encompass &quot;the next major
        release of KDE&apos;s libraries and runtime requirements,&quot; will have an &quot;emphasis... on
        modularity, dependency clarity/simplification and increasing quality to the next level.&quot;
        (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 8.8.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/cisco-and-twitter-join-linux-patent-protection-pool/9372">ZDNet/Steven J. Vaughan-Nichols: Cisco and Twitter join Linux patent protection pool</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>In case you’ve been under a rock for the last decade, you might not know that today’s technology wars aren’t over who has the best prices, the most features, or the greatest quality. No, in 2011, instead of working on innovating, tech. giants like Apple, Microsoft, and Oracle, are now wasting their resources on intellectual property (IP) lawsuits. So, perhaps it should come as no surprise that networking powerhouse <ulink url="http://www.cisco.com/">Cisco</ulink> and social networking force <ulink url="http://www.twitter.com/">Twitter</ulink>, is joining the Linux patent protection group, the <ulink url="http://www.openinventionnetwork.com/">Open Invention Network (OIN)</ulink>. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 12.8.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://olex.openlogic.com/wazi/2011/libreoffice-vs-openoffice-org-showdown-for-best-open-source-office-suite/">Wazi/Brian Proffitt: LibreOffice vs. OpenOffice.org: Showdown for Best Open Source Office Suite</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>With the release of a new version of&#160;<ulink url="http://www.libreoffice.org/">LibreOffice</ulink>&#160;this month, it’s a good time to look at the two major open source
        office suites, LibreOffice and<ulink url="http://olex.openlogic.com/packages/openoffice">OpenOffice.org</ulink>, to see what advantages each offers, and which is a better bet for
        end users.</para>
      <para>Both products are suites of office applications, comprising word process, spreadsheet,
        presentation graphics, database, drawing, and math tools. Both also spring from the same
        code base. OpenOffice.org was created by a German company called Star Division, which Sun
        Microsystems bought in 1999. Originally the suite was called StarOffice, and it was popular
        in the European market as an alternative to Microsoft Office. After picking it up, Sun
        changed the name of the product to OpenOffice.org and released its code as open source. The
        product retained some popularity in the enterprise, partly because of its cross-platform
        capabilities and no-cost license.</para>
      <para>In 2009, Oracle announced it would be acquiring Sun, and many wondered what would become
        of OpenOffice.org. When Oracle proved to be less than willing to share its plans for the
        product, a number of<ulink url="http://listarchives.documentfoundation.org/www/announce/msg00000.html">OpenOffice.org community members opted to fork the OpenOffice.org code</ulink>. In November 2010, they
        created LibreOffice, to be managed by a new German non-profit called&#160;<ulink url="http://www.documentfoundation.org/">The Document Foundation</ulink>.</para>
      <para>A few months later,&#160;<ulink url="http://lwn.net/Articles/446093/">Oracle opted to donate the OpenOffice.org project to the Apache Software Foundation</ulink>, which today
        maintains OpenOffice.org as a so-called podling project until OpenOffice.org completes the
        migration process to become fully integrated within the Apache organization. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 9.8.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.renewablepcs.com/about-linux/kde-gnome-or-xfce">Charles E. Craig, Jr.: What is the difference between GNOME, KDE, Xfce, and LXDE?</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>In Linux, there are so many choices, and this includes the desktop environments and window managers. Four of the most popular <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Desktop_environment">desktop environments</ulink> in Linux are <ulink url="http://www.gnome.org/">GNOME</ulink>, <ulink url="http://www.kde.org/">KDE</ulink>, <ulink url="http://www.xfce.org/">Xfce</ulink>, and <ulink url="http://lxde.org/">LXDE</ulink>. All four offer sophisticated point-and-click <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graphical_user_interface">graphical user interfaces (GUI)</ulink> which are on par with the desktop environments found in <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Windows">Windows</ulink> and <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mac_osx">Mac OS X</ulink>. When you ask different people which of these four is best, you will likely get many different answers. So which is the best between GNOME, KDE, Xfce, and LXDE? Well..... it is largely a matter of opinion, and the capabilities of your computer hardware can also be important in deciding. For example, users with older computers will be better served to choose Xfce or especially LXDE, while users with newer hardware can get more desktop effects by choosing GNOME or KDE. My recommendation would be to try all four of these desktop environments and decide for yourself which one works best for you. GNOME, KDE, Xfce, and LXDE are all excellent and to varying degrees each can be customized in a number of ways. My personal favorite is GNOME 2.x which is slowly being replaced by GNOME 3, though (very fortunately) GNOME 2.x is still being kept alive in <ulink url="http://www.linuxmint.com/">Linux Mint</ulink>, <ulink url="http://www.debian.org/">Debian</ulink>, and some other distros. Of the most recent desktop environments, my favorite is the newly-released Xfce 4.8. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 12.8.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.networkworld.com/community/node/77342">Network World/Stephen Spector: Can you be open source and not open source?</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Most people think of open source projects having the following features in common:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Source Code Access</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Process to Submit Code Changes</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Process to Submit Bugs</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Documentation (at varying levels of quality)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Ownership of Project Trademark</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Public Release Schedule</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>Of course, there may be other items that are commonly considered features, however, I want to focus on the second bullet; Process to Submit Code Changes. If an open source project has all of the above features except doesn’t accept code changes, is it no longer an open source project? (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 12.8.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://olex.openlogic.com/wazi/2011/four-steps-toward-a-successful-open-source-project/">Wazi/Carla Schroder: Four Steps Toward a Successful Open Source Project</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>There’s a lot to like about open source software. It can help your business by cutting costs and producing better software. It’s open, auditable, and customizable, and free of the restrictive, invasive licenses and EULAs that infest proprietary software. You can build a community around an open source project, one that incorporates contributions from both staff and outside developers. If you’re wondering how to start up and manage a genuine open source project, here are four fundamental tasks to get you started: start small, build trust and social capital, start smart, and build for the future. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 12.8.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/technology/news/8691096/10-year-old-girl-hacker-discovers-smartphone-security-flaw.html">The Telegraph: 10-year-old girl hacker discovers smartphone security flaw</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>A 10-year-old girl has uncovered a security flaw in popular Android and iOS games after
      becoming “bored” at their slow pace.</para>
      <figure id="farmville">
        <title>Farmville is similar to the type of game vulnerable to the attack</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="http://i.telegraph.co.uk/multimedia/archive/01825/farmvilleweb_1825823c.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>The young hacker, whose real name has not been disclosed, presented her findings at the
        Defcon conference in Las Vegas as part of a competition to find the next generation of
        computer security experts.</para>
      <para>Going by the hacker name “CyFi”, she found that she could manually advance the clock in
        unnamed games to avoid waiting for virtual crops to grow. Independent researchers have
        confirmed the vulnerability.</para>
      <para>She<emphasis role="bold">
          <ulink url="http://download.cnet.com/8301-2007_4-20089152-12/10-year-old-hacker-finds-zero-day-flaw-in-games/">told CNET</ulink>
        </emphasis>: “It was hard to make progress in the game, because it
        took so long for things to grow. So I thought, &apos;Why don&apos;t I just change the time?’”</para>
      <para>CyFi’s hack also involved circumventing measures within the games designed to catch such
        cheating. She found that disconnecting the device from WiFi and advancing the clock in small
        increments avoided detection.</para>
      <para>It has not been revealed how much control the technique grants an attacker over a device
        or which games are vulnerable, to allow developers to patch the security flaw.</para>
<!--($ ld: 10.8.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
<!--
  <sect2>
  <title>LOL</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
        <ulink url="http://xkcd.com/874/">FOSS Force: Top 10 Things Linux Users Don't
          Understand</ulink>
      </title>
      <para/>
  </blockquote>
</sect2> --></sect1>
