<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="tipsandtricks">
  <title>Tips and Tricks</title>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Desktop Users</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxjournal.com/content/working-frames-and-objects-scribus"
          >LinuxJournal/Bruce Byfield: Working with Frames and Objects in Scribus</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><quote>A Scribus document consists of a series of objects that are added to a page, and
          contained within a frame. In addition to the usual cut, copy, and paste functions
          available in most applications, frames in Scribus share a general set of editing
          attributes and, so far as possible, the same set of properties. As you can see from the
          Insert menu, Scribus supports four basic types of frame: <ulink
            url="http://www.linuxjournal.com/content/text-frames-scribus">text</ulink>, <ulink
            url="http://www.linuxjournal.com/content/working-images-scribus">image</ulink>, table
          and drawing primitives. Table frames are collections of individual text frames, which may
          be edited either as a group or as individual cells, while drawing primitives are
          sub-divided into shape, polygon, line, Bezier curve, and freehand line. Frames for
          primitives are added with the content, while the content of other frames must be added
          separately.</quote> (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 14.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Commandline/Script Newbies</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxconfig.org/practical-guide-to-linux-commands">Linuxconfig.org: A
          Practical Guide to Linux Commands</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>This article lists various practical Linux commands to be used only as a reference guide
        and by experienced Linux users. Not all Linux commands will be available on your system by
        default so consider install a relevant package before use. This Practical Guide to Linux
        Commands may list Linux commands you already know but cannot remember usage syntax as well
        as it may introduce some new Linux commands to improve your Linux command line efficiency.
        Note, this guide will not teach you how to use Linux commands since it relies on your
        experience to alter Linux commands syntax below to fit your needs. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 10.2.11 sat $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Developers and Programmers</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://mindby.com/2011/02/celery-and-twisted/">Brent McConnell: Celery and
          Twisted</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>"I’ve been working with <ulink url="http://celeryproject.org/">Celery</ulink>, <ulink
          url="http://twistedmatrix.com/trac/">Twisted</ulink> and <ulink
          url="https://github.com/fiorix/cyclone">Cyclone</ulink> recently on a side project I have
        going on, however the integration between Celery and Twisted is not ideal for asynchronous
        programming which prompted me to jot down some notes for what I’ve worked out. Hopefully
        this will be useful to someone, also if anyone wants to offer a better way I’m all ears :) . </para>
      <para>Celery has some built in methods to allow you to check the completeness of a remote job
        by calling the successful() method on a returned AsyncResult object. For example you can do
        something like this…" (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 14.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For System Administrators</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.ibm.com/developerworks/linux/library/l-lpic3-310-1/index.html">IBM
          developerWorks/Sean A. Walberg: Learn Linux, 302 (Mixed environments): Concepts</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>In this article, learn about these concepts: </para>
      <para>* Server Message Block (SMB)/Common Internet File System (CIFS) </para>
      <para>* File sharing </para>
      <para>* Print service </para>
      <para>This article helps you prepare for Objective 310.1 in Topic 310 of the LPI&apos;s Mixed
        Environment speciality exam (302). The objective has a weight of 1. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 10.2.11 sat $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.phpbuilder.com/columns/phpmyadmin/Jason_Gilmore02082011.php3">PHP
          Builder/W. Jason Gilmore: Top 10 phpMyAdmin Tips and Tricks You May Not Know</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>First released in 1998, <ulink url="http://www.phpmyadmin.net/">phpMyAdmin</ulink> is
        one of the longest running and most popular PHP projects on the planet. One of the first
        utilities mentioned within PHP and MySQL tutorials, and ubiquitously available on Web
        hosting providers, over the years phpMyAdmin has grown to be an indispensable tool within
        every PHP developer&apos;s toolbox.</para>
      <para>Despite approaching its 12th birthday, phpMyAdmin is still under active development,
        with at least one significant version released every year since the project&apos;s
        inception. In fact even after almost a decade of use I still marvel over discovering
        features which I had no idea existed. In this article I thought I&apos;d highlight 10 useful
        phpMyAdmin features which may have escaped you during your daily interaction with this
        fantastic utility. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 10.2.11 sat $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
