<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://blixtra.org/blog/2011/01/21/first-experiences-with-the-opensuse-build-service-obs/"
        >blixtra Blog/Chris Kühl: First experiences with the OpenSUSE Build Service</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>As part of my <ulink url="http://www.openismus.com/">Openismus</ulink>
      <ulink url="http://www.murrayc.com/blog/permalink/2010/03/09/what-our-trainees-learn/"
        >training</ulink>, I was recently tasked with packaging a Qt application using the <ulink
        url="https://build.opensuse.org/">OpenSUSE Build Service</ulink> (OBS). Here I’ll try to
      note my first impressions as well as offer some solutions to problems I encountered.<note>
        <para>This was my first attempt at packaging anything and the application I’m packaging
            (<ulink url="http://gitorious.org/conferencegoer">ConferenceGoer</ulink>) is a personal
          project which is in an unusably-early state. So let’s ignore all that and focus on OBS
          itself.</para>
      </note></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">What is OBS </emphasis></para>
    <para>The OBS allows a packager to create packages for multiple distributions and architectures
      using one spec file for <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RPM_Package_Manager">RPM
        packages</ulink> or one set of debian packaging files for <ulink
        url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deb_(file_format)">debian packages</ulink>. For example,
      in <ulink url="https://build.opensuse.org/project/show?project=home:blixtra">my OpenSUSE OBS
        repository</ulink> I’ve built packages for multiple releases of <ulink
        url="http://fedoraproject.org/">Fedora</ulink>, <ulink url="http://www.ubuntu.com/"
        >Ubuntu</ulink>, <ulink url="http://www.opensuse.org/">OpenSUSE</ulink>, <ulink
        url="http://www.mageia.org/">Mandriva</ulink> and <ulink url="http://www.debian.org/"
        >Debian</ulink> for the i586 and x86_64 architectures from one set of package files. </para>
    <para>Despite the “OpenSUSE” in the name, the OBS is useful for other distros as well. For
      example, the <ulink url="http://meego.com/">MeeGo</ulink> project has adopted it as its
      build-service of choice. I’ve used both and will refer to them as the <ulink
        url="https://build.opensuse.org/">OpenSUSE OBS</ulink> and <ulink
        url="https://build.pub.meego.com/">MeeGo OBS</ulink>. This is not an OBS how-to. See the
        <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Build_Service_Tutorial">OBS tutorial</ulink> for
      getting started with OBS. (...)</para>
    <para>
    </para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 23.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://nowwhatthe.blogspot.com/2011/01/my-way-or-highway.html">Jos
        Poortvliet: My way or the highway?</ulink></title>
    <para>2 days ago I wrote <ulink url="http://nowwhatthe.blogspot.com/2011/01/meetings-stuff.html"
        >an enthusiastic blog</ulink> about a cross-distribution collaboration meeting on App Stores
      we've organized in Nuremberg. Then, a day later, Canonical decided to <ulink
        url="http://www.markshuttleworth.com/archives/568">ship Qt with Ubuntu</ulink>. While not
      anything special from an openSUSE pov (we give both GTK and Qt equal treatment and offer the
      best platform to develop for both), it's a nice move. In the announcement Mark Shuttleworth
      emphasized Qt integration with Ubuntu. I specifically write Ubuntu, not GNOME/GTK - Aaron
      Seigo responded to that with a <ulink
        url="http://aseigo.blogspot.com/2011/01/qt-acceptance-growing-next-colaboration.html">blog
        post</ulink> showing a bit of frustration with Canonical's policy, the push for dconf &amp;
      Ubuntu-specific Qt integration in apps.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Yay, more flamewars! </emphasis></para>
    <para>Now I'm as big a fan of a good KDE vs GNOME flamewar as anyone and maybe we make them more
      fun by introducing a GNOME/Ubuntu and Qt/Ubuntu set of apps (what seems to be going on since
      Mark announced <ulink
        url="http://arstechnica.com/open-source/news/2010/10/shuttleworth-unity-shell-will-be-default-desktop-in-ubuntu-1104.ars"
        >Unity as default in Ubuntu</ulink>. More splitting up = more fun, and openSUSE's tagline is
      'have fun' so maybe we've been going at this all wrong. openSUSE has a focus on collaboration
      and integration. I <ulink
        url="http://nowwhatthe.blogspot.com/2010/10/osc-successful-absolutely.html">happily wrote
        about</ulink> the archievements at the openSUSE conference in that area in October - we
      worked with Red Hat, Mandriva, Debian... Over the last 3 days we had people from these and
      more distributions in Nuremberg to <ulink
        url="http://distributions.freedesktop.org/wiki/Meetings/AppInstaller2011">work on an app
        store spec for Linux</ulink>. Then, right now a second sprint has started, to <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:2011_Bretzn_Meeting">integrate appstore technology in
        openSUSE itself</ulink>. Yes, 2 birds, one stone: first we discuss cooperation, then
      implement results. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Learning... </emphasis></para>
    <para>We do things that way because at Novell, we've made our share of mistakes. And we learned
      - we don't tell our community what openSUSE is going to do, we let them choose. Yes, Novell
      ships GNOME on their Enterprise Desktop. The community has KDE as default. Up to them. We work
      with others because, you know, the Free Software ecosystem matters. "It is an ill bird that
      fouls its own nest". A saying well over 1000 years old but quite relevant. I wonder if
      Canonical is going to repeat those mistakes... Now maybe Mark is right, creating a special
      Ubuntu world for application developers will create more fun. Or maybe we're right - letting
      the community do it's thing is more fun. I dunno. But if anyone is unhappy about Mark telling
      you what to do in Ubuntu, you're welcome here to help shape openSUSE how you want it! Which
      includes bringing <ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/12/29/kick-off-for-gnomeayatana-project/">Ayatana to
        openSUSE</ulink>. Or <ulink
        url="http://www.wafaa.eu/entry/smeegol-status---08dec10-1-45.html">MeeGo</ulink>. And Mark,
      if you happen to hear Aaron and decide Canonical should cooperate a bit more with others,
      we're always open for that! (...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 23.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://mschlander.wordpress.com/2011/01/23/kde-is-slow-for-dummies/">Martin
        Schlander: KDE is slow – for dummies</ulink></title>
    <para>On forums, IRC, mailing lists etc. you get a lot of people complaining that “KDE is slow”.
      I finally got fed up trying to answer the same question over and over, hence I’m writing this
      blog post, to explain how most people can solve their problem in a few very simple steps.
      (...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 23.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://nowwhatthe.blogspot.com/2011/01/meetings-stuff.html">Jos Poortvliet:
        Meetings</ulink></title>
    <para>I just heard from Vincent that the <ulink
        url="http://distributions.freedesktop.org/wiki/Meetings/AppInstaller2011">Cross-distro app
        installer</ulink> meeting organized by openSUSE is in full swing. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Cross distribution Appstore Sprint </emphasis></para>
    <para>As Vincent wrote <ulink
        url="http://www.vuntz.net/journal/post/2011/01/18/Cross-distribution-meeting-on-application-installer"
        >in his blog</ulink>, the idea came up at the openSUSE conference. We should work on getting
      distributions on the same page when it comes to a Linux Appstore technology. Appstore API's
      have been in development for ages on linux so we have a strong base. The as the <ulink
        url="http://freedesktop.org/wiki/Specifications/open-collaboration-services">Open
        Collaboration Services</ulink> we currently have on freedesktop.org are inspired by the
      GetHotNewStuff technology which was developed by Josef Spillner many years ago - KDE and GNOME
      have used this to deliver wallpapers and scripts to their users. After GHNS, two possible
      successors were developed - OCS, started by Frank Karlitschek, seems the de-facto standard
      now. It was adopted by Maemo and now by MeeGo for their appstore, openoffice.org supports it
      and of course the family of <ulink url="http://opendesktop.org">opendesktop.org</ulink> series
      of sites including the popular gtk-apps.org, qt-apps.org, GNOME- and KDE-look.org are all
      accessible from this API. </para>
    <para>At the <ulink url="http://distributions.freedesktop.org/wiki/Meetings/AppInstaller2011"
        >cross-distro appinstaller meeting</ulink> which started this morning people from several
      distributions including Red Hat, Mandriva and Debian are discussing together how Linux should
      tackle this. Can we agree on a common technology shared between distributions and Desktops?
      Hopefully we can bring together the work on <ulink
        url="http://blogs.gnome.org/hughsie/2010/09/07/linux-and-application-installing/">app
        install</ulink> by <ulink url="http://blogs.gnome.org/hughsie">Richard</ulink>, the <ulink
        url="https://wiki.ubuntu.com/SoftwareCenter">Software Center</ulink> tech from Ubuntu and
      FD.o's <ulink url="http://freedesktop.org/wiki/Specifications/open-collaboration-services"
        >Open Collaboration Services</ulink> in a way that benefits all. </para>
    <para>I had a quick phone call with Frank who told me the meeting is very constructive and he
      hopes that the major distributions can agree on some kind of standard by the end of this week.
      That would be pretty awesome! The appstore sprint aims to bring people on the same page and
      will be followed by a Bretzn sprint for openSUSE. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Bretzn Sprint </emphasis></para>
    <para>At the Bretzn sprint (also sponsored by openSUSE) the goal is to get something done: work
      on appstore integration in openSUSE, as well as smoothen the process of building and
      distributing an application for developers. Bretzn, <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/10/26/from-the-developer-to-the-user-and-back-announcing-project-bretzn/"
        >first announced at the openSUSE conference in October</ulink>, is almost ready for its
      first release. At the sprint, Pavol Rusnak, who developed a web based openSUSE Games store,
      will also be present - I hope he can make sure we also have a web-accessible store for
      openSUSE! </para>
    <para>While it is unsure if the work on Bretzn and the openSUSE appstore will make it into
      openSUSE 11.4, it is clear that openSUSE is pushing innovation and standardization in the
      Linux market. Not going all alone, but thinking and caring about the larger ecosystem - I
      think that is what separates a real community effort from a company pushing a corporate
      agenda. Bringing the right people with the right skills and the right ideas together is what
      these sprints are all about - I'm happy to have helped make it possible. And less happy that I
      couldn't be there myself, there is little in the world of Free Software that gives me more
      energy than being at a developer sprint! </para>
    <para>I'd like to thank Frank and Vincent for organizing, as well as all the attendees for
      attending and I look forward to their blogs and <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org"
        >news.o.o</ulink> article ;-) </para>
    <para>Good luck and Rock the Boat!</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 18.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://blog.hennevogel.de/why-we-are-here/">Henne Vogelsang: Why we are
        here.</ulink></title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://blog.hennevogel.de/files/2011/01/12694840_204ab9cba6_o.jpg"
          width="25%" align="center"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>I’m chewing on something for a couple of weeks now and I think I need to tell you before
      my jaw turns into dust. It’s about the <ulink url="http://www.opensuse.org">openSUSE
        Project</ulink> and what’s happening with it. I’m heavily involved in the project. Since
      over 10 years I get paid by my employer to work in that project and I spend a lot of my spare
      time on it. It’s a huge part of my life, both personal and professional and I love it! I love
      the people, I love how the project is set up and I love all the cool results we produce
      together. But since a couple of weeks, I couldn’t really pin down if there was a single cause,
      what it was or when, I was in misery about it. It’s only yesterday that while talking to a
      fellow <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board">openSUSE Board</ulink> member that I
      realized what really causes my grief. All of the sudden this project went from “<emphasis
        role="bold">Hey dude, let’s do cool things together</emphasis>” to “<emphasis role="bold">I
        have this and that opinion and I’m going to stick it to you!</emphasis>”. The whole project
      went from collaboration to politics in a blink. Now I’m sure all of you tin foil hat wearing
      people out there will start to spin this as result of some single event, whatever fits your
      agenda best, but I assure you it’s not. Sometime in the last couple of weeks this tipped over
      and we started to have discussions about all aspects of the theory of politics, we argue about
      human rights or quotes from Mahatma Gandhi, people put up motions for the powers that be, the
      structure and people are questioned to the last extent, alliances are forged, opportunities
      are seized to get even and a lot of distrust is spreading around. </para>
    <para>And there are two answers so far I have heard. One is that people say that this is normal.
      Because we as open source project always ask for equal rights, democracy and all these other
      crazy liberal ideas and that now <emphasis role="bold">we reap what we sow:
        politics</emphasis>. So however you are involved in this, like me for instance that stood up
      and took responsibility for nasty things nobody else wants to do, you have asked for this and
      now got what was coming to you. <emphasis role="bold">Don’t be a crybaby now, bitch!
      </emphasis></para>
    <para>The other answer I see to this from the members of our project is to be passive. <emphasis
        role="bold">YAWN politics</emphasis>… I want to code, draw, write, fix, test. Politics are
      not of my interest and I don’t want to get involved. You idiots can fight this out, I just
      work on my stuff while you’re doing that. So however you are involved in this, like me for
      instance that stood up and took responsibility for nasty things nobody else wants to do, you
      have asked for this and now got what was coming to you. <emphasis role="bold">Don’t look at
        me, not interested!</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>Both are equally destructive and neglect the reason all of us are here. We are here for
      one thing: <emphasis role="bold">FUN</emphasis>! Yes, remember please why you have came to the
      openSUSE Project. Because it’s fun to use the software for any purpose you want. Because it’s
      great to study how the software works, and change it to make it do what you wish. Because it’s
      cool to redistribute copies so you can help your neighbor. Because it’s a great feeling to
      give the whole community a chance to benefit from your work. You know what’s wrong with us? We
      have forgot to Have a lot of fun! </para>
    <para>Can all of you who love openSUSE please go to a console, open an xterm, gnome-terminal or
      a konsole, do a <emphasis role="italic">cat /etc/motd</emphasis> and think about the output
      for a while? </para>
    <para>Then pull yourself together and stop doing what is robbing ALL OF US of the reason we are
      here! If you want to push through your agenda, don’t! If you want to stick it to the man,
      don’t! If you want to insist on all of your given rights, don’t! If you want to be pigheaded,
      don’t. If you want to be serious, don’t! </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Instead, remember to Have a lot of fun!</emphasis></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 20.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
