<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="tipsandtricks">
  <title>Tips and Tricks</title>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Desktop Users</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.unixmen.com/linux-tutorials/1823-how-to-make-your-own-20th-century-fox-and-lionsgate-intro-with-blender-25-"
          >Unixmen/M. Zinoune: How to make your own 20th Century Fox and LIONSGATE intro with
          Blender 2.5 in 5 min</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>This is an easy tutorial on how to make your own 20th Century Fox and  LIONSGATE styled
        intro using Blender 2.5. It is very easy you just need to donwload the templates blender and
        follow the instructions, it shouldn't take more than 5-10 minutes to edit it.  To do this,
        you need to have Blender 2.5 or above installed in your system, if you are an ubuntu or
        LinuxMint  user, you can install the latest release of blender using PPA from<ulink
          url="http://www.unixmen.com/linux-tutorials/1714-blender-257-is-released-with-a-new-design-multiple-windows-support-and-more"
          > this link</ulink>. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 23.7.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.linux.com/learn/tutorials/470411:screencasting-stars-of-the-linux-world"
          >Linux.com/Nathan Willis: Screencasting Stars of the Linux World</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Are you still taking screenshots? That is sooo last decade. Today if you want to
        showcase your application, your gaming skills, or even your astonishing new desktop
        wallpaper collection, you need a screen recorder (or screencasting tool) to capture
        full-motion video and audio of your desktop. You'll find several solid options, but which
        one works best for you depends a lot on the type of content you need to capture, and what
        you intend to do with it.For starters, the output produced by the tool varies considerably.
        Some alternatives give you a wide choice of video and audio codecs, others just one. But if
        that one (say, Flash) is the one you need, producing it directly is much quicker than having
        to save an intermediary file and crank it through a video editor. It also may be important
        to select just a portion of the screen rather than your whole display, or to choose a
        specific frame-rate (high for games, low for bandwidth-saving demos). Finally, there are
        always special features that vary between utilities, such as whether or not they can capture
        OpenGL content or be started remotely by script. (...)</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Editors Note:</emphasis> Both <ulink url="http://bit.ly/qoyFx6"
          >recordMyDesktop</ulink> and <ulink url="http://bit.ly/p94swf">Istanbul</ulink> are
        available via OBS.</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 23.7.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Commandline/Script Newbies</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://cgoncalves.blogspot.com/2011/07/ssh-connection-automation.html">Carlos
          Gonçalves: SSH connection automation</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Part of my daily routine envolves accessing and managing a considered amount of remote
        servers through the SSH protocol. I use screen a lot to ease the job by having a couple of
        windows opened on each server, so avoiding multiple connections to the same server. By using
        screen not only helps me grouping server windows altogether in one console window/tab but
        also is a time saver in those days when network connection is not in its glory days allowing
        me to reattach it and carrying on being productive (*sighs*). (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 19.7.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.jveweb.net/en/archives/2011/06/split-and-merge-files-from-the-command-line.html"
          >Juan Valencia: Split and merge files from the command line</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Although some file archivers offer us the option of split the files, this can be easily
        accomplished with two commands: split and cat. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 23.7.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://paskov.biz/blog/?p=724">Vladimir Paskov: Using the rpm command –
          part1</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>RPM is a package management system widely used in various GNU/Linux distributions such
        as: openSUSE, RedHat, CentOS and Fedora. All this distributions provides various package
        management tools build around librpm (This library allows programs to make use of a rpm
        database or rpm packages without using the rpm command ) or making direct use of
        the rpm command. Examples of this includes: zypper – openSUSE package management tool andyum
        – Fedora and Red Hat package management tool. This tools provides easy to use functionality
        for installing, removing, searching, repository management etc, but they lack some
        functionality provided by the rpm command such as listing the contents of a package, finding
        what package provides some file etc.</para>
      <para>This article will show you how you can use the rpm command to preform various package
        management task , such as installing, removing, querying the rpm database, etc…</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 23.7.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Developers and Programmers</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://kdemonkey.blogspot.com/2011/07/qt-inspector.html">Robert Knight: Qt
          Inspector</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Whilst debugging a widget layout problem a few days ago, I was looking around for a tool
        to view the structure of a Qt application without having to recompile it, or in other words,
        Firebug / Web Inspector for Qt widgets.  I found the <ulink
          url="http://blogs.kde.org/node/799">KSpy</ulink> tool in the KDE repositories which is in
        need of some love and there are a variety of tools to aid in runtime debugging and
        modification of QML but not much in the way of tools for QWidget-based interfaces.  Please
        let me know in the comments if I missed any.</para>
      <para>I have put together a simple tool called <ulink
          url="https://github.com/robertknight/Qt-Inspector">Qt Inspector</ulink>.</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 22.7.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://python4kids.wordpress.com/2011/07/18/tkinter-tinkering-graphical-user-interfaces/"
          >Python4Kids/Brendan Scott: Tkinter tinkering (Graphical User Interfaces)</ulink></title>
      <para>Man     Shut up! (It goes quiet next door) That’s better.He walks to a side wall and
        hangs his club on a hook beneath big old-fashioned art-nouveau sign clearly labelled `The
        Burlington Wall-banger’. He goes across to bed and gets in. In the bed are a party of four
        Japanese businessmen in suits with lapel badges, two lady American tourists with rain hats
        and cameras, three other moustached English gentlemen in pyjamas, four Tour De France
        riders, three Swedish businessmen, and Winston Churchill.</para>
      <para>So far we have been dealing with a command line interface for working with our Python
        programs.  While command lines are good for a lot of things, they’re usually pretty bad for
        interfacing with a general user of the program who doesn’t know how the various pieces
        work.  What we are going to look at now is a different way of presenting the program to a
        user (and probably a way that you are more familiar with) – GUIs.   GUI stands for
        “Graphical User Interface”. (...)</para>
      <!--($ Id: 23.7.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://olex.openlogic.com/wazi/2011/tips-for-using-vim-as-an-ide/"
          >Wazi/Juliet Kemp: Tips for using Vim as an IDE</ulink></title>
      <para><ulink url="http://olex.openlogic.com/packages/vim">Vim</ulink> isn’t just a great
        editor; it’s also a hugely flexible, configurable, and extendable application. You can even
        set up Vim as an integrated development environment (IDE), giving you all the advantages of
        a dedicated text editor together with the ability to check syntax, jump between tags,
        autocomplete, and do all the other useful things you get from a modern IDE. These Vim tips
        and tricks will get you editing like a pro. (...)</para>
      <!--($ Id: 23.7.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://net.tutsplus.com/tutorials/ruby/how-to-build-a-shortlink-app-with-ruby-and-redis/"
          >net.tutsplus.com/Charlie Somerville: How to Build a Shortlink App with Ruby and
          Redis</ulink></title>
      <para>In this tutorial, we’ll be building a quick shortlink web app with Ruby, the <ulink
          url="http://www.sinatrarb.com/">Sinatra</ulink> web framework, and the<ulink
          url="http://redis.io/">Redis</ulink> database. By the conclusion of this tutorial, you’ll
        end up with a dead simple, high performance shortlink webapp that’s super easy to scale.
        (...)</para>
      <!--($ Id: 23.7.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For System Administrators</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.linux.com/learn/tutorials/469597-weekend-project-keep-out-repeat-offenders-with-fail2ban-on-linux"
          >Linux.com/Jack Wallen: Weekend Project: Keep Out Repeat Offenders with Fail2ban on
          Linux</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Tired of automated attacks on your systems? Want to beef up security a bit by denying
        would-be attackers a third or fourth chance? Then you need <ulink
          url="http://www.fail2ban.org/">Fail2ban</ulink>. Fail2ban watches logs and then bans IP
        addresses, based on too many password failures, by updating the firewall rules. Specific
        rules can be defined by the user and multiple log files can be monitored. This weekend,
        let's get started on improving security with Fail2ban. (...)</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Editors Note:</emphasis>
        <ulink url="http://bit.ly/oVbsbq">Fail2ban</ulink> packages for openSUSE are available from
        OBS</para>
      <!--($ Id: 23.7.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://www.linux.com/learn/tutorials/470979-who-and-what-is-on-my-network-probing-your-network-with-linux"
          >Linux.com/Carla Schroder: Who and What Is On My Network? Probing Your Network with
          Linux</ulink></title>
      <para>In <ulink
          url="http://www.linux.com/component/content/article/174-tutorials/443706-whose-fault-is-it-when-your-internet-dies-troubleshooting-networks-with-linux"
          >Whose Fault is it When Your Internet Dies? Troubleshooting Networks with Linux</ulink> we
        learned some basic network troubleshooting commands. Today we're going to explore the fine
        fun world of network discovery and find out who is on our network without ever leaving our
        comfortable chairs.</para>
      <!--($ Id: 23.7.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
