<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.bryen.com/getting-articles-into-news-opensuse-org">Nelson Marques:
        openSUSE 12.1 delivers GTK+ 3.2 with Broadway backend!</ulink></title>
    <para>On the 25th of September 2001, <ulink url="http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/User:Mclasen"
        >Mathias Clasen</ulink> announces the <ulink
        url="http://mail.gnome.org/archives/gtk-devel-list/2011-September/msg00175.html">release of
        GTK+ 3.2.0</ulink>. This release includes delivers:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Many improvements to the CSS theming support;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Width-for-height support in many more widgets (ex: GtkPanel, GtkMenuBar,
            GtkNotebook, etc);</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>New experimental Wayland and <emphasis role="bold">HTML5 ‘Broadway’
              backeds</emphasis>;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>GtkFileChooser and GtkAssistant received face-lifts;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>New widgets (ex: GtkLockButton and GtkOverlay, etc);</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <!--($ ld: 03.10.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.wafaa.eu/entry/hardware-needed-for-opensuse-on-arm-1-71.html"
        >Andrew Wafaa: Hardware needed for openSUSE on ARM</ulink></title>
    <para>As I <ulink url="http://www.wafaa.eu/entry/target-arm-hardware-1-70.html"
        >mentioned</ulink> before, we have an initial target platform identified for testing the
      work of all those involved in the openSUSE ARM port. The problem is we need to obtain the
      hardware.</para>
    <para>I am in discussions trying to get some corporate sponsorship of hardware, but we can not
      rely soley on those kind companies that would like to see us succeed. We as a community need
      to help ourselves succeed, as such I've set up a <ulink
        url="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/16098">campaign</ulink> on Pledgie to enable us the
      community to contribute to the effort for obtaining hardware. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 05.10.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://openleadership.blogspot.com/2011/10/looking-back-at-opensuse-conferece-osc.html"
        >Gregory M. Zysk: Looking back at the openSUSE Conference 2011 (oSC)</ulink></title>
    <para>Well, once again, I had a chance to meet a community, one of which, I have never met
      before ;-) </para>
    <para>I arrived at <ulink url="http://www.zentrifuge-nuernberg.de/">Zentrifuge</ulink> on the
      10th of September for the warmup to the <ulink url="http://conference.opensuse.org/"
        >oSC</ulink>. Immediately after arrival, I was greeted with warm smiles, open discussions,
      and cold beer ;-) No one knew who I was, but they all welcomed me. As the evening continued, I
      was witness to how the community also made sure that they welcomed everyone, once they
      arrived. This is pure class and I would like to say is very important to a newbie who is
      entering the community. This is one aspect where openSUSE makes the difference, since it is
      not practiced to this extent in many other communities. </para>
    <!--($ ld: 05.10.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://blog.cboltz.de/archives/63-1001-bugs-or-the-golden-rules-of-bad-programming.html"
        >Gregory M. Zysk: openSUSE Marketing Hackfest 2011</ulink></title>
    <para>On the 15th and 16 of September 2011, following the oSC, the marketing team held a
      Marketing Hackfest at the SUSE headquarters in Nuremberg, Germany. </para>
    <para>I was asked to attend this event for several reasons aside from the normal Marketing
      related things, two of which were the most important to me being new to this event. One, was
      to observe how the marketing team functions as a unit. And second, to hold meetings with
      different people to discuss certain issues with an outlook of solving them for the benefit of
      the openSUSE community. Moreover, many of us had a chance to further discuss (in person)
      initiatives started at the oSC, since we had a chance to digest them and come with some
      valuable input that was used to move things forward ;-)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 05.10.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://oyranos-cms.blogspot.com/2011/09/colour-correction-concepts-for-monitors.html"
        >Kai-Uwe Behrmann: Colour Correction Concepts for Monitors</ulink></title>
    <para>Colour management for the desktop is a long standing issue not only for Linux. The
      following text will concentrate on colour correction of monitors. This means the experience,
      when you switch your computer or handheld on and look on the screen. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Why colour correct the desktop? </emphasis></para>
    <para>People tend to compensate for quite a lot of different types of monitors. They are most
      often able to adapt to one full screen and see colours as they are intended to look like.
      Thats fine as long as they are concentrated on the visual event on that one display. But in
      this article we want to discuss how to compensate the monitor colours to our human visual
      needs in environments with various displays side by side, as is the typical situation for more
      and more people today. They take pictures with mobile phones or other digital cameras and look
      at them on laptops, tablets, picture frames, TV sets and printouts often side by side. Or we
      look at them over the internet and want to share the same visual impression with other people.
      Many people with uncorrected systems see quite a difference between various colour devices and
      try to figure out how to conveniently synchronise them. Colour management should help
      accomplish that task. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 28.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://blog.jospoortvliet.com/2011/09/tumbleweed-image-dream.html">Jos
        Poortvliet: Tumbleweed image dream</ulink></title>
    <para>At the (pretty cool) <ulink url="http://www.openmind.fi/">openMind conference in Tampere,
        Finland</ulink>, it came up that a big advantage of <ulink
        url="http://opensuse.org/Tumbleweed">Tumbleweed</ulink> is that it always has the latest
      hardware support. Thanks to the rolling release, Tumbleweed comes with the latest Linux kernel
      which plays a big part of the hardware support of a Linux distro. </para>
    <para>If your hardware does not work properly with the 'stable' release of openSUSE (or other
      distro's) trying the latest kernel can solve that. But that's hard to get on your system, even
      with stuff like <ulink url="http://kernel.opensuse.org">the openSUSE Kernel
        repositories</ulink> because it usually requires you to first <emphasis role="bold"
        >install</emphasis> something. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 28.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.bryen.com/the-video-bof">Bryen Yunashko: The Video
      BoF</ulink></title>
    <para>So, one of the Birds of a Feather (BoF) sessions at the Conference that I organized was a
      Video BoF.  Specifically, the BoF was meant to start coming up with storyboarding to create
      some cool openSUSE promotional videos (ala commercials.)  There’s a number of us with some
      great creative ideas and varying levels of exertise in this area and we just haven’t gotten
      off the ground yet on how to approach some of these ideas.  For me, (relying on “old school”
      classes I took from when I was a film major) storyboarding would have helped to define exactly
      the steps we needed in order to complete and execute the ideas many of us have.</para>
    <para>However, the general discussion quickly went in another direction, and one that I think is
      equally as important and I’m glad that conversation took place as well… (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 30.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://blog.jospoortvliet.com/2011/09/meego-and-opensuse-invitation.html">Jos
        Poortvliet: MeeGo and openSUSE - an invitation</ulink></title>
    <para>Yesterday a <ulink
        url="http://www.meegoexperts.com/2011/09/linux-foundation-limo-foundation-announce-project-tizen/"
        >big announcement was made</ulink> by Intel and Samsung. It entails another big change of
      directions for Moblin/Maemo/MeeGo.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Where to go Next</emphasis></para>
    <para>Many people in your community <ulink
        url="https://meego.com/community/blogs/imad/2011/whats-next-meego">wonder where to go
        now</ulink>. Yesterday, at a MeeGo meet in Tampere, many wondered if Intel will let the
      community contribute to Tizen. Will Samsung work in the open? Intel and Linux Foundation
      didn't build a great track record with MeeGo and some said they simply didn't believe in it
      anymore. Many clearly care about the great community which was build over the last years and
      are afraid it will break up. </para>
    <para>Aaron Seigo spoke some wise words. He said: "don't rely on what big companies might or
      might not do. Find out what YOU want and how to get there!" And indeed, community is about
      making your choices together. Not depending on corporate players acting as ADHD kids in a
      candy store, tasting every candy then dropping it. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 30.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.wafaa.eu/entry/target-arm-hardware-1-70.html">Andrew Wafaa: Target
        ARM Hardware</ulink></title>
    <para>I just sent this into the <ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-arm">-arm mailing
        list</ulink>.</para>
    <para>This is a hot topic, and one that seems to generate the most noise.</para>
    <para>I've had a discussion with several people about target hardware, and I've also looked at
      what our peers are doing and saying. At the same time I've been trying to see what options we
      have for getting some sponsorship for hardware. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 01.10.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://kfreitag.tumblr.com/post/10848737554/where-do-you-put-your-data">Klaas
        Freitag: Where do you put your data?</ulink></title>
    <para>This week is <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/09/22/suse-hackweek-7-next-week/"
        >openSUSE hackweek</ulink>, as you might know, and we do fun stuff. A couple of people, I
      was one of them, were investigating in the very promising project called <ulink
        url="http://owncloud.org">ownCloud</ulink>. We were working on a better integration in the
      openSUSE desktop in upcoming releases.</para>
    <para>Why do we like ownCloud so much? </para>
    <para>Well, thats easy: ownCloud is a solution that is under the full control of the user and as
      a result very transparent. The server, were you push your data to is owned by you. You start,
      stop, erase or open it how ever you want. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 01.10.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
