<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="tipsandtricks">
  <title>Tips and Tricks</title>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Desktop Users</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.makeuseof.com/tag/create-speech-bubbles-screenshots-gimp/">MakeUseOf/Jessica Cam Wong: How To Create Speech Bubbles For Screenshots In GIMP</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Previously we have looked at some tutorials for anyone, new or advanced, to try his/her hand at creating artwork in GIMP because it CAN accomplish phenomenal works, especially in conjunction with other open-source software. Here’s a fun tutorial to <ulink url="http://www.makeuseof.com/tag/cartoonify-photos-gimp/">cartoonify photos in GIMP</ulink> (like you see in ads all over the web), here’s another one on <ulink url="http://www.makeuseof.com/tag/create-image-map-gimp/">creating image maps</ulink>, and there’s also one on <ulink url="http://www.makeuseof.com/tag/create-simple-zoomed-effect-screenshots-gimp/">creating a zoom effect on screenshots</ulink>. I’m certainly really excited about GIMP if you can’t tell already. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 29.1.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Commandline/Script Newbies</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.unixmen.com/linux-commands/1459-useful-commands-for-daily-use">Linux.com/Jack Wallen: Reclaim Deleted Files and Repair Filesystems on Linux </ulink>
      </title>
      <para><quote>Linux is as solid an operating system as you&apos;ll ever use — but that doesn&apos;t mean that the hardware you&apos;re running it on is equally solid. Hard drives are as prone to errors as are file systems. And no matter how stable an OS is, it can&apos;t prevent you from accidentally deleting files and/or folders. But don&apos;t despair: Linux is equipped with a number of tools that can help you repair filesystem errors and reclaim deleted files. Which tools? To start, <emphasis role="bold">e2fsck</emphasis>, <emphasis role="bold">scalpel</emphasis>, and <emphasis role="bold">lsof</emphasis> will get you the farthest. Let&apos;s take a look at how each of these can be used to help your file systems be free of errors and your files be freed from accidental deletion.</quote> (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 26.1.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://bashshell.net/shell-scripts/positional-parameters/">BashShell.net/mike: Positional Parameters</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Special built-in environmental  variables are positional parameters which hold command-line arguments to positions with the names 1,2,3,4, etc. which are indicated by $1,$2,$3,$4, etc.  Argument $0 is the name of the script.   These parameters are named positional because within the script the reference is to the position they occur on the command line. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 29.1.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Developers and Programmers</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.packtpub.com/article/python-multimedia-enhancing-images">Packt/Ninad Sathaye: Python Multimedia: Enhancing Images</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Python is a high-level, object-oriented language with a comprehensive standard library. Typically, one can develop complex applications in Python very quickly compared to some other languages. Multimedia applications are used in a broad spectrum of fields. Writing applications that work with images, videos, and other sensory effects is great. Not every application gets to make full use of audio/visual effects, but a certain amount of multimedia makes any application very appealing.</para>
      <para>In this article by Ninad Sathaye, author of <ulink url="http://www.packtpub.com/python-multimedia-application-beginner%27s-guide/book/ns/pythonmulti-abr6/0111?utm_source=ns_pythonmulti_abr6_0111&amp;utm_medium=content&amp;utm_campaign=naheed">Python Multimedia</ulink>, we shall cover the following recipes:</para>
      <para>* Adjusting brightness and contrast</para>
      <para>* Swap colors within an image</para>
      <para>* Change the color of a flower (...)
</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 29.1.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://net.tutsplus.com/tutorials/php/advanced-regular-expression-tips-and-techniques/">Nettuts+/Burak Guzel: Advanced Regular Expression Tips and Techniques</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Regular Expressions are the Swiss Army knife for searching through information for certain patterns. They have a wide arsenal of tools, some of which often go undiscovered or underutilized. Today I will show you some advanced tips for working with regular expressions. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 29.1.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For System Administrators</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.howtoforge.com/vboxheadless-running-virtual-machines-with-virtualbox-4.0-on-a-headless-opensuse-11.3-server">HowtoForge/Falko Timme: VBoxHeadless - Running Virtual Machines With VirtualBox 4.0 On A Headless OpenSUSE 11.3 Server</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>This guide explains how you can run virtual machines with <ulink url="http://www.virtualbox.org/">VirtualBox 4.0</ulink> on a headless OpenSUSE 11.3 server. Normally you use the VirtualBox GUI to manage your virtual machines, but a server does not have a desktop environment. Fortunately, VirtualBox comes with a tool called VBoxHeadless that allows you to connect to the virtual machines over a remote desktop connection, so there&apos;s no need for the VirtualBox GUI. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 29.1.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxaria.com/article/tool-command-line-bandwidth-linux?lang=en">Linuxaria: 3 Command line tool to test bandwidth between 2 servers</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>One element that is often not know, or that should be measured after a problem statement or after a change in the infrastructure is the network .</para>
      <para>But how do you accurately measure the speed between two servers?

Someone use ftp, scp or other file transfer protocols, these can give some indication, but probably you’ll measure the limit of your disks or CPU.</para>
      <para>In this article I will show you 3 way to measure the bandwidth from the command line, without using the disks. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 29.1.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
