<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 id="gsoc" role="gsoc">
  <title>Google Summer of Code</title>
  <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
      <imagedata width="20%" align="center" fileref="http://michal.hrusecky.net/wp-content/uploads/GSoC2011_300x200.png"/>
    </imageobject>
  </mediaobject>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://sysbytes.wordpress.com/2011/08/28/sax3-status/">Manu Gupta: SaX3 –
        Status</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>The changes I have made in SaX3 in the following week<orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed a few nasty bugs.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>The monitor module does not work which works now ( I need to be more careful the
            future)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Tried porting to openSUSE 11.3 ( Testers Required)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Pushed to factory, but it is hghly recommended to add X11:sax as your project
            repository for sax until 12.1</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 29.8.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://cbounta.wordpress.com/2011/08/29/a-utility-for-merging-configuration-sysconfig-files-%E2%80%93-final-gsoc-report/"
        >Christos Bountalis: A utility for merging configuration / sysconfig files – Final GSoC
        Report</ulink></title>
    <para>Last week was very busy for me and also very exciting. The end of Google Summer of Code
      period overlapped the beginning of a new period of my life. During these days, i moved from
      Salamis(Greece) to Amsterdam(Netherlands) where i am going to study towards a master degree in
      Artificial Intelligence. As you may understand there were and still are many things for me to
      arrange, as a person in a total new place/city/country.</para>
    <para>So enough about me, what is up with the project? Well, i am very glad to say that the
      project “ended” and reached a very satisfactory level, the merging functions are now working
      and i can say that the application is now in an alpha testing phase. There are of course
      things that always can be improved and a lot of testing to be done in order for this project
      to take its place and be useful and ready for use in openSUSE. This is the last GSoC report
      for this project. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 1.9.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.wafaa.eu/entry/what-the-opensuse-conference-means-to-me-1-67.html"
        >Andrew Wafaa: Blogged about: What the openSUSE Conference means to me</ulink></title>
    <para>I was asked the other day "What do you expect from the openSUSE Conference?" The simple
      answer is I only expect to have fun. Seriously, I expect nothing more, nothing less. I hope
      for a whole lot more, but I certainly don't expect it.</para>
    <para>ý</para>
    <para>This may sound somewhat silly, but in all honesty that's how I feel. This conference (as
      are most others) is a great way to meet the people you interact with online, ýthere's
      something satisfying to be able to replace the digital person with a real flesh and blood
      person. You can thank someone in a real sincere way with a gift (could be a pint or something
      else) or slap them and let your anger out. Digital is pretty good, but having the physical is
      always better once in a while :-D</para>
    <!--($ ld: 1.9.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
