<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
<!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://article.gmane.org/gmane.network.samba.internals/57144">Contributing to Samba: Samba now accepts corporate copyright</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Here is a change we&apos;re instituting immediately to make it easier
for corporations to contribute code changes to Samba whilst still
retaining copyright ownership of the contributed code.</para>
      <para>Feel free to ask any questions on the samba-technical &lt;at&gt; samba.org
list.</para>
      <para>We&apos;d like to thank our lawyers at the Software Freedom Law Center
for helping us to make this change. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 21.10.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="https://mail.gnome.org/archives/devel-announce-list/2011-October/msg00001.html">GNOME 3.2.1 released</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The first update to GNOME 3.2 series is now available. As usual it
provides bug fixes, translations updates and tiny improvements, in
order to make our stable release even more stable and useful. Of
course these improvements are kindly provided by our vibrant GNOME
community members and contributors: so, thanks to our wonderful GNOME
people. (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.socallinuxexpo.org/blog/design-logo-scale-10x-win-trip-la">Design a logo for SCALE 10X, win a trip to LA!</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Want a free trip to SCALE 10X in Los Angeles this January?</emphasis></para>
      <para>In marking 10 years of the Southern California Linux Expo (SCALE) and 20 years of Linux, the SCALE team wants to incorporate an open-source approach to this year’s expo logo designs for publications and for swag. 

With this in mind, the SCALE team announces a contest to select the artwork for use on this year&apos;s t-shirts, attendee bags, and other conference materials.</para>
      <para>The designer of the winning submission will win a free pass to <ulink url="http://www.socallinuxexpo.org/scale10x/">SCALE 10x</ulink>, including airfare within the continental United States, as well as a three-night stay at the <ulink url="http://www.hilton.com/en/hi/groups/personalized/L/LAXAHHH-LNX-20120116/index.jhtml?WT.mc_id=POG%20target=">Hilton Los Angeles Airport</ulink>. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 14.10.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://opensource.com/government/11/10/creative-commons-40-horizon">opensource.com/Marek Mahut: Creative Commons 4.0 on the horizon</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Creative Commons held its <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/tag/warsaw">Global Summit</ulink> a few weeks ago in Warsaw, with amazing international participation. Without question, the most-discussed topic was the upcoming 4.0 release of the licenses, including related issues and a lively debate regarding whether the licenses should be ported to specific countries – or whether we should instead try to create a new international license. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 21.10.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.theregister.co.uk/2011/10/17/opensuse_12_point_1_review/">the register/Scott Gilbertson: OpenSUSE 12.1 delivers Fedora punch with GNOME 3</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Review</emphasis> The big news in openSUSE 12.1, whose first beta
        has recently dropped, is the arrival of GNOME 3 – in this case GNOME 3.2.</para>
      <para>Unlike Fedora, which is already into its second GNOME 3-based release, openSUSE had –
        thanks to its release schedule – stuck with GNOME 2 for its last release earlier this year.
        (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 19.10.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxpromagazine.com/Online/Blogs/Off-the-Beat-Bruce-Byfield-s-Blog/How-I-Learned-to-Love-the-KDE-4-Series">Linux Pro Magazine/Bruce Byfield: How I Learned to Love the KDE 4 Series</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>For nine years, my default desktop was GNOME. About the third of the time, I&apos;d use another desktop or a shell, either for the purposes of review or just for a change, but I&apos;d always return to GNOME. It was a no-fuss interface in which I could do my common tasks without any problem. But a glitch on my system that left GNOME unstartable coincided with the release of KDE 4.2, and -- not having the time to reinstall -- I switched to KDE. I haven&apos;t looked back since.</para>
      <para>Nobody could have been more surprised than I was. I&apos;d worked in KDE 3.x many times, of course, but I was never comfortable in it. The defaults themes and icons looked so blocky and childish that it didn&apos;t look in the least modern. It was so different from GNOME that I might as well have been in another operating system.

So why did I switch permanently? Two main reasons come to mind: KDE&apos;s design philosophy and its ability to innovate without dictating. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 21.10.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
<!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.theregister.co.uk/2011/08/13/oscommerce_infection_threatens_web/">The Register/Dan Goodin: Attack on open-source web app keeps growing</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>An attack targeting sites running unpatched versions of the osCommerce web application kept growing virally this week, more than three weeks after a security firm warned it was being used to install malware on the computers of unsuspecting users.</para>
      <para>When researchers from Armorize first spotted the exploit on July 24, they estimated it had injected malicious links into about 91,000 webpages. By early last week, The Reg reported it had <ulink url="http://www.theregister.co.uk/2011/08/02/mass_injection_attack_goes_viral/">taken hold of almost 5 million pages</ulink>. At time of writing, Google searches <ulink url="https://encrypted.google.com/#num=100&amp;hl=en&amp;safe=off&amp;q=%22http:%2F%2Fwillysy.com%2Fimages%2Fbanners%2F%22&amp;oq=%22http:%2F%2Fwillysy.com%2Fimages%2Fbanners%2F%22&amp;aq=f&amp;aqi=&amp;aql=&amp;gs_sm=e&amp;gs_upl=3751l5401l10l6328l9l7l0l0l0l2l168l883l2.5l7l0&amp;fp=1&amp;biw=1365&amp;bih=913&amp;bav=on.2,or.r_gc.r_pw.&amp;cad=b">here</ulink> and <ulink url="https://encrypted.google.com/#hl=en&amp;source=hp&amp;q=%22http:%2F%2Fexero.eu%2Fcatalog%2Fjquery.js%22&amp;oq=%22http:%2F%2Fexero.eu%2Fcatalog%2Fjquery.js%22&amp;aq=f&amp;aqi=&amp;aql=&amp;gs_sm=e&amp;gs_upl=13178l40428l0l40708l35l35l0l34l0l0l105l105l0.1l1l0&amp;fp=1&amp;biw=1365&amp;bih=913&amp;bav=on.2,or.r_gc.r_pw.&amp;cad=b">here</ulink> suggested that the number exceeded 8.3 million. (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->  <sect2>
    <title>LOL</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://like-a-boss.org/2011/09/30/hacking-the-imperial-death-march/">like-a-boss.org: hacking the imperial death march</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>One of the great things about the original Star Wars trilogy, was the “lived in”, junky, hacked together aesthetic of the Star Wars universe. Everything was a bit trashed, as if real people actually lived there. Thankfully, that’s one of the things that George Lucas hasn’t tinkered with in his endless quest to ruin the childhood memories of a generation. So it’s heartening to see this tradition carried on with the playing of the imperial death march on miscellaneous hacked together hardware. Enjoy … (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 8.10.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
