<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="updates">
  <title>New/Updated Applications @ openSUSE</title>
<!--* Gnome
* KDE
* XYZ 

Version should be available at packman or software.opensuse.org/search max. 4 posts. -->  
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://packman.links2linux.org/package/clementine/198133">Packman: clementine
        0.6-8.1</ulink></title>
    <para>Clementine is a modern music player and library organiser. Clementine is a port of Amarok
      1.4, with some features rewritten to take advantage of Qt4.</para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://tittiatcoke.wordpress.com/2010/12/13/additional-package-for-chromium-on-packman/"
        >Raymond Wooninck: Additional package for Chromium (on packman)</ulink></title>
    <para>As most of you already found out, Chromium is not that easy when it comes with MultiMedia.
      Due to the heavy patches from Google to ffmpeg, it does not work just to build chromium
      against the standard ffmpeg libraries. For distributions like openSUSE, Fedora, etc this
      brings issues as that ffmpeg code is still legally a no-no. </para>
    <para>There were some attempts in the past to solve this issue, but they failed. At the moment I
      have created a new package chromium-ffmpeg which delivers the missing libffmpegsumo.so
      library. The package is available from packman and it builds the patched ffmpeg code. </para>
    <para>It still doesn’t really work 100%, but it should resolve some multimedia issues that
      people have been experiencing with the openSUSE Chromium package. In the meantime Chromium has
      already reached version 10.x.x.x, so check out the changes. </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://packman.links2linux.org/package/mkvtoolnix">Packman: mkvtoolnix
        4.4.0-1.pm.1.18</ulink></title>
    <para>Tools to create and manipulate Matroska files (extensions .mkv and .mka), a new container
      format for audio and video files. Includes command line tools mkvextract, mkvinfo, mkvmerge,
      and a graphical front-end for them, mkvmerge-gui.</para>
  </blockquote>
  <!-- ($ ld: 15.12.10 sm $) -->
  
  <itemizedlist>
    <title>You can find other interesting Packages at:</title>
    <listitem>
      <para><ulink url="http://packman.links2linux.de/rdf/packman_en.rdf">Packman</ulink></para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para><ulink url="https://hermes.opensuse.org/feeds/66367.rdf">openSUSE Build
        Service</ulink></para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</sect1>
