<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
  <!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://blog.karlitschek.de/2011/01/contest-deadline-extended.html">Frank
          Karlitscheck: Contest deadline extended</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Several developers approached me and asked for more time to port their applications. So
        we extend the deadline of the contest to 31. of march. Everybody has one more month to port
        a KDE or Qt application to Symbian or MeeGo. Remember that you can win 10.000,- so please
        consider to make your KDE or Qt application ready for mobile. </para>
      <para>You find more informatiuon in the original contest announcement: <ulink
          url="http://blog.karlitschek.de/2010/12/qtest-mobile-app-port-contest-launched.html"
          >http://blog.karlitschek.de/2010/12/qtest-mobile-app-port-contest-launched.html</ulink>
      </para>
      <para>Please make sure that you also provide binaries for you applications. This makes is a
        lot easier for the jury to test you application. Have fun and good luck.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 30.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://sourceforge.net/blog/sourceforge-net-attack/">Sourceforge:
          Sourceforge.net attack</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Yesterday our vigilant operations guys detected a targeted attack against some of our
        developer infrastructure. The attack resulted in an exploit of several SourceForge.net
        servers, and we have proactively shut down a handful of developer centric services to
        safeguard data and protect the majority of our services. </para>
      <para>Our immediate priorities are to prevent further exposure and ensure data integrity.
        We’ve had all hands on deck working on identifying the exploit vector or vectors,
        eliminating them, and are now focusing on verifying data integrity and restoring the
        impacted services. </para>
      <para>The problem was initially discovered on the servers that host CVS but our analysis
        indicates that several other machines were involved, and while we believe we’ve determined
        the extent of the attack, we are verifying all of our other services and data. </para>
      <para>As a short term response, we’ve taken down the following services to prevent any
        possible escalation:<itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>CVS Hosting</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>ViewVC (web based code browsing)</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>New Release upload capability</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Interactive Shell services</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
      <para>Once the immediate response to this attack is over, we will be providing a much more
        detailed account of what’s happened, and what specific actions we are taking to prevent
        further exploits.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 31.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.samba.xp.de/index.php?id=14">SambaXP 2011</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The Samba eXPerience 2011 in Göttingen, Germany is the 10th(!) international <ulink
          url="http://samba.org/">Samba</ulink> conference for users and developers. Meet the Samba
        Team and discuss requirements, new features and get an update on current developments! The
        conference is organized by <ulink url="http://www.sernet.de/">SerNet</ulink>.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">May 9th - 11th, 2011 - Hotel Freizeit In Göttingen -
          Germany</emphasis> (...)</para>
    </blockquote> 
  </sect2> -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://genek.net/wordpress/">Adventures in Linux: Software Review: The KDE 4.6
          Desktop Environment</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Author’s note: </emphasis></para>
      <para>most of the screenshots contained herein were taken from the KDE release announcement.
        Thanks to KDE for making these pics available for re-use. </para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Ancient History: </emphasis></para>
      <para>It’s been three years, and it’s still hard to put the KDE 4.0 debacle behind me. I was
        running KDE 3.5 on Debian stable happy as a clam, and then one fine day in January of 2008
        the KDE folks dumped their brand-new, completely re-vamped desktop environment into our
        laps. I couldn’t get it for Debian so I installed another distro just to check it out… and
        used it for less than 24 hours. I could see what they were trying to do, and there were some
        good ideas there, but the implementation was so unbelievably bad that I missed out on the
        next two releases altogether. I didn’t try KDE 4.x again until January of last year, when I
        installed Debian testing with the KDE 4.3 desktop. It was great! Since then KDE has gone
        from strength to strength. KDE 4.4 was mature and stable, and KDE 4.5 added polish and
        finesse. KDE 4.6, released a little over a week ago, ups the ante once again. (...)</para>
      <!--($ ld: 10.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.desktoplinux.com/news/NS7312694782.html">Prashanth Venkataram:
          Preview - GNOME 3 </ulink>
      </title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_c0--RsXwTkw/TUx7fv5mxCI/AAAAAAAABNQ/uNZlx1MtApA/s320/Screenshot1.png"
          />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>Usually, when I review desktop environments, I review KDE, specifically version 4. Why?
        It's constantly evolving and improving, and it's nice to be able to see such changes
        occurring on all fronts so quickly. By contrast, GNOME and Xfce (not to mention other WMs
        like Openbox) have remained relatively the same over the past few releases. Sure, Nautilus
        got tabbed browsing in version 2.22 (I think) and split-pane viewing in version 2.30. Sure,
        there may have been a couple other back-end changes. But generally speaking, where KDE 4 has
        changed pretty noticeably between point releases, GNOME has been quite stable. That's all
        going to change, because GNOME is about to be released under a whole new number: 3. That's
        right: the number preceding the decimal point in a GNOME release will no longer be
        '2'.</para>
      <para>There are some pretty big changes in store for GNOME 3, much of which can be seen in the
        front-end. Because many major distributions are planning to upgrade to GNOME 3 once that
        gets released (in a few weeks, apparently), it's important that users try GNOME 3 beforehand
        both to get accustomed to it as well as to find and report lingering bugs. Happily, the good
        people at Fedora and openSUSE have put together live CD ISO files with vanilla GNOME 3 on
        them, just for the purpose of trying out GNOME 3. I downloaded both files and intended to
        make a multiboot live setup using MultiSystem, but unfortunately MultiSystem reacted with
        error messages to both ISOs. Knowing that openSUSE doesn't play well with UnetBootin, I
        decided to just try out the Fedora version on a live USB through UnetBootin. Follow the jump
        to see how it goes.</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_c0--RsXwTkw/TUx7f_2UmHI/AAAAAAAABNU/-BlafqbqZQg/s320/Screenshot2.png"
          />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>Unfortunately, I initially had a bit of booting trouble when I selected the default boot
        menu option. The OS hung halfway through booting, so I forced a cold restart. I then
        selected the <quote>Boot </quote>option instead of either <quote>Default</quote> or
          <quote>desktop_[stuff] </quote>(the name of the ISO file) and that seemed to work fine — I
        even got to see the lovely Fedora boot splash screen (the Fedora logo <quote>filling
          up</quote>). After the boot process came the login screen. I guess GDM hasn't changed a
        whole lot since GNOME 2.30, though for some reason the GTK+ theming looked really ugly. Upon
        seeing it, I hoped it was just an issue with GDM and not the whole GNOME desktop theming
        ability, and thankfully, as I found out shortly thereafter, I was right. I then proceeded to
        the desktop. (...)</para>
      <!--($ ld: 10.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://www.itworld.com/personal-tech/134954/sony-announces-ngp-aka-psp2-and-talks-playstation-gaming-android"
          >ITworld/Peter Smith: Sony announces NGP (aka PSP2) and talks Playstation gaming on
          Android [video</ulink>]</title>
      <para>It was quite a day for Sony portable fans. Earlier today (well, technically yesterday)
          <ulink
          url="http://www.engadget.com/2011/01/26/sony-ericsson-xperia-play-playstation-phone-preview/"
          >Engadget posted</ulink> about some hands-on experience with the Xperia Play, aka the
        Playstation Phone. It sure looks real to me. Engadget is being coy about where this unit
        came from but post author Richard Lai says he&apos;s been using it as his primary phone for
        a few days now, with generally good results. </para>
      <para>No &apos;official&apos; games are available for it, but Lai loaded up some emulators and
        mapped the hardware buttons to emulator controls and had a go. This isn&apos;t final
        hardware but for an early look it seems promising enough. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 4.2.11 sat $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.enterprisenetworkingplanet.com/news/article.php/3923031">Enterprise
          Networking Planet/Sean Michael Kerner: Last of the IPv4 Addresses Allocated</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>IPv4 is dead. Long Live IPv6.</para>
      <para>Early this morning, the Asia Pacific Network Information Centre (APNIC) announced that
        it had been allocated two /8 address blocks from the Internet Assigned Numbers Authority
          (<ulink url="http://www.webopedia.com/TERM/I/IANA.html">IANA</ulink> ). Those two blocks,
        39/8 and 106/8, were the last unallocated blocks in the IANA free pool of IPv4 address
        available to Regional Internet Registries (RIR). With the allocation, the final days of IPv4
        have moved closer as the number of available addresses that can be allocated will dwindle.
        (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 4.2.11 sat $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://maketecheasier.com/kde46-review-full-of-awesomeness/2011/02/02"
          >MakeTechEasier/Tavis J. Hampton: KDE 4.6 Review: It’s Full Of Awesomeness</ulink></title>
      <para>On January 26th of this year, <ulink url="http://www.kde.org/announcements/4.6/">KDE
          released</ulink> version 4.6.0 of its Plasma Workspaces, Applications, and Development
        Platform. While many major versions of KDE have focused on features, 4.5 was mostly a
        stabilizing release, fixing thousands of bugs. The 4.6 release is all about polish. It is
        the icing on the cake for KDE 4, adding speed, visual enhancements, and increased hardware
        compatibility. </para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Faceted Browsing for Dolphin</emphasis> – Pressing Ctrl+F in
        Dolphin used to open Kfind, a search interface that used various Linux/Unix search tools
        such as “find” and “locate” to get you the files you wanted. In KDE 4.6, you can open the
        search interface within Dolphin and find indexed files quickly and easily. The addition of a
        filter side bar also allows you to find exactly the types of files you want, giving you
        options for file type, creation date, and even rating. (...)</para>
      <!--($ ld: 4.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://mindplusplus.wordpress.com/2011/02/02/finding-the-fastest-filesystem-2011-edition/"
          >mindplusplus: Finding the Fastest Filesystem, 2011 Edition</ulink></title>
      <para>In my <ulink url="http://mindplusplus.wordpress.com/2008/07/14/finding-the-fas/"
          >previous report</ulink> about journaling filesystem benchmarking using dbench, I observed
        that a properly-tuned system using XFS, with the deadline I/O scheduler, beat both Linux’s
        ext3 and IBM’s JFS. A lot has changed in the three years since I posted that report, so it’s
        time to do a new round of tests. Many bug fixes, improved kernel lock management, and two
        new filesystem (btrfs and ext4) bring some new configurations to test. </para>
      <para>Once again, I’ll provide raw numbers, but the emphasis of this report lies in the
        relative performance of the filesystems under various loads and configurations. To this end,
        I have normalized the charted data, and eliminated the raw numbers on the Y-axes. Those who
        wish to run similar tests on their own systems can download a tarball containing the testing
        scripts; I’ll provide the link to the tarball at the end of this report. (...)</para>
      <!--($ ld: 4.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linux.com/learn/tutorials/403466-review-hands-on-libreoffice-33"
          >Linux.com/Brian Proffitt: Review: Hands on LibreOffice 3.3</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The Document Foundation released the first new version of its LibreOffice suite on
        January 25th, and it was far too tempting not to grab a copy and run it through its paces.
        And while there are a few new features of note, this is still pretty much OpenOffice.org,
        with all the attendant advantages and foibles.</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://www.linux.com/images/stories/calc.png" width="25%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>This is to be expected, of course, since the fork of LibreOffice from the
        Oracle-controlled (formerly Sun-controlled) OpenOffice.org project only occurred four months
        ago. Expecting a drastic change is folly in that timeframe. But it still bears noting,
        because a lot of the problems users may have with the OpenOffice.org suite could still be
        present. </para>
      <para>A lot, but not all, so let's give credit where credit is due. The feature I found most
        helpful in LibreOffice 3.3 was a much better improvement in file importing from Microsoft
        Office. OpenOffice.org has long-touted its capability to open and save Office files, but in
        reality most users know that any file with any kind of complexity was going to have to have
        problems coming across. </para>
      <para>In LibreOffice, that's no longer the case. Opening some heavily-revised and commented
        chapter files from my last book in OpenOffice.org usually leads to mis-rendered comments and
        loads of font issues. LibreOffice Writer didn't even blink: all revisions, comments, and
        fonts came across perfectly. This was good news, since I would much rather use LibreOffice
        on Linux than fire up a Windows VM when I'm writing for publishers insistent on clean .docx
        files. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 8.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.tildehash.com/?article=interview-with-richard-stallman-2011"
          >Tildehash: Interview with Richard Stallman (2011)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><ulink url="http://www.stallman.org/">Richard M. Stallman</ulink> (born March 16, 1953),
        often shortened to RMS, is an American software freedom activist and computer programmer. In
        September 1983, he launched the GNU Project to create a <ulink
          url="http://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.html">free</ulink> Unix-like operating system,
        and has been the project's lead architect and organizer. With the launch of the <ulink
          url="http://www.gnu.org/">GNU Project</ulink>, he initiated the <ulink
          url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free_software_movement">Free Software Movement</ulink>;
        in October 1985 he founded the <ulink url="http://www.fsf.org/">Free Software
          Foundation</ulink>. </para>
      <para>Richard Stallman pioneered the concept of <ulink
          url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Copyleft">Copyleft</ulink> and he is the main author of
        several copyleft licenses including the <ulink
          url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GNU_General_Public_License">GNU General Public
          License</ulink>, the most widely used Free Software license. Since the mid-1990s, Richard
        Stallman has spent most of his time advocating for Free Software, as well as campaigning
        against both <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_patent">software
          patents</ulink> and what he sees as excessive extension of copyright laws. Stallman has
        also developed a number of pieces of widely used software, including the original <ulink
          url="http://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/">Emacs</ulink>, the <ulink
          url="http://gcc.gnu.org/">GNU Compiler Collection (GCC)</ulink>, the <ulink
          url="http://www.gnu.org/software/gdb/">GNU Debugger (GDB)</ulink>, and many tools in the
          <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coreutils">GNU Coreutils</ulink>. He co-founded
        the <ulink url="http://www.progfree.org/">League for Programming Freedom</ulink> in 1989. </para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 8.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://www.unixmen.com/gaming-on-linux/1131-19-awesome-opensource-games-for-linux-"
          >Unixmen/M. Zinoune (Zinovsky): 19 Awesome Open source games for Linux</ulink></title>
      <para>This is a nice collection of 19 open source games for Linux that contains most
        addictive, fun and refined games. For some of these games, also installation steps are
        included. Enjoy</para>
      <!--($ ld: 8.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/security/news/item/Phrack-hole-closed-in-ProFTPD-1156782.html">h-online: Phrack hole closed in ProFTPD </ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The development team behind <ulink url="http://www.proftpd.org/">ProFTPD</ulink> has
        released version <ulink url="http://www.proftpd.org/docs/RELEASE_NOTES-1.3.3d">1.3.3d</ulink>, which closes a critical security hole in the SQL module of all previous
        versions. The flaw was <ulink url="http://www.phrack.org/issues.html">reported</ulink>
        roughly a month ago in Phrack, the hacker magazine. A buffer overflow in the function
        sql_prepare_where() allows attackers to remotely execute arbitrary code on the server. The
        developers themselves suffered when this vulnerability was exploited by still unknown
        parties, who entered the project server and <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/news/item/Back-door-in-ProFTPD-FTP-server-1146592.html">installed</ulink> a back door in the source code.</para>
      <para>The new version also fixes a number of additional <ulink url="http://www.proftpd.org/docs/NEWS-1.3.3d">bugs</ulink>; as a result, the GPL-licensed
        server is reportedly now more stable. At the same time, the developers have also published
        the first release candidate for version <ulink url="http://www.proftpd.org/docs/RELEASE_NOTES-1.3.4rc1">1.3.4</ulink>. (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>LOL</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://e-tote-kala.blogspot.com/2011/01/first-joke-of-year-if-operating-systems.html"
          >Kostas Koudaras: First Joke of the year: If Operating Systems Ran The Airlines</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The first joke of the year :-) </para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
</sect1>
