<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://emmes.livejournal.com/10062.html">Matthias Hopf: Network Image
        Installer</ulink></title>
    <para>During our work in our preload department at SuSE we have to install our current image on
      several machines for each image version for smoke testing, which meant burning several DVDs
      per iteration (and there is typically one iteration per week!).In order to ease this work flow
      I created a <ulink url="http://kiwi.berlios.de/">kiwi</ulink> image for a CD or an USB stick
      for installing the latest image via network - the <ulink
        url="http://www.mshopf.de/proj/netimginst.html">Network Image Installer</ulink>. It's also
      capable of installing arbitrary openSUSE / Fedora / Ubuntu versions, so you never have to burn
      another DVD if you have a reasonably fast internet connection. Network detection is automatic,
      wireless requires the SSID etc. changed in a config file beforehand.</para>
    <para>Find the sources on <ulink url="http://gitorious.org/netimginst">gitorious</ulink>, I will
      eventually try to understand the functionality in the openSUSE build service to create images
      automatically, but for now you'll have to build the image yourself. I'll post when there is a
      downloadable image available.</para>
    <para>Now I'm off to <ulink url="http://www.fantasyfilmfest.com/">Fantasy Film Fest</ulink>
      again.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 29.08.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://www.ralf-lang.de/2011/08/30/horde-project-pushes-libraries-to-the-frontpage/"
        >Ralf Lang: Horde Project pushes libraries to the frontpage</ulink></title>
    <para>As you might know, the horde project does not only release a set of production quality
      software (and an interesting bunch more which are not yet release quality) but also provides
      over 80 well-designed loosely coupled libraries which help you build websites, business
      applications or even commandline tools. To stress that point, the Horde Project now put <ulink
        url="http://www.horde.org/components">a link to the list of components</ulink> right on
      their frontpage. Use Horde_Rdo, a lightweight ORM layer or use the RFC-compliant Imap_Client
      library which performs equally or even better compared to PHP’s interpreter extension written
      in c. Horde_Auth, a versatile and pluggable authentication layer, has recently been <ulink
        url="http://janschneider.de/news/5/342">featured in a series of blog posts by lead developer
        Jan Schneider</ulink>. Like in Symfony or Zend Framework, Components are released along with
      a <ulink url="http://update.linux-magazin.de/Heft-Abo/Ausgaben/2011/08/PHP-Unit">PHPUnit based
        test suit</ulink>e adapted in the Horde_Test class and can be obtained individually through
      the <ulink url="http://pear.horde.org">Horde Pear Channel</ulink>.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 1.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.ralf-lang.de/2011/09/01/opensuse-12-1-drops-sunoracle-java/">Ralf
        Lang: OpenSUSE 12.1 drops Sun/Oracle Java</ulink></title>
    <para>Today, <ulink url="http://www.opensuse.org">openSUSE</ulink> Program Manager Andreas
      Jaeger announced that openSUSE will stop shipping Sun Java in the upcoming 12.1
      release.</para>
    <para>Distribution users will now only be offered the GPLed openJDK. In a recent announcement,
      Oracle declared openJDK to be the new official reference implementation for Java SE7. Along
      with that move, Oracle dropped the “Distributor’s License for Java (DLJ)” which was required
      for redistributing Sun Java. Users depending on Sun/Oracle Java are now required to download
      it directly from the oracle website. Since the acquisition of sun by oracle, the companny has
      been known for questionable moves which alienate parts of the opensource community. Among
      these was the OpenOffice dispute which led to the departure of many developers to form
      LibreOffice. The former sun-owned mysql database has also seen a fork called MariaDB.
      According to Jaeger, openSUSE will continue to provide the existing packages in the <ulink
        url="https://build.opensuse.org/project/show?project=Java%3Asun%3AFactory"
        >Java:sun:Factory</ulink> project but will not update them anymore and won’t ship them with
      the new distribution. Users are urged to switch to either openJDK or the versions available
      directly from Oracle.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 1.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
