<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/02/26/opensuse-11-4-rc2-steps-out/">Helen South: openSUSE 11.4 RC2 Steps Out</ulink>
    </title>
    <note>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is Licensed under the <ulink
            url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/fdl.txt">GNU Free Documentation
          License.</ulink></emphasis></para>
    </note>
    <para>With red carpets rolling out in Hollywood, you’d expect some applause for the openSUSE 11.4 RC2 release, which has now gone live ahead of 11.4 proper. But with much of 
      the hard work going in behind the scenes, this superb release candidate isn’t getting the fanfare it deserves. The recent Bug Squashing day saw 132 bugs updated so few 
      serious issues remain. Improvements in the ‘backend’ work includes some tweaks to Wifi supplicant and drivers, and a host of small fixes across the distribution which enhance 
      stability and performance. The addition of MediaCurl backend with zsync support to libzypp iut is already being noticed. openSUSE user and forum member Pier Andreit comments 
      that “YaST install/remove software is a thunderbolt!”</para>
    <para>The transition from OpenOffice.org to LibreOffice still has a few minor documentation blips but more importantly, users should be cautious. The raft of new functionality 
      has created a few specific issues, such as loss of data in tables. Though not quite ready for the production environment, user feedback is critical for smoothing performance 
      and reliability. </para>
    <para>KDE SC 4.6 is also running beautifully though 32 BIT nVidia users may have a bug.</para>
    <para>If you’d like to help add the final touches of celebrity glam prior to the ‘big event’ of 11.4 release, <ulink 
      url="http://download.opensuse.org/distribution/11.4-RC2/iso/">download it here</ulink> and check out the <ulink 
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Most_annoying_bugs_11.4_dev#openSUSE_11.4_RC2">most annoying bugs</ulink>.</para>    
    <!-- ($ ld: 27.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
