<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://www.marques.so/2011/07/packaging-applications-with-icons-and-hicolor-macros-with-opensuse/"
        >Nelson Marques: Packaging applications with icons and ‘hicolor’ macros with
        openSUSE</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>The forums are a wonderful tool and often provide first hand feedback for things that are
      somehow interesting and many times don’t make their way into the bugzilla. There was a few
      users which complained about Chromium not displaying the icons on the window list in GNOME.
      I’ve taken a quick look into the package and found the following: (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 13.7.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://blog.jospoortvliet.com/2011/07/getting-new-ms-fonts-in-libreoffice-or.html">Jos Poortvliet: Getting the new MS fonts in LibreOffice - or rather, forget about it</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>Personal learning point of the day: when on the website of a company with dubious business and legal practices <emphasis role="bold">READ the fineprint</emphasis>...</para>
    <para>I already wrote most of the following blog (actually more, including making screenshots) before I discovered the fineprint leading me to write the above...

</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">The Font Issue</emphasis></para>
    <para>If you get a document with fonts you don&apos;t have, the result can be bad. Layout will surely not be proper and for some reason LO and Caligra pick a horrible replacement on my computer - Alien Leage, see screenshot. Guaranteed to make any normal document unreadable. And the idiotic &apos;reading mode&apos; of LO makes it impossible to change the font until you&apos;ve saved the file somewhere. The benefit of that mode always escaped me in MS Office, at least I knew how to turn it off... (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 10.7.11 sat $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://www.marques.so/2011/07/the-%C2%ABbanshee%C2%BB-incident-a-horror-tale-by-nmarques/">Nelson Marques: The «Banshee» incident…</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>The latest unstable version of Banshee (2.1.0) introduced quite a few changes and one of the most visible was the replacement of NDesk.DBus by DBus. This change came with a huge pedagogic charge on me…</para>
    <para>Since the changes with this version of Banshee were so deep, I’ve decided to re-write the spec and cleanup as much as I could and ditch as much expressions as possible for old unsupported platforms. This went fine but on the first builds failed heavily by not finding a required assembly file from dbus-sharp-glib.</para>
    <para>My first investigations provided me some really accurate information:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Local tests on the dbus-sharp-glib packages showed evidence that the dependencies required were working properly (rpm -qp –requires/provides).</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>OBS showed evidence that both devel and normal package were installed.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>A simple “rpm -qa –last” inside of the build root cage showed evidence that though the devel package was installed the normal package wasn’t…</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>And so the nightmare begun… Without having much clues on where to look for and with my helpers/mentors busy with far more important stuff it dragged for some time and started to grind my mind… (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 10.7.11 sat $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://tml-blog.blogspot.com/2011/07/i-am-just-debugging-well-not-really-i.html">Tor Lillqvist: First debugging session of LibreOffice code on iOS (simulator)</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>I am just debugging (well, not really, I am not expecting anything to actually do much interesting) for the first time cross-compiled LibreOffice code on the iOS Simulator. (So yeah, technically instruction-set-wise this is not cross-compiled, as the Simulator runs i386 code, too, but under a simulated iOS environment.) Not really that exciting, but still, couldn&apos;t help blogging. No, there is still nothing to &quot;beta test&quot;, there is still no actual LibreOffice UI showing up or even any code to draw a single pixel on iOS.</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 10.7.11 sat $)-->  </blockquote>
</sect1>
