<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="updates">
    <title>New/Updated Applications @ openSUSE</title>
    <!--* Gnome
* KDE
* XYZ http://oyranos-cms.blogspot.com/2011/05/openicc-and-basiccolor-profile-packages.html

Version should be available at packman or software.opensuse.org/search max. 4 posts. -->
    <blockquote>
        <title>
            <ulink url="http://kfreitag.tumblr.com/post/12463194435">Klaas Freitag: Kraft 0.44
                released</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>around fife month after the last release I am happy to annouce <ulink
                url="http://volle-kraft-voraus.de/Main/Releases">version 0.44</ulink> of <ulink
                url="http://volle-kraft-voraus.de/">Kraft</ulink>, the <ulink
                url="http://www.kde.org">KDE</ulink> software to manage business documents like
            offers and invoices in the small enterprise.</para>
        <para>This development cycle was very much affected by work around the integration of the
                <ulink url="http://userbase.kde.org/Akonadi">Akonadi</ulink> based address book. I
            have gone through a lot of cycles of tries and tests, with various combinations of KDE-
            and PIM libraries and Akonadi and Nepomuk setups. Not always the stack was transparent
            to me nor the integration of the various parts perfect. But we’re KDE with our welknown
            community, and so I finally had the pleasure to go through my and other code and fix it
            togehter with Kevin and Tobias on Desktop Summit this summer. That brought backý
            motivation, thanks :-)</para>
        <para>So now one of the strengthes of the KDE platform from the application developers POV,
            which is the availability of powerful software building blocks such as an easy
            integratable address book, is now back to Kraft and users can again fully benefit from
            it.</para>
        <para>Apart from that I did a lot of small and larger bugfixes, for example 0.44 contains a
            full rewrite of the text template management for head- and footer texts. It contains a
            more clear UI and context sensitive help now for the users benefit.</para>
        <para>Kraft now also comes with localized PDF templates for documents. It was possible to
            use custom templates before and there were localized ones around, but it was an
            administrative task to use them. Now Kraft picks automatically the right one depending
            on the language settings which should be a nice improvement for new users evaluating
            Kraft.</para>
        <para>As usual I am happy to get feedback. Kraft is also very open to contributions, as in
            code, documentation, marketing bug reporting and such. Please check the <ulink
                url="http://volle-kraft-voraus.de/Main/Contribution">Contribution Page</ulink> on
            the project website for details.</para>
        <!-- ($ ld: 09.11.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
        <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/11/07/webyast-0-3-is-out/">Stefan
                Schubert: WebYaST 0.3 is out</ulink></title>
        <para>
            <emphasis role="bold">“We have doubled the speed and have halved the memory
                usage”</emphasis>
        </para>
        <para><inlinegraphic
                fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/WebYaST2_screenshot2.png"
                width="40%"/></para>
        <para>The latest version of WebYaST has many improvements regarding speed, memory usage,
            usability and developing environment:<itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Speed</emphasis></para>
                    <para>Due a new caching mechanism the startup time of each module has been
                        decreased to a maximum of 1-2 seconds. So the user is able now to click
                        through WebYaST without any notable waiting time. We have made a video which
                        shows the speed improvement:<ulink
                            url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/webyast-comparison.swf"
                            > WebYaST Comparison Video</ulink>For more technical information have a
                        look to: <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:WebYaST_Caching">
                            WebYaST Caching Howto</ulink></para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Memory Usage</emphasis></para>
                    <para>Former versions of WebYaST were split into a service and into an UI part.
                        Each part has run in a own HTTP server. We have decided to bring these parts
                        together in order to save one HTTP server which halves the memory usage. One
                        additional benefit is that the architecture of WebYaST has simplified a
                        lot:</para>
                </listitem>        
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis role="bold">Simplifying WebYaST architecture</emphasis>
                    </para>
                    <para>Due the use of one HTTP WebYaST server only the development environment
                        has been simplified very much:<orderedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Setup an environment system is much more easier now. Even a
                                    setup based on the GIT repository is quite easy. For more
                                    information have a look to : <ulink
                                        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:WebYaST_Installation#WebYaST_installation_version_.3E.3D_0.3"
                                        > WebYaST Installation</ulink></para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Writing an own WebYaST plugin has been reduced to a minimum
                                    effort. Everyone who has read a Ruby on Rails tutorial is now
                                    able to write a plugin. You do not believe ? Then have a look to
                                    the <ulink
                                        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:WebYaST_ExamplePlugin#Example_plugin_for_WebYaST_.3E.3D_0.3"
                                        >Example plugin </ulink>. (...)</para>
                            </listitem>
                        </orderedlist></para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist></para>
        <!-- ($ ld: 09.11.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
        <title>Nelson Marques: Unknown Horizons – 2011.3 RC4 @ games:unknown-horizons</title>
    </blockquote>
</sect1>
