<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="community">
  <title>In the Community</title>
  <!--Put here things relevant to the openSUSE community maybe from * People of openSUSE or elections, votings 1 - 2 posts-->
  <sect2>
    <title>Postings from the Community</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blog.karlitschek.de/2011/01/2-amazing-meetings-to-change-world.html"
          >Frank Karlitschek: 2 amazing meetings to change the world</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Last week I attended two very interesting developer sprints at the SUSE office in
        Nürnberg. </para>
      <para>More and more people in the Linux world realize that a nice application installer
        (Application Store) is needed to make the Linux platform more attractive for normal users
        and third party developers. The current package managers expose way to much complexity to
        the end users. The normal users doesn´t care about dependencies, libraries and other
        internals. But the user cares about things like screenshots, description texts, ratings.
        tags, comments, recommendation from friends and other features which current package
        managers don´t provide. So the idea grow to build a better tool for finding and installing
        applications which sits on top of the current package management. </para>
      <para>It´s part of the Bretzn project to build something like this. The first sprint last week
        brought people from all major Linux distributions on one table to discuss ways to work
        together to build a common application installer API and infrastructure. Developers from
        RedHat, Fedora, Debian, Ubuntu, openSUSE, Mandriva and Mageia met and discussed ways to make
        this happen. After 2 and a half days we all agreed on an architecture and we will work in
        the next few month to bring this to all majors distributions. I´m happy that OCS was chosen
        as the standard API to access App Store Servers. </para>
      <para>The second sprint was the Bretzn sprint which took place directly afterwards and was all
        about coding. </para>
      <para>Several people from openSUSE and KDE met to build a proof of concept implementation of
        an Application Store for openSUSE and KDE. </para>
      <para>This second sprint was also super productive so after another weekend we have a basic
        App Store client together with a server running. </para>
      <para>All the basic features are in place and it just needs a bit more polishing. </para>
      <para>There is a news story coming up with some more information and screenshots. So stay
        tuned if you are looking for more information. :-)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 24.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://nowwhatthe.blogspot.com/2011/01/lca-here-i-come.html">Jos
          Poortvliet: LCA - here I come!</ulink></title>
      <para>On a more personal note, next week I'll attend <ulink url="http://lca2011.linux.org.au/"
          >Linux Conf Australia</ulink>! Luckily the bad weather around Brisbane has not made it
        impossible for the conference to go ahead as scheduled. I am finalizing my registration
        right now and travel has been arranged. I'll be there with Graham Lauder, openoffice.org's
        contact in New Zealand and openSUSE fan. We'll man a booth at the Open Day on Saturday where
        anyone can look us up and learn more about openSUSE. </para>
      <para>So any openSUSE users and contributors in the area: come look us up! </para>
      <para>Oh and for everyone with a blog or other site: here you can find <ulink
          url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Countdown">openSUSE 11.4 counters</ulink>!</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 20.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://e-tote-kala.blogspot.com/2011/01/to-be-is-to-doto-do-has-to-be-fun.html"
          >Kostas Koudaras: To be is to do,to do has to be fun...</ulink></title>
      <para>These days the Greek openSUSE community took over most of my time since some of the hard
        working members are University students and it is examination season here in Greece and so I
        had to give them less or no work at all and someone should replace them so that no community
        work will fall back. For this week we made it and we still hold on as planned. We just
        released the <ulink url="http://el.opensuse.org/Weekly_news">Greek edition of Weekly
          news</ulink>. Unfortunately I feel I left back a bit my work at the marketing team but I
        will catch up ;-) . ...But on the other hand this week I had the opportunity to start
        writing a Greek article about <ulink
          url="http://www.rosenauer.org/blog/2011/01/03/opensuse-project-evergreen/">Project
          Evergreen</ulink> that got my attention and I had some ideas about we can promote it. I
        got in touch with <ulink url="http://www.rosenauer.org/blog/">Wolfgang Rosenauer</ulink>
        about it so that I can take his personal opinion and some directions about it and with
        Stratos Zolotas from the Greek Community that makes some bug-testing in 2 desktops and a
        server for the Evergreen project. It is a really interesting project and is another thing
        that shows the free will of the people in the openSUSE community to create and develop their
        own community projects. That last goes to those who believe that the openSUSE community is a
        corporate slave... </para>
      <para>Another thing I made this week is becoming an even more active openSUSE contributor by
        entering the Greek Localization team and even making a <ulink
          url="http://developer.berlios.de/">BerliOS account</ulink>. To be honest with you this was
        not my original intention for now but it came up due to my will to translate the <ulink
          url="http://doc.opensuse.org/products/other/WebYaST/webyast-user/">WebYaST</ulink> user
        manual. I am really excited with that work because is far more exciting than I was
        expecting. Of course I still have some difficulties but it is like a new toy for me and I
        spend a lot of my time with it the past 2 days. </para>
      <para>I also joined the <ulink url="https://connect.opensuse.org/">openSUSE connect</ulink> .
        I am from those few people that don't like Facebook, that is why I have no account there and
        as Stathis told me this is the 'Lizard Facebook' without the farm game and all the other
        annoying applications. Well I thing I liked it... I am now try to find ways to make it a
        useful tool so that we will start being productive and creative with it. I would suggest to
        all of you to give it a look. </para>
      <para>Other than that there are the elections part... I found out many things about people
        through all that procedure. I got the idea that many people thought that I would give up
        everything I do in order to support my campaign. I hope I prove all of them wrong.
        Understand that nothing in life will change dramatically after the elections are over. As I
        said many times before, I prefer acting more than everything else and my positions are
        written in <ulink
          url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board_election_2010_platform_warlordfff">my election
          platform</ulink>. Sometimes doing nothing is also an action.</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>People of openSUSE</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>This Week: xyz</title>
      <para>Good Guy. Glows in the night.</para>
    </blockquote>
    </sect2> -->
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Welcome new openSUSE Members</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/fcrozat">Frederic Crozat (fcrozat)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Very active in the openSUSE GNOME Team and Bugzilla.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/helen-au">Helen South
        (helen-au)</ulink></title>
      <para>Helen works inside Marketing and the Editor Team of news.opensuse.org.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/dominian">Matt Hayes
        (dominian)</ulink></title>
      <para>Active in Bugzilla, Wiki and Mailinglists.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/tsotsos">Angelos Tzotsos
        (tsotsos)</ulink></title>
      <para>Active inside the Greek Community and Marketing.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/bekun">Kai-Uwe Behrmann
        (bekun)</ulink></title>
      <para>Kai-Uwe serves as Speaker, Boothman and Developer for the openSUSE Project.</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Events &amp; Meetings</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Past</title>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/01/11/opensuse-gnome-team-meeting-22/"
            >January 20, 2011 : openSUSE GNOME Team meeting</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Upcoming</title>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/01/19/hackweek-vi-2/">January 24, 2011 :
            Hackweek VI</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/05/13/%ef%bb%bfopensuse-kde-team-meeting/"
            >January 27, 2011 : ﻿openSUSE KDE Team meeting</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink
            url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/01/20/21st-opensuse-testing-core-team-irc-meeting/"
            >January 31, 2011 : 21st openSUSE Testing Core Team IRC Meeting</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <!-- ($ ld: 21.01.10 th $) -->
    <para>You can find more informations on other events at: <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/category/events/">openSUSE News/Events</ulink>. - <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Ambassadors_events">Local Events</ulink></para>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>openSUSE for your Ears</title>
    <para>The openSUSE Weekly News are available as livestream or podcast in German. You can hear it
      or download it on <ulink url="http://blog.radiotux.de/podcast">Radiotux</ulink>. </para>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>From Ambassadors</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://stick.gk2.sk/blog/2011/01/gnome-python-hackfest-appinstaller-meeting-and-bretzn-hackfest/"
          >Pavol Rusnak: GNOME Python Hackfest, AppInstaller Meeting and Bretzn Hackfest</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>What a cool and productive week! But let me start from the beginning … </para>
      <para>A couple of months ago we decided to start a <ulink
          url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hackerspace">hackerspace</ulink> in Prague called <ulink
          url="http://brmlab.cz/">brmlab</ulink>. Most of the members deal with hardware, but there
        are also couple of software guys like me. At the end of November we were contacted by <ulink
          url="http://blog.tomeuvizoso.net/">Tomeu</ulink> and he asked if they can organize <ulink
          url="http://live.gnome.org/Hackfests/Python2011">GNOME Python Hackfest</ulink> in our
        hackerspace. I was more than delighted about the idea, so we agreed and started to plan
        things. In the end we had 9 FOSS hackers working on GNOME and Python and I think they
        enjoyed their time in Prague. Hackerspace is a great concept, because these folks didn’t
        have to spend extra money on renting some place and our members had opportunity to meet
        foreign FOSS developers and try exotic hardware like <ulink
          url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OLPC_XO-1">OLPC XO-1</ulink>.</para>
      <figure id="fig.blogpost">
        <title>Blogposts from <ulink
            url="http://blog.tomeuvizoso.net/2010/12/python-gnome-hackfest-2011.html">Tomeu</ulink>
          and <ulink url="http://www.j5live.com/2011/01/19/pygi-in-prague/">J5</ulink> about the
          event</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://stick.gk2.sk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/gnome-python-1.jpg"
              width="25%" align="center"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>I had to leave the guys on Tuesday evening, because I spent the rest of the week in SUSE
        office in Nuernberg. The first three days were dedicated to <ulink
          url="http://distributions.freedesktop.org/wiki/Meetings/AppInstaller2011"
          >Cross-distribution meeting</ulink> about application installer organized by <ulink
          url="http://www.vuntz.net/journal/">Vincent</ulink>. It went more than well, we discussed
        and agreed on many things, which is great and in the end we were able to give a <ulink
          url="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BHeP2ZBwS_U">presentation</ulink> + we also created a
          <ulink url="http://distributions.freedesktop.org/wiki/AppStream">nice AppStream
          wikipage</ulink> as a starting point for any future work.</para>
      <figure id="fig.summary">
        <title>Vincent wrote a nice summary for <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/">openSUSE
            News</ulink>. (It is not yet there, but should appear soon.)</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://stick.gk2.sk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/appstream_meeting.jpg"
              width="25%" align="center"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>This meeting was immediately followed by <ulink
          url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:2011_Bretzn_Meeting">Bretzn hackfest</ulink>
        organized by <ulink url="http://blog.karlitschek.de/">Frank</ulink>. The main focus of it
        was implementing some of the things we agreed on previous meeting from the KDE/Qt
        perspective and porting MeeGo Garage to openSUSE. During it I was mainly dealing with
        appdata.xml format we described in the AppStream meeting – I created an XML schema so we can
        validate it and also developed a proof-of-concept generator of this piece of metadata in
        Python. (<ulink url="http://gitorious.org/appstream">git repo</ulink>) Hope we can get it in
        createrepo and dpkg-scan* utilities soon.</para>
      <figure id="fig.planetsuse">
        <title>Frank’s summary about the hackfest will appear on <ulink
            url="http://planet.opensuse.org/">Planet openSUSE</ulink> soon</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="http://stick.gk2.sk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/DSC_1674.jpg"
              width="25%" align="center"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>I would like to thank GNOME Foundation and Collabora for sponsoring the GNOME Python
        Hackfest, Novell for sponsoring the Bretzn Hackfest and Canonical, Debian, Mageia, Novell
        and Red Hat for sending their people to AppInstaller Meeting! It’s really nice and
        encouraging to see folks from various companies working on one common goal.</para>
      <para>And yeah,</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://stick.gk2.sk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/going-to.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>so see you there!</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 24.01.10 th $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://opensuseambassadors.blogspot.com/2011/01/greek-customs-new-years-pie.html"
          >Greek openSUSE Ambassadors: Greek Customs (New Year's Pie)</ulink></title>
      <para>Here in Greece we celebrate the new year except from gifts but also by cutting a New
        Year's Pie where inside there is a coin hidden. Whoever finds it wins a special gift and is
        meant to be lucky the new year. A local Linux User Group located in Volos called Volug and
        LinuxTeam Teilar in Larisa which both teams consist of colleagues had two small parties for
        cutting the New Year's Pie. I was there to celebrate with those people and inform them about
        openSUSE and openSUSE community. They were all interested about openSUSE distribution. I
        answered many questions about Tumbleweed and Evergreen and informed them about our new 11.4
        and OBS as many of them where interested about the work that is done by openSUSE community
        and by the Greek Community. I had some cds/dvds and posters with me which i gave them. In
        the future we will make some events together. Unfortunately we did not took any pictures. I
        would slightly have won the hidden coin at the first party but the next person got it. </para>
      <para>Photo of the New Year's Pie</para>
      <figure id="fig.pie">
        <title>Happy New Year All!!!!</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_jdKLYe7Jeds/TT2yTD-TOII/AAAAAAAAADc/mjbWhEdAlxo/s1600/5360749563_455c17fa19.jpg"
            />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para><ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/User:Etern4L">George Bratsos aka
        Etern4L</ulink></para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 24.01.10 th $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Communication</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/">The Mailinglists</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org">The openSUSE Forums</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Contributors</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://users.opensuse.org">The User Directory</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
