<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://michal.hrusecky.net/2011/08/libyui-in-gentoo/">Michal Hrušecký: libyui
        in Gentoo</ulink></title>
    <para>Some time ago I wrote a blog post about <ulink
        url="http://michal.hrusecky.net/2011/06/osc-client-in-gentoo/">osc in Gentoo</ulink>. As I
      already stated there, we’ve got some pretty cool technologies in openSUSE and I would like to
      promote them everywhere. And as I’m also partially Gentoo user and I have many Gentoo friends,
      I’m trying to make some of the coolest openSUSE technologies available on Gentoo. One of the
      cool things we’ve got is libYUI. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 18.08.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/08/19/opensuse-lxde-logo-contest-starting-now/">Andrea
        Florio: openSUSE-LXDE logo contest starting now!</ulink></title>
    <para>As recently announced <ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/08/12/looking-for-artists-artworks-and-graphics-for-lxde/"
        >here</ulink>, the LXDE team is looking for graphics contributors. Trying to involve as much
      people as possible i created a graphic contest! Is time for you, cool graphics, to create a
      logo for the openSUSE-LXDE team!</para>
    <para>The contest will start tomorrow, everyone is welcome to join! All the rules are in <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:LXDE_Logo_Contest">our wiki</ulink>! </para>
    <para>So? what are you waiting for??? </para>
    <para>Is just the right time to <emphasis role="bold">Have a lot of fun…</emphasis></para>
    <!--($ ld: 19.08.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.marques.so/2011/08/a-brief-update-on-things/">Nelson Marques: A
        brief update on things…</ulink></title>
    <para>I’ve been a bit away from openSUSE in the last months (mainly this summer) and this is
      related to several things that are happening in my personal life. During this time I’ve kept a
      look in several packages I maintain for GNOME, but haven’t been doing anything related to
      openSUSE.</para>
    <para>As many people know, the international pressures in Portugal are placing much demanding
      things on every citizen, mainly on the working force. I still don’t see the shackles around my
      hands, but it’s pretty much obvious they exist and they are around my wrists. It’s time to
      rethink the strategy for the life I wanted to live and move out to living it.</para>
    <para>No changes to be announced except that some weight I shouldered is going to be dropped,
      this is the case of GNOME:Ayatana, which I will discuss with Vincent once he’s around, but
      from my side the proposal is simple, salvage all the packages that are requirements to other
      packages and might have some utility in the distro, all the others, just a plain and simple
      nuke them. It served it’s purposes, but I no longer have the time or will to continue
      maintaining stuff, some that worked, others that never worked. In a way I was wrong, openSUSE
      users are far better with the traditional choices, ex: GNOME, than with other alternative
      choices.</para>
    <!--$ ld: 20.08.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://vizzzion.org/blog/2011/08/board-business/">Sebastian Kügler: Board
        Business</ulink></title>
    <para> Tonight, the new board of directors of KDE e.V. went out for dinner, generously (!)
      treated by our constituency. </para>
    <para>It was a nice and relaxed dinner, gave us some good opportunity to brief Lydia (our newest
      board member) on how we work, boring stuff like where we store our documents, what to expect
      from our bi-weekly conference calls, what granularity of emailing we found to be productive,
      and so on. One official thing we always have to do (according to German foundation
      regulations, so-called “Vereinsrecht”) is appointing roles. Cornelius was volunteered as
      president, Frank as treasurer, both accepted their new and old responsibilities. I promoted
      from regular board member to vice president (which really only has a a theoretical meaning).
      The vote was, as usual a formal thing and we got it done between dumpling 2 and 3 on my plate,
      it took all of 3 minutes. Serious, effective, yet duely diligent. :P </para>
    <para>We also used the opportunity to talk about non-board stuff, about our other projects in
      KDE (we’re also pretty active in the community outside of the board chores), private going
      ons, random fun things. I came back happy about our team, and looking forward to our work in
      the coming year. Just right. </para>
    <para>Earlier this afternoon, we met with the GNOME board. There were also some personal changes
      in the new GNOME board, I especially enjoyed Ryan Lortie (desrt) having joined the board of
      directors of the GNOME foundation. I’ve met Ryan at several occasions in the past, and always
      found that we got a good click, enough differences to keep conversations interesting, but very
      much one the same line of communication. One of the topics was communications across the
      boards, and we thought that having some kind of ‘open communication channel’ for situtations
      which might turn unproductive would be good. Ryan and me volunteered, and we took immediate
      opportunity and went out for an afternoon drink, which I very much enjoyed. </para>
    <para>While going to our dinner appointment, I had really two things in mind, love and hate. Not
      sure why those two words sprang to my mind, but I really <emphasis role="italic"
        >hate</emphasis> saying goodbye to the people I <emphasis role="italic">love</emphasis>.
      Even if it’s very much a temporary thing (our meetings in the Plasma team have become pretty
      frequent, especially with Plasma Active One being on the horizon), having people leave after
      an intensive week of excellent collaboration always makes me kind of sad. That’s of course
      just an indication of how much I enjoy working in this excellent team, or maybe just a sign of
      exhaustion after a week of pushing the Free desktop to the next level with peers who are as
      passionate about this as I am. Tomorrow in the afternoon, I’ll take a train back home to the
      Netherlands, and will commence putting our plans (and continuation, tweaks thereof) to action.
      Exhausted after week of frantic Free software conferencing, but just as energized as if it
      were my first Akademy.</para>
    <para>The coming weekend will be used for catching up on sleep, then next weekend, I’ll be at
        <ulink url="http://froscon.de">Froscon</ulink>, where I’ll be presenting Plasma Active. Be
      there if you want to touch it yourself. :) </para>
    <!--($ ld: 12.08.11 sm $-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
