<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="status-updates">
  <title>Status Updates</title>
<!--
  <sect2 role="board">
    <title>Board</title>
    <blockquote>
      <para>...</para>
    </blockquote>
    </sect2> -->  
  <sect2 role="distribution">
    <title>Distribution</title>
<!--* interesting topics relating factory (opensuse-factory) (mostly status) * topics from yast/zypp teams (mostly status) * topics from kde/gnome teams (mostly status) As needed. -->
    <!-- 
    <blockquote>
      <title></title>
      <para></para>
      </blockquote>     
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.suse.de/~coolo/opensuse_11.4/">Schedules for the next week</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>openSUSE 11.4 Milestone 5 release</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Milestone: installation workflow is feature frozen</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Proofreading of all software starts so that we have a new baseline.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Milestone: Feature and version freeze for the complete distribution (exception: patchlevel update of leaf packages until Beta1+)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Milestone: All features are coding and function complete.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Milestone: Kernel and install works on all targeted machines.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
        <para>Milestone: Last round of software translation starts - &quot;hard text freeze&quot;($ ld: 11.12.10 sm $</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>      
      </blockquote> -->
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Important Links</title>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://tinyurl.com/392jnb">Detailed Bugzilla Report</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Submitting_bug_reports">Submitting Bug Reports</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Bug_reporting_FAQ">Bug Reporting FAQ</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
<!--
  <sect2 role="susestudio">
    <title>SUSE Studio</title>

    <blockquote>
      <title>Interesting article</title>

      <para>blah laber</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->  <sect2>
    <title>Team Report</title>
<!--
    <sect3 role="artteam">
      <title></title>
      <blockquote>
        <title></title>
        <para></para>
      </blockquote>
    </sect3> --><!--
    <sect3 role="boosters">
      <title>Boosters Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3> -->    <sect3 role="buildserviceteam">
      <title>Build Service Team</title>
      <!-- News related to Build Service (mostly status) * meeting minutes As needed. -->      
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="http://tittiatcoke.wordpress.com/2010/12/13/opensuse-kdeunstablesc-repo-builds-newer-snapshots-of-4-6-with-all-opensuse-packages/">Raymond Wooninck: openSUSE KDE:Unstable:SC repo builds newer snapshots of 4.6 with all openSUSE packages</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>Are you using the openSUSE KDE 4.6 Beta 2 packages and you would like to try a newer
          version ? Then for the time being you could switch over to the KDE:Unstable:SC repository. </para>
        <para>About 2 weeks ago, I copied the official KDE 4.6 Beta 2 packages over from the
          KDE:Distro:Factory repository to the KDE:Unstable:SC repository. This has two effects,
          namely: </para>
        <para>1) People using 4.6 Beta 2, can easily update to a slightly newer version to see if
          bugs have been resolved, without loosing important patches that are openSUSE specific. </para>
        <para>2) It gives us, the openSUSE KDE team the change to easier and faster adopt to a newer
          release (e.g. RC1, RC2, etc), as that all patches are matches on a weekly basis to the
          newer source code. </para>
        <para>If you decide to switch repository, then make sure that you keep an eye on this blog,
          as that on a certain moment the KDE:Unstable:SC will switch to very unstable snapshots of
          the future KDE 4.7. I will however blog here to let you know that you should switch back
          again repostories, before I will publish the first KDE 4.7 snapshot. </para>
        <para>Feel free to contact me over email or on IRC (tittiatcoke) if you have any questions
          about this. So far KDE 4.6 has been a very stable release and also KDEPIM 4.6 is looking
          better. Let’s hope that the last glitches are also resolved, before KDE 4.6 is released. </para>
        <!-- ($ ld: 16.12.10 sm $) -->
      </blockquote>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/12/16/how-we-use-our-power/">Stephan Kulow: How we use our power</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>I had a side project the last two weeks: Make the build service more fun to use. </para>
        <para>No matter how much fun you have creating packages, if they don’t build, there is
          little point in using a Service that has Build in its name, no? So one of the major goals
          of the service is actually to help those that want to build packages as good as possible.
          But there is a problem: </para>
        <para>Let me quote from the landing page of <ulink url="https://build.opensuse.org/">build.opensuse.org</ulink>: “The openSUSE Build Service hosts 16,414 projects, with
          107,691 packages, in 26,259 repositories and is used by 25,967 confirmed users.”. That are
          quite some high numbers – especially in the relation to the ~25 servers we have for
          actually building. </para>
        <para>If you look at the build statistics of the last month (and this is just i586, x86_64
          has around the same), you notice that there is not much purple in the “Busy workers / Idle
          workers” graphic:</para>
        <figure id="fig.buildservice">
          <title>Buildservice</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata width="50%" fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/Bildschirmfoto11.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>(..)</para>
        <!-- ($ ld: 16.12.10 sm $) -->
      </blockquote>
      <blockquote>
        <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/12/18/osc-0-130-1-bugfix-release/">Marcus Hüwe: osc 0.130.1 (bugfix release)</ulink></title>
        <para>I just released a new osc version: 0.130.1 (bugfix release). The following issues were fixed:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem><para>don’t crash if a file marked as ‘A’ does not exist (<ulink
                url="https://bugzilla.novell.com/show_bug.cgi?id=658664">bnc#658664</ulink>)</para></listitem>
          <listitem><para>fixed proxy handling (<ulink url="https://bugzilla.novell.com/show_bug.cgi?id=657958"
                >bnc#657958</ulink>)</para></listitem>
          <listitem><para>fixed repairwc (<ulink url="https://bugzilla.novell.com/show_bug.cgi?id=657838"
                >bnc#657838</ulink>)</para></listitem>
          <listitem><para>fixed build for python2.4</para></listitem>
         </itemizedlist>
        <para>The new version is available in the<ulink
            url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/openSUSE:/Tools"> openSUSE:Tools</ulink>
            repo.</para>
        <!-- ($ ld: 18.12.10 sm $) -->
      </blockquote>

      <formalpara>
        <title>Build Service Statistics</title>
        <para>Statistics can found at <ulink url="http://build.opensuse.org">Buildservice</ulink></para>
      </formalpara>
    </sect3>
<!--
    <sect3 role="education">
      <title>Education Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3>

    <sect3 role="forums">
      <title>Forums Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
      </sect3> -->    
    <sect3 role="gnometeam">
      <title>GNOME Team</title>
      
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/12/10/new-indicators-the-saga-continues/">Nelson Marques: New Indicators… the saga continues…</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>As the indicator saga continues… some new indicators were built… Indicator-messages is
          a small indicator that pics up messages and stuff from applications to display them on a
          nice all-around indicator. It works fine with evolution (plugin also built and doesn’t
          require patching for what I’ve seen). </para>
        <para>This indicator support more applications, though they require some patching. As being
          discussed on the opensuse-GNOME mailing list as as proposed by Vincent Untz, this
          indicators are moving to GNOME:Apps and there _might_ an effort to support some features
          in applications like empathy. Keep in mind this is not a priority, but if it’s possible to
          support some more feature, it might happen.</para>
        <figure id="fig.gnomeindicator">
          <title>Screenshot</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata width="50%" fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/Screenshot-21.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>Additionally<xref linkend="fig.gnomeindicator"/>, I’ve also tried some other indicators… indicator-application for what I
          can tell is an indicator that removes the menu’s from the GTK applications and places them
          on the panel (MAC style). I’ve built this indicator, but I have no means to test yet
          because further patching is required at least in GTK and eventually on glib. I don’t think
          there’s actually any need to have this indicator, specially when it will bring additional
          efforts on GTK maintenance, and this feature is somehow supported by software like
          gnome-globalmenu (which I’ve also packaged for myself and works dearly with supported
          apps). </para>
        <para>I’ve done some hammering on indicator-sound as well… Ubuntu’s sound widget… I’m stuck
          with some error and I have 2 possibilities… downgrade to the last version of the previous
          branch which should built, or work the current branch (more dependency demanding). I’m
          working on it… it will happen one way or another during the next days. I guess this one is
          actually one of the most wanted :) </para>
        <para>There are few other indicators… for time and date, calendar and so on… Those will be
          last ones. After indicator-sound is done, I’m starting to clean up the packaging and make
          sure it’s compliant to the GNOME team methodology and submit them to GNOME:Apps and the
          support libraries that are required as dependencies forwarded to projects where they might
          be useful (need to check out with the people which ones those will be). </para>
        <para>A special thanks to Ken Vandine from Canonical for some guidance with libindicate. </para>
        <para>I’ve seen around some ‘hate’ waves towards Canonical, and I would like to say that so
          far in the few times I’ve interacted with them, either on bug submission or asking help,
          they have been awesome and caring. It’s really something I would like to point… they are
          pretty cool, and their devs are very helpful (but hey… so are our devs ;) ). Also a very
          special thanks to Vincent Untz, Dimstar and mrdocs which have been a great help and from
          whom I’ve learned already a lot.</para>
        <para>So picking up the useful stuff… and placing it up together in a single Indicator:</para>
        <figure id="fig.gnomeindicator2">
          <title>Screenshot 2</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata width="50%" fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/Screenshot-11.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para><xref linkend="fig.gnomeindicator2"/></para>
        <!-- ($ ld: 16.12.10 sm $) -->      
      </blockquote>
    </sect3>
<!--
    <sect3 role="kdeteam">
      <title>KDE Team</title>

      <blockquote>
        <title></title>

        <para></para>
      </blockquote>
    </sect3> --><!--
    <sect3 role="marketingteam">
      <title>Marketing Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3>

    <sect3 role="medical">
      <title>Medical Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3>

    <sect3 role="monoteam">
      <title>Mono Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3> -->    <sect3 role="openfateteam">
      <title>openFATE Team</title>
      <sect4>
        <title>Top voted Features</title>
        <para>* Features with highest vote, but no one has been assigned to yet. We are looking for volunteers to implement. </para>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/120340">Run download and install in parallel (Score: 323)</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>&quot;Network installation could be improved by running package download and package installation in parallel.&quot;</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <para>&quot;I wanted to open a fate feature about this when I first heard of plymouth, but reading http://fedoramagazine.wordpress.com/2008/10/21/interview-fedora-10s-better-startup/ really makes me think we should go this way. (...)&quot;</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/305305">1-click uninstall (Score: 115)</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>&quot;An easy way to remove Software! </para>
          <para>For  example: you installed an application with &quot;1-click install&quot; (which  will install all the packages that you need), there should be an easy  way (also with 1 click) to remove what you have installed with that  1-click operation... in another words: an &quot;1-click Uninstall&quot; to remove  installed software (dependencies and packages included).&quot;</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/308357">Please, replacement for Sax2 in 11.3, and now for 11.4 (Score: 86)</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>&quot;We  need a replacement for sax2 in 11.3, as a safety measure for when  auto  configuration fails to detect certain monitors/keyboards/mice. (...)&quot;</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/305877">Popularity contest (Score: 75)</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>&quot;We need a feedback about packages that are preferred by users and actively used. Debian already has a tool named Popularity contest (popcon) (...)&quot;</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/305548">YaST-Qt: More informative &quot;Installation Summary&quot; (Score: 60)</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>&quot;The  YaST Qt package manager should provide as much information in the   &quot;Installation Summary&quot; view as zypper, esp the overall download size to   expect and how much disk space will be freed/used after performing the   operation.&quot;</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/305582">Off-Line one click install (MSI for Linux) (Score: 52)</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>&quot;Idea from community member Raúl García.
            Same  concept as MSI packages for Windows but exploiting the One Click   Install concept of openSUSE (and therefore inheriting the simplicity,   code and security. (...)&quot;</para>
        </blockquote>
      </sect4>
      <sect4>
        <title>Recently requested features</title>
        <para>* Features newly requested last week. Please vote and/or comment if you get interested.</para>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310976">System wide media player deamon</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>&quot;Some users use computers only to play media, like music.</para>
          <para>I have a lot of friends, witch only run computer to login and put CDs inside.
We need a system wide deamon, which control how many normal users are logged in, check /usr/media directory and all removable media to start playing music/etc.</para>
          <para>When user get logged, music will stop playing.&quot;</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310979">Set the default mouse behaviour of KDE 4.x to double click to open files / folders</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>&quot;Set the default mouse behaviour of KDE 4.x to double click to open files / folders.</para>
          <para>Current default is single-click to open files / folders.&quot;</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310980">Monthly Qt updates</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>&quot;KDE has monthly updates and mainly depends on Qt.
Qt only has updates from time to time.
If you have crashes with KDE apps which are caused by (resolved) Qt bugs (e.g. <ulink url="http://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=249373">Â¹</ulink><ulink url="http://bugreports.qt.nokia.com/browse/QTBUG-15857">Â²</ulink>) we push them (days/weeks/months/years/decades?) in front of us until a new Qt release. (...)&quot;</para>
        </blockquote>
          <blockquote>
            <title>
              <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310982">Please add Lightspark as a standard avant-garde/forefront browser flash player</ulink>
            </title>
            <para>&quot;I think <ulink url="https://launchpad.net/lightspark">Lightspark</ulink>

is an avant-garde/forefront browser flash player with modern hardware support design and written from scratch.</para>
            <para>We could find it only on Packman repository, but both gnash and swfdec are in standard OpenSuSE repository (swfdec in Packman one too and in a more recent version).</para>
            <para>Are there too some language (flash, swf files) legal troubles?&quot;</para>
          </blockquote>
          <blockquote>
            <title>
              <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310987">Add Intel Atom as a specific architecture</ulink>
            </title>
            <para>&quot;Atom processors, currently very popular in lightweight devices, behave very differently from common Intel/AMD processors; although they can execute code optimized for common x86 or x86-64, they don&apos;t run it much efficiently. Because they are not that fast, every cycle counts.</para>
            <para>I believe it would be useful to consider them a separate sub-architecture that deserves its own set of compilation options.&quot;</para>
          </blockquote>
          <blockquote>
            <title>
              <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310992">WUBI like feature for openSUSE</ulink>
            </title>
            <para>&quot;A feature that I really miss in openSUSE is something like WUBI. Maybe you know this tool, what let you install Ubuntu on a Windows-partition. I think for beginners, who don&apos;t want to create a Linux-partition is this a easy and great way to have a nice welcome-unit in Linux. openSUSE will be a distro for beginners and advanced users, right? So this feature is a real nice present for beginners and people who just want test openSUSE. (...)&quot;</para>
          </blockquote>
            <blockquote>
              <title>
                <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/310994">Restore button in recycle bin</ulink>
              </title>
              <para>&quot;Need &quot;restore&quot; button near &quot;empty Trash&quot; button in Nautilus when a file is selected in Trash Folder.&quot;</para>
            
          
        </blockquote>
        <!-- ($ ld: 18.12.10 sm $) -->
      </sect4>
            
      
      <sect4>
        <title>Feature Statistics</title>
        <para>Statistics for openSUSE 11.4 <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/statistic/product/22236">in openFATE</ulink></para>
      </sect4>
    </sect3>
<!--
    <sect3 role="oooteam">
      <title>OpenOffice Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3> -->

    <sect3 role="testing">
      <title>Testing Team</title>
       <blockquote>
         <title><ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-testing/2010-12/msg00004.html">Larry Finger: Weekly News for December 18</ulink></title>
         <para>The next Testing Core Team IRC meeting to discuss 11.4 Milestone 5 will be held
         December 27 at 1800 UTC.</para>
         <para>The Team had a meeting on Monday, December 6, when we talked about our
           experiences with openSUSE 11.4 M4. The automated installation testing seems to
           be working as no one reported installation failures. Our major complaints were
           Bug #657605 (corrupted downloads), Bug #656060 (poor performance for i945
           graphics hardware), and k3b crashing. The corrupted download bug is fixed in M5,
           and k3b now works. I am aware of other problems with the i915 driver in the
           2.6.37 kernel, but those are being addresses in the upstream kernel.
         </para>
         <para>My early experience with M5 has led be to switch to it from 11.3 on both 32- and
           64-bit systems. From what I see, 11.4 should be a really good distribution.
         </para>
         <para>I repeat my plea for readers of these news to test, test, test, and and report
           all bugs to the Novell bugzilla.</para>
       </blockquote>
    </sect3> 
    
    <sect3 role="translationteam">

      <title>Translation Team</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Daily updated translation statistics are available on the
          <ulink url="http://i18n.opensuse.org/">openSUSE Localization Portal</ulink>.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://i18n.opensuse.org/stats/trunk/toplist.php">Trunk Top-List</ulink> – <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/OpenSUSE_Localization_Guide">Localization Guide</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </sect3>
<!--
    <sect3 role="wiki">
      <title>Wiki Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3>

    <sect3 role="yast">
      <title>YaST Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3> -->  </sect2>
</sect1>
