<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://omgsuse.com/content/ten-days-opensuse-day-five-scribus">OMG!
        SUSE!/rtyler: Ten Days of openSUSE, Day Five: Scribus</ulink>
    </title>
    <note>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is licensed under the <ulink
            url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">Creatice Commons
            Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License</ulink></emphasis>.</para>
    </note>
    <para>On the fifth day of openSU-SE my true love gave to me, <ulink
        url="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BgSe_gzyM1c">fiiiiveeee goollldeeen
        ringggggssss!</ulink>.</para>
    <para>Just kidding, on the fifth day of our countdown to openSUSE 11.4 I wanted to highlight an
      impressive new application that is making it's debut with this release: <ulink
        url="http://www.scribus.net/">Scribus</ulink>. If you're not "in the know" for desktop
      publishing applications, Scribus is:</para>
    <para><quote>Scribus is powerful software that helps you create great looking documents of all
        kinds. It also comes with a lot of support options to help you achieve the best
        result.</quote></para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://cdn.omgsuse.com/omg/images/Scribus-screen.png" width="20%"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>As I'm terribly un-talented when it comes to just about anything spatial, I couldn't
      honestly tell you how great Scribus is in openSUSE 11.4, but the folks I've talked about it
      with seem pretty excited about it. </para>
    <para><ulink url="http://bit.ly/f1CB8v">Install Scribus 1.4 for 11.3</ulink></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 6.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://oyranos-cms.blogspot.com/2011/03/gutenprint-talks-to-colour-management.html">Kai-Uwe Behrmann: Gutenprint talks to colour management systems</ulink></title>
    <para>The <ulink url="http://sourceforge.net/mailarchive/message.php?msg_id=27150124">Gutenprint project is going to tag its colour related print options</ulink> with the <ulink url="http://www.freedesktop.org/wiki/OpenIcc#PPDcolouring">ColorKeyWords PPD entry</ulink>. Thus Gutenprint follows a request to tag colour related options in native device API's. Marking colour related options as being colour related will help automatic profile selection depending on the calibration state in the deriver. So if Gutenprint was set to a increased brightness of 1.1 and the media size is A5, then the colour marked brightness setting will play a role in searching the correct ICC profile, while the non colour hinted paper size will not influence the ICC profile search. This concept works as well for SANE and Xorg. The colour related options can be serialised to a common file format, which still has to be defined. Then this calibration information can be embedded by profilers into ICC profiles. Such calibration data enriched ICC profiles can then even be used to setup the calibration state of a given device + driver combination and automatically ensure the correct usage, while minimising user errors. That approach is already deployed in Oyranos' Xorg module. For display profiles it is typical to embed the calibration data inside the ICC profiles for a long time. The embedded calibration data is used to setup the graphics card to work with the display. Gutenprint is the next candidate to get related to ICC colour management a similar calibration support. </para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 6.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
