<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://saigkill.wordpress.com/2011/01/24/opensuse-weekly-news-poll/">Sascha
        Manns: openSUSE Weekly News Poll</ulink></title>
    <para>Hey you’re reading the openSUSE Weekly News? Then you’re the right person who fill up this
      poll: <ulink
        url="https://connect.opensuse.org/pg/polls/read/saigkill/11553/which-outputformat-of-the-weekly-news-you-prefer"
        >https://connect.opensuse.org/pg/polls/read/saigkill/11553/which-outputformat-of-the-weekly-news-you-prefer</ulink></para>
    <para>The more who are polling the better is it :-)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 24.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/01/26/app-installer-meeting-or-more-collaboration-accross-borders/"
        >App Installer Meeting or More Collaboration Accross Borders</ulink></title>
    <para>Back in October, at the <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/01/26/2010/10/25/thanks-for-your-participation-at-the-opensuse-conference/"
        >openSUSE Conference</ulink>, several meetings and hallway discussions occurred on the topic
      of “Installation ofApplications” on openSUSE. As of today, we still have a very
      package-centric approach, while users usually do not think in terms of packages but in terms
      of applications: people want to use Firefox, LibreOffice or Frozen Bubble.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/appstream_meeting-300x225.jpg"/>
      </imageobject>
      
    </mediaobject>
    <para>We investigated the best way to approach this issue and come to a fast resolution. With
      several people from various distributions already working on some technologies that are
      related to this, we realized this could be a prime example of Collaboration Accross Borders.
      This lead Vincent Untz to contact several people from different distributions, to see if he
      could spark an interest in a cross-distribution meeting on this topic. It turned out that
      everyone replied enthusiastically! That’s how the <ulink
        url="http://distributions.freedesktop.org/wiki/Meetings/AppInstaller2011">App Installer
        Meeting</ulink> saw the light. </para>
    <para>This meeting occurred over three days last week at the Novell/SUSE offices in Nuremberg,
      with 15ish participants, from five distributions: Debian (Enrico Zini, David Kalnischkies),
      Fedora (Richard Hughes, Florian Festi), Mageia (Michael Scherer, Olivier Thauvin, Samuel
      Verschelde), openSUSE (Duncan Mac-Vicar, Michael Schroeder, Pavol Rusnak, Vincent Untz),
      Ubuntu (Michael Vogt, Sebastian Heinlein). Frank Karlitschek and Garrett LeSage joined this
      group of distribution-oriented people. This was a fantastic set of people to tackle the topic,
      some of those having a background on user experience, others on low-level bits of packaging
      systems. </para>
    <para>During these three days, we looked at various bits of technologies, including <ulink
        url="http://debtags.alioth.debian.org/">Debtags</ulink>, the <ulink
        url="https://wiki.ubuntu.com/SoftwareCenter">Ubuntu Software Center</ulink>, the <ulink
        url="http://www.freedesktop.org/wiki/Specifications/open-collaboration-services">Open
        Collaboration Services specification</ulink> and more. This helped us know what is available
      today and where we stand. We quickly agreed that we wanted to share the architecture to
      provide an Application Center for each distribution, even though some distributions might
      choose to have a different set of policies. </para>
    <para>The group worked intensively to define the architecture, from the bottom to the top: this
      includes the definition of a an application metadata format, how to create it and from which
      sources (push as much information as possible upstream!), how to handle user-generated
      metadata, the protocol used to communicate between the distribution server and the Application
      Center client, as well as the user interface. The group is working on properly documenting the
      technical results of this meeting to let the wider community understand the overall
      architecture. Watch the <ulink url="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BHeP2ZBwS_U">video</ulink>
      of a presentation delivered on the last day to Novell people to get an overview of what got
      produced. </para>
    <para>The meeting turned out to be even more productive than originally planned, and all
      participants agreed on a concrete plan with an aggressive time line to push this effort
      forward! Stay tuned! </para>
    <para><ulink url="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BHeP2ZBwS_U">Youtube</ulink> and <ulink
        url="http://blip.tv/file/get/Geeko-AppStreamMeetingSummary895.m4v">m4v</ulink> video file </para>
    <para>Many thanks to all the sponsors of this event: Novell for kindly hosting and sponsoring
      several attendees, Canonical and Red Hat for sending people, and Debian for sponsoring one
      person! </para>
    <para>Article contributed by Vincent Untz</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 26.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
