<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
<!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! --><!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://labs.qt.nokia.com/2011/10/21/the-qt-project-is-live/">The Qt Project is live!</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>I’m happy to announce that the Qt Project officially went live today. Starting today, development of Qt will be governed as a true open source project.</para>
      <para>We now have <ulink url="http://qt-project.org/">qt-project.org</ulink> – a website where all development of Qt will be centered, providing the same infrastructure and processes for everybody that wants to contribute to Qt. (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.socallinuxexpo.org/blog/scale-next-generation-invitation-participation">SCALE: The Next Generation - Invitation for Participation</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The Southern California Linux Expo is proud to announce a conference for the next generation of free and open source community enthusiasts. “SCALE: The Next Generation” — lets the FOSS community leaders of tomorrow spotlight their talents and ideas today. Open to kids 10 and older, the goal of conference is to be as “kid driven” as possible, offering a unique opportunity to see and experience the inner workings of planning a conference. Kids will be able to determine the content and help steer the direction that this mini-conference will take. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 01.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://ostatic.com/blog/tdf-celebrates-100-extensions">OStatic/Susan Linton: TDF Celebrates 100 Extensions</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Little over one month ago The Document Foundation <ulink url="http://ostatic.com/blog/new-libreoffice-extension-website-live">announced</ulink> their new online extension repository. At that time it had maybe a couple of dozen total extensions and templates, but now the number totals over 100.</para>
      <para>A short <ulink url="http://blog.documentfoundation.org/2011/11/25/we-are-100/">note</ulink> from Florian Effenberger expressed the projects pride and gratitude towards those who have been contributing. OpenOffice.org had a wide selection and many articles were devoted to the bounty. Today, LibreOffice is well on its way to closing the gap. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 02.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://www.h-online.com/open/news/item/Balsam-Enterprise-OBS-offers-a-commercial-build-platform-1388329.html"
          >h-online: Balsam Enterprise OBS offers a commercial build platform</ulink></title>
      <para>German company <ulink url="http://enterprise.open-slx.com/en/?Welcome">open-slx</ulink>
        has announced the release of the <ulink url="http://enterprise.open-slx.com/en/?BE-OBS"
          >Balsam Enterprise Open Build System (BE-OBS)</ulink>, a distribution development platform
        for Linux software. The system is a commercialised version of openSUSE's <ulink
          url="http://openbuildservice.org/">Open Build Service</ulink> which automates the build
        and release process for Linux software. openSUSE's OBS is used by SUSE and openSUSE, by
        other companies such as Dell, Cray and GENIVI, and projects including MeeGo. BE-OBS is used
        internally by open-slx to construct their own Linux products, which has also enabled the
        company to develop its own in-house expertise. </para>
      <para>The BE-OBS uses a cluster of systems with load-balanced build agents to enable building
        and packaging, testing and release, and distribution and maintenance. It is suitable for
        building custom Linux distributions, dedicated software stacks, cross-platform applications
        and virtual appliances. BE-OBS is able to automate compilation from a single codebase
        targeting different hardware architectures, including 32- and 64-bit x86 and ARM, and using
        different operating systems including SLES, RHEL and CentOS. (...)</para>
      <!--($ Id: 02.12.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.itworld.com/it-managementstrategy/228371/why-free-software-not-job-killer">ITworld/Brian Proffitt: Why free software is not a job killer</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Catching up on the post-Holiday news, I read with interest this headline on today&apos;s ComputerWorld UK site:</para>
      <para>&quot;<ulink url="http://blogs.computerworlduk.com/spannermans-edublog/2011/11/does-free-software-cost-jobs/index.htm">Does Free Software cost jobs?</ulink>&quot;</para>
      <para>The author of the article is Dr. John Spencer, who laments that during the current recession, the message of free and open source software&apos;s (FLOSS) cost benefits have indeed been taken to heart… so much so that there are hardly any open IT jobs in the British education sector. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 01.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.networkworld.com/community/blogs/learnedfrommypets">Network World/Rikki Endsley: Everything I Needed to Know about Linux I Learned from My Pets</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Perhaps you aren&apos;t a pet person. Some of my best friends aren&apos;t, either. Or maybe you are Apple-obsessed or a Windows enthusiast. I love my Mac and know plenty of people who work with Windows. In any case, here are a few ways living with my pets reminds me of living with Linux. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 01.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.esecurityplanet.com/network-security/apache-server-hit-by-reverse-proxy.html">eSecurityPlanet/Sean Michael Kerner: Apache Server Hit by Reverse Proxy</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The open source Apache HTTP Web Server is at risk from a reverse proxy flaw that is currently unpatched. The flaw was disclosed Qualys security researcher Purtha Parikh late last week and is related to a flaw that Apache first attempted to fix in October.</para>
      <para>&quot;While reviewing the patch for the older issue CVE-2011-3368, it appeared that it was still possible to make use of a crafted request that could exploit a fully patched Apache Web Server (Apache 2.2.21 with CVE-2011-3368 patch applied) to allow access to internal systems if the reverse proxy rules are configured incorrectly, Parikh <ulink url="https://community.qualys.com/blogs/securitylabs/2011/11/23/apache-reverse-proxy-bypass-issue">reported</ulink>. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 01.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
<!--<sect2>
  <title>LOL</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://like-a-boss.org/2011/09/30/hacking-the-imperial-death-march/">like-a-boss.org: hacking the imperial death march</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>One of the great things about the original Star Wars trilogy, was the “lived in”, junky, hacked together aesthetic of the Star Wars universe. Everything was a bit trashed, as if real people actually lived there. Thankfully, that’s one of the things that George Lucas hasn’t tinkered with in his endless quest to ruin the childhood memories of a generation. So it’s heartening to see this tradition carried on with the playing of the imperial death march on miscellaneous hacked together hardware. Enjoy … (...)</para>
  </blockquote>
</sect2>--></sect1>
