<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://mschlander.wordpress.com/2011/03/12/opensuse-11-4-has-been-released/"
        >Martin Schlander: openSUSE 11.4 has been released</ulink></title>
    <para>In case you hadn’t heard, openSUSE 11.4 was released this Thursday, and as usual <ulink
        url="http://opensuse-guide.org/">opensuse-guide.org</ulink> was updated at the same time. </para>
    <para>I think overall it’s a very good release, besides being the first major distribution to
      ship KDE SC 4.6, LibreOffice Linux 2.6.37 with free Broadcom wlan drivers (for some recent
      chips) and other goodies. </para>
    <para>You can read the announcement <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/10/opensuse-11-4/">here</ulink> or read the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/Product_highlights">Product highlights</ulink> for a more
      extensive presentation of the new stuff.</para>
    <para>As customary I like to also prepare people for the most likely causes of problems:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>PulseAudio is now installed and enabled in KDE installations by default. If it’s
            causing sound problems, you can disable it in YaST -> Sound -> Other -> PulseAudio
            Configuration (or run ‘setup-pulseaudio –disable’) or even uninstall it – KDE doesn’t
            have hard dependencies on it.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>GStreamer is the new default Phonon backend – enough said. You may want to use
            phonon-backend-xine or phonon-backend-vlc (from Packman) instead, if Amarok or other
            Phonon applications misbehave.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>The great new KDE Bluetooth tool – BlueDevil – has a missing dependency on
            obexd-client, which means you’ll need to install obexd-client yourself in order for
            sending files via Bluetooth to work.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>The NetworkManager plasmoid is not perfect. An online update should be along soon
            improving it significantly. If it’s causing problems you can easily install and use
            nm-applet (NetworkManager-gnome) instead – with the new oxygen-gtk theme it doesn’t even
            look bad ;-)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para>That’s it for me. Have a lot of fun with 11.4.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 13.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
