<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
  <!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://lwn.net/Articles/420487/"
        >The Document Foundation joins Open Invention Network</ulink></title>
      <para>The Document Foundation has joined the 
        Open Invention Network (OIN), to further extend the free software 
        ecosystems. By becoming a licensee, The Document Foundation - developer 
        of LibreOffice, a free office suite for personal and corporate 
        productivity - has joined the growing list of organizations that 
        recognize the importance of participating in the Open Invention Network, 
        in order to protect the free software ecosystem from the risks 
        associated to software patents.</para>
      <para><quote>The Document Foundation is a major free software project, and 
        LibreOffice a key office suite for creating, managing and sharing 
        documents. By becoming a licensee of the Open Invention Network, we 
        fight software patents - which stifle innovation and encourage predatory 
        business practices - and at the same time we improve the protection of 
        our software projects,</quote> said Charles Schulz, Member of TDF Steering 
        Committee.</para>
      <para>Patents owned by Open Invention Network are available royalty-free to 
        whichever company, institution or individual that agrees not to assert 
        its patents against free software. Through this network of developers, 
        distributors, sellers, resellers and end-users that license its patent 
        portfolio, Open Invention Network is creating a supportive and shielded 
        ecosystem to ensure the growth and adoption of free and open source 
        software. This enables OIN licensees like The Document Foundation to 
        make significant investments, helping to fuel economic growth.
      </para>
      <para>OIN has amassed a broad portfolio of patents, including patents held by 
        nominees on its behalf. These patents are available to all licensees as 
        part of the patent portfolio that OIN is creating in support of free 
        software. The license agreement is at 
        <ulink url="http://www.openinventionnetwork.com/pat_license_agreement.php">http://www.openinventionnetwork.com/pat_license_agreement.php</ulink></para>
      <para>The home of The Document Foundation is at <ulink url="http://www.documentfoundation.org">http://www.documentfoundation.org.</ulink></para>
      <para>The Document Foundation has the mission to facilitate the evolution of 
        the OOo Community into a new open, independent, and meritocratic 
        organization within the next few months. An independent Foundation is a 
        better match to the values of contributors, users and supporters, and 
        will enable a more effective, efficient, transparent, and inclusive 
        Community. TDF will protect past investments by building on the 
        achievements of the first decade, will encourage wide participation in 
        the Community, and will co-ordinate activity across the Community.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 20.12.10 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <!--  
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>gfg</title>
      <para>...</para>
    </blockquote>
    </sect2> -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://www.linuxlinks.com/article/2010121106112994/NotableGamesPart2.html"
          >21 More Notable Free Linux Games (Part 2 of 3)</ulink></title>
      <para>We have always been strong advocates of computer games. Rather than rotting the brain,
        computer games are interactive, teach essential life skills, and can stimulate learning.
        They also have been proven to enhance skills such as creativity, cooperation, teamplay, as
        well as encouraging innovative and strategic thinking and improving hand-eye coordination. </para>
      <para>Linux is not championed as a viable gaming platform in many communities, in part because
        of its smaller user base and the relatively low number of commercially supported native
        Linux games that are released each year. However, there are a number of encouraging
        developments on this front. For example, the Unigine engine should enable developers to
        produce high-quality 3D games with up-to-date visuals and advanced rendering. One title to
        be released using this engine is OilRush. This eagerly awaited title fuses a classical real
        time strategy with a Tower Wars genre. </para>
      <para>Notwithstanding these developments, Linux has an ever-expanding library of tens of
        thousands of free games, many of which are released under an open source license. A good
        proportion of these titles are entertaining, highly addictive, offer captivating gameplay,
        and are challenging. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 20.12.10 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://ostatic.com/blog/my-top-five-favorite-distributions-for-2010"
          >Ostatic/Susan Linton: My Top Five Favorite Distributions for 2010</ulink></title>
      <para>Ms. Carla Schroder shared a list of her <quote>bestest distros</quote> recently, so I thought I might
        follow suit. She called hers <quote>not-usual</quote> and looking at her list, I'd say my choices are
        probably a little more usual. In any case, here are my top five favorite Linux distributions
        for 2010, in no real order.</para>
      <para>
        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink url="http://www.mepis.org/">MEPIS</ulink></para>
            <para>SimplyMEPIS has always been one of my favorite distributions for several reasons. SimplyMEPIS was one of the first to understand that looks 
              do matter and so does out of the box functionality. It includes proprietary drivers, codecs, and browser plugins that make using Linux enjoyable. It 
              leans toward the conservative side concerning new version of its components, but that makes for an extremely stable operating system. In all its years I 
              only ran into one release that gave me any trouble, and that was about three or four years ago - possibly when it went through its Ubuntu phase. It is 
              truly one of the best.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink url="http://www.opensuse.org/">openSUSE</ulink></para>
            <para>openSUSE has been one of my favorites since it first opened up to community
              involvement in 2005. Novell's agreement with Microsoft did damper my enthusiasm a bit,
              but the distro itself remains one of the most polished and professional offerings we
              have. It just has a commercial feel to it. Like SimplyMEPIS, I only encountered one
              release that gave me any trouble. Otherwise, its been a slick and attractive distro. I
              don't run it full time mainly because I'd have to hunt up some one-clicks (that are
              available for openSUSE) or install codecs and stuff myself to get going and then worry
              about those updates. But it always remains high on my radar. I follow its development
              very closely. I'm a little worried about what will become of it despite assurances.
              But as long as it lives, so will my admiration. (...)</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 20.12.10 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://www.thevarguy.com/2010/12/16/novells-sale-to-attachmate-the-untold-story-finally-revealed/"
          >The VAR Guy: Novell’s Sale to Attachmate: The Untold Story Finally
        Revealed</ulink></title>
      <para>The VAR Guy did some digging and found an SEC filing that more fully describes Novell’s
        pending sale to Attachmate. The filing describes how J.P. Morgan, working on Novell’s
        behalf, shopped Novell around to multiple bidders, and Novell mulled potential deals
        involving Microsoft and other unnamed companies. Novell even considered running SUSE Linux
        as a standalone business. Here’s the story only The VAR Guy took the time to pursue. </para>
      <para>Overall, Novell representatives contacted 52 potential buyers. Roughly nine official
        bidders emerged. So how did Attachmate wind up buying the bulk of Novell’s assets? And what
        happened to rumored SUSE Linux bids from VMware? In a preliminary <ulink
          url="http://sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/758004/000119312510279941/0001193125-10-279941-index.htm"
          >proxy statement</ulink> dated December 14, Novell offers an extensive time line
        describing how the company’s board of directors, executive team, and external financial
        advisors pursued potential buyers for the company. The filing is more than 100 pages. Here
        are some of the highlights, paraphrased by The VAR Guy. Please note:<itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>The vast majority of the info below is based on information within Novell’s SEC
              filing.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Novell protects the names of several bidders, referring to them as Party A through
              Party E. In some cases, The VAR Guy makes some educated guesses about the actual
              identity of each company. But The VAR Guy’s educated guesses could be wrong.
              (...)</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 16.12.10 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/roll-your-own-linux-distribution-with-novells-suse-studio/7972"
          >ZDNet/Steven J. Vaughan-Nichols: Roll your own Linux distribution with Novell's SUSE
          Studio</ulink></title>
      <para>One of the advantages of Linux is that you’ve always been able to build your own Linux
        distribution… if you were an expert programmer. But, today thanks to programs like <ulink
          url="http://www.novell.com/">Novell</ulink>’s <ulink url="http://susestudio.com/">SUSE
          Studio</ulink> it’s easier than ever to create Linux appliances or your house-brand Linux. </para>
      <para>For proof that you can use SUSE Studio to create useful applications look no further
        than the winners of <ulink url="http://www.novell.com/promo/suse/the-disters-contest.html"
          >Novell’s Dister Awards</ulink>. The two $10,000 grand prizes went to software companies,
          <ulink url="http://radicalbreeze.com/">Radical Breeze</ulink> and Anderware. </para>
      <para>Radical Breeze, won in the “Commercial” category for its <ulink
          url="http://susegallery.com/a/aUkeyz/illumination-software-creation-station">Illumination
          Software Creation Station</ulink>. This program lets non-developers design their own
        software applications with no programming experience required. Anderware, a software company
        from Sweden, won in the “Community” category for its <ulink
          url="http://susegallery.com/a/qxpS1q/hypergrid-to-go">Hypergrid to Go</ulink> appliance,
        which allows users to easily set up an extension to the OpenSim platform to create a
        multi-user 3D world similar to Second Life.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 18.12.10 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://www.h-online.com/security/news/item/Gawker-break-in-123456-is-a-popular-password-1153562.html"
          >h-online: Gawker break-in: 123456 is a popular password</ulink></title>
      <para><ulink
          url="http://www.duosecurity.com/blog/entry/brief_analysis_of_the_gawker_password_dump"
          >While analysing</ulink> the user data <ulink
          url="http://www.h-online.com/news/item/User-data-published-after-Gawker-server-break-in-1151996.html"
          >stolen</ulink> from US blog operator Gawker, security experts from Duo Security have also
        cracked 400,000 of the approximately 1.3 million DES-encrypted passwords. The experts'
        analysis showed that 123456 was the most frequent password, being used more than 2,500
        times. It was closely followed by password, which was chosen by almost 2,200 users. 12345678
        was chosen by more than 1,200 users. Next in popularity were qwerty, abc123, 12345, monkey,
        111111, consumer, letmein and 1234. </para>
      <para>Simple passwords are popular in Germany. When the database of German dating portal
        flirtlife.de was hacked in 2006, 123456 was found to be the most popular password.
        (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 15.12.10 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>LOL</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>would you like to laugh? Look this</title>
      <para>hihi :-)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
</sect1>
