<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="tipsandtricks">
  <title>Tips and Tricks</title>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Desktop Users</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.makeuseof.com/tag/manage-twitter-identica-accounts-choqok-linux/"
          >MakeUseOf/Danny Stieben: Manage Your Twitter &amp; Identi.ca Accounts With Choqok</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>For people who are really tweet-o-holics, constant access to <ulink
          url="http://www.makeuseof.com/tags/twitter">Twitter</ulink> (or <ulink
          url="http://www.identi.ca">Identi.ca</ulink>, an open source clone of Twitter) is as much
        a necessity as food and water. At varying levels, this may also be true for those who are
        fans of Twitter but not necessarily tweet-o-holics.</para>
      <para>One possible choice is to have Twitter up and running in the browser most of the time.
        While this is a feasible solution, you’ll start missing out when the browser is minimized.
        Also, a browser isn’t exactly lightweight on system resources. Therefore, your best bet
        would be to use a well-built Twitter desktop client.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">About Chokoq</emphasis></para>
      <para><ulink url="http://choqok.gnufolks.org">Choqok</ulink> is a slim Twitter and Identi.ca
        client made to integrate well with the <ulink url="http://www.makeuseof.com/tags/kde"
          >KDE</ulink> desktop environment. As far as social media clients go, <ulink
          url="http://www.makeuseof.com/tag/gwibber-the-everything-client/">Gwibber</ulink> may be a
        more well known piece of software, but it’s best suited to run under a <ulink
          url="http://www.makeuseof.com/tags/gnome">GNOME</ulink> desktop. You’re always welcome to
        try Gwibber with KDE, but I’ve always preferred software native to the desktop environment
        you’re using. With Choqok, you can quickly and easily reach your Twitter stream at any time
        and get notifications that appear right on your desktop. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 14.8.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://dkukawka.blogspot.com/2011/08/how-to-undelete-files-from-ext3ext4.html">Danny Kukawka: How to undelete files from ext3/ext4</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Sometimes, especially on the command line, it happens that you delete a file or
        directory you didn&apos;t really plan to delete. A second after hit enter you realize what you
        have done, maybe you are fast enough to stop the deletion process and save some files, but
        in the most cases it&apos;s already to late, at least for some files. If you have no or a too
        old backup you&apos;re screwed.</para>
      <para>If you use ext3/ext4 you may be able to recover the file with <ulink url="http://code.google.com/p/ext3grep/">ext3grep</ulink> or<ulink url="http://extundelete.sourceforge.net/">extundelete</ulink> with information from the
        file system journal if the content of the file wasn&apos;t already overwritten by new
        data. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 10.8.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://techlaze.com/2011/08/best-plasma-widgets-kde/">Techlaze: Top 5 Plasma Widgets for the KDE Desktop</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>With KDE 4.7, the KDE team has managed to create one of the most beautiful desktops out there, and to be honest, it’s even more appealing than Windows 7 or Mac OS X. On the usability front, KDE doesn’t seem to cut corners. Trademark features like Activities and Plasmoids (widgets) are polished to near perfection. Also, since the initial KDE 4 release, a lot of quality community-created widgets and plugins have sprung up, making the KDE workspace more than just an alternative to GNOME 3 or Unity. So, if you’ve just installed KDE on your computer, here are some of the best widgets you can drop on to your desktop and make your friends jealous. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 12.8.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.brighthub.com/hubfolio/matthew-casperson/blog/archive/2011/08/08/copying-the-contents-of-a-file-to-the-clipboard-in-nautilus.aspx">Hubfolio/Matthew Casperson: Copying the contents of a file to the clipboard in Nautilus</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Hi - my name is Matthew, and I am a copy-and-paste addict. I have no idea how I would use a PC without a clipboard, and when I was on Windows <ulink url="http://www.thornsoft.com/">Clipmate</ulink> was one of my favorite utilities. I have tried over the years to find open source alternatives, but nothing has come close.</para>
      <para>One script that I did <ulink url="http://askubuntu.com/questions/55626/right-click-copy-contents-of-file-to-clipboard">come across recently</ulink> allows you to copy the contents of files selected in the Nautilus Gnome file browser to the clipboard. This is great for copying things like code snippets and customized email signatures for those applications that don&apos;t natively offer that functionality. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 12.8.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxjournal.com/content/printing-scribus">Linux Journal/Bruce Byfield: Printing in Scribus</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Scribus is designed for quality printing. Unlike a word processor, its output is not meant simply to be good enough for practical use, but to be fine-tuned until it is as close as possible to what you want. For this reason, printing is considerably more complicated in Scribus than in the office applications with which you may be familiar.</para>
      <para>Fortunately, Scribus usually chooses defaults that fit most cases. It also provides rollover help that advises you on whether you need a setting -- although, depending on your version of Scribus, some settings may not be included in this help.</para>
      <para>Still, once you know the work-flow, printing in Scribus is relatively straight-forward. Many of the options are either specifically for professional-quality printing, or for fixing specific problems. Taking the time to familiarize yourself with the options, gives you the chance to come closer to the perfectionism that is impossible in office applications. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 12.8.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Commandline/Script Newbies</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.howtoforge.com/first-steps-of-running-linux-via-terminal-instead-of-desktop">HowtoForge/Christian Schmalfeld: First Steps Of Running Linux Via Terminal Instead Of Desktop</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>This tutorial is supposed to show new Linux users how to handle Linux without having to browse through your desktop to edit files. The core commands to do this are the same on every Linux distribution, however there is a large variety of commands that differ from distribution to distribution, as does the install command. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 12.8.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Developers and Programmers</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://python4kids.wordpress.com/2011/08/08/using-images-in-the-gui/">Python4Kids/Brendan Scott: Using Images in the GUI</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><ulink url="http://www.ibras.dk/montypython/episode33.htm#4">
          <emphasis role="italic">Gladys leaps over to the tape deck, presses levers and switches. Sound of tape reversing. There is a hum and lights flash on and off. A blurred image of a lady in the street comes up on one of the monitors.</emphasis>
        </ulink></para>
      <para>In this tutorial we look at using images in a GUI environment. One of the possible
        attributes which can be assigned to a Label or Button widget is an image. You will surely
        have seen many buttons with images on them.  Every time you see a toolbar in a program,
        each of the images on it is itself on a button widget. In order to do this tutorial though
        there are a couple of issues:<itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>first, you need to have images in the Python4kids directory we set up several
              tutorials ago. You also need to start Python from within that directory.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>second, unless you install something called the Python Imaging Library (PIL),
              Python can only handle a few limited types of image file. One of the file types which
              will work is .gif, which we will be using here. This tutorial<emphasis role="bold">will not work</emphasis> with jpeg files.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>third, you need to have the gif files we’re going to use in your python for kids
              directory. (...)</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
<!--($ Id: 10.8.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://net.tutsplus.com/tutorials/ruby/ruby-for-newbies-testing-with-rspec/">Nettuts+/Andrew Burgess: Ruby for Newbies: Testing with Rspec</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Ruby is a one of the most popular languages used on the web. We’re running a Session here on Nettuts+ that will introduce you to Ruby, as well as the great frameworks and tools that go along with Ruby development. In this episode, you’ll learn about testing your Ruby code with <ulink url="http://rspec.info/">Rspec</ulink>, one of the best testing libraries in the business. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 12.8.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For System Administrators</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://olex.openlogic.com/wazi/2011/supercharge-nagios-with-plugins/">Wazi/Juliet Kemp: Supercharge Nagios with Plugins</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><ulink url="http://olex.openlogic.com/packages/nagios">Nagios</ulink> is a great application for monitoring your systems, allowing you to set alert levels and trip actions when those levels are reached. The software uses a plugin-based structure; even the most simple functions (such as check_ssh and check_disk) are plugins. This makes Nagios incredibly flexible; if there’s something you want to monitor, and you can think of a way to write it, you can write a plugin, hook it into Nagios, and start running it. But even better than that: for most things you might want to monitor, someone has already done written the plugin for you. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 12.8.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://aim4r.blogspot.com/2011/08/nmap-pentesters-one-step-shop-to.html">Houcem Hachicha: Nmap : The Pentester&apos;s One Step Shop to Network Domination </ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Nmap is one of the best security software in the world. It is free and open source. It is actively developed and new features and improvements are added to it on a daily basis.
Originally, Nmap is a network portscanner. The tool has then been extended to perform service and OS identification. With the addition of the Nmap Scripting Engine (NSE) back in 2008, Nmap is today capable of performing vulnerability scanning and even exploitation.
In this blog, I&apos;ll try to describe some of the Nmap capabilities that can be harnessed in blackbox penetration testing. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 12.8.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://flossstuff.wordpress.com/2011/08/07/using-a-file-as-a-storage-device/">Flossstuff/Ankur Aggarwal: Using A File As A Storage Device</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>We all know that file stores our information in many types of formats. But do you know that  we can use it as a storage device too. Surprised???? Let’s go through the crazy process :D</para>
      <para>We are going to create a empty file in Linux, format it and then mount it as if we are mounting a partition.  This process is long , So to understand it easily I am dividing it into 4 steps. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 12.8.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.ibm.com/developerworks/linux/library/l-lpic3-312-3/index.html?ca=drs-">IBM developerWorks/Sean A. Walberg: Learn Linux, 302 (Mixed environments): Print services</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>In this article, learn to:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Create and configure printer sharing</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Configure integration between Samba and the Common UNIX® Print System (CUPS)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Manage Windows® print drivers, and configure downloads of print drivers</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Configure the [print$] share</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Understand security concerns with printer sharing</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Set up and manage print accounting
(...)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
<!-- ($ Id: 12.8.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
