<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.bryen.com/getting-articles-into-news-opensuse-org">Bryen Yunashko:
        Getting Articles into News.openSUSE.org</ulink></title>
    <para>At the recent 12.1 Marketing hackfest, we devised an editorial schedule and folks have
      begun writing articles for promoting 12.1.ý However, some of these articles haven’t been
      submitted yet.ý We suggest that in order to minimize confusion and reduce excessive pinging,
      you create an <ulink url="http://ietherpad.com">ietherpad</ulink> with your article and link
      to it in the editorial schedule at <ulink url="http://ietherpad.com/sked"
        >http://ietherpad.com/sked</ulink> or send your article directly to news@opensuse.org.
      (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 27.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://blog.cornelius-schumacher.de/2011/09/my-opensuse-conference.html">Raymond
    Wooninck: Chromium browser got accepted into openSUSE:Factory</ulink></title>
    <para>After maintaining the Chromium browser in the openSUSE Contrib repositories, the last few weeks things 
      got accelerated and as of this moment the Chromium browser has become officially part
      of openSUSE:Factory (the future 12.1).ý </para>
    <para>The first step wa taken about 3 – 4 weeks ago
    when a separate development project was created (network:chromium). From there onwards it was
    just a matter of getting the package in the right shape for Factory and making sure that all
    legal and security conditions were met. Those who are tracking the updates of Chromium in this
    devel repo, might have noticed that a number of rebuilds were triggered for the 16.0.880 version
    of Chromium. This all had to do to get a single spec-file that would satisfy both Factory
    requirements but also would be able to build for the older distributions. At this moment this
    special repository offers builds for 11.3, 11.4, Factory and also for Tumbleweed.ý</para>
    <para>I am quite
    proud on this fact and I hope that the openSUSE Chromium users will be happy with this fact.ýAt
    the moment I am preparing an update to the 16.0.891 version and hopefully sometime beginning of
    next week the new snapshot will become available.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 27.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.wafaa.eu/entry/growing-some-opensuse-arms-1-69.html">Andrew Wafaa:
        Growing some openSUSE ARMs</ulink></title>
    <para>One of the things that came out of the recent <ulink url="http://conference.opensuse.org"
        >Geeko Love-In</ulink> for me was a new project to immerse myself in within openSUSE. Yeah I
      know, we have enough existing projects already so why create a new one? Simples! Believe it or
      not but openSUSE is behind the curve in a specific segment, and that segment has yet to
      explode to its full potential. That segment is ARM. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 23.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/09/19/osc11-slides-and-screen-cast-workshop-kvmlibvirtd/"
        >Bruno Friedmann: osc11 slides and screen cast workshop kvm/libvirtd</ulink></title>
    <para>Just a quick note, my slides and screen cast about my recent openSUSE conference workshop
      about KVM/libvirtd are online at<ulink url="http://goo.gl/fQfql">http://goo.gl/fQfql</ulink>
      Check at material subject</para>
    <!--($ ld: 24.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
