<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="status-updates">
  <title>Status Updates</title>
  <!--
  <sect2 role="board">
    <title>Board</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>openSUSE Weekly News searches for contributors</title>
      <figure>
        <title>Merry Christmas (c) Péronne vd Ham / pixelio.de</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata width="45%" fileref="http://images.pixelio.de/data/media/51/sterre_22_wr_Large.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>Hello Mates. The last year was a great year. We had seen many funny things. The Relaunch
        of the openSUSE BuildService now provides many Features for packager. Then the
        kde-obs-generator makes the life easier for cross packaging. The openSUSE Conference was
        another interesting Highlight, and last but not least the sell of Novell. </para>
      <para>The openSUSE Weekly News Team searches the whole week for new things. Now we searching one
        or two new Contributors who are collecting news with us. In the past we have given one part
        of the news to one person, and that person was responsible for this part of the Weekly News.
        As Example you provide the Section &quot;Tips and Tricks&quot; so you can add and remove that Section
        what do you think is the best.</para>
      <para>ATM we can give the following Sections to a good Hand:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Tips and Tricks</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>In the Community</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>On the Web.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>What do you need for working in the english newsletter? If you can read and a little bit
        write XML, and you know how to svn up, then you&apos;re the perfect Candidate. If you can&apos;t this
        things, and would like to learn it, you are a perfect Candidate.</para>
      <para>If you&apos;re interested in helping us, just send a Mail to: <ulink url="mailto:saigkill@opensuse.org">saigkill@opensuse.org</ulink></para>
      <para>Last but not least the openSUSE Weekly News team with the translations into hungarian,
        greek and japanese wishes merry cristmas to all people across the world.</para>
      </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
  <sect2 role="distribution">
    <title>Distribution</title>
    <!-- 
    <blockquote>
      <title></title>
      <para></para>
      </blockquote>     
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.suse.de/~coolo/opensuse_11.4/">Schedules for the next week</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>openSUSE 11.4 Milestone 5 release</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Milestone: installation workflow is feature frozen</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Proofreading of all software starts so that we have a new baseline.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Milestone: Feature and version freeze for the complete distribution (exception: patchlevel update of leaf packages until Beta1+)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Milestone: All features are coding and function complete.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Milestone: Kernel and install works on all targeted machines.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
        <para>Milestone: Last round of software translation starts - &quot;hard text freeze&quot;($ ld: 11.12.10 sm $</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>      
      </blockquote> -->
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Important Links</title>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://tinyurl.com/392jnb">Detailed Bugzilla Report</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Submitting_bug_reports">Submitting Bug
            Reports</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Bug_reporting_FAQ">Bug Reporting
            FAQ</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
  <sect2 role="susestudio">
    <title>SUSE Studio</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://www.lenzg.net/archives/332-Updated-Drupal-7-appliances-to-version-7.0-final.html"
          >Lenz Grimmer: Updated Drupal 7 appliances to version 7.0 final</ulink></title>
      <para>Congratulations to the Drupal community for getting <ulink
          url="http://drupal.org/drupal-7.0">version 7.0</ulink>
        <ulink url="http://drupal.org/drupal-7-released">released</ulink>! This is a major mile
        stone and an excellent reason to <ulink url="http://www.drupal7releaseparty.org/"
          >celebrate</ulink>! If you want to give Drupal 7 a try without having to install anything,
        I've now updated my Drupal 7 appliances on <ulink url="http://susestudio.com/">SuSE
          Studio</ulink> to the latest release. The appliance is based on <ulink
          url="http://software.opensuse.org/113/en">openSUSE Linux 11.3</ulink> and is available in
        two variants:<itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>A <ulink url="http://susegallery.com/a/Byn5dM/drupal-7-testdrive"
                >text-mode</ulink> only appliance to which you connect using your local web browser
              via the network.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>A <ulink url="http://susegallery.com/a/Byn5dM/drupal-7-testdrive-gui">GUI
                version</ulink> that starts up the Firefox browser in a minimalistic GNOME desktop
              to perform the installation locally. Remote network access is available, too.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
      <para>The database backend is phpMyAdmin has been added to support web-based administration of
        the MySQL server. You can access it via http://localhost/phpMyAdmin/. I also added <ulink
          url="http://drush.ws/">drush</ulink>, the Drupal command line shell and scripting
        interface and some additional packages (yast2-http-server, bind-utils, php5-ctype, patch). I
        also bumped up the appliance's version number to 7.0.0, to match the version number of
        Drupal included. </para>
      <para>The appliance is available in various formats:<itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>A live raw disk image, ready to be written to an USB stick or flash drive</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>A live ISO image, to be burned on a CD or used in a virtual machine</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>A hard disk image, to be dumped on a hard disk drive</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Various virtual disk formats, e.g. OVF, VMWare/VirtualBox/KVM and Xen</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
      <para>Please see the installation instructions provided on the download pages for details on
        how to use the various image formats. </para>
      <para>So congratulations to the Drupal developer community for reaching this goal and thanks
        to SuSE/Novell/Attachmate for providing the infrastructure for creating such appliances. I
        also would like to especially thank <ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/author/rbos/"
          >Richard Bos</ulink> for the testing and many suggestions for improvement of these
        appliances!</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 5.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Team Report</title>
    <!--
    <sect3 role="artteam">
      <title>Art Team</title>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="http://karl-tux-stadt.de/ktuxs/?p=2950">Sirko Kemter: openSUSE 11.4 – Color trouble</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>If you have the last Milestone of openSUSE, thats already number 5, installed then you
          can take a look into the history. You would see a dark splash as I planned them long time
          ago. You also see the KDM in the color I planned in August.</para>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata width="25%" fileref="http://karl-tux-stadt.de/graph/kdm114.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>2 weeks ago Coolo asked for some artwork for integrate it into the next Milestone, a
          weekend with lot of work, for Javier and me. After that some people woke up. First the KDE
          team wanted the color changed to celadon, whats also is the codename for 11.4. Thats ok
          for me, its there choice and it would be work with the grey what I planned for the GNOME
          side.</para>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata width="25%" fileref="http://karl-tux-stadt.de/graph/celadon.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>But now the GNOME team also want it changed. And that becomes now harder to do. There
          are some possibilities and also some borders for the work. Right now there is a little
          discussion on the mailinglist. But the default background of GNOME would be definitly not
          happen, he is nice but the blue works not with the celadon green tone. Also change that
          background to celadon green, wouldnt work because I have to choose one of the backgrounds
          for the bootsplash. Hope they find a solution I can work with. I would prefer a grey one,
          with a celadon geeko on it and change the green tone in sonar to celadon green
          also.</para>
      </blockquote>
    </sect3> -->
    <!--
    <sect3 role="boosters">
      <title>Boosters Team</title>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/29/opensuse-boosters-year-2010/">openSUSE
            Boosters Year 2010</ulink>
        </title>
        <figure id="fig.boosters">
          <title>The elusive Thirsty Thirteen</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata width="50%" align="center"
                fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/Opensuse-boosters-300x200.jpg"
              />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>At the end of the year it is the time for reviews and the openSUSE Booster <xref
            linkend="fig.boosters"/> team did not want to let that opportunity slip. So what was
          important in 2010 from an openSUSE Boosters perspective? What happened, what progress was
          made, how did the boosters help openSUSE? A report from Klaas Freitag.</para>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Who are the Boosters</emphasis></para>
        <para>For those who do not know who <ulink
            url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Boosters_team">the Boosters</ulink> are: We’re not
          Tuxies favorite boy group, but a bunch of people dedicated to help the openSUSE Project in
          any way we can. The team consists of 13 people (BTW: widely known as the thirsty thirteen)
          with skills ranging from low level C hackery over Ruby on Rails mastering to Graphical
          Design or Project Management. Our team picks milestones and works on them in a agile
          fashion while always following our mantra: Grow community by enabling community. You can
          meet us at the usual places like IRC, the mailinglists or events were we show up and
          spread the word about openSUSE. We’re there to make contributors life easier and more fun,
          so if you have anything do not hesitate to talk to us. We’re here for you.</para>
        <para role="bold"><emphasis role="bold">Events in 2010</emphasis></para>
        <para>So let’s quickly fly over the year of 2010 and see what was nice and important.</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>FOSDEM</para>
            <para>Lets start with a very important event, FOSDEM in Brussels in February. We
              traveled there by coach the first time. That was remarkable because there were some
              push back against before (long journey) but we did it because it is cheaper, which
              means more people can go. The result was that we all were quite pleased by the coach
              trip as it was comfortable and fun, and finally not so much longer than the flight.
              And yes, consider how much carbon dioxide was saved? Since that trip I am constantly
              nagging for budget for an openSUSE Coach…</para>
            <para>I held a talk about Hermes at FOSDEM which was, well, not a great success, that
              thing seems hard to market. That happens, others were more succesfull, like
              Christopher with his talk about image building with Kiwi. Michal had a meeting with
              MySQL packagers from all over the world at FOSDEM, which was probably the first real
              initiative to collaborate on cross distro topics. I also bought a GNOME T-Shirt, met
              tons of old friends, had cherry beer and got a cold as usual on FOSDEM.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Dev meeting</para>
            <para>Also in February, we hosted a dev meeting of 25 KDE hackers here in the Nuremberg
              office. They worked on the highly rated plasma workspace for KDE 4.5. I still wonder
              how Will managed to get around with definitely no sleep for days.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Bento and wiki work</para>
            <para>At home, at the beginning of the year we worked on projects called
                <quote>Integrate all Infrastructure under one Umbrella</quote> which resulted in the
              Bento web theme nowadays at all openSUSE sites use. It provides short ways from one
              site to another by thought through and pretty menus. Robert did a real great job with
              that and we got a lot of external recognition for it. At the same time the Wiki
              project started which was a huge project the Wiki community was pulling together with
              Henne and Tom. The decision was to create a new Wiki from scratch, implement reviewing
              features and transfer all relevant content into the new one while making sure to not
              transfer stuff nobody needs and maintains any more. That was a big thing and caused a
              lot of discussion. Today we can look back and say that we now have a well structured
              Wiki with valuable content. Fortune favors the bold :-)</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>OBS</para>
            <para>In parallel to that, Coolo and Tom were contributing to the new BuildService
                <ulink url="http://build.opensuse.org">web interface</ulink>. After long working
              hours we finally came out with a great web interface for OBS which was a big bum for
              the whole project, as it makes working in OBS much more fun. I remember that whole
              thing being started as a sprint called “Factory status”, aiming to provide a good
                <ulink url="https://build.opensuse.org/projectstatus?project=openSUSE%3AFactory"
                >overview page</ulink> for the Factory project in OBS. It grew a bit more ambitions,
              but, well, that’s how it goes if things are in movement ;-)</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>LinuxTag</para>
            <para>In June, there was LinuxTag in Berlin where most of us participated with talks in
              the free program or workshops on our booth. We educated a lot of people how to
              contribute to openSUSE in various ways. From submitting code fixes through the Build
              Service to creating great Geeko graphics with Inkscape to how to twist their own Geeko
              out of pipe cleaners.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>openSUSE 11.3</para>
            <para>In July, openSUSE 11.3 was released. That was lots of work beforehand with quite
              some boosters involvement, as Mr. Distro Coolo is part of the team. However not only
              he is contributing to the distribution, we all have our shares in it. 11.3 was a good
              one, it got good press and showed that we as a community are doing great. All over the
              world release parties were organized, some Boosters took over the one here in
              Nürnberg. <ulink
                url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/07/16/opensuse-11-3-launch-party-in-nurnberg/"
                >Nice party</ulink> with some talks, along with BBQ and beer. The latter ran out at
              7pm, because many community members showed up. Cool, I love that kind of stress to
              organize food and beer quickly to let the party go on :-)</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>GNOME and KDE conferences</para>
            <para>Also in Summer, GUADEC as well as Akademy took place for our desktop Boosters.
              Vincent rocked GUADEC and gave away Geekos and stuff and advertised openSUSE as a good
              platform for the upcoming GNOME3. Will could not go to Akademy this year for a very
              good reason called Anna :-)</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>openSUSE conference</para>
            <para>In autumn, the for me most exciting event of the year took place, the second
                <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Conference">openSUSE Conference</ulink>.
              We were heavily involved in organizing, program committee work, giving talks and
              presentations and all what is involved with that kind of large event. It was a huge
              success, as a very active and passionate community showed up. Discussions went from a
                <quote>This is what we did</quote> in the last year to a <quote>this is what we
                could do</quote> which is so great to see as that is resulting in innovation for the
              whole project. As a result some very concrete sub projects were created such as
                <quote>Project Brezn</quote> and openSUSE Invis which slowly evolves.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>openFATE, Connect and more</para>
            <para>After the conference and the release of 11.3 we started to dig into milestones
              again with <ulink url="http://features.opensuse.org">openFATE</ulink> and <ulink
                url="http://connect.opensuse.org">Connect</ulink>. Since a couple of weeks we have a
              nice looking openFATE that has the features that make it possible for the feature
              screening team to work on one of our most important tasks in our project: Looking into
              the future of the distribution with feature evaluation. We also implemented the future
              of the user/group handling for all the openSUSE services with a social twist: Connect.
              Our own instance of a social network that makes it possible to connect the people that
              make this project what it is and at the same time makes it possible to centralize the
              user data.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Busy 2010</emphasis></para>
        <para>So all in all the boosters had a very busy and prosperous year 2010. All of us carried
          their individual share of work in the various areas of the openSUSE project we participate
          in, be it in the openSUSE KDE and GNOME Teams, the openSUSE Distribution, the openSUSE
          tools or the openSUSE Board. We attended a lot of events and organized a couple of our own
          with great success. And we worked together on the most pressing milestones we saw for
          contributor growth in a fun and clever way. All in all we helped a lot of contributors to
          stand up, take responsibility and do get their hands dirty for the openSUSE Project. That
          makes us proud and we will do this smarter, faster, better and stronger in 2011.
          Promised!</para>
      </blockquote>
      </sect3> -->
    <sect3 role="buildserviceteam">
      <title>Build Service Team</title>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="http://michal.hrusecky.net/2011/01/mysql-5-5-in-opensuse-build-service/"
            >Michal Hrusecky: MySQL 5.5 in openSUSE Build Service</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>MySQL 5.5 is GA for more then a month already. If you are reading some news, you
          probably already heard, that it is great, million times faster, has trillion new features
          that you desperately need and much more. Of course, I’m exaggerating a little bit. But
          anyway, MySQL 5.5 is new version everybody talks about. So now when do you get it? It is
          already lying around for some time in server:database:UNSTABLE repository. It was there
          since beta, but took me some time to get final version ready. Just add it to your
          repositories for example by:</para>
        <screen>zypper ar -f http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/server:/database:/UNSTABLE/openSUSE_11.3 server-database-unstable></screen>
        <para>and then install it by</para>
        <screen>zypper in mysql-community-server_55</screen>
        <para>As it conflicts with whatever MySQL variant you currently have, it will ask you to
          confirm uninstallation of your currently installed MySQL. Then it will replace it and you
          can start trying it.</para>
        <para>And to answer question when it will be in official openSUSE. For 11.4 is too late. I
          know it was made GA last year already, but as many things depends on MySQL, I don’t want
          to accidentally break something. So you can expect it in next openSUSE (11.5 or 12.0, not
          sure what the name would be). And maybe in Tumbleweed a little bit sooner, after some
          testing, but currently don’t know when. And of course, it is build not only for openSUSE
          11.3, so here comes full list of repositories it is built for:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink
                url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/server:/database:/UNSTABLE/Fedora_12/"
                >Fedora 12</ulink></para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink
                url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/server:/database:/UNSTABLE/Fedora_13/"
                >Fedora 13</ulink></para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink
                url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/server:/database:/UNSTABLE/SLE_11/"
                >SLE_11</ulink></para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink
                url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/server:/database:/UNSTABLE/SLE_11_SP1/"
                >SLE_11_SP1</ulink></para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink url="">openSUSE 11.1</ulink></para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink
                url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/server:/database:/UNSTABLE/openSUSE_11.2/"
                >openSUSE 11.2</ulink></para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink
                url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/server:/database:/UNSTABLE/openSUSE_11.3/"
                >openSUSE 11.3</ulink></para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink
                url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/server:/database:/UNSTABLE/openSUSE_Factory/"
                >openSUSE Factory</ulink></para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <!-- ($ ld: 11.1.11 sm $) -->
      </blockquote>
      <formalpara>
        <title>Build Service Statistics</title>
        <para>Statistics can found at <ulink url="http://build.opensuse.org"
          >Buildservice</ulink></para>
      </formalpara>
    </sect3>
    <!--
    <sect3 role="education">
      <title>Education Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3>

    <sect3 role="forums">
      <title>Forums Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
      </sect3> -->
    <!--
    <sect3 role="gnometeam">
      <title>GNOME Team</title>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/12/29/kick-off-for-gnomeayatana-project/"
            >Nelson Marques: Kick off for GNOME:Ayatana Project…</ulink>
        </title>
        <para><quote>Follow effective action with quiet reflection. From the quiet reflection will
            come even more effective action.</quote> // Peter F. Drucker</para>
        <para>This has been one of the guidelines in my life for quite some time… It started as a
          curiosity a long time ago with Notify OSD and evolved to full project in openSUSE. It is
          important to acknowledge at this point the motivation provided by the openSUSE GNOME Team
          from which I’ve been getting plenty of guidance and help, namely from Vincent Untz (vuntz)
          and Dominique ﻿Leuenberger (Dimstar). Thanks to them, we have now a GNOME:Ayatana Project
          on OBS (openSUSE Build Service), currently being populated with the support libraries for
          Ayatana’s Unity and Indicators.</para>
        <para>Susan Linton has made a small article for Linux Journal about this project in the
          past. Though some people pointed to me that it was advertising and excelling Ubuntu… I
          would like to leave a statement… We’re not taking a hike on Ubuntu visibility, and it
          isn’t bad at all, on the contrary… In fact it will help Ubuntu, us and many others…
          specially if some Ubuntu patches are accepted faster by upstream. I hope other RPM
          distributions will follow the way we, openSUSE, proudly seem to pioneering! From my
          personal point of view… a distribution <quote>distributes</quote>… and despite this
          software isn’t attractive for some openSUSE users, I’m happy it is available (totally or
          partially) for all those who want to test it… Wait… you don’t even need to install Ubuntu
          or changing the platform you run!</para>
        <para>Due to several reasons, being the most important of them versioning, this repository
          will start on the next release of openSUSE in March 16th (World day of Conscience,
          interesting point). This is also interesting as if YOU are willing to improve a package or
          submit a package you can now do it to this repository.</para>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata width="65%" align="center"
              fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/Screenshot-nmarques@magtheridon...ketherielayatana.png"
            />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>This goes with a very huge cookie for Dimstar and Vuntz for taking care of this
          repository and making sure that everything will comply with the openSUSE Guidelines. You
          are my personal heroes. (...)</para>
      </blockquote>
    </sect3> -->
    <sect3 role="kdeteam">
      <title>KDE Team</title>
      <blockquote>
        <title><ulink
            url="http://tittiatcoke.wordpress.com/2011/01/04/opensuse-kdeunstablesc-repo-becomes-trunk-again/"
            >Raymond Wooninck: openSUSE KDE:Unstable:SC repo becomes Trunk again !</ulink></title>
        <para>A little warning to those that have switched over to the KDE:Unstable:SC repo. The
          target is that either tonight or tomorrow a new Trunk snapshot will be loaded in this
          repo. That would mean that the Unstable becomes unstable again.</para>
        <para>I have already been building a number of snapshots based on the opened KDE 4.7 trunk
          and have to admit that things are still looking very stable and even kdebindings is
          compiling well :-) But this might of course change from the moment that KDE 4.6 has been
          released and the focus shifts to the newer 4.7 release. </para>
        <para>I will keep you posted on the developments around this repository, but this would be
          the moment to switch over to KDE:Distro:Factory if you want to get the RC1, RC2 and KDE
          4.6 final version for your openSUSE system. Currently it contains RC1, but this would
          change in the next few days once RC2 is released. </para>
        <!-- ($ ld: 5.1.11 sm $) -->
      </blockquote>
    </sect3>
    <sect3 role="marketingteam">
      <title>Marketing Team</title>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink
            url="http://dev-loki.blogspot.com/2011/01/review-of-opensuse-trademark-guidelines.html"
            >Pascal Bleser: Review of openSUSE Trademark Guidelines</ulink>
        </title>
        <para><ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/User:Byunashko">Bryen</ulink> just opened an <ulink
            url="https://features.opensuse.org/311039">interesting feature request about a review of
            the current openSUSE trademark guidelines (#311039).</ulink>
        </para>
        <para>The current state of things is that Novell owns the openSUSE and openSUSE related
          trademarks (which include things like the openSUSE name and the openSUSE branding). While
          at some point I would love to see those trademarks go into the ownership of the openSUSE
          foundation (but let&apos;s first actually have that foundation ;)), it is better to keep
          them with Novell until we have a properly working and funded foundation, because owning
          trademarks is also an obligation to enforce them. And that potentially means legal
          enforcement as well. </para>
        <para>As the trademarks are owned and enforced by Novell, permissions to use trademarked
          material must be sent to Novell (<email>permission@novell.com</email>, actually), but in
          practice, Novell&apos;s legal team has been delegating the responsibility of evaluating
          such requests to the openSUSE board. </para>
        <para>Nevertheless, the board has to take decisions within a certain framework. Part of that
          framework, obviously, are a few legal aspects, but more prominently, it is what is
          currently defined in the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Trademark_guidelines"
            >openSUSE Trademark Guidelines</ulink> document. </para>
        <para>Bryen&apos;s feature request (which is essentially filed as such because <ulink
            url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Openfate">openFATE</ulink> gives us a good tool for
          transparency and collecting feedback) is precisely about that point: let&apos;s take a
          step back and rethink our trademark guidelines. </para>
        <para>The task isn&apos;t as simple as it might sound, of course, as we have to find a good
          balance between a few, most probably contradictory things:<itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>make the rules short and simple: the simpler they are, the easier to grasp and
                the less daunting to approach</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>enable derivatives of openSUSE: yes, we&apos;d love to see more and more
                derivative works based on openSUSE (but the <ulink
                  url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Trademark_guidelines">current
                  guidelines</ulink>, which the board has to abide by, do not really reflect
                that)</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>prevent abuse</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist></para>
        <para>Which is why we&apos;d love to hear from YOU what you believe are genuinely good use
          cases that we want to enable and support and what you believe would be cases of abuse,
          especially if you have been involved or have been pondering about making a derivative of
          openSUSE or, more generally, use the openSUSE trademarks in one way or another. </para>
        <para>To do so, <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311039">just click here</ulink>,
          log in with your openSUSE account, and give us constructive feedback. Thanks !</para>
        <!-- ($ ld: 7.1.10 sm $) -->
      </blockquote>
    </sect3>
    <!--
    <sect3 role="medical">
      <title>Medical Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3>

    <sect3 role="monoteam">
      <title>Mono Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
      </sect3> -->
    <sect3 role="openfateteam">
      <title>openFATE Team</title>
      <sect4>
        <title>Top voted Features</title>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Features with highest vote, but no one has been assigned to yet.
            We are looking for volunteers to implement. </emphasis></para>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/120340">Run download and install in parallel
              (Score: 331)</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>&quot;Network installation could be improved by running package download and package
            installation in parallel.&quot;</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/305493">Look at plymouth for splash during
              boot (Score: 159)</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>&quot;I wanted to open a fate feature about this when I first heard of plymouth, but
            reading
            http://fedoramagazine.wordpress.com/2008/10/21/interview-fedora-10s-better-startup/
            really makes me think we should go this way.</para>
          <para>Ray&apos;s comment starting with &quot;Every flicker and mode change in the boot
            process takes away from the whole experience.&quot; is especially interesting. Is it
            okay to track the &quot;don&apos;t show grub by default&quot; here?&quot;</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/305305">1-click uninstall (Score: 123)</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>&quot;An easy way to remove Software! </para>
          <para>For example: you installed an application with &quot;1-click install&quot; (which
            will install all the packages that you need), there should be an easy way (also with 1
            click) to remove what you have installed with that 1-click operation... in another
            words: an &quot;1-click Uninstall&quot; to remove installed software (dependencies and
            packages included).&quot;</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/308357">Replacement for Sax2 (Score:
              96)</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>&quot;We need a replacement for sax2 in 11.3, as a safety measure for when auto
            configuration fails to detect certain monitors/keyboards/mice. (...)&quot;</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/305877">Popularity contest (Score: 76)</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>&quot;We need a feedback about packages that are preferred by users and actively
            used. Debian already has a tool named Popularity contest (popcon) (...)&quot;</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/305548">YaST-Qt: More informative
              &quot;Installation Summary&quot; (Score: 60)</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>&quot;The YaST Qt package manager should provide as much information in the
            &quot;Installation Summary&quot; view as zypper, esp the overall download size to expect
            and how much disk space will be freed/used after performing the operation.&quot;</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/305582">Off-Line one click install (MSI for
              Linux) (Score: 57)</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>&quot;Idea from community member Raúl García. Same concept as MSI packages for
            Windows but exploiting the One Click Install concept of openSUSE (and therefore
            inheriting the simplicity, code and security. (...)&quot;</para>
        </blockquote>
        <!-- ($ ld: 8.1.11 sat *updated* $) -->
      </sect4>
      <sect4>
        <title>Recently requested features</title>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Features newly requested last week. Please vote and/or comment
            if you get interested.</emphasis></para>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311024">add pyudev, the python bindings for
              libudev, as a package</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>it would be nice to have the python-bindings for libudev as a package in the
            opensuse distribution.</para>
          <para>http://packages.python.org/pyudev/</para>
          <para>they work very well and are under quite active development.</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311026">Ability to list reiser4 partitions in
              Yast partitoner</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>Ability to list reiser4 partitions in Yast partitoner</para>
          <para>I have a kernel installed [1] which handles this type of partition but yast cant see
            or manipulate it in any way.[1]</para>
          <para>http://www.spinics.net/lists/reiserfs-devel/msg02657.html
            http://www.spinics.net/lists/reiserfs-devel/msg02654.html</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311027">How to simplify partitioning during
              install for people who are new to Linux</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>Currently, you have to know a thing or two about partitioning if you want to install
            openSUSE. I&apos;ve found that it&apos;s possible to simplify the partitioning process
            by suggesting two frequently used configurations alongside the advanced partitioning
            system that is currently used by the installer. (...)</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311028">Add &quot;Enable/disable numlock at
              startup&quot; option to installer and YaST</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>Related thread: https://features.opensuse.org/310152</para>
          <para>Some people who don&apos;t have a QWERTY layout can&apos;t use the numbers on the
            top of the keyboard. I&apos;m an AZERTY user so I have to hold Shift to use the numbers
            on top of the keyboard. Therefore I usually prefer using the numpad, but that isn&apos;t
            possible if the numlock is switched off. Auto-enabling numlock at startup would be a
            huge time-saver. (...)</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311029">Add Link to Documentation Site</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>The official documentation seems to be not very known in the openSUSE world. To make
            it more visible, I would suggest the following improvements: </para>
          <para>* Add a link http://docs.opensuse.org to the welcome screen (SUSEgreeter?) of a
            fresh installation </para>
          <para>* Include http://docs.opensuse.org to the list of pre-installed bookmarks in
            Firefox, Konqueror, ... </para>
          <para>* Maybe add an icon on the desktop which refers to the above link. </para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311030">Add the new ZFS file system Kernel
              module</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>This is very cool, ZFS will be available on Linux in a few days and it will have
            decent performance. </para>
          <para>http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=article&amp;item=linux_kqzfs_benchmarks&amp;num=1</para>
          <para>http://zfs.kqinfotech.com/</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311031">Support of Mp3-konvert in KDE /
              Dolphin</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>Its a longt time ago, you can convert an Audio CD very easy into mp3 Files. You just
            type audiocd:/ in dolphin or konqueror and copy the mp3 Files to your Hard disk. Its
            much more easy than in Windows. (...)</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311033">GPS devices</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>It woul be nice to update, control and use my TomTom without the need for a
            Winbox.</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311035">Support different linux installations
              in grub</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>When you update your kernel via Suse updater, the entries for different linux
            installations in grub disappear. Just the Suse and the Windows (!) entries are
            preserved. (...)</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311037">let partitioner create faster
              RAID</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>Both mkfs.ext[234] and mkfs.xfs have options to tune the filesystem for striped RAID
            (i.e. RAID0/RAID10), so it would be nice if yast2/disk could make use of it.</para>
          <para>The options are</para>
          <para>-E stride=x -E stripe-width=y and -d sunit=x,swidth=y</para>
          <para>notice that units of above sizes may vary.</para>
          <para>There are several sites out there describing how to choose the proper values for x
            and y, e.g. </para>
          <para>http://www.mythtv.org/wiki/Optimizing_Performance</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311038">Update to Eclipse 3.6.1</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>Update from Eclipse 3.4 from OpenSuse 11.3 to Eclipse 3.6.1 is desirable.</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311039">Review of openSUSE Trademark
              Guidelines</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>This feature request is meant to collect the comments of the community at large The
            current guidlines can be found here</para>
          <para>http://en.opensuse.org/OpenSUSE_Trademark_Guidelines</para>
          <para>The openSUSE Board will review comments posted here along with concerns and
            considerations collected elsewhere and find ways to strengthen/clarify the
            guidelines.</para>
          <para>Please review the current guidelines and post comments on language. (Giving specific
            language change suggestions is helpful) and if you have specific cases where current
            guidelines have been a problem, please post here as well.</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311040">Remote Desktop</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>In example like xrdp, but with better services with i.e. german keyboards and
            supplying with sound and videos.</para>
          <para>Most ThinClients can connect to ICA Xen-Desktop-Server and Windows-RDP-Protokoll. It
            should be also an option, than to use Microsoft Server 2003/2008 for enterprises.</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311043">switch to a UEFI-ready bootloader by
              default</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>While reading a review of a Sandy Bridge motherboard in Anandtech it was pointed
            that upcoming intel motherboards will ship with a UEFI firmware instead of a BIOS. While
            reading the documentation for UEFI firmware I noticed that the bootloader has to be a
            UEFI application. In order to support this new hardware we need a bootloader that
            supports UEFI booting, GRUB legacy as far as I know doesn&apos;t support this. I think
            it&apos;s time to retire GRUB legacy and use GRUB2, elilo or rEFIt (though this one is a
            long shot).</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311045">Old-repositories handling during
              upgrade (inst_upgrade_urls) needs rewriting</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>See more in Bug <ulink url="https://bugzilla.novell.com/show_bug.cgi?id=556469"
              >#556469</ulink></para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311046">Autoredirect to specify language
              version wiki</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>Can make autoredirect from wiki.opensuse.org to *language*.opensuse.org. As in
            www.opensuse.org (for me it&apos;s autoredirect to www.opensuse.org/ru/).</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311047">Remove Windows Local Installer</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>The local installer which starts up when a windows user loads the openSUSE DVD,
            allowing installation to be started from a running windows OS, IS an absolute
            disaster.</para>
          <para>Did I say it was an absolute disaster?</para>
          <para>Oh yes, I did say that. Either remove it or include a unmistakable warning, that
            using it is likely to lead to disaster and that installation is best done by booting
            from the DVD.</para>
        </blockquote>
        <!-- ($ ld: 8.1.11 sat $) -->
      </sect4>
      <sect4>
        <title>Feature Statistics</title>
        <para>Statistics for openSUSE 11.4 <ulink
            url="https://features.opensuse.org/statistic/product/22236">in openFATE</ulink></para>
      </sect4>
    </sect3>
    <!--
    <sect3 role="oooteam">
      <title>OpenOffice Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
      </sect3> -->
    <!--
    <sect3 role="testing">
      <title>Testing Team</title>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-testing/2011-01/msg00000.html">Larry
            Finger: Weekly News for January 1</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>The next Testing Core Team IRC meeting will be held 2011-01-31 at 18:00 UTC and will
          discuss 11.4 M6.</para>
        <para>Attendance at the December 27 meeting was optional. As many of the team were on
          holiday, only two were present. Neither of us had any particular problems with 11.4 M5,
          thus we took some time to get to know each other. As we did not have a real meeting, the
          IRC log will not be posted.</para>
        <para>The openSUSE forums have not had many complaints about M5, thus it appears to be
          shaping up quite well. In addition, the 2.6.37 kernel, which is used in 11.4, will have
          its release in roughly 1-2 weeks, thus there will be approximately 3 months of kernel
          testing before 11.4 is released. That is good timing.</para>
        <para>Wishing everyone a happy and prosperous new year.</para>
      </blockquote>
    </sect3> -->
    <sect3 role="translationteam">
      <title>Translation Team</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Daily updated translation statistics are available on the <ulink
              url="http://i18n.opensuse.org/">openSUSE Localization Portal</ulink>.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://i18n.opensuse.org/stats/trunk/toplist.php">Trunk Top-List</ulink>
            – <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/OpenSUSE_Localization_Guide">Localization
              Guide</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </sect3>
    <!--
    <sect3 role="wiki">
      <title>Wiki Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3>

    <sect3 role="yast">
      <title>YaST Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
      </sect3> -->
  </sect2>
</sect1>
