<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <figure id="fig.holiday">
    <title>Holiday Geeko</title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/holiday-geeko-245x300.png" width="15%"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </figure>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/13/holiday-wishes-from-the-opensuse-board/"
        >Holiday Wishes from the openSUSE Board</ulink></title>
    <para>Seasons Greetings to everyone in the openSUSE Community and beyond from the openSUSE
      Board! </para>
    <para>As we come to the end of 2010, we’d like to take a moment to reflect on a banner year in
      the Project. We’ve had some very good progress this year and 2011 promises to be an even
      greater year. This year, we hosted our second annual openSUSE Conference in Nuremberg, Germany
      with over 70 presentations and many BoF discussions. Attendance grew from the first year. </para>
    <para>Also, this year, the Board rolled up its sleeves and opened up a discussion with the
      Community about the strategic direction of openSUSE. A finalized strategic statement is
      imminent. The creation of an openSUSE Foundation is well underway. We’re currently reviewing
      legal documents related to the creation and are very excited about this. The Foundation will
      be a step forward in further empowering our Community. More and more people are stepping up to
      champion openSUSE’s role in the open source world. We saw ambassador growth in countries like
      Brasil and Greece, and stengthened in other places like India, Europe and the United States.
      We’re seeing more people available to show up at conferences and events to present and
      demonstrate openSUSE. </para>
    <para>In addition to releasing openSUSE 11.3, the openSUSE Build Service also reached a critical
      milestone earlier this year with the release of 2.0. A gem of our Project, the Build Service
      aims to not only make package management easier for our own distro but to also make it easier
      with other distros. Truly an open project. Community days abounded all over the place
      throughout the year from Collaboration days to bug/hacking days as teams set aside time to
      complete tasks and move forward with their plans. The openSUSE Board will be holding its final
      meeting of 2010 this Wednesday at 19:00 UTC in the #opensuse-project IRC channel on Freenode.
      We invite you all to attend, as all of our meetings our public and we do appreciate the many
      contributions our Community offers during our meetings, particularly during the “Where can we
      improve?” session we implemented earlier this year. Incidentally, it is election season again
      for the openSUSE Board and we’re excited to see so many candidates. If you’ve been thinking
      about running for one of the two seats, we encourage you to apply for candidacy ASAP! </para>
    <para>To be sure, serving on the Board is a rewarding experience, and also requires commitment
      and dedication. 2011 is going to be a turning point year for the Project. With the creation of
      the Foundation and implementation of the openSUSE Strategy, there is no doubt that many new
      initiatives from the Community will come forth and the Board will play an important role in
      guiding and shaping the future of openSUSE as a Project. </para>
    <para>So, as we close here, we’d like to wish each and every one of you a safe and joyous
      holiday season with friends and loved ones. You can be sure that as we Board members toast in
      the New Year from various corners of the world, we’ll be thinking of you all and rejoicing
      being part of a strong, dedicated and passionate community. </para>
    <para>See you all at Wednesday’s meeting, and in 2011! </para>
    <para><emphasis role="italic">The openSUSE Board Pascal Bleser, Rupert Horstkötter, Pavol
        Rusnak, Henne Vogelsang, Bryen Yunashko</emphasis><xref linkend="fig.holiday"/>
    </para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 14.12.10 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/14/alan-clark-new-opensuse-board-chairman/"
        >Alan Clark new openSUSE Board Chairman</ulink></title>
    <figure id="fig.aclarc">
      <title>Alan Clark. Chairman of the openSUSE Board</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/AlanClark-252x300.jpg" width="25%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>As you know, Michael Loeffler has left the openSUSE Board to pursue new opportunities, we
      are sad to see him go and wish him well. With his departure and with the upcoming Board
      elections, we have a desire to see a new Chairperson selected. The election rules state that
      the Chairperson be appointed by Novell and yesterday Markus Rex, General Manager of Novells
      Open Platform Solutions, presented Alan Clark to us as the new Chairperson. </para>
    <para>As you may be aware, we have focused a significant amount of our time on the creation of
      an openSUSE Foundation to be independent and to be able to collect and spread funds. And
      Novell has been very supportive with our desire to see this come to fruition. Markus told us
      that one of the reasons he selected Alan is that he has a lot of expertise in setting up
      foundations. Alan helped to form the Open Source Development Labs (OSDL) and the Linux
      Foundation, as well as several other open source projects and organisations. We, along with
      Markus, believe that Alan’s experience and expertise will be an asset of immense value to the
      Board, and we welcome that as we, and Novell, partner together in forging ahead on an exciting
      and promising future for the openSUSE Project. </para>
    <para>Alan has already been working with us on the foundation work, but most of you probably
      don’t know him, so we asked Alan to introduce himself: </para>
    <para>Having the opportunity to work closely with the openSUSE community is an exciting
      endeavour. My work assignments over the past few years have enabled me to work directly with
      members of the community. By attending the recent openSUSE conference I was able to make many
      more friends and acquaintances. As always it was a great experience. One of my personal goals
      from this role will be to get to know and to work with as many members of the community as
      possible. </para>
    <para>A bit about me: Though my engineering roles have varied throughout the years, I am a
      software developer at heart. I began my career writing Unix based network protocols. Anybody
      remember LAT? My past projects have helped me develop a broad technical base across the
      spectrum of software development, from device drivers, to file systems, to network protocols,
      to identity and security, to developer SDKs and across multiple operating systems. I remember
      that the first day I was able to do my work on Linux was a great day. </para>
    <para>I am extremely optimistic for the future of openSUSE, the potential growth of the
      community, delivery of the openSUSE strategy and the advancement of Linux in general. Our
      community has a great future! My goal is to help facilitate the many ambitions of the openSUSE
      community members and advance the openSUSE Guiding Principles.</para>
    <para>Please join us in welcoming Alan to his new role! Alan will begin his position at the next
      openSUSE Board meeting tomorrow at 19:00 UTC in the #opensuse-project channel on the Freenode
      network. All of our meetings are open to the public and we welcome you to our meeting to meet
      Alan.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 14.12.10 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.novell.com/promo/suse/the-disters-contest-winners.html">Novell
        "The Disters" Award</ulink></title>
    <para>Novell has released at Wed, 15 Dec 2010 the winners of the "The Disters" award. We
      congratulate all Winners.</para>
    <para>Other Souces: <ulink
        url="http://www.linux.com/news/enterprise/biz-enterprise/390534-novell-names-first-annual-dister-winners"
        >Linux.com</ulink></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 16.12.10 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/08/join-us-on-saturday-for-the-next-opensuse-zombie-bug-day/"
        >Join us on Saturday for the next openSUSE “Zombie” Bug Day</ulink></title>
    <para>On Saturday the 27th of November a Bug Day was organized to <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/11/22/opensuse-bug-day-on-saturday-november-27th/">solve
        the issue with Zombie bugs</ulink>, bugs against old, non-maintained versions of openSUSE. A
      team got together in the <ulink url="irc://irc.freenode.net/opensuse-bug"
        >#opensuse-bug</ulink> channel on the <ulink url="http://freenode.net">freenode</ulink>
      network to review the bugs for any important and still valid information, otherwise closing
      them to clean up <ulink url="http://bugzilla.novell.com">bugzilla</ulink>.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Results</emphasis> The outcome has been <ulink
        url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-project/2010-11/msg00205.html"
      >awesome:</ulink></para>
    <table frame="all">
      <title>Results</title>
      <tgroup cols="5">
        <colspec colname="open Bugs in:" colnum="1"/>
        <colspec colname="openSUSE 10.2" colnum="2"/>
        <colspec colname="openSUSE 10.3" colnum="3"/>
        <colspec colname="openSUSE 11.0" colnum="4"/>
        <colspec colname="Total" colnum="4"/>
        <thead>
          <row>
            <entry>open Bugs in: </entry>
            <entry>openSUSE 10.2</entry>
            <entry>openSUSE 10.3</entry>
            <entry>openSUSE 11.0</entry>
            <entry>Total</entry>
          </row>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry>Before</entry>
            <entry>40</entry>
            <entry>162</entry>
            <entry>526</entry>
            <entry>728</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>After</entry>
            <entry>15</entry>
            <entry>89</entry>
            <entry>360</entry>
            <entry>464</entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Join us in this effort!</emphasis> Here is what you need to
      participate:</para>
    <para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>A recent version of<ulink url="http://software.opensuse.org/"> openSUSE like
              11.3</ulink> or a <ulink url="http://software.opensuse.org/developer">milestone of
              11.4</ulink>. It’s of course okay to run openSUSE in a virtual machine.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>An IRC client to interact with the other participants</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Good mood :-)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para>But the most important thing that you should know is that everybody can help: just join us
      and we’ll guide you, even if you only have 30 minutes of free time! A small team will organize
      the event by providing lists of bugs, and will be available to guide new contributors if
      needed. So it will be easy to help, you just have to come to the #opensuse-bug channel on the
      freenode network at Saturday! </para>
    <para>The team had a lot of fun last time, so be sure to join them and help out!</para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/17/next-tuesday-social-media-collaboration-day/">Next
        Tuesday: Social Media Collaboration Day</ulink></title>
  <para>Last Monday the second Marketing Collaboration Day happened – with a focus on Marketing
      Materials. The moderators, Chuck Payne and Bryen Yunashko, would like to thank everyone who
      got involved for their hard work! It was a successful day with many items covered, added and
      expanded for openSUSE Marketing. </para>
    <para>Among other things, some how-to’s were updated like <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Launch_party_HOWTO">how to organize a Launch
        Party</ulink> (yes, openSUSE 11.4 is coming!) Moreover two short presentations on SUSE
      Studio and OBS were created which can be used in presentations from the Ambassadors. Already
      some Greek ambassadors are using them and they promised to contribute back translated
      versions. Besides the wiki and the presentations, volunteers took on the task of developing
      success case stories involving openSUSE, creating models for Letters of Sponsorship requests,
      and how to collaborate and work with educational institutions. Obviously a broad range of
      topics and opportunities to promote openSUSE. </para>
    <para>But the team isn’t done yet. Like in the previous Collaboration Day, which focused on our
      Ambassador Program, several items have been picked up to be finished later. Thanks for that! </para>
    <para>There is a renewed energy in our team as we collectively begin to have a broader
      bird’s-eye view of the state of our marketing resources and build up enthusiasm and motivation
      amongst our team members. </para>
    <para>Meanwhile, next week a new Collaboration Day will happen, this time on Tuesday December
      21. This, because one of it’s principle organizers, Manu Gupta, will return from his hard work
      at FOSS.in on Monday. The other organizer is Jos Poortvliet and the topic of this
      Collaboration day will be Social Media. </para>
    <para>The goal is to work on our press and media channels and our communication on the web.
      Writing short project descriptions, gathering features for our 11.4 announcement, creating a
      Prezi presentation about openSUSE, gathering screenshots and creating themes for
      Identica/twitter/blogger and other outlets are all on the agenda. </para>
    <para>And of course the plumbing: making sure all accounts are connected properly so an
      announcement or news.o.o article goes to all the proper channels automatically, making sure
      the account details are in the hands of several different people and much more. All in all it
      promises to be a great Collaboration day, so if you’re interested in Social Media and doing
      some work, join us and help out! </para>
    <para>The meeting will be held in the <ulink url="irc://irc.freenode.net/opensuse-marketing"
        >#openSUSE-Marketing</ulink> IRC channel on Freenode. Collaboration Days begin at 9:00 UTC
      and end at 24:00 UTC See you there!!! <!-- ($ ld: 17.12.10 sm $) --></para>
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
