<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/01/18/obs-books-project/">OBS Books Project</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>openSUSE Build Service (OBS) has a problem. It is horrible powerful, but no one knows. Or
      no one knows how to make use of it in short. </para>
    <para>Our documentation exists only in the wiki so far. While the wiki is still and will remain
      as a documentation resource, several of us OBS users and developers think we need something
      more structured and edited. A real book in short, which you can read to get an entire
      overview. </para>
    <para>Therefore we started to create the infrastructure to write such books, it is part of the
      openSUSE documentation project. This means the documentation is written in docbook and hosted
      in svn. </para>
    <para>The docbook code get currently generated into html once a day. There are currently two
      books set up, one as <ulink
        url="http://doc.opensuse.org/products/draft/OBS/obs-reference-guide/">reference
        guide</ulink> and one as <ulink
        url="http://doc.opensuse.org/products/draft/OBS/obs-best-practices/">best practice
        guide</ulink>. </para>
    <para>The great thing about docbook is that we can put also instance specific content inside,
      for example chapters or paragraphs which are only valid for build.opensuse.org or for
      build.meego.com for example. We can generate specific books out of this common source
      afterwards. </para>
    <para>So far the only article which really exists in these books is the how to to join book
      writing. So come, provide patches or create an account on <ulink
        url="http://developer.berlios.de/account/register.php">berlios</ulink> for direct submission
      permissions. It is not needed currently that you need to know OBS perfectly, it is enough to
      know something in some area. We will improve it afterwards. </para>
    <para>Don’t care about the current structure either a lot atm. We will rethink about it once we
      have more content. </para>
    <para>Please read also the current <ulink
        url="http://doc.opensuse.org/products/draft/OBS/obs-best-practices/pr01.html"
        >preface</ulink> which defines the goals of these books. </para>
    <para>Also the license of these books is the same as the license of the texts in the openSUSE
      wiki (GFDL). This means we can copy all text parts from the wiki to the book and vice versa. </para>
    <para>And of course, come to the <ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-buildservice/"
        >opensuse-buildservice mailing list</ulink> for discussing any of the articles, goals or
      suggestions. Nothing is in stone :)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 18.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
