<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/01/18/obs-books-project/">OBS Books Project</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>openSUSE Build Service (OBS) has a problem. It is horrible powerful, but no one knows. Or
      no one knows how to make use of it in short. </para>
    <para>Our documentation exists only in the wiki so far. While the wiki is still and will remain
      as a documentation resource, several of us OBS users and developers think we need something
      more structured and edited. A real book in short, which you can read to get an entire
      overview. </para>
    <para>Therefore we started to create the infrastructure to write such books, it is part of the
      openSUSE documentation project. This means the documentation is written in docbook and hosted
      in svn. </para>
    <para>The docbook code get currently generated into html once a day. There are currently two
      books set up, one as <ulink
        url="http://doc.opensuse.org/products/draft/OBS/obs-reference-guide/">reference
        guide</ulink> and one as <ulink
        url="http://doc.opensuse.org/products/draft/OBS/obs-best-practices/">best practice
        guide</ulink>. </para>
    <para>The great thing about docbook is that we can put also instance specific content inside,
      for example chapters or paragraphs which are only valid for build.opensuse.org or for
      build.meego.com for example. We can generate specific books out of this common source
      afterwards. </para>
    <para>So far the only article which really exists in these books is the how to to join book
      writing. So come, provide patches or create an account on <ulink
        url="http://developer.berlios.de/account/register.php">berlios</ulink> for direct submission
      permissions. It is not needed currently that you need to know OBS perfectly, it is enough to
      know something in some area. We will improve it afterwards. </para>
    <para>Don’t care about the current structure either a lot atm. We will rethink about it once we
      have more content. </para>
    <para>Please read also the current <ulink
        url="http://doc.opensuse.org/products/draft/OBS/obs-best-practices/pr01.html"
        >preface</ulink> which defines the goals of these books. </para>
    <para>Also the license of these books is the same as the license of the texts in the openSUSE
      wiki (GFDL). This means we can copy all text parts from the wiki to the book and vice versa. </para>
    <para>And of course, come to the <ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-buildservice/"
        >opensuse-buildservice mailing list</ulink> for discussing any of the articles, goals or
      suggestions. Nothing is in stone :)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 18.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/01/12/the-opensuse-board-election-2010/">The
        openSUSE Board election 2010</ulink></title>
    <para>The openSUSE Board Election process, started in December 2010, is heading full-speed for
      the planned announcement of the results on January 26, 2011. Today the voting begins and it’s
      time to take a closer look at the candidates and <ulink
        url="https://connect.opensuse.org/pg/polls/read/digitaltomm/10769/opensuse-board-election-2011"
        >make up our minds</ulink>!</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata width="25%"
          fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/vote.jpeg" align="center"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>In this election we will have 2 seats to be voted upon as the board periods of Pascal
      Bleser and Henne Vogelsang expire. With the existing company affiliations in the board (Pavol
      Prusnak- Novell, Bryen Yunashko – none, Rupert Horstkötter – openSLX) the restraint is that at
      most one of the to be elected members can be affiliated with Novell and at most one with
      openSLX. According to the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board_election#Company_affiliation">election
        rules</ulink>, no single organization or company can control more than 40 percent of the
      electable Board seats. That means, in this election, that if two candidates from either Novell
      or openSLX score a first and second place, only the one with most votes will have a seat. The
      other seat will to go to the third candidate in line (provided of course that person is not
      also affiliated with the same company). This time we have seven candidates, all contributors
      with different experiences and backgrounds. </para>
    <para>You can check their user pages, blogs and the platform page explaining their vision and
      plans for openSUSE:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/User:Terrorpup">Chuck “PUP” Payne</ulink>,
            ambassador from the US (<ulink url="http://opensuse.terrorpup.net/">blog</ulink>) <ulink
              url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board_election_2010_platform_terrorpup"
              >Platform</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/User:Vizzzion">sebas</ulink>, open-slx user
            experience expert (<ulink
              url="http://vizzzion.org/blog/2010/12/running-for-the-opensuse-board/">blog</ulink>)
              <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board_election_2010_platform_sebas"
              >Platform</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/User:Warlordfff">Kostas Koudaras</ulink>,
            ambassador from greece (<ulink url="http://warlordfff.tk/">blog</ulink>) <ulink
              url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board_election_2010_platform_warlordfff"
              >Platform</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/User:Mrdocs">Peter Linnell aka mrdocs</ulink>,
            OSS It consultant <ulink
              url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board_election_2010_platform_mrdocs"
              >Platform</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/User:Hennevogel">Henne Vogelsang</ulink>,
            Booster, currently Board Member, Novell (<ulink url="http://blog.hennevogel.de/"
              >blog</ulink>) <ulink
              url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board_election_2010_platform_hennevogel"
              >Platform</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/User:Psankar">Sankar P</ulink>, Programmer,
            Hacker, FOSS Enthusiast, Novell <ulink url="http://psankar.blogspot.com/">(blog</ulink>)
              <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board_election_2010_platform_psankar"
              >Platform</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/User:Ketheriel">Nelson Marques</ulink>,
            Contributor (<ulink url="http://nmarques.digitalwhores.net/">blog</ulink>) <ulink
              url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board_election_2010_platform_ketheriel"
              >Platform</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>The openSUSE board was set up to lead the overall project. The main tasks for members of
      the board are:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Act as a central point of contact</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Help resolve conflicts</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Communicate community interests to Novell</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Facilitate communication with all areas of the community</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Facilitate decision making processes where needed</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>The board should provide guidance to and support for existing governance structures, but
      shouldn’t direct or control development, since community mechanisms exist to accomplish the
      goals of the project. The board does however document decisions and policies, as well as
      mediate when issues arise. The board decides on usage of the trademarks of openSUSE, deals
      with conflicts, works with the Novell openSUSE community manager on funding decisions, works
      with the community on the organization of events and in general does a lot of ‘small things’
      often only visible when they are not handled. The board members are elected according to
        <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board_election">Board Election rules</ulink> by
      the members of the community who’ve been accepted as official ‘openSUSE Members’ and the chair
      person is appointed by Novell. Current chair is Alan Clark. </para>
    <para>Our current Board has had a busy time in the last year, setting up the foundations for a
      great 2011 for openSUSE. And the new Board members will need to put in some hard work to bring
      openSUSE to this new level. This includes the work on setting up the Foundation and the new
      responsibilities waiting for the board once that work has completed. Moreover challenges that
      might come up related to the Attachmate takeover of Novell have to be handled but also the
      usual day to day work in the community must continue. </para>
    <para>Ballots have just been opened and all openSUSE members whose membership is in good
      standing are eligible to vote. Please verify if your email address is valid and that you are
      able to read emails sent to your openSUSE address! The ballots are being done via the web on
        <ulink
        url="https://connect.opensuse.org/pg/polls/read/digitaltomm/10769/opensuse-board-election-2011"
        >connect.opensuse.org</ulink> and have been announced on <ulink
        url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-project/2011-01/msg00048.html">opensuse-project IRC
        channel and Mailing Lists</ulink>. Once a vote has been submitted it may not be changed
      afterwards. Finally, voting will end on <ulink url="http://bit.ly/gkQypN">January 26th,
        2011</ulink> when the ballots close. Shortly thereafter, you can expect the announcement of
      our two new board members! </para>
    <para>More detailed information can be found on the generic <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board_election">Board Election</ulink> and <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board_election_2010">board election 2010</ulink> wiki
      pages. Have a good vote!</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 13.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
