<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="community">
  <title>In the Community</title>
  <!--Put here things relevant to the openSUSE community maybe from * People of openSUSE or elections, votings 1 - 2 posts-->
  <sect2>
    <title>Postings from the Community</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://stick.gk2.sk/blog/2011/03/opensuse-11-4-release-party-prague/">Pavol
          Rusnak: openSUSE 11.4 Release Party – Prague</ulink></title>
      <para>Last Friday we held an <ulink url="http://brmlab.cz/event/opensuse_11.4_release_party"
          >openSUSE 11.4 Release Party</ulink> in Prague, more particularly in the first Czech
        hackerspace called <ulink url="http://brmlab.cz/">brmlab</ulink>. We decided to go with
        later date and not doing the party immediately after the release, so we could have promo
        materials available. This included openSUSE posters, DVD media, T-shirts but alsoý<ulink
          url="http://wiki.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Beer">openSUSE beer</ulink>! Thanks <ulink
          url="http://michal.hrusecky.net/">Michal</ulink> and <ulink
          url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/author/kfreitag/">Klaas</ulink> for delivering them to
        Prague. In the beginning we had 100 promo DVDs and we ended with slightly more than 10, so I
        think the event was a huge success! (...)</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
          url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/">CC-BY-NC-SA</ulink></para>
      <!--($ ld: 29.3.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/03/23/chemnitzer-linuxtage-2011/">Klaas Freitag: Chemnitzer Linuxtage 2011</ulink></title>
      <para>Last weekend I spent on <ulink url="http://chemnitzer.linux-tage.de/2011/">Chemnitzer
          Linuxtage 2011</ulink> which is a popular linux event in Chemnitz, Germany. It was the
        first time I have been there and was very positively surprised. It is a very well organised
        event, in a building providing the perfect environment and a large amount of volunteers
        helping to make the whole weekend enjoyable and relaxed. Thanks for that, it really was fun
        to meet so many people in this all-inclusive atmosphere <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_surprised.gif"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="http://robert.fedorapeople.org/events/2011/chemnitzer-linux-tage/024.jpg"
            width="25%"/>
        </imageobject>        
      </mediaobject>
      <para>openSUSE had a booth there (thanks Fedora for the picture) and we were lucky enough to
        have brand new 11.4 promo DVDs there which were handed to interested people. openSUSE 11.4
        in general is very well received at most visitors, they were quite happy with our latest
        release. That is also true for the feelings for openSUSE all over: I heard so much positive
        feedback about what we do and how we do it, for example the OBS with the collaboration
        features, the distribution or the activity all over. People recognize our efforts.</para>
      <para>I gave a talk about <ulink url="http://volle-kraft-voraus.de">Kraft</ulink>, as people
        hinted me that there might be the right audience for the topic of Linux in the small
        business. The interest was huge, the room was more than full and people seemed to like the
        way I was approaching the challenge. Unfortunately I had to fight with the notebook/beamer
        phalanx in the beginning (I apologize for that) so that I had to skip the live demo of Kraft
        in the end. But still I got a lot of interesting discussions afterwards and got some nice
        contributions already. Thanks for that. </para>
      <para>On saturday noon there was a <quote>Distribution competition</quote> where I was pulled
        in to show openSUSE. It went ok for all distros taking part and was fun for us presenting <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject></para>
      <para>Booster Michal was giving a workshop about creating packages in the OBS for multiple
        distributions and a very well <quote>received whats new in 11.4?</quote> talk was given by
        Sirko in the beginners track. </para>
      <para>It was a great event, even though I quite exhausted arrived home late on sunday night. I
        will be there next year again.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
          url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GFDL 1.2</ulink></para>
      <!--($ ld: 23.3.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://oyranos-cms.blogspot.com/2011/03/oyranos-on-clt-2011.html">Kai-Uwe Berhrmann: Oyranos on CLT 2011</ulink></title>
      <para>The weekend on Chemnitzer Linux Tage happened in a very nice atmosphere at the TU
        campus. </para>
      <para>The Oyranos booth had this year lots of place to show ideas on the hot topics like
        desktop and print colour management. Unfortunately my long planed co exhibitor could not
        make it to Chemnitz to show openSUSE-medical. We planed to display medical images on a
        properly setup 30-bit system as is required by the DICOM specification. Sirko Kemter
        designed one artistic 2 meter banner and helped with the basic design of the other posters,
        which we used for the new space. The Oyranos posters included some schematic graphics and
        the usual "Why do we need colour management" style explanations. For the later one I
        sketched a comparison of three non colour managed monitors showing the same fashion person.
        The SVG graphics from the open clip art library was colour converted to three real world
        monitor profiles. It resembles a typical shop over web situation, where colour counts for
        selection of the right looking goods.</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-G9og8HNBsB8/TYo211lX37I/AAAAAAAAABk/gaAkHsUEJlI/s400/OyranosCMS-2_UebersichtPlakat_comparision.png"
            width="25%"/>
        </imageobject>        
      </mediaobject>
      <para>Several visitors allowed me to start the actual SuseStudio created Oyranos LiveCD on
        their laptops with different success. We used the exhibited measurement devices and a camera
        target to create custom ICC profiles for use in digikam, Scribus, Inkscape and friends. The
        LiveCD is still based on openSUSE-11.3 and worked in many but not all cases. I found it
        impressive how good looked the featured KDE desktop, when the CompICC plug-in launched
        immediately. Working OpenGL, which is needed for the desktop colour server shader, was still
        not always available.</para>
      <para>The newest openSUSE-11.4 version was demonstrated on the neighboring openSUSE booth.
        openSUSE-11.4 was released only some days ago. The <ulink
          url="http://software.opensuse.org/">OBS </ulink>color_management repository was updated
        with the help of Stanislav Brabec just some days before to have nearly all packages build
        for 11.4. Thus Oyranos workes flawless on 11.4 too.</para>
      <para>All in all a great weekend with lots of good talks and meeting of old and new
        friends.</para>
      <!--($ ld: 26.3.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blog.cornelius-schumacher.de/2011/03/show-us-your-work-on-free-desktop.html">Cornelius Schumacher: Show us your work on the free desktop</ulink></title>
      <para>The deadline for the <ulink url="https://desktopsummit.org/cfp">Call for
          Participation</ulink> of the <ulink url="http://www.desktopsummit.org/">Berlin Desktop
          Summit</ulink> is approaching. The deadline for submitting proposals for presentations and
        lightning talks is tomorrow. So you still have the chance to submit a presentation and talk
        about your work on the free desktop at the wonderful event in Berlin that the desktop summit
        promises to be. It takes place from 6th to 12th August this year and combines the annual
        conferences of the <ulink url="http://www.kde.org/">KDE</ulink> and <ulink
          url="http://www.gnome.org/">GNOME</ulink> communities.</para>
      <para>Some of you might think that your contributions to the free desktop to the event are not
        relevant enough to warrant submitting a talk. That often is not true. While we will have
        well-known speakers who have done ground-breaking things on the free desktop, we all have
        started small, and sometimes especially the small projects, which are still young, are the
        most interesting ones to hear about. So please don't hesitate to try it, submit a
        presentation, talk about the projects you are passionate about, share the love for the free
        desktop with the community. Berlin is the right place for this.</para>
      <!--($ ld: 26.3.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <!--
    <sect2>
    <title>People of openSUSE</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>This Week: xyz</title>
      <para>Good Guy. Glows in the night.</para>
    </blockquote>
    </sect2> -->
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Welcome new openSUSE Members</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/fcrozat">Frederic Crozat (fcrozat)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Very active in the openSUSE GNOME Team and Bugzilla.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/helen-au">Helen South
        (helen-au)</ulink></title>
      <para>Helen works inside Marketing and the Editor Team of news.opensuse.org.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/dominian">Matt Hayes
        (dominian)</ulink></title>
      <para>Active in Bugzilla, Wiki and Mailinglists.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/tsotsos">Angelos Tzotsos
        (tsotsos)</ulink></title>
      <para>Active inside the Greek Community and Marketing.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/bekun">Kai-Uwe Behrmann
        (bekun)</ulink></title>
      <para>Kai-Uwe serves as Speaker, Boothman and Developer for the openSUSE Project.</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Events &amp; Meetings</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Past</title>
<listitem>
<para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/02/09/opensuse-project-meetings/">March 23, 2011 : Project Meeting</ulink></para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/01/20/testing-core-team-meeting/">March 28, 2011 : Testing Core Team Meeting</ulink></para>
</listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Upcoming</title>
<listitem>
<para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/12/open-bugs-day-from-the-testing-team/">April 02, 2011 : Open Bugs Day from the testing team</ulink></para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/02/09/opensuse-project-meetings/">April 06, 2011 : Project Meeting</ulink></para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/02/09/opensuse-project-meetings/">April 20, 2011 : Project Meeting</ulink></para>
</listitem>      
    </itemizedlist>
    <!-- ($ ld: 01.04.11 th $) -->
    <para>You can find more informations on other events at: <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/category/events/">openSUSE News/Events</ulink>. - <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Ambassadors_events">Local Events</ulink></para>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>openSUSE for your Ears</title>
    <para>The openSUSE Weekly News are available as livestream or podcast in German. You can hear it
      or download it on <ulink url="http://blog.radiotux.de/podcast">Radiotux</ulink>. </para>
  </sect2>
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>From Ambassadors</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://www.bryen.com/opensuse-11-4-arrives-in-san-diego/">openSUSE 11.4 Arrives in San Diego</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The latest release of openSUSE 11.4 on Thursday proved to be a very good release day for
        us around the world. And in celebrating the release day, several of us came to visit San
        Diego’s Kernel Panic Linux User Group (<ulink url="http://www.kernel-panic.org/"
          >KPLUG</ulink>). It was a good crowd at the event with the members of KPLUG and friends
        some of us invited to join the festivities and learn about openSUSE.</para>
      <para>Representing openSUSE were local openSUSE guru Tony Su, Brazilian Ambassadors Carlos
        Ribeiro and Izabel Valverde (In town for the recent SCALE and openSUSE Marketing Hackfest in
        Los Angeles) and myself.</para>
      <figure>
        <title>Opening presentation statements</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://www.bryen.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/DSC00641-KPLUG-Tony-Bryen-300x199.png"
            />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>As most people present weren’t users of openSUSE, we decided to focus our message not
        just on what is so cool and awesome about openSUSE, but rather on how openSUSE complements
        the Project itself. I started out by giving a brief overview of what openSUSE represents as
        a Project and the various things we do in the Project. Tony then continued by giving a live
        demonstration of KDE and then moved on to an in-depth look at YaST. Occasionally, Carlos
        also offered useful information about the various features of openSUSE and even helped out
        with a couple of users after the presentation.</para>
      <figure>
        <title>Tony extolls the virtues of YaST</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://www.bryen.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/DSC00648-Tony-KPLUG-300x199.png"
            />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>A lot of good questions were generated by the audience, and we saw questions focusing on
        our OBS ervice, SUSE Studio and virtualization. Additionally, people asked questions about
        the Project itself and how it is sponsored. I think people were generally impressed to learn
        and understand that our openSUSE Project is truly a community-driven project and that our
        relationship with our sponsors are collaborative rather than managed.</para>
      <para>Afterwards, in the grand tradition of openSUSE Launch Parties, we gave out cake and DVDs
        as well as a bunch of stickers. As I kept near the DVDs to answer questions, I was genuinely
        pleased to see people not only took DVDs for themselves, but asked if they could also take
        extra copies to give to their friends.</para>
      <figure>
        <title>Every green morsel was delicious!</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://www.bryen.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/DSC00628-KPLUG-Cake-300x199.png"
            />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>I have to say that the KPLUG folks were truly a nice group of people, and their
        backgrounds truly very interesting, ranging from systems administrators to piano teacher to
        retiree who can’t quite give up his love for Linux. It was also a pleasure to meet with
        Neil, the president of KPLUG.</para>
      <para>Cake was definitely delish. I only wish I had extra days in San Diego before the KPLUG
        event so I could have ordered a proper openSUSE photo cake with logo and all. But, once it
        gets in your stomach, I guess it really doesn’t matter. :-)</para>
      <para>Hope to have a chance to visit the guys at KPLUG again, the next time I visit San Diego.
        If you live in the San Diego area, check them out. Next month, they’re doing a presentation
        of MythTV. Should be very interesting!</para>
      <para>Next stop, representnin’ GNOME Foundation Accessibility at the CSUN Assistive Technology
        conference in San Diego this week. I’ll update you all on what happens there.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://opensuseambassadors.blogspot.com/2011/03/opensuse-114-release-party-next-day.html">Greek openSUSE Ambassadors: openSUSE 11.4 Release Party-The Next day</ulink></title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/_EX6cn8rqip4/TX1ywq6uNSI/AAAAAAAAAyU/AV-VhjC4u1k/s320/SAM_0746.JPG"
          />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>Last night the first Release Party for 11.4 of the Greek openSUSE Community took place.
        We had every reason to celebrate since we have this great distribution that attracted
        peoples attention from the first day of it's release.</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/_EX6cn8rqip4/TX1z1A1LVlI/AAAAAAAAAy8/g5RDT6EdV98/s320/SAM_0754.JPG"
          />
        </imageobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/_EX6cn8rqip4/TX10_m1oTnI/AAAAAAAAAzk/0HiGhXLldHY/s320/SAM_0760.JPG"
          />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>The Party was once again awesome. Many beautiful people gathered to Rock 'n' Roll and
        celebrate the arrival of openSUSE 11.4. Of course The ambassadors and the other members of
        the community talked to people about the greatness of the openSUSE Project.</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/_EX6cn8rqip4/TX11Fq8uePI/AAAAAAAAAzs/s0Rwf8ocSBw/s320/SAM_0761.JPG"
          />
        </imageobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/_EX6cn8rqip4/TX10Mh_SFqI/AAAAAAAAAzM/SAPtsONGfYs/s320/SAM_0756.JPG"
          />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>We had all kind of freebies for the people to take. We had some serious party equipment
        like balloons and whistles. Of course we also had 11.3 DVD with instructions stickers for
        upgrade on. Also we burned a few 11.4 and we had stickers, openSUSE cheat-cubes, openSUSE
        Calendars and various other openSUSE stuff.</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/_EX6cn8rqip4/TX10ljqk9TI/AAAAAAAAAzc/FmoXgjojklI/s320/SAM_0758.JPG"
          />
        </imageobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/_EX6cn8rqip4/TX19HDLZS0I/AAAAAAAAA3w/yn6dK1vHwaE/s320/SAM_0805.JPG"
          />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>All attendants were given a number and in the end of the night we had a draw and gave
        away 3 openSUSE t-shirts. Also at the end of the night we all sign an openSUSE poster as
        something for the community to remember from that wild night.</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/_EX6cn8rqip4/TX1-uhteigI/AAAAAAAAA4w/DXSpksZLWus/s320/SAM_0815.JPG"
          />
        </imageobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/_EX6cn8rqip4/TX1wt2uhucI/AAAAAAAAAxI/GUjMOAI3DsM/s320/SAM_0733.JPG"
          />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>We proved once again that openSUSE people most of all have fun because openSUSE is more
        than a more than a product.</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/_EX6cn8rqip4/TX12q0B7xNI/AAAAAAAAA0g/TPsSuzwxOAg/s320/SAM_0769.JPG"
          />
        </imageobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/_EX6cn8rqip4/TX13b7eTrvI/AAAAAAAAA04/zXjC0tsHX_w/s320/SAM_0774.JPG"
          />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>Unfortunately it is impossible to fit all photos from the party here so if you like to
        see some more go to: <ulink
          url="https://picasaweb.google.com/warlordfff/OpenSUSE114ReleaseParty#"
          >https://picasaweb.google.com/warlordfff/OpenSUSE114ReleaseParty#</ulink></para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
          url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">CC-BY-SA</ulink></para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Communication</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/">The Mailinglists</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org">The openSUSE Forums</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Contributors</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://users.opensuse.org">The User Directory</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
