<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="updates">
  <title>New/Updated Applications @ openSUSE</title>
  <!--* Gnome
* KDE
* XYZ http://oyranos-cms.blogspot.com/2011/05/openicc-and-basiccolor-profile-packages.html

Version should be available at packman or software.opensuse.org/search max. 4 posts. -->
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://oyranos-cms.blogspot.com/2011/05/openicc-and-basiccolor-profile-packages.html"
        >Kai-Uwe Behrmann: OpenICC and basICColor profile packages</ulink></title>
    <para>Originally I wanted to have most packages ready for Montreal. But it was good to not
      announce them. Now they are slowly rolling out. </para>
    <para>Today came the <ulink
        url="http://lists.freedesktop.org/archives/openicc/2011q2/004133.html"
        >basICColor_Offset_2009 package 1.1.1</ulink> shortly after <ulink
        url="http://lists.freedesktop.org/archives/openicc/2011q2/004130.html">OpenICC Data package
        1.2.0</ulink>. Both form now a fairly distributable and stable usable set of ICC profiles
      with completely free licenses. </para>
    <para>ICC Examin had some issues in the CinePaint plugin. So I decided to first fix that and as
      well finish the started ICC v4 support in ICC Examin. Most of that should work already in
        <ulink url="http://www.oyranos.org/scm">git</ulink>. </para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 30.5.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/2011/05/28/smb-traffic-analyzer-1-2-5-released/">Holger
        Hetterich: SMB Traffic Analyzer 1.2.5 released</ulink></title>
    <para><emphasis role="italic">Just in case you’re wondering what this article is about, check
        out the <ulink url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/smb-traffic-analyzer/">SMB Traffic
          Analyzer project</ulink> to get more information.</emphasis></para>
    <para>The team is proud to release <emphasis role="bold">SMB Traffic Analyzer version
        1.2.5</emphasis>. Among numerous changes and enhancements, this release brings <ulink
        url="http://morelias.org/smbta/smbta-guide.html#_websmbta">a huge documentation update on
        webSMBTA</ulink>, thanks to Benjamin of the SMBTA team. In <emphasis role="bold"
        >smbtaquery</emphasis>, we had a bug that caused the “from..to” and “since” time modifiers
      on functions not to work (bso#8169). Furthermore, this release fixes an error condition on
      smbtad which we encountered during the SambaXP conference, when a directory was created that
      already existed. Packages for Gentoo Linux and openSUSE should be available very soon, and
      with release 1.2.5, we’ve sub-packaged webSMBTA. The “one click install” optioný for openSUSE
      will install all required repositories such as rails3 to run webSMBTA from the apache
      webserver. We have added installation instructions to the source tarball.</para>
    <para>SMB Traffic Analyzer 1.2.5<emphasis role="bold"> makes changes to the database being used
        by SMBTA</emphasis>. We provide an <emphasis role="bold">upgrade path</emphasis> from
      whichever version of SMBTA you are coming from. Just run “smbtaquery -C” and follow the
      instructions.</para>
    <para>Checkout the <ulink url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/smb-traffic-analyzer/">SMB Traffic
        Analyzer homepage</ulink> to get more information and download options. </para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 30.5.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://blog.karlitschek.de/2010/11/owncloud-11-released.html">Frank
        Karlitschek: ownCloud 1.1 released</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>10 minutes ago I released ownCloud 1.1Iým really happy with this release. </para>
    <para>Not only because we have a lot of new features and bugfixes but also because the ownCloud
      development team is growing and more and more people are contributing to ownCloud.I gave
      several presentation about ownCloud in the last few month and I'm trilled by the positive
      reactions I get. People really seams to like to idea behind ownCloud.</para>
    <para>You can download ownCloud 1.1 now and run you own cloud storage on your own
      hardware.</para>
    <para>So what is ownCloud?</para>
    <para>ownCloud is a central place where you can store your files and documents. You don't have
      to upload your personal data to central closed services like Google Docs, Dropbox or Ubuntu
      One. All the data is under your own control.You can access your files via WebDAV from Linux,
      Mac and Windows Desktops without a special client because WebDAV support is build into all
      modern operation systems and distributions. On Linux you can use the KDE KIO-Slaves or mount
      it via FUSE into your home directory.If you canýt use WebDAV for example on your smart phone
      you can use the webinterface to access your files.</para>
    <para>The data transfer is encrypted if your web-server supports SSL and ownCloud has no
      problems with firewalls and proxy servers.</para>
    <para>ownCloud support the Open Collaboration Services API so your ownCloud can push
      notification to your KDE Desktop if something interesting happens, like your storage is full
      or somebody is accessing a shared file of you.</para>
    <para>So what is new in ownCloud 1.1?<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>New Plugin system</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>User management</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>ownCloud can now be installed in a DB shared with other applications since ownCloud
            tables has a prefix (default is "oc_" but can choose it)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Experimental PostgreSQL support</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Text viewer with syntax highlighting</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Support for OCS private attribute storage and activity</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixes, fixes, fixes...</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Code cleanup</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>Future plans are:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Versioning of all files using git as a backend.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Easy sharing of your files with others.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Syncing client so you can access your files offline. (work has already
            started)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>We have a nice new plugin system in 1.1 and developers can write add ons for your ownCloud
      easily.</para>
    <para>Examples are:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>A photo gallery plugins. So you can share your photos with others without uploading
            it to services like Flickr or Picasa.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Music server. You can listen to your music from every device without copying it
            around.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Podcast catcher. A central place to collect your audio and video podcasts and access
            it via a HTML5 interface or a native media player.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>You find the download file and more information on the website ownCloud.org.If you want to
      help with the development or integration with other projects send a message to the ownCloud
      mailing-list.</para>
    <para>You can find more information here:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://owncloud.org/">http://owncloud.org</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://owncloud.org/index.php/OwnCloud_1.1"
              >http://owncloud.org/index.php/OwnCloud_1.1</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://www.gitorious.org/owncloud"
              >http://www.gitorious.org/owncloud</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="https://mail.kde.org/mailman/listinfo/owncloud"
              >https://mail.kde.org/mailman/listinfo/owncloud</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License:</emphasis>
      <ulink url="https://mail.kde.org/mailman/listinfo/owncloud">CC-BY-SA</ulink></para>
    <!--($ ld: 2.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
