<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
  <!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://dot.kde.org/2011/01/05/46-rc2-available-last-chance-test">KDE
          News/Sebastian Kügler: 4.6 RC2 Available, Last Chance to Test</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><quote>KDE&apos;s release team has rolled another set of 4.6 tarballs for us all to test
          and report problems: 4.6 RC2 This is the last test release leading up to 4.6.0, which is
          planned for 26th January.</quote></para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 6.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://qt-apps.org/news/?id=340">QT Apps: Win 10.000,- EUR at the <quote>Qtest Mobile App Port</quote></ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Welcome to the Qtest Mobile App Port! As developers of applications using Qt, you
        already know how great it is to work with - but how about on mobile platforms, such as
        Symbian and MeeGo? How would you like to take that step you have been wanting to take, but
        not been able to justify: Take your application from the desktop and bring it into the
        hand-held world via the Ovi store. Let this contest be the justification, with the
        possibility of a new phone or even 10,000 euros waiting at the end. </para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Dates</emphasis>: The contest starts on 20th of December, 2010,
        and runs till 28th of February. The 31st of December is important for you if you wish to
        take part in the Early Bird competition. If you do no win, you will still take part in the
        main competition, and will be allowed to continue your work and submit new versions to the
        Ovi Store. The 28th of February is the deadline for taking part in the main
        competition.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Developer Sprint</emphasis>: There will be a sponsored developer
        sprint organized together with the KDE e.V. during the competition. The travel and stay can
        be paid for if you do not have the budget yourself. Further details will be made public at a
        later time, and all participants will be notified of this information via email. </para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Judging and prizes</emphasis>: The Qtest Mobile App Port is
        evaluated by a panel of judges which will be announced in the next few days. The jury will
        pic 5 winners at 31th of December as the early bird winners. Every winner gets a free N900
        phone. The main competition first prize is EUR 10,000, which will be awarded to the
        application which the judges find to be the best ported application. The second to sixth
        price will be another 5 N900 phones.</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata width="25%" fileref="http://qt-apps.org/CONTENT/news-pics/340-pic4.jpg"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>And, finally: Everybody who takes part in the competition will be awarded a gift bag,
        with a T-shirt and other merchandise.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Eligibility</emphasis>: To be able to take part in the contest,
        the ported application must be submitted for Ovi Store signing by one of the two deadlines:
        - Early bird entries must be submitted by December 31st - Standard entries must be submitted
        by February 28th.</para>
      <para>You also have to submit your application to the &quot;Mobile Contest&quot; category on
        Qt-Apps.org or MeeGo-Central.org </para>
      <para>You can submit your application to the Ovi Store as many times as you wish during the
        competition. This allows you to get feedback from the public on your software. It´s possible
        to submit new or existing KDE/Qt applications.</para>
      <para>So have fun and good luck everybody!</para>    
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://linuxcanuck.wordpress.com/2011/01/09/what-you-can-expect-from-a-linux-distribution/"
          >linuxcanuck: What You Can Expect From a Linux Distribution</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>There are some things that you can expect with a new installation of a Linux
        distribution such as Ubuntu or Fedora that you would not get with an OS such as Windows 7 or
        OS /X. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 10.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/networking/browser-wars-internet-explorer-loses-and-firefox-wins-in-europe/499"
          >OSTatic/Lisa Hoover: Black Duck Software Buys Olliance Consulting Group</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>In its continued march across the open source industry landscape, <ulink
          url="http://www.blackducksoftware.com">Black Duck Software</ulink>, a Boston-based company
        which services managed and secure implementations of open source software, announced today
        the purchase of <ulink url="http://www.olliancegroup.com/">Olliance Group</ulink>, an open
        source enterprise consulting firm. After <ulink
          url="http://ostatic.com/blog/black-duck-buys-koders">acquiring open source search engine
          Koders</ulink> in 2008, Black Duck got quiet for a while then slurped up three more
        companies in the last three months -- <ulink url="http://www.ohloh.net/">Oholoh</ulink>,
          <ulink
          url="http://ostatic.com/blog/black-duck-extends-its-string-of-open-source-acquisitions"
          >SpikeSource</ulink>, and now Olliance. We caught up wtih Peter Vescuso, Executive Vice
        President of Black Duck Software to find out more about this acquisition and what the future
        holds for the company.</para>
      <para>According to Vescuso, the decision to purchase Olliance was a natural evolution in
        response to the changing needs of Black Ducks' customer base. <quote>Over the last few years
          as our business has grown we’ve encountered more and more customers that not only needed a
          software platform to manage their use of open source components, but wanted help with
          business strategy around their use of open source, policy development, etc. Last year we
          formalized a partnership with Olliance to address this need which has been successful
          beyond our expectations. So much so that we realized for Black Duck to achieve its vision
          of being the company that organizations trust for all their FOSS-enablement needs, we
          needed to acquire Olliance, the leading consultancy in this area</quote>, says
        Vescuso.</para>
      <para>Although Black Duck already offers some consulting services to clients, they are mainly
        focused on pre- and post-deployment support. Olliance's consulting services, on the other
        hand, help businesses map out how open source fits into a their overall business strategy
          <quote>Black Duck’s services have been mostly focused on process integration and
          implementation, roll out, with some services for policy development</quote>, says Vescuso.
          <quote>Olliance’s strength and deep knowledge developed over hundreds of customer
          engagements is in business strategy, policy and process, which is highly complementary to
          what we were offering, hence the motivation to acquire Olliance</quote>.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 10.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6tw2JOuct7k">Youtube-- "Be Free with KDE"
          advertisement</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Youtube: <quote>Created as part of the Google Code In program</quote></para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 10.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://infoworld.com/t/linux/linux-iq-test-round-2-657">InfoWorld's Linux IQ
          test: Round 2</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>So you live and breathe Linux, eh? You've aced <ulink
          url="http://www.infoworld.com/t/linux/linux-admin-iq-test-066">Linux IQ Test: Round
          1</ulink> and our <ulink
          url="http://www.infoworld.com/d/open-source/open-source-iq-test-766">Open Source IQ
          Test</ulink> to boot. The free OS runs on your phone, your netbook, your desktop, and even
        your alarm clock. You named your dog Linus and you have Tux wallpaper. You take such great
        pride in your uptimes that you brag about them at the lunch table. Andrew Morton signed your
        underwear. You're in the game. But how much do you really know about the most pervasive open
        source project on the planet? Take Round 2 of our Linux IQ test and find out. </para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 11.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.eweekeurope.co.uk/interview/novell-community-wants-opensuse-foundation-17980"
          > EweekEurope/Tom Jowitt: Novell: Community Wants OpenSUSE Foundation </ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Open source commentators were suspicious when news emerged that <ulink
          url="http://www.eweekeurope.co.uk/news/concerns-raised-over-opensuse-spin-off-17723"
          >openSUSE will move to an independent foundation</ulink>, during the acquisition of
        Novell, which currently supports openSUSE development. </para>
      <para>But the move is in line with the wishes of the openSUSE community, will be properly
        funded, and does not represent any fading of Novell’s interest in the Linux version – or any
        lack of involvement by <ulink
          url="http://www.eweekeurope.co.uk/news/microsoft-gets-novell-ip-in-2-65-billion-carve-up-13995"
          >Novell’s prospective owner, Attachmate</ulink>. </para>
      <para>That is the view of Jos Poortvliet, Jos Poortvliet, openSUSE Community Manager at
        Novell, who contacted us to give some background to the move, which he says dates back well
        before the Attachmate deal was announced. (...) <emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>:
          <link linkend="credits">2</link></para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 13.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.groklaw.net/article.php?story=http://itmanagement.earthweb.com/osrc/article.php/3919321/Switching-to-Linux-For-the-Right-Reasons.htm"
          >internet.com/Matt Hartley: Switching to Linux (For the Right Reasons)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Why are you using Linux on your desktop? </para>
      <para>Before answering this question, consider the advantages and disadvantages and then come
        back full circle to your own motivation for using Linux. Nearly every week, I find my news
        feeds filled with the usual generic articles describing rather vanilla reasons for using
        Linux on the desktop. </para>
      <para>Why do I have a problem with this? Perhaps because the reasons often being shared are
        just echoes of other opinions that clearly aren&apos;t that of the author. Instead, we are
        reading the thoughts and ideas of many articles since past. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 5.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.consortiuminfo.org/standardsblog/article.php?story=20110105174405322"
          >Consortiuminfo/Andy Updegrove: Attachmate and the SUSE Linux Project: What&apos;s
          Next?</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Over the last few months, I&apos;ve frequently pointed out the vulnerability of
        important open source projects that are supported and controlled by corporate sponsors,
        rather than hosted by independent foundations funded by corporate sponsors. One of the
        examples I&apos;ve given is SUSE Linux, which has been hosted and primarily supported by
        Novell since that company acquired SuSE Linux AG in 2003. Novell, as you know, is expected
        to be acquired by a company called Attachmate a few weeks from now, assuming approval of the
        transaction by the Novell stockholders and by German competition regulators. </para>
      <para>Recently, the future of the SUSE Linux Project (as compared to the Novell commercial
        Linux distribution based on the work of that project) has become rather murky, as reported
        by Pamela Jones, <ulink url="http://www.groklaw.net/article.php?story=20101227144336645">at
          Groklaw</ulink>. Apparently, Novell is facilitating some sort of spin out of the Project,
        which is good but peculiar news. </para>
      <para>Why peculiar? Because when a company is subject to an agreement of sale, one of the
        requirements the buyer imposes during the sale-pending period is that the seller cannot
        engage in any transactions outside of the ordinary course of business without the consent of
        the acquiror. This makes sense, because once the buyer has committed to a price, it
        doesn&apos;t want the value of any of the assets it is purchasing to fall. That means that
        one would expect that Novell would at minimum be abstaining from taking any action in
        connection with any effort to move the project out and into an independent entity.
        (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://tirania.org/blog/archive/2010/Dec-31.html">Miguel de Icaza: Open Source
          Contribution Etiquette</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Some developers, when faced with fixing, or adding a feature to an open source project
        are under the mistaken impression that the first step before any fixing takes place, or
        before adding a new feature takes place is to make the code &quot;easier for them&quot; to
        work on.</para>
      <para>&quot;Easier for them&quot; usually is a combination of renaming methods, fields,
        properties, locals; Refactoring of methods, classes; Gratuitous split of code in different
        files, or merging of code into a single file; Reorganization by alphabetical order, or
        functional order, or grouping functions closer to each other, or having helper methods
        first, or helper methods last. Changing indentation, aligning variables, or parameters or
        dozen other smaller changes. </para>
      <para>This is <emphasis role="bold">not how you contribute to an open source
          project</emphasis>. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 8.1.11 sat $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.groklaw.net/article.php?story=20101227144336645">Groklaw/Pamela
          Jones: How to Tell When an Open Source Foundation Isn&apos;t About You - Updated
          2Xs</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Stephen Walli, now technical director of the Outercurve Foundation, has written a guest
        post for OStatic, <ulink
          url="http://ostatic.com/blog/guest-post-the-rise-of-open-source-software-foundations">The
          Rise of Open Source Software Foundations</ulink>. I guess he thinks Outercurve is one. He
        explains why Microsoft set up the foundation in the first place, which I have wondered about
        for quite a while. His article also reminded me that I promised to explain what bothered me
        so much about the recent <ulink
          url="http://community.opensuse.org/meetings/opensuse-project/2010/opensuse-project.2010-12-15-19.01.log.html"
          >OpenSUSE Project meeting</ulink> on December 15th. We&apos;re still working on the Comes
        v. Microsoft exhibits, but I need to take a break. So here goes. I will use the OpenSUSE
        Foundation discussion to show you why it&apos;s so important, if you are setting up a
        foundation, to set it up right in the beginning, and why you absolutely must have a lawyer
        to protect your interests. It&apos;s not good if only the corporate entity&apos;s guys know
        what bylaws are and how to set up corporate structures, and the community is relying on them
        to explain it. Your interests are not identical. Not by a long shot. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 8.1.11 sat $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://news.softpedia.com/news/Best-Windows-Games-and-Apps-That-Run-Under-Linux-176410.shtml"
          >Softpedia: Best Windows Games and Apps That Run Under Linux</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">The following article was created to inform our readers about
          popular native Windows games and applications which install and run under Linux-based
          operating systems, with the help of the Wine software. </emphasis></para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata width="15%"
            fileref="http://i1-news.softpedia-static.com/images/newsrsz/Best-Windows-Games-and-Apps-That-Run-Under-Linux-2.jpg"
          />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>We have recently discovered that many people have no idea that games such as the popular
        World of Warcraft, Call of Duty or Left 4 Dead work flawlessly under Linux. Therefore,
        we&apos;ve decided to make a list with all of them. </para>
      <para>While most of the following games work flawlessly, other will require some special
        configuration from the user. Also, a couple of the listed applications and games will have
        minor issues. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 6.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.makeuseof.com/tag/linux-web-server-software-apache-alternatives/"
          >MakeUseOf/Dave Drager: The Best Linux Web Server Software (&amp; Apache
          Alternatives)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Since the protocol that runs the world wide web – the <ulink
          url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hypertext_Transfer_Protocol">HTTP protocol</ulink> – is
        open and viewable to the entire world, anyone with the programming knowledge is able to
        write their own web server. In fact Wikipedia <ulink
          url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comparison_of_web_servers">lists over 60 web
          servers</ulink> and those are only the ones released to the public. So which is the best
        one that you should run on your Linux server? </para>
      <para>To be able to determine the ‘best’ one we need to look at several factors. Ultimately it
        depends on what your end goal is since some <ulink
          url="http://makeuseof.com/tags/web-server">web servers</ulink> are geared towards a kind
        of client, others for speed and others for security. The main factors we are going to look
        at are <emphasis role="bold">reliability, speed, security</emphasis> and <emphasis
          role="bold">ease of use</emphasis>. </para>
      <para>A lot of web servers will make claims to being the “king” of one or more of these
        factors. However I believe the proof is in the pudding and if you look at actual web server
        usage across the internet you get a better idea of the wisdom of the crowds. Netcraft has
        been keeping track of web server types, hostnames and other data since 1995 and is a great
        way to see what the current trends are in web server usage.</para>
      <para>Here is their web server usage survey up until December 2010:</para>
      <figure id="fig.survey">
        <title>Server Survey</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata width="50%"
              fileref="http://main.makeuseoflimited.netdna-cdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/netcraft-survey.png"
            />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>Of the top <xref linkend="fig.survey"/>web servers in current use, Microsoft’s web
        server IIS is the only pure-Windows one. Apache by and large is the most widely used web
        server software based on the number of users. It is also good to note that it is
        cross-platform and will run on both Windows and Linux systems. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 6.1.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/security/news/item/Phrack-hole-closed-in-ProFTPD-1156782.html">h-online: Phrack hole closed in ProFTPD </ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The development team behind <ulink url="http://www.proftpd.org/">ProFTPD</ulink> has
        released version <ulink url="http://www.proftpd.org/docs/RELEASE_NOTES-1.3.3d">1.3.3d</ulink>, which closes a critical security hole in the SQL module of all previous
        versions. The flaw was <ulink url="http://www.phrack.org/issues.html">reported</ulink>
        roughly a month ago in Phrack, the hacker magazine. A buffer overflow in the function
        sql_prepare_where() allows attackers to remotely execute arbitrary code on the server. The
        developers themselves suffered when this vulnerability was exploited by still unknown
        parties, who entered the project server and <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/news/item/Back-door-in-ProFTPD-FTP-server-1146592.html">installed</ulink> a back door in the source code.</para>
      <para>The new version also fixes a number of additional <ulink url="http://www.proftpd.org/docs/NEWS-1.3.3d">bugs</ulink>; as a result, the GPL-licensed
        server is reportedly now more stable. At the same time, the developers have also published
        the first release candidate for version <ulink url="http://www.proftpd.org/docs/RELEASE_NOTES-1.3.4rc1">1.3.4</ulink>. (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
  <sect2>
    <title>LOL</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://e-tote-kala.blogspot.com/2011/01/first-joke-of-year-if-operating-systems.html"
          >Kostas Koudaras: First Joke of the year: If Operating Systems Ran The Airlines</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The first joke of the year :-) </para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
