<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://blog.jospoortvliet.com/2011/05/code-of-conduct-or-anti-harassment.html">Jos
        Poortvliet: Code of Conduct or anti-harassment policy</ulink></title>
    <para> I went to LCA 2011 in Januari. There, <ulink url="http://lwn.net/Articles/425661/">a
        'mild controvercy' (or rather 'nuclear war') developed</ulink> around a <ulink
        url="http://linuxconfau.blip.tv/file/4851926">keynote</ulink> by <ulink
        url="http://www.cultofmarkpesce.com/">Mark Pesce</ulink> and <ulink
        url="http://www.techworld.com.au/article/374877/pesce_sorry_raunchy_pics_linux_conf_au/">how
        it was handled</ulink> by the conference team. Now personally, I had little issue with
      Mark's keynote. Ok, there was some harsh language and some explicit imagery, but nothing that
      offended <emphasis role="italic">me</emphasis>. So when an apology was made during the closing
      ceremony, I was suprised and later on spoke out with some others against the
      'censorship'.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Changing mind</emphasis></para>
    <para>But after a while I realized that the point of all this isn't about censorship or Freedom
      of Speech (vs freedom of 'not being insulted'). Those issues surely play in the wider, public
      area. I don't want to have laws which allow our government to prosecute anyone who talks about
      something they don't like! But that is not relevant here. LCA is NOT a public place. It is a
      conference organized by a team which has <emphasis role="bold">EVERY</emphasis> right to tell
      us under what condictions we can join! It is <emphasis role="bold">their
      conference</emphasis>, after all. And yes, one of those conditions is that we are supposed to
      watch what we say so we ensure a welcoming place for <emphasis role="italic"
        >everyone</emphasis>. </para>
    <para>As I've already been convinced that we <emphasis role="bold">do</emphasis> need to think
      about diversity, openness and anti-harassment after reading <ulink
        url="http://lwn.net/Articles/417952/">this LWN article about the darker side of open source
        conferences by Valerie Aurora</ulink>, I've decided to draft up a Code of Conduct for the
      openSUSE Conference today. </para>
    <para>You can find the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Code_of_Conduct">Code of
        Conduct draft on the wiki</ulink> and would love input! </para>
    <!--($ ld: 10.5.11 sm $)-->    
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://people.gnome.org/~michael/blog/2011-05-09-libreoffice-fud.html"
        >Michael Meeks: LibreOffice is the future of Free Software Office suites</ulink></title>
    <para>This is of course my view, and I hope yours, but naturally it is worth presenting at least
      some rational and working for this conclusion. Unfortunately, there are <emphasis role="bold"
        >so</emphasis> many reasons why TDF and LibreOffice are done right, that I can't list them
      all in linear time. However, I'll try to address some of the major ones recently raised by
      congenital worriers. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">LibreOffice is vendor neutral</emphasis></para>
    <para>LibreOffice does not belong to any single vendor, neither is it a single vendor's product.
      To characterise it that way is just silly. We have full-time developers from Novell, RedHat,
      Canonical and Lanedo working currently, with many key volunteer contributors, and
      contributions from other companies and distributions eg. CodeThink's Unity integration work,
      or the many Google Summer of Code students we've enjoyed working with. No-one is excluded from
      our governance - oh, except over-dominant corporations, there are strict limits in our <ulink
        url="http://wiki.documentfoundation.org/CommunityBylaws">bylaws</ulink> on the proportion of
      representation (one third) that any single company can have in any of our key institutions.
      Elections will be by a fair method (Single Transferable Vote), and be participated in by all
      significant contributors equally. The contrast with the mess of ridiculously gerrymandered
      governance, with layers of stacked privilege given to a single corporation in a previous
      project is quite stark. </para>
    <para>SUSE is the largest corporate contributor to TDF, though we are small compared to our huge
      group of motivated volunteers. My aim is to ensure that no vendor dominates (including SUSE):
      and that there is room for all contributors. Looking at our structures: the Steering
      Committee, Membership Committee, and the Engineering Steering Committee, we seem to be doing
      well there. </para>
    <para>Of course, having vendor neutrality around open standards is also good, but this is
      someone else's fight. I'm interested in the best result Free Software implementation possible,
      with a fun community to stand behind it, rather than the different good of enabling
      competition between implementations. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 10.5.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
