<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="tipsandtricks">
  <title>Tips and Tricks</title>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Desktop Users</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.techrepublic.com/blog/opensource/how-to-use-calibre-to-access-your-ebook-collection-online/2275">TechRepublic/Jack Wallen: How to use Calibre to access your ebook collection online</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Takeaway</emphasis>: Calibre is one of the most powerful ebook managers available. But did you know that Calibre has a built in server that 
      allows you to access your library from a web browser? In this how-to, Jack Wallen shows you how to set up Calibre to serve up your book library.</para>
      <para>I have been in near-saturation mode with ebooks lately, due to the publishing of my own works of fiction (find them on <ulink url="http://amzn.to/hmXIQN">Amazon</ulink>, 
        <ulink url="http://bit.ly/e8coZL">Barnes &amp; Noble</ulink>, and <ulink url="http://bit.ly/e553VF">Smashwords</ulink>). For many indie writers/publishers and readers of 
        ebooks the challenge of managing a vast collection of works can be a bit overwhelming (thanks to the ereaders’ insufficient built-in book management tools). Thankfully there 
        are tools available for the PC to help you manage those collections.</para>
      <para>Naturally Linux is not left out of this mix. The <ulink url="http://calibre-ebook.com/">Calibre</ulink> ebook manager is one of the best tools of the trade I have 
        found for managing ebooks. And for administrators looking for ways to convert and add books, PDFs, howtos, etc. to an ereader for portable reading, Calibre is exactly 
        the tool you need. Let’s take a look at this tool and how you can benefit from using it. (...)</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Copyright</emphasis>: <link linkend="extcopyright">1</link></para>
      <tip>
        <para>The Calibre Package for openSUSE can be downloaded from the <ulink url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/Documentation:/Tools/">Documentation:Tools Repository</ulink>. 
        Because the Developer uses brand new Libs, it is just available for &gt;= 11.4</para>
      </tip>
<!-- ($ Id: 01.3.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://artax.karlin.mff.cuni.cz/~kendy/blog/archives/monthly/2011-03.html">Jan Holesovsky: LibreOffice Findbar improvements</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Yesterday I played a bit with the Findbar in LibreOffice, and changed it to look and behave more like in the applications like Firefox, or Evolution:</para>
      <para>It is now hidden by default, and opens when you press Ctrl-f (for the old <emphasis role="bold">Search and Replace</emphasis> dialog I changed the keybinding to 
        Ctrl-Alt-f), or when you choose <emphasis role="bold">Find</emphasis> in the menu. It opens at the bottom of the document, and you can close it again (and return back to 
        the document) by pressing Escape. I also made the text entry wider so that more characters fits in there. </para>
      <para>Enjoy! :-) - will be available in LibreOffice 3.4.</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 4.3.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://scribblesandsnaps.wordpress.com/2011/02/22/work-with-photo-metadata-in-digikam/">Scribbles and Snaps/Dmitri Popov: Photography and Open Source Work with Photo Metadata in digiKam</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>&quot;Inside each digital photo hides metadata in the <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Exif">EXIF</ulink>, <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IPTC_Information_Interchange_Model">IPTC</ulink>, or <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extensible_Metadata_Platform">XMP</ulink> formats, and digiKam provides tools for viewing and editing this useful information.

</para>
      <para>For starters, digiKam’s main window features the dedicated <emphasis role="bold">Metadata</emphasis> sidebar which lets you view EXIF, Makernote, IPTC, and XMP metadata. You can switch between concise and full views as well as print the metadata, save them as a file, and copy them into the clipboard. (...)&quot;</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 5.3.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Commandline/Script Newbies</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://bashshell.net/utilities/exercise-6-set-variables-in-scripts/">BashShell.net/Mike: Exercise #6: Set Variables in Scripts</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>When you need to set variables, you can do that in the BEGIN section of an awk script. Here the variable firstuser is set to 1000. The BEGIN section sets that 
      variable and it is then used later in the script. (...)</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Copyright:</emphasis><link linkend="extcopyright">3</link></para>
<!-- ($ Id: 01.3.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://bashshell.net/script-of-the-week/log-parser/">BashShell.net/Mike: LogParser</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The idea behind a log parser is to create a loop that will check all of your required logs to return information about specific needs that you may have as an 
        administrator. For example, with this script you may want to search a specific log for one or two text strings that are very important to the function of your 
        system.(...)</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Copyright:</emphasis><link linkend="extcopyright">3</link></para>
<!-- ($ Id: 01.3.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Developers and Programmers</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://python4kids.wordpress.com/2011/02/24/a-big-jar-of-pickles/">python4kids/Brandan Scott: A Big Jar of Pickle</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>In the last tutorial we learned how to pickle our objects.  Pickling is a way of storing the object (on the computer’s file system) so that it can be used later. 
        This means that if we want to re use an object we can simply save it and load it when we need it, rather than re-creating it each time we want to use it.  This is very 
        useful when our object is a list of questions for our trivia game.  We really only want to type the questions in once and then reload them later.</para>
      <para>Now we need to settle on a way to structure our data.  We saw in our earlier tutorial that each question was a list, and that the list itself had a certain 
        structure.  We also need to think about how a number of questions will be stored.  We will use a list to do that as well!  In this case we will have a list of questions. 
        Each of the elements in the list will itself be a list. Let’s build one. First we make an empty list to store all the questions: (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 1.3.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For System Administrators</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.ibm.com/developerworks/linux/library/l-lpic3-310-2/index.html">IBM developerWorks/Roderick W. Smith: Learn Linux, 302 (Mixed environments): Samba roles</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>&quot;Samba isn&apos;t a single program; rather, it&apos;s a series of interrelated servers and utilities, each of which has its own specific purpose. Understanding the differences between these servers and utilities will help you manage your Samba system. Furthermore, Samba implements a number of different security models, which you must understand to properly integrate Samba into an existing network or to set up a new network with Samba servers at its core. (...)&quot;</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 5.3.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
