<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://anditosan.blogspot.com/2010/12/new-idea-about-chat-program.html"
        >Andres Silva: New Idea About Chat Program</ulink></title>
    <para><quote>I am a good user of social networking sites, such as Facebook and Twitter. They
        have used very interesting features on their websites, such as instant messaging. By that I
        do not mean the chat application that Facebook uses, or the immediate update on Twitter
        messages. I am talking about the idea of instant messaging on settled messages. For example,
        when a person posts a comment on Facebook and is able to keep a conversation from one person
        to the next. It is a minifeed that also includes the rest of the present contacts that are
        involved in the message box.</quote></para>
    <figure id="fig.fbminifeed">
      <title>Facebook Minifeed</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata width="25%"
            fileref="http://startupmeme.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/06/facebook-minifeed.jpg"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para><quote>Twitter is a little similar, you are able to scroll through the many messages on
        your home page as well as the rest of the contacts who have posted messages on your Twitter.
          (...)<xref linkend="fig.fbminifeed"/></quote></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 20.12.10 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="https://saschpe.wordpress.com/2010/12/12/braindead-python-packaging/">Martin
        Vidner: network-autoconfig: Find a connected eth interface and create an ifcfg for
        it</ulink></title>
    <para>Use case: I want to create an appliance image for a build farm worker machine. I don't
      know its hardware configuration beforehand; in particular, it may have multiple network
      interfaces and I don't want to bother figuring out which is which. I will simply include
        <emphasis role="bold">network-autoconfig.rpm</emphasis> and plug the cable into any socket
      before booting.</para>
    <para>network-autoconfig helps setting up machines with multiple network interfaces. At the
      first boot, all available Ethernet interfaces are cycled until one is successfully configured
      with DHCP.</para>
    <para>I have submitted it to openSUSE:Factory now. Enjoy it in the upcoming openSUSE
      11.4!</para>
    <para>It is referenced as <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311012"
        >Feature#311012</ulink>. You are welcome to improve it on <ulink
        url="http://gitorious.org/opensuse/network-autoconfig">Gitorious</ulink>. (...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 22.12.10 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/12/23/more-unity-news/">Nelson Marques: More
        ‘Unity’ news…</ulink></title>
    <para>I’ve finished with the base packages required for Unity, in fact Unity already builds,
      though I’ve not really tested it yet as some components still need to take care… so far what’s
      done:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>dee – is now properly packaged and ready for submission (no patching required);</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>bamf – is now properly packaged and ready for submission (includes a patch modified by
          Adam Williamson based on a Debian patch);</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>ux – builds and in a way it’s ready, though I want to split this package in the nearby
          future.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>unity – builds for the time being… though it requires proper integration on the
          system. This build also builds with support for Indicators, since the dependencies are
          already prepared. Will take now a bit of time due to integration. I will offer this
          package installed on /opt/unity and not on usual system path.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>While fighting for dependencies there emerged a small problem with ‘glewmx’, which builds
      from the same sources of ‘glew’. I’m currently working on this package as a priority to fix it
      and submit it to ‘multimedia:libs’ which also hosts ‘glew’. This package has also a small
      patch by Adam Williamson which was already submitted upstream that allows the proper build of
      ‘libGLEWmx.so*’ and glewmx.pc. Currently I’ve built this package only offering the libs. I’ve
      removed the binaries (and made a dependency on ‘glew’ for the binaries) and I’ve also removed
      the headers from the includes which will be shared with ‘glew’ and made a proper dependency.
      I’ve consulted Dimstar regarding this operation which promptly offered some quick guidance on
      the process and showed a couple of useful examples on how to this ‘the openSUSE way’.</para>
    <para>I hope that before the new year there’s a test package of Unity for Factory users. I would
      also take this opportunity to thank everyone which has helped me so far on this ‘one man
      inglorious rush’ towards bringing Unity to openSUSE as an option for those who want to check
      it out.</para>
    <para>My sincere thanks to the following:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Vincent Untz (openSUSE/Novell);</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Ken Vandine (Canonical);</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Cristopher Roges (Ubuntu);</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Adam Williamson (Fedora/Red Hat);</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>openSUSE GNOME team;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The openSUSE community, specially those which have supported this effort since day
          #1.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Arch Linux contributors (which were working on this and from which I got some guidance
          from their ‘forums’);</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>Nelson Marques</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 23.12.10 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://psankar.blogspot.com/2010/12/meego-naming-conflicts-controversies.html">Josef
        Reidinger: Easy scripting actions with susestudio alias new rubygem
      studio_api</ulink></title>
    <para>Now I work for SLMS ( Suse Lifecycle Management Server ) project. It cooperate with SuSE
      studio and use its API. I get idea that more people could benefit from easy access to studio
      API from ruby so I extract functionality and improve behavior, documentation and testing and
      now there is new rubygem studio_api. Why you should use this gem?</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>ActiveResource Behavior</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Actively maintained ( and will be due to SLMS support )</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Tightly developed with guys from studio team</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Well documented with yard</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Good test coverage.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>I think then a lot of glory words is better to show example. It is example based on
      example from documentation. Example goal is simple. Create new appliance in studio, add own
      cool rpm and build appliance with it. It can be useful to test your new version of software in
      stable environment and have automatic appliance in which you can test it. (...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 23.12.10 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://nowwhatthe.blogspot.com/2010/12/good-news.html">Jos Poortvliet: good
        news!</ulink></title>
    <para>Hello world, Some good news. </para>
    <para>First of all, the dutch Linux Starter I blogged about a few days ago is now <ulink
        url="http://www.hubstore.nl/informatie.asp?LN=STLIN2010">available online</ulink>. So if
      you're dutch and want to try out openSUSE - go and get it! </para>
    <para>And second of all, the board has just announced that Alan Clark has been appointed by
      Novell as new chair of the board. Most of you probably don't know him, I do as I have been
      working with him for the last few months on the openSUSE Foundation and some other things.
      He's in my humble opinion one of those people who gets Free Software and a pleasure to work
      with. Only after this announcement I discovered he was pretty "high in the tree" as we in NL
      say - being on the Senior Leadership team of Markus, his experience in the Linux Foundation
      and other organizations... But while working with me he had a simple "let's get this done and
      do it well" attitude. Still an engineer on the inside - something you actually see a lot in
      Novell and something I appreciate greatly.</para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://www.wafaa.eu/entry/fed-up-of-fud-against-novell-suse--opensuse-1-47.html">Andrew
        Wafaa: Fed up of FUD against Novell, SUSE</ulink></title>
    <para>tl;dr – To all you doomsday FUD mongers about Novell/SUSE/openSUSE STFU &amp; let us show
      you what we can and will do!! </para>
    <para>For those living under a rock, yes Novell has agreed to be acquired. Welcome to the world
      of business, and especially in software this sort of thing is very common. </para>
    <para>Now for some reason a whole heap of people seem to think that this spells doom for Novell,
      SUSE and openSUSE. Why? I really can't answer that. What I do know is that all their negative
      speculation is at best counter productive, at worst foolish and damaging. </para>
    <para>As with any form of speculation there are no facts to back up what they reckon is going to
      happen – hence the speculation. If there is enough negative talk, negative things will happen.
      Current customers will look at switching from Novell products whether they be SUSE based or
      not, purely based on all the negativity that is being generated. </para>
    <para>No-one is giving Attachemate a chance to prove what they have openly said – Novell, SUSE
      and openSUSE's contribution to the wider community will continue and that it is business as
      usual. If you look at when Oracle bought Sun they said sod all about OpenSolaris and the rest
      of Sun. This is different. The new overlords are actually communicating – maybe not as much as
      we would like, but hey it's a bloody good step in the right direction. </para>
    <para>The latest negative piece comes from the <ulink
        url="http://blogs.the451group.com/opensource/2010/12/08/linux-kernel-solid-but-what-will-become-of-novell-contribution"
        >451 Group</ulink>. Why the frig would Novell's purchase change their kernel contributions?
      Why the frig would Novell's purchase change any of their current contributions to the vast
      array of projects including GNOME/KDE/Banshee/LibreOffice/Systemd and a whole heap of others?
      Simple, it doesn't. </para>
    <para>Don't get me wrong Novell has screwed up big time in the past, but we are working together
      as a community to learn from these mistakes. All this negative noise is counter productive and
      just gets in the way. If you want to see Novell, SUSE and openSUSE flourish hows about you
      roll your sleeves up and get stuck in? If you don't want to chip in STFU and wait and see if
      something does happen. Then you can berate us and tell us how and where we went wrong.</para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/12/15/verein-computerspende-hamburg-and-opensuse/"
        >Klaas Freitag: Verein Computerspende Hamburg and openSUSE</ulink></title>
    <para>This <ulink url="http://www.spiegel.de/netzwelt/netzpolitik/0,1518,706047,00.html"
        >article</ulink> of the German news magazine <ulink url="http://www.spiegel.de/">Der
        Spiegel</ulink> made me aware of the <ulink url="http://www.computerspendehamburg.de/"
        >Verein Computerspende Hamburg</ulink>. A German verein is a non profit association, there
      are lots in Germany for sports, culture and these kind of stuff. </para>
    <para>The Verein Computerspende Hamburg does something very useful: It takes used computer parts
      that other people do not longer need and refurbish them to working computers again. These
      computers are handed to people who happen to be in a difficult situation in life. They have to
      live from Hartz IV which is a kind German social security, following the unemployment benefit
      which ends after a short period. Hartz IV means very, very little money the people have to
      make their lives from, too little to buy a new computer. </para>
    <para>On the other hand, an increasing amount of the job offerings are posted on the web, so
      people currently unemployed basically have to search the web, not speaking about preparing the
      resumes to apply for a job. So how would one do that without a computer? </para>
    <para>Computing is not only hardware and well known operating systems and applications are far
      away from free, so it’s obvious that our great project is a perfect partner here: Not that we
      only offer a user friendly, easy to install, secure, feature rich and last but not least
      completely free <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Distribution">Linux
        Distribution</ulink>, we as a community are also able to help if problems come up,
      regardless if somebody has money or not and what kind of problem it might be. This is another
      very concrete example where free software and the FOSS communities help your neighbor, or you
      – as it is very easy to get into a difficult situation in life. </para>
    <para>We sent 500 openSUSE 11.3 DVDs to Hamburg with our warm invitation and welcome to all new
      users to show up and join our community. So be aware of new kids on the block :-) </para>
    <para>And if you are in Hamburg or around and want to help, I am sure <ulink
        url="http://www.computerspendehamburg.de/">Verein Computerspende</ulink> can make use of the
      help of more Geekos, such as installation, first hand user support and probably much more. And
      if you know of a similar interested initiative, let me know, I am sure I will find more DVDs
      ;-) </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/12/16/10-minutes-of-your-time/">Nelson
        Marques: 10 minutes of YOUR time…</ulink></title>
    <figure id="fig.pirate">
      <title>Be a pirate</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="http://www.openclipart.org/image/800px/svg_to_png/Clue_Calico_Jack_pirate_logo.png"
            width="15%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>Fellow openSUSE Contributor, I am not as gifted as Mizmo, so I can’t really present some
      cool metaphore in the form of a cartoon… Nevertheless I will try my best.<xref
        linkend="fig.pirate"/></para>
    <para>During the OSC2010 in Nürnberg I tried without much success to pass on the word that
      Marketing isn’t about a Team, but comes also down to us. This in an awesome time to
      demonstrate that on practice… Right now with an important release on the horizon, your
      Marketing team is starting a process to gather information to promote the features of the next
      release. Speaking for myself, I don’t feel confortable in taking an assingment of gathering
      features for example about the Kernel. As I won’t feel confortable producing contents about
      KDE which I barelly know… Nevertheless if those contents aren’t provided to us…. we have to
      dig for them… sometimes not even having a clue of the extention of their importance. </para>
    <para>Many times I’ve heard the ultimate excuse ‘Marketing is for Ubuntu, because they are just
      Marketing and nothing else’… and things on that line… Well… think again… who’s fault is this
      that only them care about Marketing ? I see a good opportunity for you all to achieve some
      things in the next days… with only 10 minutes of your time… and why could be nice it happened
      this way:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>You run a project that is on Factory… cool… Please take 10 minutes, make a small
            list of 10 features that are really cool on the next release… make a 7/15 lines text on
            how your project changed and the benefit of the improvements for our users (if you don’t
            know your users, then write it as if you were talking about yourself)… This way you save
            your Marketing Team ‘wild goose chase’ on a stack of Changelogs we might not understand…
            even worst, we might even pass on the wrong stuff….</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>By doing this… you are doing Marketing… you are promoting your own project within
            openSUSE, giving it more visibility and with 10 mins of your time… you will pass on the
            right word to the Marketing Team and help them. Instead of spending 50 hours searching
            for stuff and taking some hard decisions that might not work out in the best way for
            YOUR project, we have 50 mins more to work your information and make sure it is better
            used for the interests of YOUR project.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para> If Marketing takes 3 features to write an article or make Marketing materials… and
            just lists the other 7… If like at least we get contributions in this form from: Kernel,
            GNOME, KDE and Ambassadors (yes, people should also be on the release)… thats 3×4 = 12
            featured articles for the release and a feature list of 40 new exciting
            features….</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>Now… does this seem so surreal to ask 10 minutes of your time to help out your
      Marketing Team and make the best release ever! Oh! And have a lot of fun! </para>
    <para>Someone said that I was crazy… and that projects and developers would never comply and
      would most likely laugh on my face after proposing such thing… I might be crazy… or I might
      very well on the wrong track. I’ve decided not to back down from facing the ‘mob’, and still
      risking to be laughed upon, I brought this to your attention.</para>
    <para>Become a openSUSE Pirate ? <ulink url="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JiPnuuE60r8"
        >You-are-a-pirate</ulink> Youtube Video.</para>
  </blockquote>
  <!-- ($ ld: 17.12.10 sm $) -->
</sect1>
