<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="forums">
  <title>openSUSE Forums</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/pre-release-beta/453982-opensuse-11-4-rc1-have-you-installed-did-do-you-have-any-issus.html">
	openSUSE 11.4 RC1, have you installed it? Did you have any issues?
	</ulink></title>
    <para>
      There's only a couple of weeks left before the final release of openSUSE 11.4. After the Milestone releases we've now come to the first Release Candidate, which should be pretty close to what 11.4 is going to be. As usual members of the forums have started a thread to share experience, issues and thoughts about this RC1. From what we read there's still some work to be done, but the overall impression is that 11.4 is going to be a good one. Public release of openSUSE 11.4 is scheduled for 10th of March 2011. 
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/install-boot-login/454139-updating-process-different-various-linux-os-e-g-suse-ubuntu.html">
      Is updating process different in various Linux OS, e.g. Suse and Ubuntu?
      </ulink></title>
    <para>
      An interesting thread for those who wonder about differences between various linux distros, where it concerns kernel-updates etc. The thread's starter noticed that his Ubuntu install keeps the previous kernel available after an update, where openSUSE by default replaces the kernel. But that's not the only thing discussed in this thread, quite a lot related to the subject is drawn into the conversation. 
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/other-forums/community-fun/surveys-polls/454197-forum-display-mode-do-you-prefer.html">
      Which forum display mode do you prefer?
      </ulink></title>
    <para>
      From time to time we have polls/surveys on the forums, to see how the community feels about certain aspects, features of the forums. This one is about the display mode of the threads in the forums, At this very moment it seems that the default, the linear mode, is most used, maybe because it's the default. Read and see how our members think about this. Don't forget to vote !!
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>This week's subforum: <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/other-forums/news-announcements/tech-news/">
      Tech News
      </ulink></title>
    <para>
      In this week's subforum we find openSUSE and linux related announcements and news. One example is the announcement of yet another issue of this weekly news magazine, other examples: the release of new third party drivers, overviews of security fixes and patches, release of new software. A nice place to get an idea of what's going on in the openSUSE world outside the forums. Also, changes in repos are mostly announced here first. Just check in and see what's there.
      </para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 17.2.11 gl $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
