<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://vizzzion.org/blog/2011/04/im-going-to-the-kde-ux-sprint-then-tokamak-is-coming-to-me/"
        >Sebastian Kügler: I’m going to the KDE UX sprint, then Tokamak is coming to
      me!</ulink></title>
    <para> On Thursday, I’ll be travelling to Berlin for the KDE UX sprint, which is kindly hosted
      by relevantive in their office in the heart of Berlin. I’ll be meeting Nuno, Celeste, Hugo and
      a few others there, and we’ll be making plans. Topics are the human interface guidelines,
      getting more designers involved with KDE, and of course <ulink
        url="http://vizzzion.org/blog/2011/04/plasma-active-a-desirable-user-experience-encompassing-the-device-spectrum/"
        >Plasma Active</ulink>. </para>
    <para> A few days after coming back, hell will break loose in Nijmegen, as the Plasma crew holds
      their Tokamak gathering here. Here means at our new house in Nijmegen in the east of the
      Netherlands (which is in the west of Europe ;)). I’m really looking forward to having my
      fellow Plasma hackers here, especially with all the excitement, new ideas and concepts coming
      along with Plasma Active. I’m sure it will be an epic Tokamak, and a really long one, too.
      Between first arrivals and least departures, there will be a whopping 12 nights. We’ll likely
      be doing an Open Day, so if you’re in the region, drop me an email if you’d like to come by to
      see the magic happen.</para>
    <para> Speaking of Plasma Active itself, it’s off to a good start. We’ve spent crazy amounts of
      hours in very little time before I announced it on my blog, and we kicked off a surge of blog
      posts about this subject — with more to come. I’m really happy with the positive interest it
      generated so far, very promising.</para>
    <para> With the past two weeks spending most of my time on documentation, packaging and
      communication, I got back into hacking mode today, and polished up my small metadata engine I
      had started writing not long ago. It’s working now, you can query all kinds of resources,
      either by filename, URL, Nepomuk Identifier or simple query term, and it gives you back a list
      of Nepomuk resources and their metadata. It’s pretty simple, but very powerful. It already
      provides most of what you need to write a simple filebrowser, or search widget in Plasma
      Quick. I’ll write a more detailed blog post (including screenshots) once I’m more happy with
      it, also visually. The basic metadata engine is already in master, and will be appearing in
      the next update of the Plasma Active packages, probably tomorrow. Now, back to hacking. =) </para>    
    <!--($ ld: 13.4.11 sm $)-->    
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://blog.jospoortvliet.com/2011/04/upcoming.html">Jos Poortvliet:
        Upcoming...</ulink></title>
    <para>I've been quite busy over the last few months - after Michael Loeffler left and AJ went on
      parental leave for 2 months life got crazy. Luckily openSUSE doesn't exactly depend on me and
      while some things slipped, I don't think big things broke down. Ok, my boss wasn't happy with
      me as especially internal budget things suffered. I've given those sending me interviews and
      other writing stuff (like my column for <ulink url="http://www.linuxuser.co.uk/"
        >LinuxUser</ulink>) a very hard time too. And personally, I'm unhappy with it because I
      tried to do to many things which resulted in many of them unfinished. </para>
    <para>back on track But AJ is back, we're getting some processes on track and the 11.4 release
      worked out great. So it is time to focus again and get things finished. First is the strategy
      stuff. The openSUSE Board had a few comments we'll look through, then it should go up for
      voting. Really. I know, it already needs some updating - we'll try to do that first. Once that
      is done, it's time to vote on it and get it out however. We need to get the DVD's out which we
      created for GNOME 3 and KDE. For both I spend a lot of time collecting materials to include on
      the disk and imho the end result is pretty ok. But there's also room for improvement,
      something for the future... And we have marketing materials to create for the US. There have
      been only a few suggestions on the marketing ML so it looks like I'm gonna have to lock myself
      in my room for a day or two to write some stuff... Finally, I have to catch up with mail. With
      over 2300 unread mails that'll be quite a job but in some folders I'll probably just mark all
      read... And then it's on to new stuff! </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Like..</emphasis>. </para>
    <para>Last Saturday I gave a talk at a FLISOL meeting - and in the preparations for that I
      updated a number of presentations I have. Will share them with the marketing team and
      hopefully put them in Git &amp; the wiki with the marketing materials. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">wiki stuff</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>The openSUSE ambassador talking points have been improving and I'm working on an upcoming
      features. I've also went through the wiki pages for new contributors, making small changes and
      adding links there, improving the Junior Jobs pages. Now the openSUSE Boosters are planning to
      work on that as well, smoothing out the process of getting involved in openSUSE. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">openhatch </emphasis></para>
    <para>Once we have that up, I'd like to investigate openSUSE joining openHatch. For that we'd
      need junior jobs in a variety of areas as well as mentors - but I think I can just start
      small. We have a convention in Bugzilla which is followed by practically nobody: mark simple
      bugs with "JJ" so they can be easily found. I'll try and get a few of those on openhatch, see
      if we can get a contributor or two to chip in. If that works we have a good reason to expand
      upon that! </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">and a promise </emphasis></para>
    <para>Finally I promise to work harder on being available &amp; in meetings - I know I missed a
      few ;-) </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">CC-BY-SA</ulink></para>
    <!--($ ld: 15.4.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://ungethym.blogspot.com/2011/04/contributions-that-matter.html">Thomas
        Thym: Contributions that matter</ulink></title>
    <para>In the last days I read two post on planetkde and planetsuse, written by (to me) new
      contributors with the best intention to help their projects. However the response of the
      community was not as positive as they would have expected. What happened?3 types of potential
      new contributors Some lines from <ulink
        url="http://thym.org/downloads/Akademy2010-Thym-The-7-OS-Principles.pdf">my last years
        Akademy paper</ulink>.
      <para>"Krogh, Spaeth and Lakhani analyzed the characters of
        potential new contributors in mailing lists.[12] Based on that work three types could be found.<itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Proactive problem-solver: They use the program, find a bug, and work out the
              solution. In the first mail to the list they send the patch. These people are very
              successful in communities and often become continuous contributors.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Waiting volunteer: This group offers their abilities to the community and waits
              until they get a job allocated. In general this character is not very active. Most
              communities can not integrate them successfully.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Visionary: They use the program and have ideas on how the program should be
              improved. Although visions and aims are important in communities, the character-type
              visionary is not successful. In the past his/her visions were not identical with the
              ideas of the code developers. The resulting costs of conflicts exceed the benefits of
              the discussion."</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>Even the headline of one of the post gives you a hint which type
      might be behind the post in question. Visionaries often use words like "it should", "you have
      to" etc. instead of "I have done" or "I am going to do".</para>
    <!--($ ld: 15.4.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://mschlander.wordpress.com/2011/04/14/more-love-for-kdeupdatedapps/"
        >Martin Schlander: More love for KDE:UpdatedApps</ulink></title>
    <para>The KDE:UpdatedApps repository for openSUSE (formerly known as KDE:Backports), hasn’t been
      getting the love it deserves as of late. This repo lets you easily and safely update many KDE
      applications without needing to do unofficial upgrades of your base libraries or base desktop
      environment, with the risks and annoyances this involves. </para>
    <para>After I had been complaining loudly about the state of things for a while, I ended up
      being given permissions to the repository on the openSUSE BuildService to shut me up, and I’ll
      attempt to do the janitorial work needed from now on – which basically just means linking
      relevant package revisions from KDE:Distro:Factory. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 15.4.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/04/15/calibre-repository-moved/">Thomas
        Schraitle: Calibre Repository Moved</ulink></title>
    <para>Maybe not everybody knows it or it may be a bit too late, but nevertheless… the Calibre
      repository on home:thomas-schraitle:calibre has been moved to <emphasis role="bold"
        >Documentation:Tools</emphasis>. It was necessary due to some internal reorganisation. The
      new location is now the official devel project. Have fun! :-)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 15.4.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
