<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/05/16/opensuse-conference-2011-to-be-creative-and-open/"
        >Ready…Set…Code!</ulink></title>
    <para>Yesterday marked the official start of Google Summer of Code’s Coding Period. And openSUSE
      mentors are right in the thick of it working with 16 students seeking to make a better world
      in FOSS.</para>
    <para>openSUSE can take particular pride in GSoC further supporting the openSUSE goal of
      creating an environment thatý supports not only openSUSE but FOSS in general. Indeed we are
      mentoring several projects that directly benefit openSUSE, but there’s also several projects
      that support other projects, like the Arch Linux backend for our Open Build Service, a test
      suite for btrfs, ext4 snapshots in snapper, PackageKit backend in Software Center, and ICC
      device profile repository.<blockquote>
        <para>I do believe that our main contribution is that we will be sharing our enthusiasm
          about Free Software with our students and students from other organizations. And this is
          what will, hopefully, keep the students involved in the Free Software world after GSoC.
            <emphasis role="italic">– Vincent Untz, openSUSE GSoC Organizer</emphasis></para>
      </blockquote>And it is true that students are already experiencing the spirit of the openSUSE
      Project. As student Alex Eftimie says:</para>
    <para>
      <blockquote>
        <para>What can I say? I’m excited about everything. openSUSE is the perfect umbrella for
          such a project. What I like most about it is that the result will be usable in a
          cross-distro fashion. Until GSoC, I wasn’t familiar with openSUSE efforts on
          collaboration. Package management is a domain where distros can do better, and I’m glad to
          be a part of this effort.</para>
      </blockquote>
    </para>
    <para>You can see the complete list of student projects we’re working with <ulink
        url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-project/2011-04/msg00495.html">here</ulink>.</para>
    <para>Pavol Rusnak, our other openSUSE GSoC organizer, reminds us that there are also some
      long-standing tasks directly beneitting the openSUSE Project which will now be tackled by some
      of our student projects.</para>
    <blockquote>
      <para>With projects like Open Build Service for Android, a new python OBS library, and
        solutions to enhance SUSE Studio and YaST, we’ll be further strengthening some of the unique
        selling points of openSUSE.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">The Timeline</emphasis><itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>May 23 – Coding begins</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>July 11 – Midterm Evaluation</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>August 15 – Suggested Pencil Down</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>August 26 – Final Evaluation Deadline</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Stay informed</emphasis></para>
    <para>Students are asked to post weekly reports. You can follow it on their blogs, which are
      aggregated on <ulink url="http://planet.opensuse.org/global/">Planet openSUSE</ulink> or
      through our <ulink url="mailto:opensuse-project+subscribe@opensuse.org">openSUSE Project
        mailing list</ulink>.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GFDL 1.2</ulink></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 26.5.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>  
</sect1>
