<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
  %myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="kernel">
  <title>Kernel Review</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://www.kroah.com/log/linux/longterm-proposal-08-2011.html">Greg Kroah-Hartman:
        Future of the -longterm kernel releases.</ulink>
    </title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">tl;dr;</emphasis><itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>-stable kernel releases stay the same</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>this proposal is how we pick the -longterm releases</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>-longterm kernels will be picked every year, and maintained for 2 years before being
            dropped.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>the same Documentation/stable<emphasis role="italic">kernel</emphasis>rules.txt will
            apply for -longterm kernels, as before.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">History:</emphasis></para>
    <para>2.6.16 became a "longterm" kernel because my day job (at SUSE) picked the 2.6.16 kernel
      for its "enterprise" release and it made things a lot easier for me to keep working at
      applying bugfixes and other stable patches to it to make my job simpler (applying a known-good
      bunch of patches in one stable update was easier than a set of smaller patches that were only
      tested by a smaller group of people.)</para>
    <para>Seeing that this worked well, a cabal of developers got together at a few different Linux
      conferences and determined that based on their future distro release cycles, we could all aim
      for standardizing on the 2.6.32 kernel, saving us all time and energy in the long run. We
      turned around and planted the proper seeds within the different organizations and
      low-and-behold, project managers figured that this was their idea and sold it to the rest of
      the groups and made it happen. Right now all of the major "enterprise" and "stable" distro
      releases are based on the 2.6.32 kernel, making this trial a huge success.</para>
    <para>Last year, two different community members (Andi and Paul) asked me if they could maintain
      the 2.6.34 and 2.6.35 kernels as -longterm kernel releases as their companies needed this type
      of support. I agreed, and they have done a great job at this.</para>
    <para>Andi reports that the 2.6.35 kernel is being used by a number of different distros, but
      they will be phased out as their support lifetime expires. There are also a number of embedded
      users of the kernel as well as some individual ones. So that -longterm kernel is having a lot
      of benefit for a wide range of users.</para>
    <para>Today:</para>
    <para>Now that 2.6.32 is over a year and a half, and the enterprise distros are off doing their
      thing with their multi-year upgrade cycles, there's no real need from the distros for a new
      longterm kernel release. But it turns out that the distros are not the only user of the
      kernel, other groups and companies have been approaching me over the past year, asking how
      they could pick the next longterm kernel, or what the process is in determining this.</para>
    <para>To keep this all out in the open, let's figure out what to do here. Consumer devices have
      a 1-2 year lifespan, and want and need the experience of the kernel community maintaining
      their "base" kernel for them. There is no real "enterprise" embedded distro out there from
      what I can see. montaVista and WindRiver have some offerings in this area, but they are not
      that widely used and are usually more "deep embedded". There's also talk that the CELF group
      and Linaro are wanting to do something on a "longterm" basis, and are fishing around for how
      to properly handle this with the community to share the workload. Android also is another huge
      player here, upgrading their kernel every major release, and they could use the support of a
      longterm kernel as well.</para>
    <para id="para_bao_efu_hd"><emphasis role="bold">Proposal:</emphasis></para>
    <para>Here's a first cut at a proposal, let me know if you like it, hate it, would work for you
      and your company, or not at all:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>a new -longterm kernel is picked every year.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>a -longterm kernel is maintained for 2 years and then dropped.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>-stable kernels keep the same schedule that they have been (dropping the last one
            after a new release happens.) These releases are best for products that require new
            hardware updates (desktop distros, community distros, fast-moving embedded distros (like
            Yocto)).</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>the normal -stable rules apply to these -longterm kernels as described in
              Documentation/stable<emphasis role="italic">kernel</emphasis>rules.txt</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>This means that there are 2 -longterm kernels being maintained at the same time, and one
      -stable kernel. I'm volunteering to do this work, as it's pretty much what I'm doing today
      anyway, and I have all of the scripts and workflow down.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Public Notifications:</emphasis></para>
    <para>The current kernel.org site doesn't properly show what is and is not being maintained as a
      -stable and -longterm kernel. I have a proposal for how to fix this involving 'git notes', I
      just need to sit down and do the work with the kernel.org admins to get this running
      properly.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Thoughts?</emphasis></para>
    <para>Feel free to comment on the <ulink
        url="https://plus.google.com/111049168280159033135/posts/VyWdYvHnAS2">google+ thread</ulink>
      about this, or on the <ulink url="https://lkml.org/lkml/2011/8/15/5">lkml</ulink>
      thread.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 15.8.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/Kernel-Log-Coming-in-3-1-Part-1-Networking-1323463.html"
        >h-online/Thorsten Leemhuis: Kernel Log: Coming in 3.1 - Part 1 - Networking</ulink></title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Among the most important advancements of Linux 3.1 are improvements
        for all major Wi-Fi drivers and virtualisation optimisations. </emphasis></para>
    <para>One week after <ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/Kernel-Log-First-release-candidate-for-Linux-3-1-1319559.html"
        >issuing</ulink> Linux 3.1-rc1, Linus Torvalds<ulink
        url="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.kernel/1179341"> presented</ulink> the second
      release candidate of Linux 3.1 late on Sunday night. The new version has been taken as an
      opportunity to <ulink
        url="http://git.kernel.org/linus/93ee7a9340d64f20295aacc3fb6a22b759323280">rename</ulink>
      the kernel, which had been christened "Sneaky Weasel" <ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/news/item/First-release-candidate-of-Linux-3-0-available-1252280.html"
        >at the end of May</ulink>; its new name is "Wet Seal". Torvalds didn't provide any
      background reasons for his choice of name – it could be to do with the diving course he <ulink
        url="https://plus.google.com/102150693225130002912/posts/RLmbspKyr68">attended</ulink> as a
        <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Divemaster">divemaster</ulink>.</para>
    <para>In his release email for the second release candidate, Torvalds was pleased to report that
      the merge window had been "pretty normal". From now until the final release of Linux 3.1, only
      corrections and minor improvements that don't present any risk – apart from rare exceptions –
      will now be accepted into the Linux main development branch. </para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 18.8.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://schaiba.wordpress.com/2011/08/13/kernel-weekly-news-13-08-2011/">Rares
        Aioanei: kernel weekly news – 13.08.2011</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>Rares gives his weekly Kernel Review with openSUSE Flavor.</para>
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
