<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="tipsandtricks">
  <title>Tips and Tricks</title>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Desktop Users</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://ubuntumanual.org/posts/344/five-cool-kde-widgets-for-your-desktop">UbuntuManual: Five cool KDE widgets for your desktop! </ulink>
      </title>
      <para>With all the hype around Unity and Gnome 3, KDE fans might be having a lousy time and
        feel ignored. We are bored with those two anyway ;-). Its time for a change. KDE fans
        rejoice!! KDE has many very cool and useful widgets which you can add on your KDE desktop or
        in your taskbar. Lets have a look at the top 5 widgets. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 30.5.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.tricksmachine.com/2011/05/4-things-to-do-after-you-install-kde.html">Tricksmachine/Vishal Gaikar: 4 Things to Do After You Install KDE</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">KDE</emphasis> is a free and <ulink url="http://www.tricksmachine.com/tag/open-source">open source</ulink> desktop workspace,
        application suite, and development environment for Unix-like operating systems such as
        Linux. Its applications are also available for <ulink url="http://www.tricksmachine.com/tag/mac-os-x">Mac OS X</ulink> and <ulink url="http://www.tricksmachine.com/category/computer-tricks">Windows</ulink>. One of the
        most impressive features of KDE is its flexibility. You can customize KDE to look and feel
        however you want.</para>
      <para>The KDE workspace is a unique experience not found with any other desktop environment or
          <ulink url="http://www.tricksmachine.com/tag/operating-system">operating system</ulink>.
        It is called Plasma and is fully integrated with a widget system and is easily themeable.
        When you first install KDE, it will already look beautiful, but half of the fun of a free
        and open source workspace is tweaking. These are simple customizations you can do to make
        your KDE desktop truly yours. (...)</para>
<!--($ Id: 31.5.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Commandline/Script Newbies</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://bashshell.net/script-of-the-week/script-of-the-week-changing-terminal-color/">BashShell.net/Mike: Script of the Week: Changing Terminal Color</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>term_color.sh</para>
      <para>This simple script can be run in a tty to that you can change the color to be more easily read.  Note that the tty uses 8 colors so you will not get the most beautiful output.  The 8 colors are; black, white, red, blue,green, yellow, magenta, and cyan.  (perform as normal user not root)</para>
      <para>You do not want to mess up your root account so use a test account to try this. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 3.6.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Developers and Programmers</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://olex.openlogic.com/wazi/2011/get-the-most-out-of-phpmyadmins-visual-query-designer/">Wazi/Colin Beckingham: Get the Most Out of phpMyAdmin’s Visual Query Designer</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Database programmers and administrators often need to design SQL queries against database structures with which they’re not intimately familiar. By using a visual query designer, programmers and admins can cut down on coding errors and save time. FOSS tool <ulink url="http://olex.openlogic.com/packages/phpmyadmin">phpMyAdmin</ulink> offers a simple builder that can help anyone design <ulink url="http://olex.openlogic.com/packages/mysql">MySQL</ulink> queries. Here’s how to get started designing basic queries visually in phpMyAdmin.

(...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 3.6.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://dominique.leuenberger.net/blog/2011/05/how-to-fix-brp-and-rpmlint-warnings-%E2%80%93-today-i-statement-might-be-overflowing-a-buffer-in-strncat/">Dominique Leuenberger: how to fix brp and rpmlint warnings – today: I: Statement might be overflowing a buffer in strncat.</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Malcolm Lewis sent me a link to one of his failing packages, with the idea to bring the
        next post for this series (which has had a too long break already). So Malcolm: Thank you
        for the heads up and here we go with another hopefully helpful solution to one of brp error
        (brp actually stands for Build Root Policy)</para>
      <para>So, just like before, we have a look at the error, including the specific code parts
        raising the errors:</para>
      <blockquote>
        <para>I: Statement might be overflowing a buffer in strncat. Common mistake:</para>
        <para> BAD: strncat(buffer,charptr,sizeof(buffer)) is wrong, it takes the left over size as
          3rd argument</para>
        <para> GOOD: strncat(buffer,charptr,sizeof(buffer)-strlen(buffer)-1) </para>
      </blockquote>
      <para>Ok, so the error is very helpful with even telling us what is a bad use of strncat and
        what a good use of it would look like. For completeness, let’s see what the compiler itself
        reports on this error:</para>
      <blockquote>
        <para>In function ‘strncat’,</para>
        <para> inlined from ‘gtkui_icmp_redir’ at ec_gtk_mitm.c:173:14:</para>
        <para> /usr/include/bits/string3.h:152:3: warning: call to __builtin___strncat_chk might
          overflow destination buffer [enabled by default] </para>
      </blockquote>
      <para>Let’s see what <emphasis role="bold">
        <ulink url="http://linux.die.net/man/3/strncat">man 3 strncat</ulink>
      </emphasis> tells us about the usage of strncat.</para>
      <blockquote>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Synopsis</emphasis></para>
        <para>#include char *strcat(char *dest, const char *src); char *strncat(char *dest, const
          char *src, size_t n);</para>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Description</emphasis></para>
        <para> The strcat() function appends the src string to the dest string overwriting the ‘\0′
          character at the end of dest, and then adds a terminating ‘\0′ character. The strings may
          not overlap, and the dest string must have enough space for the result.</para>
        <para>The strncat() function is similar, except that it will use at most n characters from
          src. Since the result is always terminated with ‘\0′, at most n+1 characters are written.
        </para>
      </blockquote>
      <para>The package suggested by Malcolm contains this code (snipped
        together):<screen>#define PARAMS_LEN 50 static char params[PARAMS_LEN]; 
strncat(params, gtk_entry_get_text(GTK_ENTRY(entry1)), PARAMS_LEN); 
strncat(params, "/", PARAMS_LEN); 
strncat(params, gtk_entry_get_text(GTK_ENTRY(entry2)), PARAMS_LEN);</screen></para>
      <para>This is not an uncommon error at all. We create a buffer, 50 chars long, we concatenate
        text into the buffer and specify a max length of PARAMS_LEN. What is not taken into account
        here is that the string in params is getting longer, and we do not account for this when
        adding text to it. And additionally the leading \0 is ignored as well.</para>
      <para>Translating the BRP Result’s suggestion stating how we should write this code, we will
        result in
        this:<screen>#define PARAMS_LEN 50 static char params[PARAMS_LEN]; 
strncat(params, gtk_entry_get_text(GTK_ENTRY(entry1)), sizeof(params)-strlen(params)-1); 
strncat(params, "/", sizeof(params)-strlen(params)-1); 
strncat(params, gtk_entry_get_text(GTK_ENTRY(entry2)), sizeof(params)-strlen(params)-1);</screen></para>
      <para>sizeof(params) is what we had there before, and equals to PARAMS_LEN. But we now also
        take into account that we already do have some characters stored in params and also account
        for a trailing NULL byte.</para>
      <para>And with this simple fix, the error vanished.</para>
      <!--($ Id: 30.5.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For System Administrators</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.phocean.net/2011/05/28/headphones-not-muting-the-speakers-with-a-gigabyte-motherboard.html">Jean-Christophe Baptiste: Headphones not muting the speakers with a Gigabyte motherboard</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>It had been months since I had an weired issue with the embedded audio controller of my
        Gigabyte motherboard.</para>
      <para>Plugin the headphones on the front panel of my box didn’t mute the output to the
        speakers, which nullified the purpose of having headphones.</para>
      <para>I long thought that it was some hardware issue that I would have to sort some day by
        opening the box and checking the connections.</para>
      <para>Yesterday, I decided to solve it for good and I started to google… and found out that it
        was a pure software issue!</para>
      <para>The culprit sounded to be some unproper settings of the ALSA module and this <ulink url="https://help.ubuntu.com/community/HdaIntelSoundHowto">Ubuntu guide</ulink> just saved
        me.</para>
      <para>I carefully followed the steps and it appeared that for my <ulink url="http://www.gigabyte.com/products/product-page.aspx?pid=3258">Gigabyte GA-790FXTA-UD5</ulink>, it was necessaryýto this line:</para>
      <programlisting>add options snd-hda-intel model=3stack-hp</programlisting>
      <para>to</para>
      <programlisting>/etc/modprobe.d/alsa-base.conf</programlisting>
      <para>Ok, it did not go so smoothly as I picked out randomly models from the list until I find
        the right one (I had no idea of what was embbeded on my board). I hope this may help, as I
        have quite a lot of people with similar issues with all kinds of vendors.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Editors Note:</emphasis>openSUSE Users should use <emphasis
          role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">/etc/modprobe.d/50-sound.conf</emphasis></emphasis>
        instead.</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 4.6.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
