<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/02/26/opensuse-11-4-rc2-steps-out/">Helen South: openSUSE 11.4 RC2 Steps Out</ulink>
    </title>
    <note>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is Licensed under the <ulink
            url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/fdl.txt">GNU Free Documentation
          License.</ulink></emphasis></para>
    </note>
    <para>With red carpets rolling out in Hollywood, you’d expect some applause for the openSUSE 11.4 RC2 release, which has now gone live ahead of 11.4 proper. But with much of 
      the hard work going in behind the scenes, this superb release candidate isn’t getting the fanfare it deserves. The recent Bug Squashing day saw 132 bugs updated so few 
      serious issues remain. Improvements in the ‘backend’ work includes some tweaks to Wifi supplicant and drivers, and a host of small fixes across the distribution which enhance 
      stability and performance. The addition of MediaCurl backend with zsync support to libzypp iut is already being noticed. openSUSE user and forum member Pier Andreit comments 
      that “YaST install/remove software is a thunderbolt!”</para>
    <para>The transition from OpenOffice.org to LibreOffice still has a few minor documentation blips but more importantly, users should be cautious. The raft of new functionality 
      has created a few specific issues, such as loss of data in tables. Though not quite ready for the production environment, user feedback is critical for smoothing performance 
      and reliability. </para>
    <para>KDE SC 4.6 is also running beautifully though 32 BIT nVidia users may have a bug.</para>
    <para>If you’d like to help add the final touches of celebrity glam prior to the ‘big event’ of 11.4 release, <ulink 
      url="http://download.opensuse.org/distribution/11.4-RC2/iso/">download it here</ulink> and check out the <ulink 
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Most_annoying_bugs_11.4_dev#openSUSE_11.4_RC2">most annoying bugs</ulink>.</para>    
    <!-- ($ ld: 27.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/02/build-service-team-releases-new-versions-fixing-security-problems/">News Team: Build Service team releases new versions fixing security problems</ulink></title>
    <note>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is Licensed under the <ulink url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/fdl.txt">GNU Free Documentation
      License.</ulink></emphasis></para>
    </note>
      <para>The openSUSE Build Service team has released verison 2.0.8 and 2.1.6. of OBS. Both versions are fixing a critical security leak which can be miss-used to modify 
        projects or packages without having write permission there. We highly recommend to update your instance of OBS as soon as possible to these new versions. Version 1.7 is 
        not affected by this issue.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="italic">Thanks to Marcus Hüwe for reporting this issue.</emphasis></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Details on OBS 2.1.6</emphasis></para>
    <para>OBS 2.1.6 is also fixing security issues in LDAP mode and a possible crossite scripting attack vector on the login screen (full XSS protection in all webui interfaces 
      will be part of OBS 2.3). <emphasis role="italic">Thanks to Dean Pierce from Intel for discussing these issues and possible solutions with us.</emphasis></para>
    <para>Version 2.1.6 can be downloaded as usual from gitorious, openSUSE:Tools (or openSUSE:Tool:2.0 for version 2.0.8) project repositories or as <ulink 
      url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Build_Service_Appliance">appliance for testing and production systems</ulink>.</para>
    <para>OBS 2.1.6 contains several further changes, please read the release notes below.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">openSUSE Build Service 2.1.6</emphasis></para>
    <para>Updaters from any OBS 2.1 release can just upgrade the packages and restart all services. Updaters from former releases should read the README.UPDATERS file.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Security fixes</emphasis></para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>api: fix security leak which allowed to modify packages or projects without write access (CVE-2011-0466)</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>api: change password in LDAP mode was possible for foreign user (bnc #648982)</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>webui: Fix possible XSS attack vectors in login page (bnc #669909, CVE-2011-0462)</para></listitem>      
    </itemizedlist>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Feature backports</emphasis></para>
    <para>None</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Changes</emphasis></para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>openSUSE 11.4 and Debian 6.0 got added as default target.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>adding reviewers or changing the review state is only allowed for requests which are in review state now.</para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Bugfixes</emphasis></para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>webui: Fix link to moved OBS web forums</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>webui: Fix adding of repositories from remote projects in advanced repository interface</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>api and webui: Do not use (and fail with) rails 3 environment</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>api: allow admins to raise “sourceaccess” permissions on existing projects or packages</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>api: do not allow to create packages with invalid chars via branch command</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>api: do not fail on “mbranch” when a package gets found directly and indirectly via project link</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>backend: Allow browsing of repositories of remote projects (fixes advanced webui view for adding repos)</para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <!-- ($ ld: 3.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/02/opensuse-11-4-and-kde-2/">News Team: openSUSE 11.4 and KDE</ulink></title>
    <note>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is Licensed under the <ulink url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/fdl.txt">GNU Free Documentation
        License.</ulink></emphasis></para>
    </note>
    <para>KDE fans must definitely watch out for openSUSE 11.4, which will be the first major Linux distribution to feature <ulink url="http://www.kde.org/announcements/4.6/"
      >KDE’s Plasma Workspaces, Applications and Development Platform version 4.6</ulink>. This trio of releases by the KDE community brings much better performance as well as 
      many usability and feature improvements all over the place. Upgraders will feel a double dose of KDE goodness, as openSUSE 11.4 brings two major releases’ improvements 
      over the KDE 4.4 shipped with openSUSE 11.3.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/snapshot22-300x187.png"/>
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">On the Desktop or on your Netbook</emphasis></para>
    <para>The Plasma Desktop Workspace, which is openSUSE’s default graphical desktop, introduces several new features. First up is a more intuitive and smarter power management 
      UI and a new Bluetooth stack which makes it easier to share files or use features of other Bluetooth devices such as headsets and mice . Plasma also introduces many 
      improvements to the innovative ‘Activities’ management. Activities allow users to associate applications with tasks which can be saved, stopped and resumed at any time.</para>
    <para>For those with less screen estate to spend, the Plasma Netbook Workspace offers an experience more optimized for small screens. Plasma Netbook shows all your 
      applications full-screen with a automatically hiding panel on the top of the screen offering a way to see all your windows as well as closing the current one, starting new 
      applications and seeing the status of your battery or wifi connection. Plasma Netbook 4.6 has become more touch-friendly and much faster than the previous versions. Read 
      more about these and other new Plasma Workspace features <ulink url="http://www.kde.org/announcements/4.6/plasma.php">in the KDE Plasma 4.6 announcement</ulink>.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">KDE Applications</emphasis></para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/digikam-picasaweb-e1299039264422-150x150.png"/>
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <para>The KDE Applications 4.6 release introduces improvements like a new faceted search as well as non-indexed files search and support for git repositories in Dolphin, the 
      file manager; social sharing of photos to sites like Flickr, Facebook and Picasaweb are now easy to reach from Gwenview, Digikam and KSnapshot.  Developers will appreciate 
      Kate’s new plugins for working with SQL and with GDB.</para>
    <para>KDE Games 4.6 marks the return of Klickety, also replacing KSame. Thanks to the KGameRenderer framework, KDE games take on a more consistent look and feel and perform 
    better. Palapeli makes creating jigsaw puzzles out of your own images easier and Kajongg became easier and smarter.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/kdegames-300x187.png"/>
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <para>KDE PIM 4.6 is available in openSUSE as experimental feature. While openSUSE 11.4 ships with the more stable and more dependable KDE Kontact Suite 4.4.10, the latest 
      and still experimental Akonadi based Kontact 4.6 is available for installation using <ulink 
        url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/KDE:/Unstable:/SC:/kdepim46/KDE_Distro_Factory_openSUSE_11.4/">this repository</ulink>.</para>
    <para>openSUSE 11.4 also ships with many KDE applications not part of the regular KDE Software Compilation releases. This includes the latest KOffice, Amarok and many more. 
    Some highlights include:</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/scribus-e1299039158288-150x150.png"/>
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>Painting application Krita 2.3 has been designated by its developers as the first end-user ready version since 1.6. Their standards are high and they have 
        been working with a variety of artist to make sure 2.3 is indeed fulfilling the needs of graphics ninjas. Krita 2.3 provides many new features, ranging from brush 
        settings presets to canvas rotation, from warp transform to a new color selector — and of course many new brush engines. But the many improvements to stability, 
        usability and especially performance probably make the biggest difference in everyday usage.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Amarok 2.4.0 has a much faster collection scanner and can write statistics and covers directly to your audio files. Speaking of tags, there’s a new feature 
        to work along with the rewritten collection scanner: Integration with the MusicBrainz music library to update your songs with accurate information. Having a well 
        organized collection is easier than ever, now that you can select what you want tagged and do it with two clicks. Other notable features are improved iPod support (the 
        Touch 3G should work great now), better transcoding support, Guitar and Bass tab information fetching, OPML export for Podcast subscriptions, an upcoming event applet 
        and finally this release introduces support for UPnP.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>KOffice 2.3.1 brings improved performance, stability and usability in all applications. In the feature department, there is a new slide sorter view and a 
        shape animations tool for KPresenter. OpenDocument support (especially text rendering) has been improved in all KOffice applications, as well as support for reading 
        Microsoft file formats (doc, xls, ppt, docx, xlsx, pptx). KPlato and Kexi introduce a new report engine.</para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">For developers</emphasis></para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/snapshot40-150x150.png"/>
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <para>openSUSE prides itself on being a prominent development platform for KDE applications and again offers the latest KDE Platform libraries and tools in openSUSE 11.4. 
      Improvements brought by KDE Platform 4.6 include QML support in the Plasma framework, improvements to Nepomuk and a “Mobile Build Target” for those who want to build a 
      thinner version of the KDE libraries.</para>
    <para>The toolkit KDE develops its applications and framework upon is Qt, a Nokia product. openSUSE ships the latest Qt 4.7.1 which introduces Qt Quick, the Qt UI Creation 
      Kit. that enables the creation of dynamic user interfaces, easier and more effective than possible with existing UI technologies. With the help of IDE’s like Qt Creator 
      and the powerful build tools like OBS openSUSE offers the best possible Linux software development environment in the Free Software world.</para>
    <para>Conclusion</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/snapshot27-300x187.png"/>
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <para>With the latest KDE Plasma Netbook and Desktop Workspaces and the many updated KDE applications as well as the latest development tools and libraries, openSUSE 11.4 
      will offer a stellar experience for desktop users. openSUSE is the home of many KDE developers and contributors, which shows in the polished KDE products and the latest 
      KDE updates which we make available for all supported openSUSE releases. Of course openSUSE ships the latest GNOME, XFCE and LXDE for those who prefer other desktops and 
      we ship many different applications, all of which work perfectly well with the Plasma Workspaces as well as other desktops. Stay tuned for an article about one of those 
      applications, LibreOffice, coming soon!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="italic">Article contributed by Manu Gupta.</emphasis></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 3.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>News Team: GNOME on openSUSE 11.4</title>
    <note>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is Licensed under the <ulink url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/fdl.txt">GNU Free Documentation
        License.</ulink></emphasis></para>
    </note>
    <para>The upcoming new release of openSUSE 11.4 will be shipped with the latest and greatest <ulink url="http://library.gnome.org/misc/release-notes/2.32/">GNOME 2.32</ulink>
      . GNOME 2.32 is the last release in the GNOME 2.x series and has a number of final refinements to offer openSUSE users a stable base for the next 8 months. At the same 
      time, the openSUSE GNOME team is already busy preparing for <ulink url="http://www.gnome3.org/">GNOME 3</ulink>. A preview of GNOME 3 and the new GNOME Shell will be 
      available in openSUSE 11.4.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/evince-300x240.png"/>
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Features and improvements in 2.32</emphasis></para>
    <para>There have been several small updates to <ulink url="http://live.gnome.org/Mousetweaks/Home">Mousetweaks</ulink>, which makes it easier to use a mouse for those users 
      who may have limited mobility. It now has updated documentation including an updated manual and man pages so users can now see all the options they have and look up how 
      things are supposed to work.</para>
    <para>The <ulink url="http://projects.gnome.org/evince/">Evince</ulink> document viewer has improved accessibility support through the use of the AtkText interface, which 
      allows <ulink url="http://live.gnome.org/Orca">Orca</ulink>, the GNOME screen reader, to read documents in Evince. The maximum zoom level has also been increased when 
      viewing a document. Annotation support has been improved and you can now add annotations from the side panel, change the default properties including author, color, 
      transparency and more. Evince now supports “SyncTeX” which enables synchronization between a TeX source file and the resulting PDF (or DVI) output.</para>
    <para><ulink url="http://live.gnome.org/Empathy">Empathy</ulink>, the universal instant messaging client, now allows you to group a contact’s information together using 
      “metacontacts.” For example, if one of your contacts uses multiple instant messaging accounts you can now link the different services together under one name for your 
      contact. Empathy has also added live contact search, which allows you to type into the contact list to quickly find somebody. The new and improved Empathy in GNOME 2.32 
      also adds chat logging support and the ability to import security certificates.</para>
    <para><ulink url="http://projects.gnome.org/eog/">Eye of GNOME</ulink>, <ulink url="http://www.gnome.org/projects/totem/">Totem</ulink> and <ulink url="http://projects.gnome.org/gst/"
      >GNOME System Tools</ulink> all come up with minor tweaks like enhancing image contrast, automatically deinterlacing interlaced videos and setting up permissions for home 
      directories. For openSUSE’s vast international audience, this latest release of GNOME 2 will support over 50 languages.</para>
    <para>Outside of the official GNOME release, openSUSE 11.4 will bundle a number of great third-party GNOME applications including Banshee, GIMP, AbiWord and more! 
    Some of the major highlights include:</para>
    <para><ulink url="http://www.yorba.org/shotwell/">Shotwell</ulink> 0.8.1 is included openSUSE 11.4 bringing a number of major new features with it such as video support for 
      all major fileformats, video uploading to YouTube, Facebook and Flickr, monitoring the library directory and writing metadata behind the scenes to give users a more 
      responsive interface.</para>
    <para>Media player <ulink url="http://projects.gnome.org/rhythmbox/">Rhythmbox</ulink> 0.13.3 “Country Rain” is available in openSUSE 11.4. This will most likely be the last 
      stable release before the move to GNOME 3 and introduces several new features and bugfixes. Most prominent are the reimplementation of source lists, updated notifications, 
      MPRIS and MediaServer2 support and a new context pane tab showing links to various websites.</para>
    <para>The popular media player <ulink url="http://banshee.fm/">Banshee</ulink> is updated to 1.8 in this release of openSUSE 11.4. Some highlights of this release are: a “Now
      Playing” simplified mode, play queue shuffle action, improved cover art downloading, MusicBrainz ID support and improved Last.fm integration. Banshee 12.8 also includes 
      several developer features like an improved WebBrowser API for WebKit browsers and DBus API additions. Finally, device support has been greatly improved! Among others, 
      Banshee now works better with the Droid X, Galaxy Portal, Xperia X10, Maemo and MTP capable devices in general.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">For developers!</emphasis></para>
    <para>openSUSE 11.4 has a lot to offer GNOME developers. Starting GNOME development is a matter of a few simple clicks in YaST, while GLib 2.26 now includes support for 
      GSettings, the replacement for GConf as well as GDBus. Anjuta users can now enjoy full support for Vala and Python projects while MonoDevelop users get a myriad of new 
      features and improvements from <ulink url="http://monodevelop.com/Download/MonoDevelop_2.4_Released">MonoDevelop 2.4</ulink>. And good news for those anxious to adapt 
      their applications to GTK3 or write new applications with this latest GNOME framework: openSUSE 11.4 is the first major linux distribution to ship <ulink 
        url="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.comp.gnome.announce/9389">GTK 3.0</ulink> so developers, Start Your IDE’s!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Getting GNOME 3</emphasis></para>
    <para>For those of us anxious to try out GNOME 3 and GNOME Shell, Vincent Untz, openSUSE GNOME packager and until recently GNOME release manager has the following to say:</para>
    <para><quote>You can test a beta version of GNOME Shell, which will be a core part of GNOME 3. Note that GNOME Shell has already moved a lot since the version we include in 11.4.</quote></para>
    <para>There is also a GNOME 3 live USB test image available from another openSUSE GNOME contributor, get it from <ulink url="http://blog.crozat.net/2011/01/gnome-3-live-cd-usb-test-image.html">fcrozat’s home repo</ulink>. Once openSUSE 11.4 is out, openSUSE users can easily be up to date with GNOME development using the GNOME OBS repositories.</para>
    <para>Conclusion</para>
    <para>In short, openSUSE 11.4 will offer a stellar experience for desktop users and developers alike. If the GNOME desktop isn’t quite your cup of tea, you’re in luck! openSUSE 11.4 will ship with updates to KDE, LXDE and XFCE which we’ll cover in another article. Stay tuned!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Article contributed by Manu Gupta</emphasis></para>
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
