<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <important>
    <para>The Articles inside this Section are in full. If you are already knowing the stuff in
      news.opensuse.org, then you can skip this section through using the TOC.</para>
  </important>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/27/opensuse-strategy-voting-close-to-the-finish-line/"
        >openSUSE strategy voting close to the finish line!</ulink></title>
    <para>As we wrote <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/07/time-to-vote-on-the-opensuse-strategy/">three weeks
        ago</ulink>, June 30th is the deadline for <ulink url="http://bit.ly/kZaAC2">voting for the
        openSUSE Strategy</ulink>!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Relevance</emphasis></para>
    <para>2 years ago the subject came up at the openSUSE conference: <emphasis role="italic">what
        do we want</emphasis>? That is not a simple question. We are a large community with
      wide-ranging diverse backgrounds, goals and interests.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Having a coherent answer matters</emphasis>: it shows potential new
      contributors what they can (although not limited) contribute to; it helps us make decisions.
      Do we focus on fancy web stuff? Do we go for a stable or more experimental product? Do we
      simplify at all costs or cater to more advanced users? These and more are questions brought up
      in our strategy discussion.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Discussion</emphasis></para>
    <para>It took a long time – we are an open community and as such, strategic discussions take
      time. However, we went through the effort. Lots of input came from a variety of people – each
      iteration had sometimes over a hundred comments. You can view some of the  <ulink
        url="https://lite.co-ment.com/text/lNPCgzeGHdV/history/">although you should notice that
        co-ment is just one of the ways we collected feedback (others being the mailing lists, IRC,
        forums and more)</ulink>.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Serious</emphasis></para>
    <para>While the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Strategy">current proposal</ulink>
      is not meant to be limiting new directions or will be forever set in stone, it is meant to
      provide clarity to our community for the time being. So we do want it to be taken seriously.
      We develop major software products promoting open source and the use of Linux world wide.
      We’re a major Linux distribution, the second largest by most metrics. We provide a packaging
      build service that is used by distributions more than just openSUSE. We have an obligation to
      deliver a consistent, quality product to our users. And to provide an open and fun place to be
      around for contributors. We can’t satisfy every need to the fullest, but what we can do is
      make clear what we are trying to do here.</para>
    <para>Providing that clarity to our users and contributors through this strategy is a major step
      towards our future. So, we need our membership to vote. To make your voice heard and to know
      if it truly has the support it needs.</para>
    <para>So, if you’re an openSUSE Member, go,<ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Strategy"
        >read the document one more time</ulink> andý<ulink url="http://bit.ly/kZaAC2">cast your
        vote</ulink>!</para>
    <!--($ ld: 28.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/22/opensuse-releases-milestone-2/">openSUSE
        releases milestone 2</ulink></title>
    <para><inlinegraphic
        fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/geeko-cast-my-vote.png"
        width="20%"/></para>
    <para>About 3 weeks after the <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/01/first-step-towards-12-1-with-milestone-1/">first
        milestone for openSUSE 12.1</ulink>, today the second milestone has been made available.
      Following the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Roadmap">Roadmap</ulink>, this is
      the second of 6 milestone until the openSUSE 12.1 release in November.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Milestones</emphasis></para>
    <para>openSUSE is developed in a repository called <ulink
        url="http://opensuse.org/Portal:Factory">Factory</ulink>. Packages flow from the <ulink
        url="http://nl.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Build_Service_Collaboration#Devel_Project_maintainer.27s_workflow"
        >devel projects</ulink> into Factory upon OK from the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Release_team">release team</ulink> following the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Factory_development_model">Factory Development
        Model</ulink>. During the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Roadmap">development
        cycle</ulink> (<ulink url="http://www.suse.de/%7Ecoolo/opensuse_12.1/">more detailed
        model</ulink>) periodic releases are made available for testing – these are the milestones.
      Six of them become available. After some several freezes go into effect, the component freeze
      just before the fourth milestone for instance. And about a couple of weeks after the last
      milestone the first of two Release Candidates is made ready for testing. The final openSUSE
      12.1 release is expected on November 11th.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Progress since the previous milestone</emphasis></para>
    <para>The first milestone had a huge number of changes and improvements on top of the latest
      openSUSE release. Again, many packages have been updated. You can check the latest package
      versions on <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Factory_versions">this page</ulink>.
      What are the major changes?</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Firefox 5 RC</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Horde4 packages (php5-pear-horde)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>“The Board”</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>rawstudio</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>llvm/clang 3.0 snapshot</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>many smaller updates to KDE and GNOME applications and desktops</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>Also nspluginwrapper is now updated which will allow a more stable Flash plugin on 64bit
      platforms. With this change you can now watch two flash videos at the same time. And over 100
      new packages have been added, including extensions for Banshee, some small tools like <ulink
        url="http://software.opensuse.org/search?q=dds2tar">DDS2tar</ulink> and <ulink
        url="http://brainfuck.tk/">brainfuck interpreter</ulink>, Cdecl (turns C/C++ gibberish into
      English), cint (small C/C++ interpreter) and a number of other devel and language
      tools.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">systemd</emphasis></para>
    <para>On the openSUSE <ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-project/">project</ulink>
      and <ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-factory/">factory</ulink> mailing lists a
      discussion is taking place centered around the new systemd init system. After <ulink
        url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-factory/2011-06/msg00210.html">the introduction of
        the road to systemd for openSUSE 12.1</ulink> by <ulink
        url="http://blog.crozat.net/2011/06/road-to-systemd-for-opensuse-121.html">Frederic
        Crozat</ulink>, issues, complaints and limitations of systemd are being discussed and
      dissected. Changing an init system is an invasive change and systemd has ambitions beyond just
      replacing sysV not everyone always agrees with. Work will be needed to ensure a stable and
      usable init system for 12.1 and the team welcomes help and bugreports!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Helping out easier than ever!</emphasis></para>
    <para>As expected from a development release, there is still a lot of work to do, so your input
      at this early stage will be a huge help in making the final release into the beautifully
      polished work that we aim for. openSUSE 12.1 Milestone 2 has a <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Most_annoying_bugs_12.1_dev">list of most annoying bugs
        here</ulink>, please add issues you find and help fix them. As Will Stephenson <ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/05/16/have-you-burped-yet-today/">recently
        blogged</ulink>, fixing an issue is a matter of <emphasis role="bold">BURP</emphasis>ing on
        <ulink url="http://build.opensuse.org">build.opensuse.org</ulink>! Find a how-to <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Build_Service_Collaboration#Example_with_web_interface"
        >here</ulink>.</para>
    <para>So go and see for yourself what the next version of openSUSE has in store for you at our
        <ulink url="http://software.opensuse.org/developer">download center</ulink>.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 23.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
