<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="community">
  <title>In the Community</title>
  <!--Put here things relevant to the openSUSE community maybe from * People of openSUSE or elections, votings 1 - 2 posts-->
  <sect2>
    <title>Postings from the Community</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://omgsuse.com/content/day-one-scale9x">OMG! SUSE!: Day one at SCALE9x</ulink></title>
      <note>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is licensed under the <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">Creatice Commons
          Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License</ulink></emphasis>.</para>
      </note>
      <para>As I mentioned in my <ulink url="http://omgsuse.com/content/catch-me-scale">previous post</ulink>, I am at the Southern California Linux Expo in Los Angeles this weekend. What I failed to mention 
        in my previous post was <emphasis role="bold">massive showing</emphasis> from the openSUSE community at the exposition.</para>
      <para>Throughout the day the openSUSE team was <emphasis role="bold">extremeley</emphasis> busy introducing a myriad of different people to openSUSE and SUSE Studio at 
      the openSUSE booth.</para>
      <figure id="fig.team">
        <title>Parts of the openSUSE team at SCALE9x</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5292/5481281536_34b3d3100e_m.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>          
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>Outside of the expo show floor, the team <xref linkend="fig.team"/> was also running "<ulink url="http://www.socallinuxexpo.org/scale9x/special-events/opensuse-day"
        >openSUSE Day</ulink>", taking the opportunity to run a few classroom-styled events on topics like: using YaST, building packages with the <ulink 
          url="https://build.opensuse.org/">OBS</ulink> and using SUSE Studio like a pro.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">At the booth</emphasis></para>
      <para>I found myself manning the booth the majority of the day, giving me an opportunity to talk with plenty of folks about one of my favorite topics: openSUSE. Due the 
        large number of Geekos (openSUSE folk) at the conference and the <emphasis role="bold">giant</emphasis> beacon of green coming from the booth, interested people clustered 
        around the booth for most of the day asking <emphasis role="italic"></emphasis>plenty of questions.</para>
      <para>I wish I could say that everybody was there because they were genuinely curious about openSUSE, but that's not entirely true. As soon as word spread about the cute 
        <ulink url="http://www.flickr.com/photos/omgsuse/5477367803/in/set-72157626140989222/">Tux and Geeko plushes</ulink> that Novell had provided the team, people started 
        dropping by asking how they could get their hands on those adorable little animals.</para>
      <para>Overall, the reactions and responses to openSUSE I got from Linux users were very positive. It <emphasis role="italic">seems</emphasis> that lots of folks out there 
        in the Linux world are apprehensive about the direction Ubuntu is heading in current, and are starting to explore other options for easy-to-use and solid distros like 
        openSUSE. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 27.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://nowwhatthe.blogspot.com/2011/03/opensuse-marketing-meeting-in-los.html">Jos Poortvliet: openSUSE Marketing Meeting in Los Angeles</ulink></title>
      <note>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is licensed under the <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">Creatice Commons
          Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License</ulink></emphasis>.</para>
      </note>
      <para>Finally, after well over a week of telling myself I should blog I have found some time. Sleep is overrated and I can't actually get any while flying anyway so let me 
      tell you why I had to blog.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Marketing Meeting and SCALE</emphasis></para>
      <para>Last week the openSUSE Marketing team had their first dedicated marketing meeting in Los Angeles. This was followed by the whole bunch attending SCALE. SCALE is 
      probably the most prominent Free Software conference in the USA and we made a big splash there so that was really cool!</para>
      <para>At the meeting we had lots of fun of course. We had an incredible team from all over the world - Australia (Helen), Greece (Kostas), Swiss (Bruno), Brazil (Izabel 
        and Carlos), USA (Chuck, Tony and Bryen) and myself (a Dutchie). Stephen and Tyler (from OMGSUSE fame) joined us for SCALE. And I should mention that <ulink 
          url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/14/alan-clark-new-opensuse-board-chairman/">Alan Clark</ulink> was there as well for the full week. Unfortunately, some we hoped 
        would be there could not make it - including James, who was ill, and Manu Gupta from India who had Exams interfere with his trip. Luckily both of them as well as others 
        joined us via IRC.</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/_WMsbUl3phhU/TXAJSwZ-_pI/AAAAAAAABR8/q_zmipJQ3c4/s288/working%20hard.jpg"/>
        </imageobject>        
      </mediaobject>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Results</emphasis></para>
      <para>So what has the team been up to? First of all, getting to know each other. Most of us never ever met in real life. And we've got a great team, really cool! During 
        the week we worked, initially quite organized (we set up an agenda, split in teams and worked on the tasks) later on in a more 'organic' fashion with constantly changing 
        teams and tasks. We did a variety of things - work on marketing materials, preparation of the 11.4 release, GSOC (thanks, Izabel &amp; Kostas), a bit for the openSUSE 
        Conference and some writing. And as usual we didn't get 10% done of what we wanted to do - yet I'm very happy with the results. For our 11.4 release we'll have a lovely 
        Feature Guide, showing our users what's new in this release. Based on the Feature guide you can expect some articles to be released before and after the release, as well 
        as other marketing materials. We've prepared a bunch of presentations on a variety of subjects (Tony, thanks for your work on Tumbleweed!) and improved some wiki pages 
        with information for our ambassadors (Kostas!!!!). And a series of posters was made - a really *awesome* series of posters! Clearly, putting Carlos &amp; Helen in one 
        room leads to some cool stuff!</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/_WMsbUl3phhU/TXAGkzJpx_I/AAAAAAAABRY/Xm8gqVtf4fQ/s288/having%20fun.jpg"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>And we learned a lot from each other - especially Bruno and Tony who were the more technical among us were answering questions a lot of the time. During the 
        evenings - well, we usually kept working, but we also had a few beers and cigarettes outside the conference room. Usually people stayed around until 2-3, I usually went 
        to bed early 'cuz I had to open it up which I did around 8. Food we got from a supermarket (Novell paid) so we always had fresh sandwiches with lots of stuff to put on 
        them. That was really good - the first day we had lunch at Denny's but nobody really liked that much so the other three days we just made our own food...</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/_WMsbUl3phhU/TXAGfIsUBkI/AAAAAAAABRU/-EWaq_HquGk/s288/eating.jpg"/>
        </imageobject>        
      </mediaobject>
      <para>Friday we enjoyed a day off - at least, most of the day. A bunch of us went 'tourist' and saw the Hollywood sign, the famous stars and of course LA traffic, traffic 
      and traffic...</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/_WMsbUl3phhU/TXAGZ5ieFmI/AAAAAAAABRQ/a1rz6_QrO8Q/s288/being%20tourists.jpg"/>
        </imageobject>        
      </mediaobject>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">And now...</emphasis></para>
      <para>Now I have some more pics to upload and some people to kick about the reports they have to write. And I have to thank Bryen again and again for the organization 
      of this meeting, as well as Novell for paying for it! SCALE deserves a blog of its own, which I'll do tomorrow or Saturday.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 4.3.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <!--
    <sect2>
    <title>People of openSUSE</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>This Week: xyz</title>
      <para>Good Guy. Glows in the night.</para>
    </blockquote>
    </sect2> -->
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Welcome new openSUSE Members</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/fcrozat">Frederic Crozat (fcrozat)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Very active in the openSUSE GNOME Team and Bugzilla.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/helen-au">Helen South
        (helen-au)</ulink></title>
      <para>Helen works inside Marketing and the Editor Team of news.opensuse.org.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/dominian">Matt Hayes
        (dominian)</ulink></title>
      <para>Active in Bugzilla, Wiki and Mailinglists.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/tsotsos">Angelos Tzotsos
        (tsotsos)</ulink></title>
      <para>Active inside the Greek Community and Marketing.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/bekun">Kai-Uwe Behrmann
        (bekun)</ulink></title>
      <para>Kai-Uwe serves as Speaker, Boothman and Developer for the openSUSE Project.</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Events &amp; Meetings</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Past</title>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink
            url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/02/15/opensuse-testing-team-bug-killing-session/"
            >February 20, 2011 : openSUSE Testing Team: Bug killing session</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/03/24/opensuse-board-meeting/">February 23,
            2011 : Board Meeting</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/01/20/testing-core-team-meeting/">February
            28, 2011 : Testing Core Team Meeting</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Upcoming</title>
      <listitem>
<para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/02/09/opensuse-project-meetings/">March 09, 2011 : Project Meeting</ulink></para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/02/09/opensuse-project-meetings/">March 23, 2011 : Project Meeting</ulink></para>
</listitem>

    </itemizedlist>
    <!-- ($ ld: 04.03.11 th $) -->
    <para>You can find more informations on other events at: <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/category/events/">openSUSE News/Events</ulink>. - <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Ambassadors_events">Local Events</ulink></para>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>openSUSE for your Ears</title>
    <para>The openSUSE Weekly News are available as livestream or podcast in German. You can hear it
      or download it on <ulink url="http://blog.radiotux.de/podcast">Radiotux</ulink>. </para>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>From Ambassadors</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://opensuseambassadors.blogspot.com/2011/02/opensuse-installed-on-scouts-computers.html">Greek openSUSE Ambassadors: openSUSE installed on Scouts Computers</ulink>
      </title>
      <note>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is licensed under the <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">Creatice Commons
          Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License</ulink></emphasis>.</para>
      </note>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://www.sep.org.gr/sites/all/themes/sep_zen/images/logo.png"/>
        </imageobject>        
      </mediaobject>
      <para>Greek openSUSE community in association with <ulink url="http://greeklug.gr/index.php?lang=en">GreekLUG</ulink>, helped 13th Scout Team of Thessaloniki, to upgrade 
        the hardware and install openSUSE on 3 computers. Unfortunately one computer was broken broke due to hardware malfunction, but Efstathios Iosifidis found another one and 
        replace it.</para>
      <para>Those 3 computers are very old. One of them comes with Gnome (Pentium 4 with 1GB RAM) and the other 2 with LXDE (Pentium 3 with 256MB RAM or less) but both are very 
      slow. Unfortunately they didn't have Internet installed yet, since this would be a good task for them.</para>
      <para>Kids already started to check the graphical interface and of course check some games (see the pictures).</para>
      <para>Scout organization based on volunteer work of people who want to pass some values to kids. We, as Greek Community, hope that the kids will have a lot of fun with 
      openSUSE and maybe in the future someone can provide them with better hardware so they can learn more about the futures of openSUSE. </para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://dl.dropbox.com/u/20413076/opensuse/scouts/computers/2_thumb.jpg"/>
        </imageobject>        
      </mediaobject>
      <!-- ($ ld: 27.02.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Communication</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/">The Mailinglists</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org">The openSUSE Forums</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Contributors</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://users.opensuse.org">The User Directory</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
