<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="community">
  <title>In the Community</title>
  <!--Put here things relevant to the openSUSE community maybe from * People of openSUSE or elections, votings 1 - 2 posts-->
  <sect2>
    <title>Postings from the Community</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blip.tv/file/4726423">openSUSE TV: COMAR, Gökmen
        Göksel</ulink></title>
      <para>A new approach to system management COMAR is COnfiguration MAnageR of Pardus Linux,
        which is a DBus service that helps the installed software operate flawlessly. COMAR knows
        the tasks that can be provided by each application, together with the functionality they
        depend on and other information. Different applications may adapt themselves according to
        the presence and capability of their peers. </para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 7.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blip.tv/file/4726612">openSUSE TV: Using NixOS for declarative
          deployment and testing (Sander van der Burg)</ulink></title>
      <para>NixOS is a Linux distribution built on top of the Nix package manager, a purely
        functional package manager. In NixOS, a system configuration is built from a declarative
        specification capturing the complete system configuration. Moreover, because of the Nix
        heritage, a user can safely and efficiently install multiple configurations next to each
        other without interference. This allows users to perform atomic upgrades and rollbacks of a
        complete Linux distribution.In this talk we explain how we can use NixOS to manage a network
        of machines by using a declarative specification of a network of NixOS
        configurations.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 7.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blip.tv/file/4726978">openSUSE TV: Gentoo's RelEng and catalyst use
          (Jorge Manuel B. S. Vicetto)</ulink></title>
      <para>A short introduction to Gentoo's Release Engineering team and its current model to
        produce media to install Gentoo. An introduction to the the catalyst tool and a description
        of the current configuration to produce our official stages and isos, specifically the
        weekly autobuilds.A short demonstration of how to configure and use catalyst to create
        stages and isos on one's hardware.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 7.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blip.tv/file/4728026">openSUSE TV: Gentoo's Reform and Future
          (Petteri Räty, Jorge Manuel B. S. Vicetto)</ulink></title>
      <para>The purpose of this talk is to present the view of a few Gentoo Developers that are part
        of the Council, Foundation and Developer Relations about the future of Gentoo and its
        reform. We'd like to start a debate involving other Gentoo Developers and interested
        attendees about this.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 7.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blip.tv/file/4728567">openSUSE TV: Gentoo Q</ulink></title>
      <para>Do you have anything on your mind related to Gentoo?It can be technical, organizational
        etc. I will do my best to answer any question the time allows for and there should also be
        other Gentoo developers around if I am not able to.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 7.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blip.tv/file/4729040">openSUSE TV: Ada in Debian and other
          distributions (Ludovic Brenta, Miguel Telleria de Esteban)</ulink></title>
      <para>This talk will:briefly describe Ludovic's work maintaining the Ada part of GCC as part
        of the larger Debian-GCC team;describe the Debian Policy for Ada packages; why one is needed
        and why it is written the way it is;compare (in a constructive way, obviously) Debian with
        other distributions that also have good support for Ada, in particular Gentoo and FreeBSD,
        and with complementary third-party efforts such as the GNU Ada project on SourceForge[2] and
        MacAda[3] "GNAT for Macintosh";propose coordination between distributions on how to package
        Ada software.Followed by a live demonstration</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 7.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blip.tv/file/4729068">openSUSE TV: The difficulty of forking (Anne
          Nicolas, Michael Scherer)</ulink></title>
      <para>and why you should not do it, yet prepare for itForking a project is never an easy task
        both on social and technical level.Mageia, like Libreoffice, is a big project born from a
        fork, and faced several issues regarding community and infrastructure. The lessons learned
        from forking can be generalized to any software project.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 7.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blip.tv/file/4729150">openSUSE TV: Can we build a simple,
          cross-distribution installation framework? (Dieter Plaetinck)</ulink></title>
      <para>First, this talk will entail the philosophy behind the shellscript-based Arch Linux
        installation framework (AIF), as well as some implementation information and lessons
        learned. Second, I want to initiate a discussion on how multiple distributions could work
        together maintaining an installation framework following a "keep it simple" philosophy, and
        how feasible it would be to do so. In my experience, quite some necessities, issues and
        features are distribution-independent. Specific distributions could be supported with
        plugins or feature branches.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 7.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="openSUSE TV: How to be a good downstream">openSUSE TV: How to be a good
          downstream</ulink></title>
      <para>Taking a released tarball and packaging it for a distribution is a standard and well
        understood process for about every distribution package. But there's more to 'packaging than
        just tinkering with the source: Having good connections to 'upstream' makes life easier for
        both sides in the long run. Taking a released tarball and packaging it for a distribution is
        a standard and well understood process for about every distribution package. But there's
        more to 'packaging than just tinkering with the source: Having good connections to
        'upstream' makes life easier for both sides in the long run.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 7.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blip.tv/file/4729299">openSUSE TV: Sharing package description [and
          translations] between distros. (Dominique Dumont)</ulink></title>
      <para>This session proposes to share concrete ideas, gather requirements and wishes (and
        hopefully volunteers) towards an implementation to help collaboration between distros teams.
        (The ones that don't talk much together otherwise).The basic idea revolves around creating a
        central DB that would collect package description.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 7.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blip.tv/file/4729392">openSUSE TV: Swimming Upstream (Jared K.
          Smith)</ulink></title>
      <para>How Distributions Help Open Source Communities This talk will discuss the ways that
        distributions (such as Fedora) work collaboratively with upstream communities, and the value
        that distributions bring. It will also explore ways that distributions can improve their
        communication and collaboration with upstream projects.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 7.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blip.tv/file/4729446">openSUSE TV: Example of cross-distro
          collaboration: Application Installer (Vincent Untz)</ulink></title>
      <para>Nearly all distributions are slowly moving towards making it easier to deal with
        applications, and get information about those. However, many of us are working in our own
        corners: unfortunately, this is often what happens with many topics that would move faster
        if they were looked from a cross-distro perspective.A small team of people from various
        distributions will meet in January to discuss what can be done in a cross-distro way. This
        talk will present the conclusions from this meeting, and will come back on the experience of
        organizing work in a cross-distro way.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 7.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blip.tv/file/4729504">openSUSE TV: Distribution collaboration
          manifesto (Stefano Zacchiroli, Jared K. Smith, Jos Poortvliet)</ulink></title>
      <para>The FOSS distribution communities work toward very similar goals: each distribution aims
        at providing a coherent set of (Free) softwares to their users.A good deal of work (and
        patches!) can be shared across distributions and in part already is. The more we
        collaborate, among us and with our (common!) upstreams, the more we can improve Free
        Software as a whole. Sometimes, however, social obstacles get in the way of collaboration:
        volunteers don't like each other or each other distro; they might also easily get
        "religious" about the everlasting question "which is the best distro out
        there?".Understanding why we should collaborate across distros is the first needed step in
        improving how we collaborate.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 7.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blip.tv/file/4729511">openSUSE TV: HP and Community Linux
          distributions</ulink></title>
      <para>(no further description available)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 7.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blip.tv/file/4729527">openSUSE TV: Downstream packaging
          collaboration (Hans de Goede, Michal Hrušecký)</ulink></title>
      <para>patch sharing or start a new upstream?Most distributions contain packages where upstream
        is completely dead or very close to it, yet there still is a significant user group for the
        packages in question, be it directly or through other packages depending on them. But even
        when upstream is alive, packages often needs some additional patching.All distributions seem
        to end up carrying some custom distro grown patchset, with some patches being shared and
        other patches being unique per distro. Clearly not an ideal situation and one which most
        distributions try to avoid by feeding all necessary changes upstream and aiming for having
        packages which use the upstream provided code as is.Clearly the usual model of sharing code
        fixes / integration work done at the distribution level between distributions by pushing it
        upstream does not work for projects where there is no upstream. And even with upstream
        around, distributions sometimes needs to fix bugs in versions that upstream no longer care
        about or fix bugs that are not important/considered feature upstream and it may take a long
        time to get them fixed there. In the end we can't avoid all patching. But we can try to
        avoid duplicating the work by better sharing the results.The plan for this sessions is to
        give a short presentation sketching the problem, show two possible approaches to help
        solving this problem together with few generally helpful ideas. After presenting these
        hopefully somewhat structured discussion with the audience about this topic is
        planned.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 7.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blip.tv/file/4729541">openSUSE TV: Model Checking the Linux
          Kernel</ulink></title>
      <para>Linux Kernel evolves rapidly and, as every software, is subject to bugs.Some people are
        trying to find defects in the code by searching for known patterns and known misuse,
        documented either as part of the kernel API usage or after bugs being known. At Mandriva,
        and as foundation of my PhD subject, we want to explore another way which is well-known but
        complex: Model-Checking. Main goal of this talk will be to introduce the subject and present
        the state of the art around kernel code checking.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 7.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blip.tv/file/4729545">openSUSE TV: Who the bloody hell cares about
          Debian? (Stefano Zacchiroli)</ulink></title>
      <para>Debian has also several unique technical features, still unmatched by concurrent
        newfangled distributions (and more of those are coming with Debian Squeeze!).Even more
        importantly, Debian is unique in: (1) its independence from money, infrastructure, people
        power, and similar "features" that companies use to control the progress of free software
        distributions; (2) its culture of freedom and democracy, which are both at stake with
        company-driven decisions on the evolution of free software distributions.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 7.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blip.tv/file/4729654">openSUSE TV: ZYpp your distro (Dominik Heidler
          Duncan Mac-Vicar P.)</ulink></title>
      <para>ZYpp is an opensource project originated in the openSUSE distribution which groups the
        most advanced and fast dependency solver (satsolver), a package management library and a
        command line package management tool (zypper). Over the years ZYpp has matured to become one
        of openSUSE most appreciated features.This talk will show ZYpp's main features and work
        being done to have it running on other rpm-based distributions.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 7.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blip.tv/file/4730529">openSUSE TV: Hackweek 6 Finale - Andrew
          Fitzsimon</ulink></title>
      <para>openSUSE's Hackweek 6 is here - follow our hackers while they present their projects at
        the beginning of hackweek</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 7.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blip.tv/file/4730556">openSUSE TV: Hackweek 6 Finale - Dinar
          Valeev</ulink></title>
      <para>openSUSE's Hackweek 6 is here - follow our hackers while they present their projects at
        the beginning of hackweek</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 7.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blip.tv/file/4730579">openSUSE TV: Hackweek 6 Finale - Lukas
          Lipavsky</ulink></title>
      <para>openSUSE's Hackweek 6 is here - follow our hackers while they present their projects at
        the beginning of hackweek</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 7.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blip.tv/file/4730632">openSUSE TV: Hackweek 6 Finale - Andrew
          Fitzsimon</ulink></title>
      <para>openSUSE's Hackweek 6 is here - follow our hackers while they present their projects at
        the beginning of hackweek</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 7.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blip.tv/file/4730642">openSUSE TV: Hackweek 6 Finale - Michal
          Cihar</ulink></title>
      <para>openSUSE's Hackweek 6 is here - follow our hackers while they present their projects at
        the beginning of hackweek</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 7.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blip.tv/file/4730657">openSUSE TV: Hackweek 6 Finale - Michal
          Hrusecky</ulink></title>
      <para>openSUSE's Hackweek 6 is here - follow our hackers while they present their projects at
        the beginning of hackweek</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 7.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://hedgehogpainter.livejournal.com/11599.html">Katarina Machalkova: I
          survived FOSDEM 2011</ulink></title>
      <para>After some reports from other LibreOffice crowd members (<ulink
          url="http://luxate.blogspot.com/2011/02/fosdem-2011-summary.html">here</ulink> and <ulink
          url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/ItalosOOoBlog/~3/pJrk3wbKI9g/">here</ulink>), I'm
        adding mine to the heap: </para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Friday</emphasis>
      </para>
      <para>The fun has started at Prague airport already. Due to (to put it mildly) incompetence of
        the printing shop I'm not gonna name, Kendy and me had exactly 10 minutes to dispatch 45
        kilos of swag through the check-in -- that meant distributing the load into our luggage and
        shipping the remaining boxes as overweight ( including paying criminal surcharge for it). I
        hereby apologize to Czech Airways check-in clerk for spoiling her shift with it ;-) Getting
        the material from Brussels luggage claim to the train station was rather challenging as
        well, but fortunately there were some helping hands waiting for us at Brussels Nord (thanks
        Thorsten, Rene and Kohei). In Kendy's words: "T<emphasis role="italic">he experience doesn't
          necessarily have to be positive, but it definitely has to be remarkable. We would have
          nothing to talk about otherwise</emphasis>." Friday's beer event (my first ever) was also
        an enchanting experience. Met Caolan and Florian 'flr' Reuter for the first time (who, in
        slightly boozed state, asked me "Hey, so you are my successor at Novell?"). It was amazing
        to see LibreOffice crew almost having blocked the street in front of Delirium Cafe :)
        (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 10.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>People of openSUSE</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>This Week: xyz</title>
      <para>Good Guy. Glows in the night.</para>
    </blockquote>
    </sect2> -->
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Welcome new openSUSE Members</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/fcrozat">Frederic Crozat (fcrozat)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Very active in the openSUSE GNOME Team and Bugzilla.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/helen-au">Helen South
        (helen-au)</ulink></title>
      <para>Helen works inside Marketing and the Editor Team of news.opensuse.org.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/dominian">Matt Hayes
        (dominian)</ulink></title>
      <para>Active in Bugzilla, Wiki and Mailinglists.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/tsotsos">Angelos Tzotsos
        (tsotsos)</ulink></title>
      <para>Active inside the Greek Community and Marketing.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/bekun">Kai-Uwe Behrmann
        (bekun)</ulink></title>
      <para>Kai-Uwe serves as Speaker, Boothman and Developer for the openSUSE Project.</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Events &amp; Meetings</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Past</title>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink
            url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/01/20/21st-opensuse-testing-core-team-irc-meeting/"
            >January 31, 2011 : 21st openSUSE Testing Core Team IRC Meeting</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Upcoming</title>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/05/13/%ef%bb%bfopensuse-kde-team-meeting/"
            >February 10, 2011 : ﻿openSUSE KDE Team meeting</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <!-- ($ ld: 04.02.11 th $) -->
    <para>You can find more informations on other events at: <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/category/events/">openSUSE News/Events</ulink>. - <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Ambassadors_events">Local Events</ulink></para>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>openSUSE for your Ears</title>
    <para>The openSUSE Weekly News are available as livestream or podcast in German. You can hear it
      or download it on <ulink url="http://blog.radiotux.de/podcast">Radiotux</ulink>. </para>
  </sect2>
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>From Ambassadors</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://stick.gk2.sk/blog/2011/01/gnome-python-hackfest-appinstaller-meeting-and-bretzn-hackfest/"
          >Pavol Rusnak: GNOME Python Hackfest, AppInstaller Meeting and Bretzn Hackfest</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>What a cool and productive week! But let me start from the beginning … </para>
      <para>A couple of months ago we decided to start a <ulink
          url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hackerspace">hackerspace</ulink> in Prague called <ulink
          url="http://brmlab.cz/">brmlab</ulink>. Most of the members deal with hardware, but there
        are also couple of software guys like me. At the end of November we were contacted by <ulink
          url="http://blog.tomeuvizoso.net/">Tomeu</ulink> and he asked if they can organize <ulink
          url="http://live.gnome.org/Hackfests/Python2011">GNOME Python Hackfest</ulink> in our
        hackerspace. I was more than delighted about the idea, so we agreed and started to plan
        things. In the end we had 9 FOSS hackers working on GNOME and Python and I think they
        enjoyed their time in Prague. Hackerspace is a great concept, because these folks didn’t
        have to spend extra money on renting some place and our members had opportunity to meet
        foreign FOSS developers and try exotic hardware like <ulink
          url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OLPC_XO-1">OLPC XO-1</ulink>.</para>
      <figure id="fig.blogpost">
        <title>Blogposts from <ulink
            url="http://blog.tomeuvizoso.net/2010/12/python-gnome-hackfest-2011.html">Tomeu</ulink>
          and <ulink url="http://www.j5live.com/2011/01/19/pygi-in-prague/">J5</ulink> about the
          event</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://stick.gk2.sk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/gnome-python-1.jpg"
              width="25%" align="center"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>I had to leave the guys on Tuesday evening, because I spent the rest of the week in SUSE
        office in Nuernberg. The first three days were dedicated to <ulink
          url="http://distributions.freedesktop.org/wiki/Meetings/AppInstaller2011"
          >Cross-distribution meeting</ulink> about application installer organized by <ulink
          url="http://www.vuntz.net/journal/">Vincent</ulink>. It went more than well, we discussed
        and agreed on many things, which is great and in the end we were able to give a <ulink
          url="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BHeP2ZBwS_U">presentation</ulink> + we also created a
          <ulink url="http://distributions.freedesktop.org/wiki/AppStream">nice AppStream
          wikipage</ulink> as a starting point for any future work.</para>
      <figure id="fig.summary">
        <title>Vincent wrote a nice summary for <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/">openSUSE
            News</ulink>. (It is not yet there, but should appear soon.)</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://stick.gk2.sk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/appstream_meeting.jpg"
              width="25%" align="center"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>This meeting was immediately followed by <ulink
          url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:2011_Bretzn_Meeting">Bretzn hackfest</ulink>
        organized by <ulink url="http://blog.karlitschek.de/">Frank</ulink>. The main focus of it
        was implementing some of the things we agreed on previous meeting from the KDE/Qt
        perspective and porting MeeGo Garage to openSUSE. During it I was mainly dealing with
        appdata.xml format we described in the AppStream meeting – I created an XML schema so we can
        validate it and also developed a proof-of-concept generator of this piece of metadata in
        Python. (<ulink url="http://gitorious.org/appstream">git repo</ulink>) Hope we can get it in
        createrepo and dpkg-scan* utilities soon.</para>
      <figure id="fig.planetsuse">
        <title>Frank’s summary about the hackfest will appear on <ulink
            url="http://planet.opensuse.org/">Planet openSUSE</ulink> soon</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="http://stick.gk2.sk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/DSC_1674.jpg"
              width="25%" align="center"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>I would like to thank GNOME Foundation and Collabora for sponsoring the GNOME Python
        Hackfest, Novell for sponsoring the Bretzn Hackfest and Canonical, Debian, Mageia, Novell
        and Red Hat for sending their people to AppInstaller Meeting! It’s really nice and
        encouraging to see folks from various companies working on one common goal.</para>
      <para>And yeah,</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://stick.gk2.sk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/going-to.png"
            width="10%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>so see you there!</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Communication</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/">The Mailinglists</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org">The openSUSE Forums</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Contributors</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://users.opensuse.org">The User Directory</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
