<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--q
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/11/07/the-green-planet/">The Green
        Planet</ulink></title>
    <para>The last few days those of you linked to the planet by <ulink url="http://planetsuse.org/"
        >http://planetsuse.org/</ulink> are experiencing connection problems. This is not because
      openSUSE Planet is down but as Pascal Bleser announced a few days ago into the openSUSE
      Project ML because this domain name is not under the Project’s control but by and individual
      who left the openSUSE Project some years ago. </para>
    <para>The only way to go to the openSUSE planet is now by typing http://planet.opensuse.org/ and
      the correct way to connect your RSS is by adding <ulink
        url="http://planet.opensuse.org/global/rss20.xml">that</ulink> .xml . </para>
    <para>In case you are experiencing troubles with your aggregator please contact
      admin@opensuse.org there is someone there to help you solve any problem you might have.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 09.11.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/11/08/geekos-go-on-g/">Geekos go on
      G+</ulink></title>
    <para>The IT world moves fast and along with it does social networking. It’s been only a few
      days since Google <ulink
        url="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2011/11/google-pages-connect-with-all-things.html"
        >announced</ulink> the limited availability of Google+ pages and already thousands of
      Google-plussers have created a Google+ page. Of course, we’re social too and thus the openSUSE
      project now has an official Google+ page!</para>
    <para> If you are created a page for an openSUSE community, like Kostas for the Greece
      community, then don’t forget to add your page to <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Social_media_contacts#Social_networks">openSUSE Social
        media contacts</ulink> so that openSUSE enthusiasts can easily <ulink
        url="http://gpc.fm/l/opensuseusers">find the official pages and add it</ulink> to their
      circles. That page is also a reference for other social media activities that openSUSE is
      involved in like Facebook, Twitter or LinkedIn.</para>
    <para>Also, if you like to get involved promoting openSUSE on social media and networks, please
      talk with the openSUSE marketing team.</para>
    <para>I’d like to thank Roger Luedecke for taking care of the new openSUSE Google + page and
      invite everybody to share contents on it, promote it and follow what we do!</para>
    <!--($ ld: 09.11.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/11/10/continuous-integration-testing-for-opensuse-available/"
        >Continuous Integration testing for openSUSE available!</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>The development process of the Open Build Service (OBS) code base as well as it’s
      accompanying tools is largely test-driven. Major parts of the OBS source code are covered by a
      comprehensive test-suite. Traditionally, after each new code submission, these tests have been
      run by a custom shell-script on a local machine that wasn’t publicly available for several
      reasons. Even though this setup served us well for a long time, but we needed more. We want to
      provide a more transparent solution that allows the community to participate and maybe take
      over some responsibilities. Thus, your hard-working OBS-team hereby kindly introduces
      ci.opensuse.org, our new public interface for continuous integration (CI) testing!
      (...)</para>
    <para><inlinegraphic
        fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/ci_o_o_frontpage-300x224.png"
      /></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 09.11.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
