<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/04/25/opensuse-coming-to-lfnw/">openSUSE Coming
        to LFNW</ulink></title>
    <para>Following in the growing list of appearances we’re making worldwide, openSUSE will land in
      Bellingham, Washington for the LinuxFest Northwest conference ( <ulink url="http://lfnw.org"
        >LFNW</ulink> ) on Saturday, April 30 and Sunday, May 1 at the <ulink
        url="http://www.linuxfestnorthwest.org/information/venue">Bellingham Technical
        College</ulink>. We’re excited to be joining in the festivities there, along with an
      exxpected attendance of over 1,000 visitors, running a booth and 3 presentations, doing our
      best to help make the event interesting and successful for everyone.</para>
    <para>Doing what we do best, you’ll find the same great booth you’ve come to expect at other
      events. There, you’ll be able to pick up a DVD of <ulink
        url="http://software.opensuse.org/114/en">openSUSE 11.4</ulink>, just released last month
      amid great reviews. You’ll also be able to show your support for openSUSE and LFNW at the same
      time by buying an openSUSE <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/File:Black_t-shirt.jpg"
        >T-shirt</ulink> for just $5. Every dollar we make will go directly to supporting the great
      work of the LFNW crew. These FOSS events are very important to the community and openSUSE
      wants to do its part to promote that.</para>
    <para>For those of you that prefer a game of chance, be sure to sign up for the
        <quote>World-Famous</quote> LFNW <ulink
        url="http://www.linuxfestnorthwest.org/sessions/world-famous-raffle">raffle</ulink>; we’ve
      donated a few bigger-ticket items there as well, and again, all funds support LFNW.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GFDL 1.2</ulink></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 27.4.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/04/26/opensuse-11-4-dvds-for-events/">openSUSE
        11.4 DVDs for Events</ulink></title>
    <para>Following the huge success for filling requests of openSUSE 11.3 media in <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/02/18/help-the-project-spread-opensuse-dvds/"
        >February</ulink>, we have produced openSUSE 11.4 DVDs to distribute at events, Linux user
      groups, universities etc.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">The PromoDVDs</emphasis></para>
    <para>These <quote>PromoDVDs</quote> are meant to promote openSUSE and help users get a quick
      taste of what we have to offer. A PromoDVD is different from the usual openSUSE DVD’s you can
      download from our <ulink url="http://software.opensuse.org/114/en">download portal</ulink>.
      They contain a reduced set of packages for installation to make room for a Live GNOME and Live
      KDE image. And the DVD’s are double-sided with both 32 and 64 bit on one disc!</para>
    <para>In some countries, where network connections are an issue, users can bring these DVD’s
      from an event home for installation. In other places, the Live images and added convenience
      giving people a chance to test drive and see right away why openSUSE is a great distro for
      them!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GFDL 1.2</ulink></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 23.4.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>  
</sect1>
