<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://ungethym.blogspot.com/2011/02/google-code-in-my-summary.html">Thomas Thym:
        Google Code In – My Summary</ulink>
    </title>
    <figure id="fig.mensch">
      <title>(C) by Wade Olsen</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_uRmToxm-PAQ/TU6wEtbe6YI/AAAAAAAAACs/YPv8edxeXZ0/s1600/560184_16070576_large.png"
            width="20%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>It was my first time I mentored a couple of students <xref linkend="fig.mensch"/>during a
      Google sponsored project. It was possible to submit non-coding tasks as well. So I focused on
      promo stuff. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Results </emphasis></para>
    <para>Over all I submitted ten tasks (nine could be closed). </para>
    <para>The first block of tasks (solved by Todor Stoyanov and Paul) was about the creation of a
        <ulink url="http://community.kde.org/Promo/Material/OpenContent">free/open content
        collection</ulink> that could be shown during demos and presentations or could be integrated
      into live CD/DVDs. </para>
    <para>The second block of task was covering KDE and FLOSS in the area of education (solved by
      TheOne and Giannis Konstantinidis). It started with a <ulink
        url="http://community.kde.org/Promo/SchoolSurvey">survey of needs of students</ulink>,
        <ulink url="http://community.kde.org/Promo/SchoolSurveyResult">doing the survey</ulink>,
        <ulink url="http://community.kde.org/Promo/Schools/StudentTasks">analyzing student
        tasks</ulink> and ended with a <ulink url="http://community.kde.org/Promo/Schools">concept
        for students</ulink> how to promote KDE and FLOSS at their school (incl. <ulink
        url="http://dl.dropbox.com/u/6538846/KDE_marketing_material.zip">promo material</ulink> e.g.
        <ulink url="http://dl.dropbox.com/u/6538846/KDE_poster.tar.gz">a poster</ulink>, <ulink
        url="http://www.google-melange.com/gci/work_submission/download_blob?key=AMIfv94cKKVFpAA8e706_2J1ACCc8MoqCqhBAWjiABsEpIzGtTuq9VwmxwFuwODmAadK2XMV1RKEjIGCAH2i87BN6z29AhGH_4i-SRjme1fHwknxKtrN1OZo1TQjvp7XZlYmeZyQZtDJexAQsHkRVScJdEvIjXQ7Ew"
        >presentation</ulink>, <ulink url="http://community.kde.org/Promo/Schools/TalkingPoints"
        >talking points</ulink> for students etc.). One of the students is going to test it within
      his school. Isn't that rocking? </para>
    <para>I truly believe that KDE and FLOSS (esp. KDE EDU and the openSUSE based Desktop4Education
      and Server4Education projects) have so much to offer for schools and students. We should do
      even more in this area. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Challenges </emphasis></para>
    <para>For me it was very difficult to set the level and the time needed to fulfill the task when
      I was submitting it. It depends so much on the skills and the age of the student. The task to
      find free music and test it with Amarok (support for CD cover, lyrics and Wikipedia
      information) would be easy for a student with installed KDE and with some experiences with
      free and open stuff. A student new to the open source world will need days to work out that
      (for him) difficult task. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Summary</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>All in all it was much more work than I expected, on the other side it was a wonderful
      experience to see how the students developed themselves over time (and how fast the tasks were
      taken). It was a great success and I am looking forward to the next time. </para>
    <para>@my students: Thanks for your contribution. It was a great pleasure to work with you.
      Let's keep in touch. Let's keep on rocking the world!</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 7.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://blip.tv/file/4732649">openSUSE TV: Amazing openSUSE</ulink></title>
    <para>openSUSE has developed both great infrastructure technology and a powerful enduser
      product; where is it going now? </para>
    <para>Over 5 years ago Novell decided to turn their new asset, SuSE Linux into a community
      distribution. It was a long and laborious process but since almost 2 years now the development
      processes have been opened up to the community. We now speak of openSUSE, a community which is
      now searching for it's direction. The project has state-of-the-art infrastructure at its
      disposal and develops a modern, stable and powerful linux distribution. Meanwhile,
      communication and marketing are it's weak points - innovative technologies like the openSUSE
      Build Service and SUSE Studio do not get the exposure they deserve. In this talk an overview
      is given of openSUSE's history, the developments in the community and the latest openSUSE
      technology is presented.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 8.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://florianreuter.blogspot.com/2011/02/just-came-back-from-fosdem.html"
        >Florian Reuter: FOSDEM</ulink></title>
    <para>Just came back from FOSDEM. Felt really good to meet the “usual suspects” again. Thanks
      for the great weekend! </para>
    <para>I also had a chance to talk with Jos about ODF Web and ODF Collaboration. Jos gave a great
      talk about his ODF Web Javascript Framework which emerged from his ODFKit efforts. </para>
    <para>Jos had a very important slide in his talk which echoed my own believe: NO CONVERSION!
      This principle guided the design of his ODF Web Framework. NO CONVERSION simply means that Jos
      does not try to heuristically (aka lossy) map ODF to HTML and then map HTML heuristically (aka
      lossy) back to ODF. Instead Jos decided to have a clean 2-tier architecture which cleanly
      separates the content- and the view layer: ODF is content and HTML is the view. I think that’s
      the right approach. Even more: I think if you start adding “smart conversions”/”heuristics”
      and other “intelligent mappings” things will get ugly sooner or later. [And from my experience
      on OpenOffice.org filter hacking things will get messy sooner than you like. Always keep
      Murphy’s law in mind: What can go wrong will go wrong!]. </para>
    <para>We also had a chance to talk about Operational Transformation (OT) in the context of ODF.
      I tried to argue that what is really missing in ODF is a list of “atomic changes” a user can
      make to an ODF document. If we had this list of “atomic changes” we could build a
      transformation on top of it. For OT it is very important that you have “atomic” operations,
      since you need operation transformations for every pair of operation. E.g. if you have |OPS|
      operations you need |OPS x OPS| transformations. So keeping |OPS| small is quite important! </para>
    <para>Assembling the list of atomic operations is a lot of work --- admitted. However it is work
      that every designer of an API needs to do anyway. I really believe that some input from the
      ODF API projects like Oracles’ ODFDOM, IBM’s Simple API for ODF, ANR’s LPOD and Jos’ ODFKit
      could really help. </para>
    <para>Let me finish my post by a classification of change to an ODF document:</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_k9bd8YQpZ7Y/TVARD-e1z0I/AAAAAAAAAIQ/aejOhYvKRZg/s400/changeclasses.jpg"
          width="30%"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para> I believe that for change tracking we only need “atomic operations” and a way to combine
      them to “compound operations”. I don’t think we need to be able to track changes to the XML
      tree or the XML text. In fact I think it does more harm than good. </para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 8.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://dev-loki.blogspot.com/2011/02/fosdem-2011-eol.html">Pascal Bleser:
        FOSDEM 2011 EOL</ulink></title>
    <para>So <ulink url="http://fosdem.org/2011">FOSDEM 2011</ulink> is over, at last, and it was a
      huge success, as always (mind you, I'm one of the organizers, my opinions might be just a
      little subjective here ;)). </para>
    <para>From the organizational point of view, I was less active this year compared the the 7
      previous ones (yes, it's already the 8th time for me, and I noticed how annoying it is to say
      "8th" in English quite a few times during the weekend): lots of procastrination and my "spare
      time" being vampirized by other activities, most prominently work on the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board">openSUSE Board</ulink> (which I am now <ulink
        url="http://dev-loki.blogspot.com/2011/01/why-i-am-not-running-for-opensuse-board.html">no
        longer part of</ulink>). Definitely something to fix for next year, and a big mea culpa to
      my mates on the FOSDEM organization team. </para>
    <para>That being said, it was still a lot of work, as it is for every edition, and while I
      suppose that most if not all the visitors are sorry that the event is already over, we're
      pretty happy it is, I'm sure you can understand why :). </para>
    <para>All in all, it was very successful. There were more visitors, as each year, and I believe
      that we've really reached the limits of the infrastructure we're using at the moment. That
      means we'll have a few "interesting" challenges ahead of us for the next edition (no, we won't
      move away from the ULB nor from the Solbosch campus, we'll just have to stretch the space used
      by FOSDEM a bit more to use more and larger rooms). But more about that in a few months' time. </para>
    <para>It was also very smooth for everything else. Having so many volunteers to help us out
      during the weekend, including for the very tedious task of setting things up, was really
      ${deity}-send. Thanks to the support of the ULB networking team, Belnet as well as Cisco made
      FOSDEM provide what must be the best possible wifi infrastructure at an event of such size.
      Our usual <ulink url="http://bit.ly/ewcvgx">collaboration with LPI</ulink> went great as well
      (was awesome to meet my good friend <ulink url="http://twitter.com/fabricemous">Fabrice
        Mous</ulink> again) as it provided the opportunity for ~130 exams to be taken by FOSDEM
      visitors. </para>
    <para>We even managed to fill up our largest room, <ulink
        url="http://fosdem.org/2011/schedule/room/janson">Janson</ulink>, which is one of the
      largest auditoriums in Belgium with 1400 seats, up to the limit and even a bit more for the
      keynotes. That was impressive, to say the least. </para>
    <para>It was a great pleasure to meet so many fine people and friends again (including, but not
      exclusively, Henne Vogelsang, Peter Linnell, Andrew Wafaa, Jürgen Weigert, Will Stephenson,
      Bruno Friedmann, Pavol Rusnak, Michal Hrusecky, Vincent Untz, Michael Meeks, Daniel Seuffert,
      Frank Karlitschek, Delphine Lebedel, Tristan Nitot, William Quiviger, Tom Marble, etc etc
      etc... -- sorry if I forgot you, I'm just too lazy and tired to keep pulling names out of my
      brain at this point, too many to list :)), even if it was usually only for a short chat as I
      have to keep running around all over the venue to get things done. </para>
    <para>That's usually the point where one realizes again that it is so much about the people,
      more than anything else (you are fine to disagree here, dear reader, it is just my very humble
      opinion). So many FOSS projects are driven by so many great people, I'd just love it to last
      for a couple of weeks to have the time to have beers (or coffee) with every single one of
      them, at the very least the ones I already know. I'm really happy and thankful -- to FOSDEM, I
      guess -- to be so lucky to have been in touch with so many interesting people, and obviously
      hope to still be in the future. </para>
    <para>And FOSDEM is also a very inclusive event, where projects and initiatives covering the
      whole spectrum in terms of technologies, domains and (OSI compatible) licenses get together to
      have a great deal of fun. I believe that every single visitor would agree that it is the most
      effective way to get our motivation batteries loaded to spend our spare time, energy, love,
      sweat and blood into doing such great things. </para>
    <para>On the cross-pollination front, which is more and more of a priority for us, I'm happy to
      see the <ulink url="http://fosdem.org/2011/schedule/track/crossdistro_devroom">Crossdistro
        developer room</ulink> clearly evolve into the right direction (thanks to <ulink
        url="http://grep.be/">Wouter Verhelst</ulink> (of Debian fame) to take care of that); where
      not quite there yet, as intentions need to be followed by much more action, but it is a step
      forward already, and such things do take a good deal of time, as much as many of us would like
      to see it happening as soon as possible, especially at openSUSE. FOSDEM is such a great
      opportunity to get together with other projects and people, as so many of them are on the
      spot. </para>
    <para>For a couple of final words, my big "thank you" goes out, in no particular order, to the
      volunteers who helped us during the weekend, to the sponsors that support the event, to the
      visitors who have donated money in order to keep giving us the chance of remaining
      independent, to the people and projects who were there at the stands, devrooms, lightning
      talks, to the speakers who accepted our invitations, obviously to the other members of the
      FOSDEM organization team (we did it again! :D), to the ULB and CI for providing us with their
      infrastructure, and, of course, to the people who attended. </para>
    <para>On a side note, if you were at FOSDEM 2011, please take a minute to fill out our <ulink
        url="http://fosdem.org/2011/census">census </ulink>as well as our <ulink
        url="http://fosdem.org/2011/feedback">feedback form</ulink>.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 8.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://blog.jprosevear.org/2011/02/11/sleeping-on-a-couch-transferring-culture/">JP
        Rosevear: Sleeping on a Couch: Transferring Culture</ulink></title>
    <para>In the first half of 2009 the Preload department at Novell was building a team in Taiwan.
      There were two main reasons for this – our customers (the OEMs and ODMs) were located there
      and we wanted to be near them and the first question a customer in Taiwan always seemed to be
      “how many people do you have here”. Local support in the native language backed with a large
      team is very important to companies in Taiwan. </para>
    <para>We hired excellent people who were both experienced Linux engineers and people straight
      out of university. However, all were pretty inexperienced working with open source communities
      and I had a perception that any previous workplaces they were at in Asia was more likely to be
      hierarchical in nature where open communication was discouraged because you don’t question the
      boss. I believe this type of work place leads to the surfacing of issues until its way too
      late to solve them and leads to sub-optimal problem solving. I wanted to ensure that the new
      team understood open source was a key component of our work and that open communication was
      important both internally and externally in support of this. </para>
    <para>This type of situation is not one I would have thought about at all when I first became a
      manager, but a couple of prior experiences (including failure) suggested this was something I
      could and should address. In particular the OpenOffice “indoctrination” about 4 years ago when
      we were expanding the team. At that time I managed the OpenOffice team at Novell and <ulink
        url="http://people.gnome.org/~michael/">Michael Meeks</ulink> interviewed everyone we hired
      during the expansion and many of them spent 1-2 nights sleeping on his couch in the UK or
      getting trained in the Toronto office in person. Due to this, that team (now the team working
      on <ulink url="http://bit.ly/e60nXF">LibreOffice</ulink>) to this day cares a lot about
      tenacious fixing of customer problems, reducing code duplication/bloat and particularly about
      building a great community around the project. </para>
    <para>So for Taiwan <ulink url="http://www.kroah.com/log/">Greg KH</ulink>, Michael Meeks,
        <ulink url="http://bit.ly/f7rQXN">Aaron Bockover</ulink> and Stefan Dirsch all visited the
      office within a year to cover engaging with community, supportability (no one time throw away
      code here!), upstreaming commitment to debug and find the real root cause and more. This had
      two major benefits. First the culture of open source and open investigation into problems was
      transmitted by people who lived it. Second communication pathways were built so that the
      engineering team in Taiwan felt comfortable asking questions and had people they had met to
      ask the questions to, without needing “big boss” (me) to facilitate or hear potentially “dumb”
      questions. So what do we have now? Those previously inexperienced with open source engineers
      who are now <ulink url="http://bit.ly/eTVRqt">proposing</ulink>, <ulink
        url="http://bit.ly/go4W1V">submitting</ulink> and <ulink url="http://bit.ly/hL5CQ9"
        >maintaining</ulink>
      <ulink url="http://bit.ly/fcpdvq">code</ulink> upstream. </para>
    <para>(BTW Greg is really great at the kernel piece of this and was able to help <ulink
        url="http://bit.ly/iih0G8">Ralink in a similar manner</ulink> with these two items as well –
      in fact Novell is happy to help any component vendor this way). </para>
    <para>Don’t get me wrong, you can’t just hire anyone and expect to imbue them with your
      organization’s culture, you have to have to get people that are interested in and receptive to
      the culture. For instance its unlikely every single Facebook engineer was previously part of a
      culture of shared code base ownership and review that required them to be <ulink
        url="http://bit.ly/hVntIJ">in the room to fix bugs on the fly or allowed them to change and
        submit code to any part of the app or required checkin review</ulink>. These are cultural
      pieces that are transmitted post hire, but you still have to pick people who are in general
      receptive to that culture. </para>
    <para>I will always think about training engineering people in a cultural context not just in a
      technical manner now, particularly when building new teams or offices since it will be tougher
      for them to get it by osmosis. Future communication connections are built and you display the
      culture you have and want to have in the organization.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 12.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
