<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
  <!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://www.opendocsociety.org/news/odf-tc-approves-odf-1.2">Opensociety:
          ODF 1.2 approved as Committee Specification</ulink></title>
      <para>The OASIS Open Document Format for Office Applications (OpenDocument) TC has officially
        and unanimously <ulink
          url="http://lists.oasis-open.org/archives/office/201103/msg00089.html">approved</ulink>
        ODF 1.2 as a Committee Specification. The new version of the standard has taken four years
        to complete and has been adopted by many applications already. Next stage is the official
        vote within OASIS to adopt this specification as an OASIS standard. OASIS is the designated
        maintenance body for ISO/IEC JTC1 SC34 IS26300.</para>
      <para>ODF describes an XML-based application-independent and platform-independent digital
        document file format, as well as the characteristics of software applications which read,
        write and process such documents. The ODF standard is applicable to document authoring,
        editing, viewing, exchange and archiving, including text documents, spreadsheets,
        presentation graphics, drawings, charts and similar documents commonly used by personal
        productivity software applications. A significant number of governments worldwide have
        chosen ODF as the standard for exchanging documents within government and with external
        contacts such citizens and companies.</para>
      <para>OpenDoc Society congratulates the members of the ODF TC on their work. <quote>This is an
          important step for the entire ecosystem</quote>, states Michiel Leenaars, board member of
        OpenDoc Society, <quote>There is significant demand for this new version of the standard, as
          it enables new exiting and unique features such as RDF metadata, advanced digital
          signatures and enhances key areas of ODF such as formula's. That means the next stage of
          interoperability for office applications is finally there</quote>. With already very
        strong vendor support for the new version of the standard and the formal adoption as an
        OASIS standard likely to occur in a matter of several weeks (i.e. a 30 day ballot period),
        OpenDoc Society encourages customers to evaluate and start planning the adoption of ODF
        1.2.</para>
      <!--($ ld: 29.3.11 sm $)-->   
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://www.computerworld.com/s/article/9215252/10_ways_that_Linux_is_making_life_better"
          >Computerworld/Katherine Noyes: 10 ways that Linux is making life better</ulink></title>
      <para id="first_paragraph">Linux has long played a leading role <ulink
          url="http://www.pcworld.com/businesscenter/article/204423/five_reasons_linux_beats_windows_for_servers.html"
          >in the world of servers</ulink>, due in large part to its stability, security and lower
        total cost of ownership (TCO). What many don't realize, however, is just how ubiquitous it's
        becoming in other parts of life as well.</para>
      <para>Not only are distributions like <ulink
          url="http://www.pcworld.com/businesscenter/article/221517/work_begins_on_ubuntu_1110_oneiric_ocelot.html"
          >Ubuntu</ulink> helping Linux make great strides <ulink
          url="http://www.pcworld.com/businesscenter/article/208111/reports_of_linuxs_desktop_death_are_premature.html"
          >on the desktop</ulink>, but the open-source operating system is now quietly powering
        myriad innovations that many of us take for granted.</para>
      <para>Where can Linux be found today? Let's count just a few of the many places it's making
        life better. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 28.3.11 sm $) -->    
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blogs.fsfe.org/mario/?p=130">Mario Fux: We need you for Nepomuk
          (integration)!</ulink></title>
      <para>First I’d like to thank David Vignoni for his work on the logo for the Randa meeting.
        It’s the basis for the work of the <ulink url="http://blogs.fsfe.org/mario/?p=121">young
          informatic trainees</ulink>. But the results are still secret (as even I haven’t seen
        anything myself but get the first results at the end of this week <inlinemediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://blogs.fsfe.org/mario/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif"/>
          </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject> .</para>
      <para>And now to the ideas and proposals (btw this has nothing in common with the <ulink
          url="http://community.kde.org/GSoC/2011/Ideas">GSoC ideas of KDE</ulink>!). As you
        probably or hopefully already know the <ulink url="http://nepomuk.kde.org">KDE Nepomuk
          team</ulink> will have a meeting in <ulink url="http://community.kde.org/Sprints/Randa"
          >Randa</ulink> this June (from the 1st to the 7th of this month) and we still want
        application developers to integrate this technology in their application or to work on some
        interesting and great new ideas. And there will be really good help as <ulink
          url="http://trueg.wordpress.com/">Sebastian Trýg</ulink> will be in Randa and he is going
        to do one or the other workshop of Nepomuk basics. And here are some ideas and thoughts of
        mine to start your imagination engines:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>The KDE semantic clipboard. There is <ulink
              url="http://websvn.kde.org/trunk/playground/base/nepomuk-kde/semclip/">some
              code</ulink> in the old subversion playground of KDE and in December 2010 I wrote a
              <ulink url="http://blogs.fsfe.org/mario/thesis_template.pdf">paper</ulink> about this
            topic. In short, this clipboard enhances to normal one with the capability of knowing
            what (in the context of meaning) it copy-and-pastes. This clipboard does not just copy
            numbers and formatting but addresses, geographic coordinates or blbliographic
            references. Take a look and bring it to a releasable state. There are even some solution
            proposals in the above mentioned paper.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>All of the new <ulink url="http://community.kde.org/KDE_PIM">KDE PIM</ulink>
            application use Nepomuk technology through their <ulink
              url="http://community.kde.org/KDE_PIM/Akonadi">Akonadi</ulink> interactions.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://www.digikam.org">Digikam</ulink> had (or has?) some capabilities
            to exchange its information and metadata with the Nepomuk storage. What about tagging
            your pictures with the contacts (and <ulink
              url="http://www.semanticdesktop.org/ontologies/pimo/">PIMO::Persons</ulink>) of the
            new Kaddressbook and projects which are then usable system wide.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>And <ulink url="http://amarok.kde.org">Amarok</ulink> had (or again has?) some
            functions to share it’s music database with Nepomuk and thus make it system wide and not
            just enclosed in one applicatition.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>But there are as well good examples for existing Nepomuk integration: <ulink
              url="http://bangarangkde.wordpress.com/">Bangarang</ulink>. A multimedia player which
            remembers what you like, what music and videos you have on your system and where is more
            information about this media data (in the web).</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Another idea could be a (scientific) paper or article collector which understands
            the connections (or quotations) between the articles and that the strings at the top
            (authors) are actually persons and the references at the end of the articles are
            actually links and thus relations to other papers and articles. Take a look at the
              <ulink url="http://ontoware.org/swrc/">SWRC ontology</ulink>.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Yet another project which extensively uses Nepomuk is the new <ulink
              url="http://community.kde.org/Real-Time_Communication_and_Collaboration">KDE Telepathy
              framework</ulink>. They don’t just invent yet another represenation of a person and
            its contacts but use PIMO::Person and thus make connections to them system wide
            comprehensible and reusable.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>And let’s not forget the <ulink url="http://plasma.kde.org">Plasma framework</ulink>
            and its <ulink url="http://userbase.kde.org/Plasma#Activities">activities</ulink>. But
            there is more and better information about this on the <ulink
              url="http://ivan.fomentgroup.org/blog/">site of ivan Cukic</ulink>.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Or something completely new. An ontology for TV series, recordings and shows…
            (Update: Sebastian told me that there is already one: <ulink
              url="http://sourceforge.net/apps/trac/oscaf/ticket/44">NMM</ulink>. And Bangarang and
            some other applications use it.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>And there is <ulink url="http://zeitgeist-project.com/">Zeitgeist</ulink> and <ulink
              url="http://releases.zeitgeist-project.com/qzeitgeist/">QtZeitgeist</ulink>…
            (...)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <!--($ ld: 30.3.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://www.h-online.com/open/news/item/openSUSE-11-4-Edu-Li-f-e-released-1217365.html"
          >h-online: openSUSE 11.4 Edu Li-f-e released</ulink></title>
      <para>Just over two weeks after the release of openSUSE 11.4, the <ulink
          url="http://en.opensuse.org/Education">openSUSE Education</ulink> development team has
        announced the availability of openSUSE 11.4 Edu: Linux for Education (Li-f-e). The Edu
        Li-f-e edition is a customised variant of the openSUSE aimed at education. It includes
        selected applications and resources for students and educators, including parents, and
        attempts to offer a system which can be productively used at home or in an educational
        establishment. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 29.3.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://linuxblog.darkduck.com/2011/03/kde-or-gnome.html">Unixmen/M. Zinoune
          (Zinovsky): OpenSUSE Edu Li-f-e 11.4 for education is released!</ulink></title>
      <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/29/opensuse-edu-li-f-e-11-4-out-now/"
          >OpenSUSE Edu Li-f-e 11.4 </ulink>for education is released. Based on <ulink
          url="http://www.unixmen.com/linux-tutorials/linux-distributions/suse/1558-opensuse-114-is-released-with-screenshots-tour"
          >openSUSE 11.4</ulink>,<quote>this release includes the latest carefully selected software
          for students, educators, as well as parents. The software selection encompasses everything
          required to make a productive computing experience for either home or educational use
          without having to install anything additional. Right out of the box, educators and parents
          will be pleased to see over 150 applications to fit their student's needs. A wide range
          including mental exercise tools like Brain Workshop and GBrainy, science applications like
          Chemtool, mathematical programs like Euler, artistic development software like TuxPaint
          and GIMP</quote>.</para>
      <para><ulink url="http://www.youtube.com/v/O-xU1ldUoeM">YouTube Video: openSUSE Li-f-e
          Overview</ulink></para>
      <para>More information can be found on the<ulink
          url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/29/opensuse-edu-li-f-e-11-4-out-now/"> release
          announcement</ulink>.</para>
      <para>If you are using a previous release of Opensuse Edu and you want to upgrade to this new
        release, please <ulink
          url="http://www.unixmen.com/linux-tutorials/documentations-a-howto/1578-upgrade-opensuse-to-114"
          >check out previous post</ulink>.</para>
      <para><ulink url="http://www.youtube.com/v/6NWg8I2N_6U">openSUSE Edu: Li-f-e applications
          (Video)</ulink></para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Editors Note</emphasis>: Screenshots available in the Original
        Article.</para>
      <!--($ ld: 30.3.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://looksblo.wordpress.com/2011/03/30/german-subforum-on-forum-kde-org-opens-its-gates/"
          >Frederik Schwarzer: German subforum on forum.kde.org opens its gates</ulink></title>
      <para>A few minutes ago, a subforum was created on <ulink url="http://forum.kde.org/"
          >forum.kde.org</ulink> for all the German-speaking users out there (and yes, developers
        are users as well :)). So please come and make yourself at home, so it will grow and become
        the best and nicest German-speaking place to get help for those little itches KDE users
        sometimes have to scratch.</para>
      <para>On your mouse, get ready, <ulink url="http://forum.kde.org/viewforum.php?f=204"
          >Go!</ulink></para>
      <!--($ ld: 31.3.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://www.unixmen.com/news-today/1579-open-source-kimono-lanterns-to-the-rescue">Unixmen/Anuradha Shukl: Open source Kimono Lanterns to the rescue</ulink></title>
      <para>The devastation in Japan is heart rending and compels each of one of us to contribute to help improve the situation. Similar thoughts have been running through developers at <ulink url="http://freaklabs.org/">Freaklabs</ulink> . At the <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hackerspace">hackerspace</ulink> they are involved with, a solar rechargeable lantern was designed for garden and patio use. Called the Kimono Lantern, today they are able to put it to better use. Donating the complete design to the open source hardware community, they are indeed standing true to the commitments of the Open Source community.</para>
      <para>(...)</para>
      <para><ulink url="http://www.pcworld.com/article/222160/opensource_kimono_lantern_could_help_tsunami_victims.html">Kimono lanterns</ulink> are basically designed for small output but with long battery life. Running on solar cells that are recharged due to exposure to sunlight will glow for 8 hours providing the quake victims much needed night light. As flashlights, and the other standard and regular artificial light sources area premium and essential for critical situations as in makeshift hospital rooms, a Kimono lantern should do the desired needful. Light the pathway and generally offer a comforting glow amid all the darkness. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 26.3.11 sat $) -->    
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://www.brighthub.com/hubfolio/matthew-casperson/articles/110077.aspx">Hubfolio/Matthew Casperson: Five things to do in your new OpenSuse 11.4 Installation</ulink></title>
      <para>OpenSuse 11.4 is out, and it includes some of the latest and best software available for Linux. But there are still a few things you can do to spruce things up.</para>
      <para>With KDE 4.6, Libre Office, the latest Linux kernel, a preview of what is to come with Gnome 3 and so much more, OpenSuse 11.4 is ready to take your <ulink url="http://www.brighthub.com/guides/linux-desktop.aspx">Linux desktop</ulink> to the next level.</para>
      <para>But while OpenSuse 11.4 does provide a rich ecosystem of Linux applications, there are still a few things every Linux user needs to make their desktop shine, and to make it functional.</para>
      <para>Here are five steps to take after you install OpenSuse 11.4 to put the icing on the cake. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 26.3.11 sat $) -->   
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://www.itworld.com/operating-systems/140885/opensuse-114-blast-linux-past">ITworld/Steven J. Vaughan-Nichols: OpenSUSE 11.4: A blast from Linux past</ulink></title>
      <para>I&apos;ve liked openSUSE since before it was named openSUSE and went by the unlikely name S.u.S.E Linux 4.2 back in 1996. It&apos;s come a long, long way since then. Today, this Novell-supported community Linux distribution makes both a strong, server and desktop. For all that, though I&apos;ve found in this go-around some fit and polish issues.</para>
      <para>To test it out, I put openSUSE 11.4, on two computers. The first was a Gateway SX2802-07 desktop. This PC uses a 2.6GHZ Intel Pentium Dual-Core E5300 processor and has 6GBs of RAM and a 640GB hard-drive and was being wasted doing nothing but serving as a full-time Windows PC. The other was VirtualBox 4.04 VM (virtual machine) running on my Mint 10 desktop. Behind the VM was a Dell Inspiron 530S powered by a 2.2-GHz Intel Pentium E2200 dual-core processor with an 800-MHz front-side bus. This box has 4GBs of RAM, a 500GB SATA (Serial ATA) drive, and an Integrated Intel 3100 GMA (Graphics Media Accelerator) chip set. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 26.3.11 sat $) -->    
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://dasublogbyprashanth.blogspot.com/2011/03/review-opensuse-114-kde.html">Das U-Blog/Prashanth Venkataram: Review: openSUSE 11.4 KDE</ulink></title>
      <para>This review you are about to read was originally going to be about Scientific Linux 6. However, two things changed that: one, openSUSE 11.4 got released yesterday, though I did think about doing Scientific Linux today and openSUSE in a few days, and two, Scientific Linux didn&apos;t play well with either UnetBootin or MultiSystem. In any case, that review will have to wait a bit. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 26.3.11 sat $) This article is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. -->   
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://www.linuxjournal.com/content/mingle-opensuse-ites-connect">Linux Journal/Susan Linton: Mingle with openSUSE-ites on connect</ulink></title>
      <para>The ever-inventive openSUSE gang have come up with another cool service to enhance user experience and promote good will. This time it is a little less technical and a little more social. Connect with other openSUSE users, developers, and groups. You can make friends, find out the latest news, and get involved.</para>
      <para>Henne Vogelsang introduced the new service a few days ago and he said connect was the answer to &quot;What are we really doing when we develop a new tool to handle openSUSE users and groups?&quot; The purpose is to connect people to projects, groups and with each other; connect faces to names, nicknames and to email addresses; and, ultimately, connect all our other tools to this one so we can share the data, as Vogelsang explained. In other words, it&apos;s openSUSE&apos;s very own little social network. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 26.3.11 sat $) -->    
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://www.petur.eu/blog/?p=349">Petur.eu: Linux can be hacked with an USB
          device</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>I have to admit, over the years I haven’t given openSUSE enough love or credit for being
        the outstanding Linux distribution is it. With that said, I wanted to give some attention to
        the latest release coming out of the openSUSE project. And, since the default desktop for
        openSUSE 11.4 is KDE, I will be giving a little extra attention to the KDE desktop. Since
        both might well gain some serious ground, when Ubuntu 11.04 is released, it will be nice for
        users to not only know of its existence, but to also know that openSUSE 11.4 is, in fact, a
        solid distribution worth giving a look. (...)</para>      
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>LOL</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://xkcd.com/874/">XKCD: Time Management</ulink></title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/time_management.png" width="50%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
          url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.5/">CC-BY-NC</ulink></para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
</sect1>
