<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/07/opensuse-11-4-will-be-first-to-roll-out-with-libreoffice/">openSUSE 11.4 Will Be First To Roll Out With LibreOffice</ulink>
    </title>
    <note><para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is Licensed under the <ulink url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GNU Free Documentation License version 1.2.</ulink></emphasis></para>
    </note>
    <para>openSUSE 11.4 is set to release on 10th March 2010. A highlight among many exciting features is the debut of <ulink url="bold">LibreOffice</ulink>, successor project of the popular cross-platform desktop office suite by OpenOffice.org.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/LibreOffice-splash-150x150.jpg"/>
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">LibreOffice features</emphasis></para>
    <para>LibreOffice comes with many improvements over its predecessor, OpenOffice.Org-3.2.1. The new Search Bar, Title Page, and Print Dialogs are impressive additions. Petr Mladek, long standing LibreOffice and openSUSE contributor, comments:</para>
    <para><quote>I think that users will appreciate the new hierarchical axis labels for charts, RTF export, easier slide layout handling, and all the other features we were able to add thanks to our more open development model.</quote></para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/11.4-screenshot-libreoffice-calc-on-xfce-300x225.jpg" align="right"/>
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <para>LibreOffice provides some unique benefits over other Office solutions beyond simply being free, like Online Help, as well as a host of usability improvements. Different Formula Syntaxes are implemented, including Calc A1, Excel A1 and Excel R1C1. Inline form editing is a lot easier to use. Another useful feature is the ability to use a split view on a sheet, while in multi-lingual documents we now have the ability to change language for a particular sentence. Presentations with LibreOffice will sparkle with the new 3D slide transitions in Impress.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">LibreOffice in openSUSE</emphasis></para>
    <para>Mladek notes several advantages of LibreOffice in openSUSE; one of them being a huge group of LibreOffice Developers inside openSUSE benefiting from the suite’s faster development model and no need of any copyright assignment. Another advantage he mentions is the use of the <ulink url="https://build.opensuse.org/">openSUSE Build Service</ulink>, which helps to keep the packages up-to-date and compatible for older distributions. And finally, openSUSE is the only distribution using the split build (separate packages for each component) which makes it easier to hack on LibreOffice, providing a quicker development path for bug fixes and incremental feature improvements.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/libreoffice-300x187.png" align="left"/>
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Developers and packagers at both LibreOffice and openSUSE have taken special care that the migration and update process from OpenOffice.org to LibreOffice moves on smoothly. Backward compatibility and improved import &amp; export filters were set as top priorities.</para>
    <para>LibreOffice receives major contributions from Novell and SUSE hackers, as <ulink url="http://cedric.bosdonnat.free.fr/wordpress/?p=758">a recent blog from Cedric Bosdonnat showed</ulink>. Bosdonnat also notices the growth of LibreOffice:</para>
    <para><quote>LibreOffice now counts 133 new hackers and 55 localizers (since the fork).</quote></para>
    <para>Michael Meeks, another prominent LibreOffice contributor and openSUSE developer, adds:</para>
    <para><quote>I’m really excited to have LibreOffice in openSUSE 11.4, and the converse, to have so many great openSUSE developers involved with LibreOffice both in testing and developing. It is great to work together with the wider community to get the best Free Software Office experience possible into users’ hands.</quote></para>
    <para><quote>openSUSE 11.4 will be the first stable distribution to ship with LibreOffice, a happy accident of timing. If you happen to be an enterprise user of SLED, don’t worry – there will also be updates to LibreOffice across our portfolio of supported products.</quote></para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/11.4-screenshot-libreoffice-writer-on-lxde-300x225.jpg" align="right"/>        
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Foundations</emphasis></para>
    <para>Meeks, who was closely involved with the decision to fork LibreOffice away from the control of Oracle and create the <ulink url="http://www.documentfoundation.org/">Document Foundation</ulink>, sees similarities between the Document Foundation and the work going on to set up an openSUSE Foundation:</para>
    <para><quote>in some ways, openSUSE’s trajectory is close to that of LibreOffice’s with the creation of a truly independent foundation. Surely openSUSE is under the stewardship of a company which is very much open to contributions, unlike OpenOffice.org was, but for sustained growth and a secure future a Foundation is really important.</quote></para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/11.4-screenshot-libreoffice-start-300x225.jpg" align="right"/>
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Coming soon!</emphasis></para>
    <para>Watch out for LibreOffice in the upcoming scheduled release of openSUSE 11.4 on 10th March, 2011 which besides being the first major distribution to ship LibreOffice in a stable release promises many other new and updated applications, features and extensions, as well as numerous improvements to and stability and performance.</para>
    <para>A recent <ulink url="http://sysbytes.wordpress.com/2011/03/07/an-interview-with-petr-mladek-libre-office-developer/">interview with openSUSE LibreOffice developer Petr Mladek</ulink> gives additional information.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="italic">Article contributed by Manu Gupta</emphasis></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 7.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/07/live-code-party/">Live.Code.Party.</ulink></title>
    <note><para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is Licensed under the <ulink url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GNU FreeDocumentation License version 1.2.</ulink></emphasis></para>
    </note>
    <para><ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:11.4">openSUSE 11.4</ulink> is going to be released this Thursday (<emphasis role="bold">March 10th, 2011</emphasis>) and there is no better way to enjoy the new release than having fun with your fellow openSUSE Lizards! That’s why community members all over the world prepare launch parties. Launch parties are events around the release of a new openSUSE version, what kind of event is up to the organizers. But it’s usually about sharing knowledge with each other, get new people to know the distribution, the tools and the project and most important about <emphasis role="italic">having a lot of fun</emphasis>, celebrating our success! Interested? Here are a couple of parties to check out!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Europe/Nürnberg</emphasis></para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://en.opensuse.org/images/5/51/Release_party_poster_nuernberg.png" align="right"/>
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <para>In the town where openSUSE was born, that still hosts the SUSE headquarters and therefor a large portion of the community the launch event will happen on Wednesday March 16 (19:00) in the <ulink url="http://artefakt-nuernberg.de/">Bar/Cafe/Gallery Artefakt</ulink>. In the historic district of Nürnberg the folks plan to have a blast with an introduction to 11.4 by the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Boosters_team">Boosters</ulink>, live music from <ulink url="http://www.myspace.com/ukuleleinsanity">Ukulele Insanity</ulink> and lots of the openSUSE brew <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Beer">Old Toad</ulink>. They expect a couple of high profile visitors like the man that pulled it off for the 6th time, Stephan Kulow (coolo), release manager of the distribution, Henne Vogelsang, long time openSUSE Board member and maybe even a couple of the SUSE founders!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">North America/San Diego</emphasis></para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/the-party-150x150.jpg" align="left"/>        
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <para>In the land of the free, Lizards will meet in San Diego, Americas finest city. The <ulink url="http://www.kernel-panic.org/">Kernel-Panic Linux User Group (KPLUG)</ulink> kindly hosts the openSUSE 11.4 launch party at their general meeting on March 10 (18:30) in the <ulink url="http://extension.ucsd.edu/">UC San Diego Extension</ulink> Mission Valley, the continuing education and public program branch of the University of California. Among the guests will be openSUSE news own Izabel Valverde and openSUSE Board, Marketing, GNOME and a11y team member Bryen Yunashko. Join them in celebrating and learn about the features of the new release!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">South America/Guatemala</emphasis></para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/frets_on_fire-300x240.jpg" align="right"/>
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <para>openSUSE Ambassadors Fernando Mejía, founder of the <ulink url="http://www.opensuse.org.gt/">openSUSE LUG Guatemala</ulink> and Axel Ruiz will host a party in the beautiful Centro Histórico, Ciudad de Guatemala. It’s going to take place in a cultural center called Bakabs (15:00). On the event they will introduce the crowd to the principles and philosophies of free software and teach them about new developments in and around the distribution. An install fest, lots of giveaways, like T-shirts and DVDs, and their legendary Frets on Fire tournament will round off the event. We heard there is usually also a nice after-party!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Asia/Honk Kong</emphasis></para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3068/2824169709_859f70f4e2_m.jpg" align="left"/>
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <para>In Hong Kong, organizers are still looking for more participants for their launch party! They are contemplating to have lunch together in a <ulink url="http://jojofood.com/main.htm">restaurant</ulink> or to meet up at the seaside mid March. Dates and locations are still not set in stone and are worked out, like everything else, in a collaborative fashion. The launch party will not only be about food and drinks but also host an install fest where you can grab DVDs and community members will then help you with your installation if you bring your computer along.  All Lizards in Hong Kong that are interested to celebrate 11.4 together, please get in contact with the organizers on the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:11.4_Launch_party_Hong_Kong">openSUSE Wiki</ulink>!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">More parties…</emphasis></para>
    <para>For more launch party locations around the globe like Paris, Prague, Thessaloniki, San Salvador, Utrecht, Atlanta, Neuss, Colombo or Managua and for dates, addresses and a large scale map check the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Launch_parties">openSUSE Wiki launch party</ulink> page.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">…or how about you run your own?</emphasis></para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/party_map-e1299503361641-300x147.png" align="right"/>
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <para>By the way if you’re interested in hosting your own launch party, see our <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Launch_party_HOWTO">Launch Party HOWTO</ulink> for starters. Also note that launch parties aren’t limited to the release date! Feel free to plan yours at any time convenient to you and your guests.  Just remember one thing:</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Have a lot of fun…</emphasis></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 8.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
