<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://dominique.leuenberger.net/blog/?p=149">Dominique Leuenberger: VLC /
        openSUSE 11.0 repository to be removed</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>"openSUSE 11.0 has been End-Of_life for a good while already, but the VLC Repository kept
      on being available for the users still relying on it. There have not been any updates and
      rebuilds for a long time (maintaining new versions became a nightmare, as underlying libraries
      started to be outdated). </para>
    <para>For this reason I’m hereby announcing that the 11.0 repositories will be removed from the
      videolan download infrastructure by <emphasis role="bold">March 1st 2011</emphasis> ! If you
      rely on having the packages available for your personal installations, please make sure to
      create a local copy of the FTP tree. </para>
    <para>On the bright side though: the 11.4 repository has just been uploaded. It is built against
      the latest snapshot of 11.4, which is somewhat between RC1 and RC2. Most likely not much is
      changing that would affect stability of the VLC packages. And like always of course: Factory
      package keep on existing. But they did for a long time already." </para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 20.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://log.or.cz/?p=119">Petr Baudis: Arduino Software Tone
      Generator</ulink></title>
    <para>"This is something really trivial, but I have not actually googled out a recipe so I
      thought I’d post it anyway for the googlers out there. Sometimes, you discover the Arduino
      tune() function does not really work – in our case, it was since we have ethernet shield
      attached and apparently, some other piece of the software drives the timer (not surprising at
      all) – besides, the tune() function may silently abuse other pins than the chosen one, AIUI,
      due to its timer usage."</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 20.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://ungethym.blogspot.com/2011/02/gsoc-mentors-wanted-elegant-display.html">Thomas
        Thym: GSoC: Mentors wanted! - Elegant display settings for presentations</ulink></title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-gyZKgILFwj4/TWDqR2A4SuI/AAAAAAAAAC0/cvVPRXHTlP8/s1600/computer-laptop_and_video-projector.png"
          width="20%"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>"I recently mentored some students during the Google Code In project. Now the <ulink
        url="http://linuxgrandma.blogspot.com/2011/02/gsoc-2011-start-your-engines.html"
        >preparations for Google Summer of Code have begun</ulink>. Unfortunately I am not a hacker,
      I am a promo guy and I can't mentor here. Nevertheless I have some <ulink
        url="http://community.kde.org/GSoC/2011/Ideas">ideas for GSoC</ulink> and I hope to scratch
      somebodies itch so she or he will mentor that idea. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Idea 1: (More elegant) Display settings for presentations
      </emphasis></para>
    <para>Application/component: Plasma </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Brief explanation:</emphasis> The handling of multiple screens has
      continuously improved during the last releases. The handling of a stationary setting of two
      screens seems to be rather good. When it comes to presentation-mode with a projector I would
      be delighted to see even more elegance (simplicity).</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Expected results:</emphasis> When doing presentations there is in
      general only one question to decide. The presentation mode:<orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>The same picture of both screens or </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>The notes on the notebook, the presentation on the projector. </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist></para>
    <para>To 1: Autodetect the smallest max. resolution of the two displays. Instead of scaling the
      picture to full screen it would be nicer to keep the ration and leave some space blank on the
      left and right notebook screen. </para>
    <para>To 2: Autodetect the max. resolution of each of the two displays and set those different
      resolutions. The panel, all the widgets and all the open windows should stay on the notebook
      screen. The projector screen shows only the wallpaper. It does not matter if the projector
      “screen” is located above or on the right or wherever of the notebook screen. </para>
    <para>It would be very useful to link that dialog to the keyboard shortcut (e.g. Fn+F7) or to
      start it automatically when a projector is attached. (At the moment I have to start krandrtray
      from krunner first or have the symbol in the taskbar all the time. I am not sure if a new
      users could work that out in a couple of seconds.) </para>
    <para>Save the display/plasma settings (esp. widget positions etc.) to restore them when the
      projector is detached. (Perhaps that could be solved with activities.) </para>
    <para>Extra points: It is possible to save the standard settings. In a second step different
      screen setting profiles could be saved and loaded (like in powerdevil). Presentation-mode 1
      and 2 could be such profiles and a user could modify them (e.g. projector on top or right) if
      it is necessary. </para>
    <para>So what do you think. Is that scratching your itch? Can you imagine how cool this would be
      to have? At least for me as a presenter that would really rock."</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 21.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://dev-loki.blogspot.com/2011/02/packman-service-interruption-and.html"
        >Pascal Bleser: Packman service interruption and migration</ulink></title>
    <para>The <ulink url="http://packman.links2linux.org/">Packman</ulink> website and <ulink
        url="http://packman.inode.at/suse/">repositories</ulink> are going to be broken and in the
      works for several days (possibly up to a week) starting tonight at 20:00 CET, during which the
      following services will not be available, or only sporadically: <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>the Packman website itself: <ulink url="http://packman.links2linux.org/"
              >http://packman.links2linux.org</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>the Packman repositories, except "Essentials" (see "new repository layout"
            below)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>The reason is that we are performing a major migration of our services to <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>the latest version of the openSUSE Build Service (we were still using an old
            version)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>a new layout of our repositories, to enable a more fine-grained control over what
            parts of Packman should be used (see below)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>In order to try to keep a minimum service going during that time, you may use and point
      people to our new repositories, that already contain the "Essentials" part, which are almost
      complete with the bare minimum everyone needs (mplayer, vlc, libraries, ...). The URLs for the
      new repositories are as follows: <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://packman.inode.at/suse/openSUSE_11.3/"
              >http://packman.inode.at/suse/openSUSE_11.3/</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://packman.inode.at/suse/openSUSE_11.2/"
              >http://packman.inode.at/suse/openSUSE_11.2/</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://packman.inode.at/suse/Factory/"
              >http://packman.inode.at/suse/Factory/</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://packman.inode.at/suse/SLE_11/"
              >http://packman.inode.at/suse/SLE_11/</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>There are no .repo files there yet, so adding one of these is done as
      follows:<screen>zypper ar -n packman http://packman.inode.at/suse/openSUSE_11.3/ packman</screen></para>
    <para>(obviously adapt the URL to your openSUSE version). You may also use one of our mirror
      sites, as they already have our new repositories: <ulink
        url="ftp://packman.links2linux.de/pub/packman/MIRRORS"
        >ftp://packman.links2linux.de/pub/packman/MIRRORS.</ulink></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">New repository layout</emphasis></para>
    <para>As has been announced (including here), we have had a discussion back in December about
      whether and how we should reorganize the layout of our repositories. Up to now, and for many
      years, it has always been "one big repository", which had pros and cons: <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="underline">good</emphasis>: easy to use, just add onr repository and
            be done with it</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="underline">good</emphasis>: easy for us to manage</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="underline">bad</emphasis>: you get everything and the kitchen sink,
            including packages that are duplications of stuff from other repositories, specifically
            from build.opensuse.org (which didn't exist when Packman was created), and potential
            conflicts with those</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="underline">bad</emphasis>: large metadata files to synchronise
            (although zypper has become pretty fast at that)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>We came up with a solution to this, as more and more people requested having split
      repositories, in order to control whatthey want to use from Packman: <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>we will have four repositories instead of one: Essentials, Multimedia, Games and
            Extras</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Essentials will be the bare minimum to get your multimedia experience on openSUSE
            going (libraries, MPlayer, vlc, ffmpeg, ...)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Multimedia will contain additional applications that are not available for openSUSE
            or only in a crippled build, such as avidemux, etc...</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Games are, well, games, although we will try to move most of what may be hosted on
            build.opensuse.org to the games project there</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Extras is all the rest</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>In order to provide the best of both worlds or, rather, still provide you with the old
      option of adding everything, we are using a little trick and are running "createrepo" on the
      top-level directory, which results in having repository metadata that contains all the
      packages from all the above mentioned repositories without having to duplicate the RPM files
      on our server (and mirrors). </para>
    <para>Hence, to make it short and less technical, you can still also use the "old way"
      too.</para>
    <para>As an example of what needs to be added to zypper, once the migration is complete and
      .repo files are available too: <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>add the Essentials
            repository:<screen>zypper ar -r http://packman.inode.at/suse/openSUSE_11.3/Essentials/Essentials.repo</screen></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>add the "everything"
            repository:<screen>zypper ar -r http://packman.inode.at/suse/openSUSE_11.3/packman.repo</screen></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>I will announce our progress <ulink url="http://dev-loki.blogspot.com/">on my blog</ulink>
      (which is also aggregated on <ulink url="http://planet.opensuse.org/">Planet openSUSE</ulink>)
      and will obviously post another announcement here once our migration is complete. </para>
    <para>In advance, sorry for the inconvenience, and thank you for your understanding. We are
      convinced that our move will not only provide us with a better infrastructure, but also
      improve your experience with Packman and openSUSE.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 21.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
