<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb"><title>On the Web</title>Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.novell.com/news/press/2011/5/suse-announces-executive-leadership-team-with-dedicated-focus-on-driving-growth-and-innovation-in-the-linux-marketplace.html">SUSE Announces Executive Leadership Team with Dedicated Focus on Driving Growth and Innovation in the Linux Marketplace</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>SUSE, a new business unit of The Attachmate Group, today announced its organizational focus on developing, marketing and supporting a portfolio of innovative solutions centered around SUSE® Linux Enterprise, the most interoperable platform for <ulink url="http://www.novell.com/linux/missioncritical.html">mission-critical computing</ulink> across physical, virtual and cloud environments. Nils Brauckmann, a 20-year industry veteran with both Attachmate and Novell® heritage, will lead the SUSE organization&apos;s passionate commitment to quality engineering, excellent customer service and open source innovation.</para>
      <para>(...)</para>
      <para>&quot;I am thrilled to lead this business and team in our pursuit of providing comprehensive Linux solutions that solve real problems for IT and the line of business. With a laser focus on making SUSE successful, we are committed to the products and services that our customers and partners rely on to run their businesses. Moreover, we recognize and celebrate the value of the <ulink url="http://www.opensuse.org/">openSUSE</ulink> Project and will remain a strong supporter of the openSUSE community,&quot; said Brauckmann. &quot;We reiterate our long-term commitment to the open source communities at the heart of our ecosystem. Our presence in these communities will help our customers benefit from the rich value of Linux, while encouraging the collaboration that has made Linux the foundation of so many computing environments today.&quot;</para>
      <para>Leading SUSE from its newly based headquarters in Nuremberg, Germany, Brauckmann and his team of experienced industry executives will be responsible for the organization&apos;s continued development and sale of solutions based on SUSE Linux Enterprise, through the Open Platform Solutions division of the former Novell, Inc. Specifically, Brauckmann will drive SUSE sales, marketing, engineering, technical support and consulting and training services that align with customer needs and demands. He will passionately advocate enterprise adoption of open source solutions and support the activities of the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Project">openSUSE community</ulink>. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 19.5.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://tirania.org/blog/archive/2011/May-16.html">Announcing Xamarin</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Today we start<ulink url="http://www.xamarin.com/"> Xamarin</ulink>, our new company focused on Mono-based products.</para>
      <para>These are some of the things that we will be doing at Xamarin:

    </para>
      <para>* Build a new commercial .NET offering for iOS
    </para>
      <para>* Build a new commercial .NET offering for Android
    </para>
      <para>* Continue to contribute, maintain and develop the open source Mono and Moonlight components.
    </para>
      <para>* Explore the Moonlight opportunities in the mobile space and the Mac appstore. </para>
      <para>(...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 19.5.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2><!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxfoundation.org/collaborate/workgroups/lsb/fhs">The Filesystem Hierarchy Standard (FHS)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The LSB workgroup is preparing FHS 3.0, which will be the first FHS release since 2004. As part of that release, we are soliciting contributions from all interested parties.

</para>
      <para>Our goal is to release FHS 3.0 by July 1 if possible. (...)</para>
  </blockquote> 
  </sect2> --><sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/security/news/item/Getting-a-grip-on-Flash-cookies-Adobe-publishes-Flash-10-3-1242645.html">h-online: Getting a grip on Flash cookies: Adobe publishes Flash 10.3 </ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Adobe has <ulink url="http://kb2.adobe.com/cps/901/cpsid_90194.html?cjsku=47050364&amp;PID=3848922">published</ulink> version 10.3 of its <ulink url="http://get.adobe.com/flashplayer/">Flash Player</ulink> for all platforms. This version finally gives users control of their
        Flash cookies, but only if one of the currently supported web browsers is used: <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/What-s-new-in-Firefox-4-0-1212755.html">Firefoxý4</ulink>, <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/news/item/Chrome-11-Google-s-web-browser-learns-to-listen-1233908.html">Chromeý11</ulink>, Internet Explorerý8 (or higher) and, soon, Safari. The new
        ClearSiteData API allows the browser to <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/news/item/Chrome-12-Beta-brings-Flash-cookie-protection-1240386.html">take care</ulink> of Flash cookies (LSOs – Local Shared Objects), which it can manage as
        though they were normal cookies. Up until this release, users had to visit the <ulink url="http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html">Settings Manager</ulink> on Adobe&apos;s website to handle the stubborn Flash cookies.</para>
      <para>Under Windows, Flash cookies can also be managed via a new entry in the control panel.
        Here, users will also find all of the settings that concern security and privacy. Flashý10.3
        now also alerts Mac OSýX users about updates automatically. Developers of VoIP applications
        can now access echo and noise suppression. Adobe has integrated the Media Measurement
        analysis function that provides developers with detailed usage statistics in combination
        with <ulink url="http://www.omniture.com/en/products/online_analytics/sitecatalyst">SiteCatalyst</ulink>. The update for <ulink url="http://labs.adobe.com/technologies/flashplatformruntimes/incubator/features/">Flash Player Incubator</ulink>, Adobe&apos;s test bed for new functions, will be of interest for
        developers with its JSON support and secure random number generator.</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 16.5.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/open/news/item/De-Icaza-announces-new-Mono-centric-company-Xamarin-1244119.html">h-online: De Icaza announces new Mono-centric company - Xamarin</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Miguel de Icaza has&#160;<ulink url="http://tirania.org/blog/archive/2011/May-16.html">announced</ulink>&#160;the launch of&#160;<ulink url="http://www.xamarin.com/">Xamarin</ulink>, a
        company dedicated to creating Mono-based products. Those products will include new
        commercial .NET products for iOS and Android, similar to and source-compatible with
        MonoTouch and MonoDroid, developed from scratch and based on the open source Mono but still
        not open source. Xamarin will also be exploring possible opportunities for Moonlight in
        mobile and in the Mac app store. Icaza adds that the new company will continue to make code
        contributions, maintain and develop both open source Mono and the Moonlight
        components.</para>
      <para>De Icaza has also finally given public confirmation that Attachmate began laying off all
        the Mono developers, starting with those in Canada and America, on 2 May, followed by the
        Europe, Brazil and Japan teams in the days following. This included all the MonoTouch and
        MonoDroid engineers and other key Mono developers. The layoffs happened amid the&#160;<ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/news/item/Layoffs-begin-at-Novell-s-Utah-base-1236676.html">wider layoffs</ulink>&#160;that were instituted by Novell&apos;s new owners. Attachmate would not
        comment on who had been laid off and claimed that &quot;all technology roadmaps remain
        intact&quot;.</para>
<!--($ ld: 17.5.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.fsf.org/blogs/rms/microsoft-skype">Free Software Foundation/Richard Stallman: Microsoft Skype</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>How will this affect the success of Skype&apos;s spyware, they ask? Was it good strategy for
        one or the other? Did Microsoft pay too much? How does this affect the possible success of
        this or that other company? Questions whose perspective regards people as nothing more than
        terrain for these nonhumans to squabble over. </para>
      <para>All those questions alter nothing that matters for us. </para>
      <para>The Skype client program is nonfree software: it gives its owner power over its users.
        Presently it will give the same power to a different company. The identify of the master is
        just a detail, because freedom means not having a master. </para>
      <para>One part of freedom, for computer users, is not using Skype. </para>
      <para>The GNU Project is developing <ulink url="http://www.gnutelephony.org/index.php/GNU_Telephony">free software to do more or less the same job</ulink>, and multiple free programs <ulink url="http://directory.fsf.org/category/tel/">by others</ulink> also already do the basics.
        When free software makes it possible to do full-featured VOIP while maintaining your
        freedom, that will be a real change. </para>
      <para>Replacing Skype with free software is an FSF <ulink url="http://www.fsf.org/campaigns/priority-projects/#skypereplacement">High Priority Project</ulink>.</para>
<!--($ ld: 18.5.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://linuxconfig.org/linux-job-portal-launched-linuxcareercom">Linuxconfig.org: Linux job portal launched: LinuxCareer.com</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>As a demand for Linux-related jobs has jumped unexpectedly high in the last couple of years, <ulink url="LinuxCareer.com">LinuxCareer.com</ulink> as a new Linux related job portal attempts to compensate for this sudden surge in demand for Linux skilled professionals and will surely accommodate both employers and job seekers.  LinuxCareer.com is not affiliated with any local or international company, nor is it a recruitment or employment agency and it is specialising only in Linux based careers and closely related Information Technology fields. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 19.5.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2><sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxaria.com/pills/cheat-sheet-collection-best?lang=en">Linuxaria: Cheat Sheet collection</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>For <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cheat_sheet">Wikipedia</ulink>: A cheat sheet or crib sheet is a concise set of notes used for quick reference. “Cheat sheet” may also be rendered “cheatsheet”.

</para>
      <para>People working in informatics in general and on unix terminals in particular know that is not so easy remember every single command and so it’s usual to have “Cheat Sheet”, a collection of the most useful commands in a single A4 page for a particular program or environment.

</para>
      <para>And this is my small collection. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 19.5.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2><sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://blog.jprosevear.org/2011/05/13/webgl-security/">JP Rosevear: WebGL</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Recently Context Information Security Limited gathered a lot of attention for <ulink url="http://contextis.co.uk/resources/blog/webgl/">a blog post on the state of WebGL security</ulink>. For Mozilla, <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WebGL">WebGL</ulink> was first released in Firefox 4, and there are implementations in Chrome,
        Safari and Opera as well. The blog post outlines an abstract concern that WebGL is
        inherently insecure because it allows fairly direct access to the hardware, along with two
        specific attacks, a Denial of Service and a Cross-Domain Image Theft.</para>
      <para>The Denial of Service attack does not generally endanger user data or privacy, but it
        can be highly annoying for users, not unlike sites that pop up multiple dialogs or have
        long-running javascript that hangs the browser. The Khronos WebGL working group has been
        aware of this type of issue for some time and has discussed it openly. Shader validation can
        help somewhat, as can <ulink url="http://www.opengl.org/registry/specs/ARB/robustness.txt">GL_ARB_robustness</ulink>, but the forthcoming GL_ARB_robustness_2 extension will help
        even more. There are also user confirmation approaches available as well depending on what
        real world data we uncover over time. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 14.5.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2><!--<sect2>
  <title>LOL</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://xkcd.com/874/">XKCD: Time Management</ulink>
    </title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/time_management.png" width="50%"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.5/">CC-BY-NC</ulink></para>
  </blockquote>
</sect2>--></sect1>
