<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="tipsandtricks">
  <title>Tips and Tricks</title>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Desktop Users</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.unixmen.com/linux-tutorials/documentations-a-howto/1578-upgrade-opensuse-to-114">Unixmen: Howto upgrade Opensuse to 11.4</ulink>
      </title>
      <para> How to upgrade Opensuse 11.x to 11.4 ? Unixmen gives the answer... (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 28.3.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://masterpatricko.blogspot.com/2011/03/opensuse-114-first-steps.html">Tejas Guruswamy: openSUSE 11.4 - first steps</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Finally term is over and I&apos;m on my Easter break, which means I can step up my
        contributions again. First step was to install the new release on my desktop - openSUSE 11.4
        looks really, really good! No hassles during installation at all, took about 20mins from
        DVD. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 28.3.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Commandline/Script Newbies</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.unixmen.com/linux-commands/1602-watch-al-jazeera-live-with-one-command">Unixmen/M. Zinoune (Zinovsky): Watch Al Jazeera Live in Linux with one command</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>If you are a fun of Aljazeera News channel, this is a nice command that allow you to
        watch Al Jazeera live in your Linux desktop. I tested the command and is working like a
        charm.</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://cdn.unixmen.com/images/stories/thumbnails/images-stories-videos-aljazeera1-400x225.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>First check if you have rtmpdump installed, if not install it using the command
        :<screen>sudo apt-get install rtmpdump</screen></para>
      <para>Now to start watching Aljazeera live, open terminal and enter the following
        command</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">To use Mplayer :</emphasis><programlisting><emphasis role="bold">$ rtmpdump -v -r rtmp://livestfslivefs.fplive.net/livestfslive-live/ -y &quot;aljazeera_en_veryhigh&quot; -a &quot;aljazeeraflashlive-live&quot; -o -| mplayer -</emphasis></programlisting></para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">To use VLC player:</emphasis><screen>$<emphasis role="bold">
            <emphasis role="bold"> rtmpdump -v -r rtmp://livestfslivefs.fplive.net/livestfslive-live/ -y &quot;aljazeera_en_veryhigh&quot; -a &quot;aljazeeraflashlive-live&quot; -o -| vlc -</emphasis>
          </emphasis></screen></para>
      <para>Enjoy :)</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Editors Note:</emphasis> For openSUSE you should install via:
          <emphasis role="italic">zypper in rtmpdump</emphasis> instead of sudo apt-get</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 30.3.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Developers and Programmers</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://dominique.leuenberger.net/blog/?p=178">Dominique Leuenberger: how to fix brp and rpmlint warnings – today:I: Program causes undefined operation(likely same variable used twice and post/pre incremented in the same expression)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>It seems the planned series sort of finds an audience, which in turn of course is
        motivational to keep on writing it. Today, we’ll have a look at this Informational message
        in BRP
        checks:<screen>I: Program causes undefined operation
 (likely same variable used twice and post/pre incremented in the same expression).
 e.g. x = x++; Split it in two operations.</screen></para>
      <para>This is currently informational only and is not failing the build, but you might want to
        address them together with upstream. </para>
      <para>I assume you do know what “a++” means in C (otherwise, you should start reading
        C-books), so we just try to reproduce this error in a simple c test
        case:<screen>#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;
 
int main() {
 int i=5;
 i = i++ * ++i;
 printf(&quot;The current value of i is %d\n&quot;, i);
 return 0;
 }</screen></para>
      <para>When building this using gcc -Wall test.c, we get this compiler warning (which in turn
        is what brp translates to the information we’re discussing
        here)<screen>&gt; gcc -Wall test2.c
 test.c: In function ‘main’:
 test.c:5:5: warning: operation on ‘i’ may be undefined</screen></para>
      <para>So, let’s first see for ourselves what we would expect this to be? Hmm.. already for us,
        this looks not logic (and I surely hope nobody would write this code). Let’s just see what
        starting this executable gives shall we?<screen>The current value of i is 37</screen></para>
      <para>Now, is this surprising? We multiplied, assigned it to i and as a result we get a prime
        number? By closely analyzing the line you will likely understand what the compiler did. But
        was this expected? If this is actually what the programmer intended, the code should just be
        rewritten to be more logical, like:<screen>i = (i+1) ^2 + 1;</screen></para>
      <para>This is understandable for all of us and does not yield the surprise of what is going
        on.</para>
      <para>And that is actually all this warning is about: it requests the programmer to write code
        that can be understood and does not depend on what the compiler interprets. It might even
        very well be that the different optimization levels or the usage of different compilers
        might end up in different results.</para>
      <para>If you want to read some more about this topic, I suggest to have a look at:<itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sequence_point">Wikipedia</ulink></para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink url="http://publications.gbdirect.co.uk/c_book/chapter8/sequence_points.html">http://publications.gbdirect.co.uk/c_book/chapter8/sequence_points.html</ulink></para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
<!-- ($ Id: 28.3.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For System Administrators</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.serverwatch.com/tutorials/article.php/3929346/article.htm">Serverwatch/Juliet Kemp: Use Linux and WebDAV to Facilitate Online Collaboration</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The WebDAV protocol enables users to store and share files via HTTP. This is
        particularly valuable in cases where HTTP is usually read-only, as WebDAV allows writing as
        well. In addition to accessing documents, users can (with suitable permissions) edit and
        re-upload them. Think of it as a networked file-system run over HTTP; or as a way of
        supporting long-distance collaboration on files. The protocol supports locking and
        versioning information, so once you&apos;ve accessed the WebDAV folder, you can edit files
        without risking overwriting other people&apos;s edits. These days, there are more and more ways
        available to undertake online collaboration, but WebDAV remains a useful and straightforward
        way to share files, especially as it&apos;s supported by plenty of software at both server and
        client end. (...)</para>
<!--($ Id: 30.3.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.howtoforge.com/perfect-server-opensuse-11.4-x86_64-ispconfig-2">HowtoForge/Falko Timme: The Perfect Server - OpenSUSE 11.4 x86_64 [ISPConfig 2]</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>This is a detailed description about how to set up an OpenSUSE 11.4 server (x86_64) that offers all services needed by ISPs and hosters: Apache web server (SSL-capable), Postfix mail server with SMTP-AUTH and TLS, BIND DNS server, Proftpd FTP server, MySQL server, Dovecot POP3/IMAP, Quota, Firewall, etc. In the end you should have a system that works reliably, and if you like you can install the free webhosting control panel ISPConfig 2 (i.e., ISPConfig runs on it out of the box).

</para>
      <para>I will use the following software:

    </para>
      <para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Web Server: Apache 2.2.17 with PHP 5.3.5, Ruby, and Python </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Database Server: MySQL 5.1.53</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Mail Server: Postfix </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>DNS Server: BIND9 </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>FTP Server: proftpd * POP3/IMAP: I will use Maildir format and therefore install
              Courier-POP3/Courier-IMAP. </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Webalizer for web site statistics </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </para>
      <para>Please note that this setup does not work for ISPConfig 3! It is valid for ISPConfig 2 only! (...)</para>
<!--($ Id: 2.4.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
