<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
<!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.marketwire.com/press-release/statements-on-openofficeorg-contribution-to-apache-nasdaq-orcl-1521400.htm">Statements on OpenOffice.org Contribution to Apache</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>REDWOOD SHORES, CA--(Marketwire - Jun 1, 2011) - &quot;With today&apos;s proposal to contribute the OpenOffice.org code to The Apache Software Foundation&apos;s Incubator, Oracle continues to demonstrate its commitment to the developer and open source communities. Donating OpenOffice.org to Apache gives this popular consumer software a mature, open, and well established infrastructure to continue well into the future. The Apache Software Foundation&apos;s model makes it possible for commercial and individual volunteer contributors to collaborate on open source product development.&quot; -- Luke Kowalski, vice president, Oracle Corporate Architecture Group. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 3.6.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
<!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/open/news/item/GNOME-and-KDE-2011-Desktop-Summit-programme-published-1246775.html">h-online/Chris von Eitzen: GNOME and KDE 2011 Desktop Summit programme published</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The GNOME Foundation and KDE e.V. boards have published the <ulink url="https://www.desktopsummit.org/program">programme</ulink> for this year&apos;s <ulink url="https://www.desktopsummit.org/about">Desktop Summit</ulink>. Following the opening keynote, attendees can visit one of four different rooms, each with a variety of tracks including community, applications, platforms, tablets, development and accessibility &amp; help.</para>
      <para>The 2011 event will take place over the course of a week from 6 to 12 August at the <ulink url="http://www.hu-berlin.de/standardseite-en">Humboldt University</ulink> in Berlin, Germany; it is open to developers, community members and users alike. The joint conference is supported locally by the Berlin Senate and the TSB Innovation Agency Berlin GmbH, and is expected to bring together more than one thousand core contributors, open source leaders and representatives from government, education and corporate environments. (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://aseigo.blogspot.com/2011/05/plasma-active-quick-catch-up.html"> Aaron Seigo: Plasma Active: Quick Catch-Up! </ulink>
      </title>
      <para>(<emphasis role="bold">Note</emphasis>: This post is about Plasma Active, a community
        collaboration to bring KDE software to consumer devices. To learn more about Plasma Active,
          <ulink url="http://aseigo.blogspot.com/2011/04/active-routes.html">read this blog post</ulink>.) </para>
      <para>We&apos;ve been a bit quiet lately around the Plasma Active farm. This is mostly due to us
        being rather busy, both with technical as well as organizational tasks. On the technology
        front, things continue to plow forward at a very brisk pace with <ulink url="http://community.kde.org/Plasma/Active/Contour">Contour</ulink> shaping up with every
        passing day and libplasma2 (a big part of the Plasma Quick track) zipping ahead nicely. </para>
      <para>Organizationally, we&apos;re learning new lessons every day as to how to best coordinate
        efforts between companies currently involved and reaching out to ones that should be
        involved. <ulink url="http://www.basyskom.com/">Basyskom</ulink> sent a bunch of people to
        the recent MeeGo conf, and the response was fantastic, including some <ulink url="http://www.ubergizmo.com/2011/05/basyskom-shows-off-new-meego-ui-design/">bloggers</ulink><ulink url="http://www.netbooknews.com/26445/basyskom-demos-meego-user-interface-contour-peregrine/">writing</ulink> about the demo that was on offer.</para>
      <para>There&apos;s also been some learning-as-we-grow happening that has hampered outbound
        communication somewhat. For some of the people involved, this is their very first open
        source experience. For others, this is their first foray into the interesting world of
        devices. While it is terrific to expand our merry band of freedom makers, it also has meant
        some learning curves.</para>
      <para>Amongst all that, code is getting written, the user experience design continues to
        mature and new operating system images are being spun. All is good in the land of technical
        progress. Marco is hanging out at my place for a couple days prior to the upcoming Platform
        11 meeting (which starts Wednesday) and we&apos;re getting some work done at a nice pace. </para>
      <para>Today we&apos;re working on Share-Like-Connect and building integration points in Contour for
        it.I am, however, behind on posting news about new Active Apps as well, which I&apos;m going to
        remedy in a moment.</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 31.5.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://aseigo.blogspot.com/2011/05/plasma-active-marble-to-go.html"> Aaron Seigo: Plasma Active: Marble To Go! </ulink>
      </title>
      <para>(<emphasis role="bold">Note</emphasis>: This post is about Plasma Active, a community
        collaboration to bring KDE software to consumer devices. To learn more about Plasma Active,
          <ulink url="http://aseigo.blogspot.com/2011/04/active-routes.html">read this blog post</ulink>.) </para>
      <para>What is an Active App? It&apos;s a project built with Qt and/or KDE libraries that fits into
        the spirit and use cases of Plasma Active. That means it needs to be touch friendly,
        preferably present the user interface with QtQuick, have a nice separation between data and
        visualization where appropriate and integrate well with the platform.</para>
      <para>In the Plasma Active meta-project, which includes things like Contour and live OS
        images, we&apos;re building up a small army of such apps in the hopes that those projects can
        learn from each other and us from them. It will also help ensure that when someone goes to
        use a Plasma Active device, they don&apos;t just have the Contour user experience but also a host
        of useful stand-alone applications as well.</para>
      <para>I announced our first Active App a couple weeks back: <ulink url="http://community.kde.org/Calligra">Calligra</ulink>. Today, we add another to the
        books: <ulink url="http://edu.kde.org/marble/">Marble</ulink>!Marble has already had a
        mobile version for some time, and since mapping is very important functionality for devices
        you carry around with you it was only natural for Plasma Active to meet Marble.</para>
      <para>There is a project going on right now to provide a QtQuick interface to Marble, and we
        will be including this effort in the live images as it matures.</para>
<!--($ ld: 31.5.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.ubuntuvibes.com/2011/05/opensuse-workstations-used-for.html">Ubuntu Vibes/Nitesh: OpenSUSE Workstations Used for Rendering Real Facial Expressions in L.A. Noire (By Rockstar Games)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Couple of days back, we reported that how a <ulink url="http://www.ubuntuvibes.com/2011/05/fedora-kde-system-spotted-running-maya.html">Fedora system running KDE SC4</ulink> was used for Animation production in BBC&apos;s Doctor Who Series.</para>
      <para>Here is yet another instance where Linux systems are being used for production in entertainment industry. This time <ulink url="http://www.rockstargames.com/">Rockstar games</ulink>, who gave the world Grand Theft Auto series used Linux systems (OpenSUSE/SUSE Linux) in rendering real life facial expressions to the characters in their game <ulink url="http://www.rockstargames.com/lanoire/">L.A. Noire</ulink> (released on May 17th). Again, KDE is used as the desktop environment. Though I am not able to identify which software (not seems to be native) is being run on the system. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 3.6.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://mybroadband.co.za/news/internet/20495-printing-out-of-the-cloud.html">MyBroadband/Alastair Otter: Printing out of the cloud</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Forget the networked printer. The cloud printer is coming</emphasis></para>
      <para>Most PC users have used a networked printer at one time or other. Soon, printing documents over the Internet may become just as commonplace. Especially if Google has its way.</para>
      <para>Google’s long-awaited <ulink url="http://code.google.com/apis/cloudprint/docs/overview.html">Cloud Print</ulink> service was unveiled as a beta earlier this year. The service allows users to setup a printer and then print to it over the internet. This includes being able to print from a mobile device to a remote internet-connected PC anywhere in the world. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 3.6.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/security/news/item/Skype-protocol-being-reverse-engineered-1254721.html">h-online/Dj Walker-Morgan: Skype protocol being reverse engineered</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>A freelance researcher named Efim Bushmanov has created a site named &quot;<ulink url="http://skype-open-source.blogspot.com/">skype-open-source</ulink>&quot; and says that he
        is reverse engineering the VoIP service Skype &quot;to make skype open source&quot;. Skype&apos;s
        proprietary protocols have allowed the company to maintain control over its peer-to-peer
        voice and video communications network and have been the subject of various types of
        research over the years.</para>
      <para>Bushmanov is not taking a clean room approach, where a researcher examines the network
        inputs and outputs of the software. He has instead opted for the potentially riskier process
          of&#160;<ulink url="http://skype-open-source.blogspot.com/2011/06/when-binary-files-is-not-just-general.html">modifying</ulink>&#160;the Skype binary files to remove autoupdate, obfuscation and
        anti-debugging measures. Bushmanov may also be taking a risk by redistributing these
        modified files; they are easier to decompile and it is easier to trace and log what the code
        does, but they are still Skype&apos;s intellectual property.</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 3.6.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://ostatic.com/blog/google-releases-voice-and-video-chat-technology-as-open-source">OStatic/Sam Dean: Google Releases Voice and Video Chat Technology As Open Source</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Among major technology companies, Google open sources many of its own projects at a prolific rate, and now the company has announced that it is open sourcing WebRTC, an open technology for voice and video on the web. The code and API are <ulink url="http://sites.google.com/site/webrtc/">available here</ulink>. WebRTC is a free, open project that enables web browsers with Real-Time Communications (RTC) capabilities via simple Javascript APIs. According to Google: &quot;This first release of WebRTC is mainly targeted at the browser community. It enables browser vendors to integrate the components required for rich communication into their web browsers.&quot; (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 4.6.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxuser.co.uk/news/the-issue-of-bringing-harmony-to-copyright-assignment/">Linux User &amp; Developer/Jos Poortvliet: The issue of bringing harmony to copyright assignment</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Identi.ca has been buzzing with ‘project Harmony’ discussions lately. Harmony aims to be the ‘Creative Commons’ of Copyright Assignment Agreements (CAAs). A CAA is basically a contract you sign where you give away ownership of your code, and some free software projects already allow or even demand this for contributions. The Free Software Foundation itself, for example, requires a CAA.</para>
      <para>Essentially, they want to own the code so they can sue anyone who doesn’t abide by the GPL licence (and upgrade to newer versions of the GPL). Other projects have non-mandatory CAAs for similar reasons. I’m not convinced you really need a CAA, however. Several projects including Linux itself have sued copyright violators successfully without it and you can have a ‘GPLv3+’ licence if you want to move to a newer GPL in the future. But in case of a charitable institution, I guess it probably doesn’t hurt.

(...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 3.6.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.techrepublic.com/blog/opensource/shouldnt-linux-embrace-drm/2569">TechRepublic/Jack Wallen: Shouldn&apos;t Linux embrace DRM?</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>I want to preface this entry by stating something very important to me and my world. I am a writer. Not just a writer of technical documentation, how-tos, and other sundry articles, but a writer of fiction. I currently have three published books (you can find them in both paperback and ebook format on <ulink url="http://www.amazon.com/">Amazon</ulink> and <ulink url="http://productsearch.barnesandnoble.com/">Barnes &amp; Noble</ulink>) and, I get the argument on both sides of the DRM fence.</para>
      <para>What’s DRM? Simple. Digital Rights Management (DRM) is a term for access control technologies that are used by hardware manufacturers, publishers, copyright holders to limit the use of digital content and devices. In other words, I have created a piece of digital content and I want to ensure it is clear who the holder of the copyright is, but also that I get paid for the content I have created. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 3.6.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://blog.internetnews.com/skerner/2011/06/oracle-gives-openoffice-to-apa.html">internetnews.com/Sean Michael Kerner: Oracle gives OpenOffice to Apache - What a Terrible move</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>From the &apos;That Makes No Sense&apos; files:</para>
      <para>Oracle announced this AM that it was giving the OpenOffice.org open source project to Apache. The effort has already been endorsed by IBM as well.</para>
      <para>To me this move makes no sense at all.</para>
      <para>Oracle and Sun before them, messed up the OpenOffice.org community which is what eventually led to the LibreOffice fork. Oracle earlier this year finally admitted that it was the right thing to do to give OpenOffice back to the community, and hey now they&apos;ve decided that Apache is the right community. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 3.6.11 sat $) --><!--Note for Japanese translation: This article is already translated into Japanese - http://japan.internet.com/busnews/20110602/3.html-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linux.com/learn/tutorials/453689:weekend-project-write-and-publish-ebooks-on-linux-with-sigil">Linux.com/Joe Brockmeier: Weekend Project: Write and Publish eBooks on Linux with Sigil</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Calling all writers — do you have a book you want to publish as an eBook? Ready to
        self-publish? Maybe you just want to provide some documentation in EPUB formats? Whether you
        want to publish prose, poems, or help the world RTFM,&#160;<ulink url="http://code.google.com/p/sigil/">Sigil</ulink>&#160;can help tame the text and massage it
        into the industry standard EPUB format.</para>
      <para>What&apos;s Sigil? It&apos;s a What You See Is What You Get (WYSIWYG) ebook editor that&apos;s open
        source (GPLv3) and runs on Linux. Which makes it&#160;<emphasis role="italic">perfect</emphasis>&#160;for our needs. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 4.6.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
<!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://omgsuse.com/content/yet-another-flash-player-security-update">OMG!SUSE! team: Yet another Flash Player security update</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Security Team member <ulink url="http://www.suse.de/~thomas/">Thomas Biege</ulink>
        published an advisory this morning more critical security updates in..you guessed it:
        <emphasis role="bold">flash-player</emphasis>.</para>
      <para>According to the security announcement this package update affects openSUSE 11.3, 11.4
        as well as SUSE Enterprise Linux Desktop 10 SP4 and 11 SP1. This announcement also mentions
        that this is a <emphasis role="bold">remote code execution</emphasis> vulnerability, which
        means not updating to the latest flash-player package will leave you open to attackers
        running programs and exploits on your machine!</para>
      <para>Adobe has posted more <ulink url="http://www.adobe.com/support/security/bulletins/apsb11-12.html">details on this bulletin on their site</ulink> if you&apos;re <emphasis role="italic">that</emphasis>
        interested in the different issues this fix addresses.</para>
      <para>For most users, you&apos;ll just need to follow these steps:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Open up <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/YaST2-GTK">Yast2</ulink><emphasis role="bold">or</emphasis> click on the &quot;Online Update&quot; applet running in your GNOME or
            KDE panels</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Select the flash-player update and install it</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Make sure you restart <emphasis role="bold">
            <emphasis role="italic">all</emphasis>
          </emphasis> of your browsers, this will ensure that no program is
            running the older vulnerable flash-player package</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Relax with a Long Island Ice Tea</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
          </blockquote>
  </sect2> --><!--<sect2>
  <title>LOL</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://xkcd.com/874/">XKCD: Time Management</ulink>
    </title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/time_management.png" width="50%"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.5/">CC-BY-NC</ulink></para>
  </blockquote>
</sect2>--></sect1>
