<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
  <!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://www.opendocsociety.org/news/odf-tc-approves-odf-1.2">Opensociety:
          ODF 1.2 approved as Committee Specification</ulink></title>
      <para>The OASIS Open Document Format for Office Applications (OpenDocument) TC has officially
        and unanimously <ulink
          url="http://lists.oasis-open.org/archives/office/201103/msg00089.html">approved</ulink>
        ODF 1.2 as a Committee Specification. The new version of the standard has taken four years
        to complete and has been adopted by many applications already. Next stage is the official
        vote within OASIS to adopt this specification as an OASIS standard. OASIS is the designated
        maintenance body for ISO/IEC JTC1 SC34 IS26300.</para>
      <para>ODF describes an XML-based application-independent and platform-independent digital
        document file format, as well as the characteristics of software applications which read,
        write and process such documents. The ODF standard is applicable to document authoring,
        editing, viewing, exchange and archiving, including text documents, spreadsheets,
        presentation graphics, drawings, charts and similar documents commonly used by personal
        productivity software applications. A significant number of governments worldwide have
        chosen ODF as the standard for exchanging documents within government and with external
        contacts such citizens and companies.</para>
      <para>OpenDoc Society congratulates the members of the ODF TC on their work. <quote>This is an
          important step for the entire ecosystem</quote>, states Michiel Leenaars, board member of
        OpenDoc Society, <quote>There is significant demand for this new version of the standard, as
          it enables new exiting and unique features such as RDF metadata, advanced digital
          signatures and enhances key areas of ODF such as formula's. That means the next stage of
          interoperability for office applications is finally there</quote>. With already very
        strong vendor support for the new version of the standard and the formal adoption as an
        OASIS standard likely to occur in a matter of several weeks (i.e. a 30 day ballot period),
        OpenDoc Society encourages customers to evaluate and start planning the adoption of ODF
        1.2.</para>
      <!--($ ld: 29.3.11 sm $)-->   
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://www.computerworld.com/s/article/9215252/10_ways_that_Linux_is_making_life_better"
          >Computerworld/Katherine Noyes: 10 ways that Linux is making life better</ulink></title>
      <para id="first_paragraph">Linux has long played a leading role <ulink
          url="http://www.pcworld.com/businesscenter/article/204423/five_reasons_linux_beats_windows_for_servers.html"
          >in the world of servers</ulink>, due in large part to its stability, security and lower
        total cost of ownership (TCO). What many don't realize, however, is just how ubiquitous it's
        becoming in other parts of life as well.</para>
      <para>Not only are distributions like <ulink
          url="http://www.pcworld.com/businesscenter/article/221517/work_begins_on_ubuntu_1110_oneiric_ocelot.html"
          >Ubuntu</ulink> helping Linux make great strides <ulink
          url="http://www.pcworld.com/businesscenter/article/208111/reports_of_linuxs_desktop_death_are_premature.html"
          >on the desktop</ulink>, but the open-source operating system is now quietly powering
        myriad innovations that many of us take for granted.</para>
      <para>Where can Linux be found today? Let's count just a few of the many places it's making
        life better. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 28.3.11 sm $) -->    
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blogs.fsfe.org/mario/?p=130">Mario Fux: We need you for Nepomuk
          (integration)!</ulink></title>
      <para>First I’d like to thank David Vignoni for his work on the logo for the Randa meeting.
        It’s the basis for the work of the <ulink url="http://blogs.fsfe.org/mario/?p=121">young
          informatic trainees</ulink>. But the results are still secret (as even I haven’t seen
        anything myself but get the first results at the end of this week <inlinemediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://blogs.fsfe.org/mario/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif"/>
          </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject> .</para>
      <para>And now to the ideas and proposals (btw this has nothing in common with the <ulink
          url="http://community.kde.org/GSoC/2011/Ideas">GSoC ideas of KDE</ulink>!). As you
        probably or hopefully already know the <ulink url="http://nepomuk.kde.org">KDE Nepomuk
          team</ulink> will have a meeting in <ulink url="http://community.kde.org/Sprints/Randa"
          >Randa</ulink> this June (from the 1st to the 7th of this month) and we still want
        application developers to integrate this technology in their application or to work on some
        interesting and great new ideas. And there will be really good help as <ulink
          url="http://trueg.wordpress.com/">Sebastian Trýg</ulink> will be in Randa and he is going
        to do one or the other workshop of Nepomuk basics. And here are some ideas and thoughts of
        mine to start your imagination engines:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>The KDE semantic clipboard. There is <ulink
              url="http://websvn.kde.org/trunk/playground/base/nepomuk-kde/semclip/">some
              code</ulink> in the old subversion playground of KDE and in December 2010 I wrote a
              <ulink url="http://blogs.fsfe.org/mario/thesis_template.pdf">paper</ulink> about this
            topic. In short, this clipboard enhances to normal one with the capability of knowing
            what (in the context of meaning) it copy-and-pastes. This clipboard does not just copy
            numbers and formatting but addresses, geographic coordinates or blbliographic
            references. Take a look and bring it to a releasable state. There are even some solution
            proposals in the above mentioned paper.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>All of the new <ulink url="http://community.kde.org/KDE_PIM">KDE PIM</ulink>
            application use Nepomuk technology through their <ulink
              url="http://community.kde.org/KDE_PIM/Akonadi">Akonadi</ulink> interactions.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://www.digikam.org">Digikam</ulink> had (or has?) some capabilities
            to exchange its information and metadata with the Nepomuk storage. What about tagging
            your pictures with the contacts (and <ulink
              url="http://www.semanticdesktop.org/ontologies/pimo/">PIMO::Persons</ulink>) of the
            new Kaddressbook and projects which are then usable system wide.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>And <ulink url="http://amarok.kde.org">Amarok</ulink> had (or again has?) some
            functions to share it’s music database with Nepomuk and thus make it system wide and not
            just enclosed in one applicatition.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>But there are as well good examples for existing Nepomuk integration: <ulink
              url="http://bangarangkde.wordpress.com/">Bangarang</ulink>. A multimedia player which
            remembers what you like, what music and videos you have on your system and where is more
            information about this media data (in the web).</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Another idea could be a (scientific) paper or article collector which understands
            the connections (or quotations) between the articles and that the strings at the top
            (authors) are actually persons and the references at the end of the articles are
            actually links and thus relations to other papers and articles. Take a look at the
              <ulink url="http://ontoware.org/swrc/">SWRC ontology</ulink>.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Yet another project which extensively uses Nepomuk is the new <ulink
              url="http://community.kde.org/Real-Time_Communication_and_Collaboration">KDE Telepathy
              framework</ulink>. They don’t just invent yet another represenation of a person and
            its contacts but use PIMO::Person and thus make connections to them system wide
            comprehensible and reusable.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>And let’s not forget the <ulink url="http://plasma.kde.org">Plasma framework</ulink>
            and its <ulink url="http://userbase.kde.org/Plasma#Activities">activities</ulink>. But
            there is more and better information about this on the <ulink
              url="http://ivan.fomentgroup.org/blog/">site of ivan Cukic</ulink>.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Or something completely new. An ontology for TV series, recordings and shows…
            (Update: Sebastian told me that there is already one: <ulink
              url="http://sourceforge.net/apps/trac/oscaf/ticket/44">NMM</ulink>. And Bangarang and
            some other applications use it.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>And there is <ulink url="http://zeitgeist-project.com/">Zeitgeist</ulink> and <ulink
              url="http://releases.zeitgeist-project.com/qzeitgeist/">QtZeitgeist</ulink>…
            (...)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <!--($ ld: 30.3.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://www.h-online.com/open/news/item/openSUSE-11-4-Edu-Li-f-e-released-1217365.html"
          >h-online: openSUSE 11.4 Edu Li-f-e released</ulink></title>
      <para>Just over two weeks after the release of openSUSE 11.4, the <ulink
          url="http://en.opensuse.org/Education">openSUSE Education</ulink> development team has
        announced the availability of openSUSE 11.4 Edu: Linux for Education (Li-f-e). The Edu
        Li-f-e edition is a customised variant of the openSUSE aimed at education. It includes
        selected applications and resources for students and educators, including parents, and
        attempts to offer a system which can be productively used at home or in an educational
        establishment. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 29.3.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://linuxblog.darkduck.com/2011/03/kde-or-gnome.html">Unixmen/M. Zinoune
          (Zinovsky): OpenSUSE Edu Li-f-e 11.4 for education is released!</ulink></title>
      <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/29/opensuse-edu-li-f-e-11-4-out-now/"
          >OpenSUSE Edu Li-f-e 11.4 </ulink>for education is released. Based on <ulink
          url="http://www.unixmen.com/linux-tutorials/linux-distributions/suse/1558-opensuse-114-is-released-with-screenshots-tour"
          >openSUSE 11.4</ulink>,<quote>this release includes the latest carefully selected software
          for students, educators, as well as parents. The software selection encompasses everything
          required to make a productive computing experience for either home or educational use
          without having to install anything additional. Right out of the box, educators and parents
          will be pleased to see over 150 applications to fit their student's needs. A wide range
          including mental exercise tools like Brain Workshop and GBrainy, science applications like
          Chemtool, mathematical programs like Euler, artistic development software like TuxPaint
          and GIMP</quote>.</para>
      <para><ulink url="http://www.youtube.com/v/O-xU1ldUoeM">YouTube Video: openSUSE Li-f-e
          Overview</ulink></para>
      <para>More information can be found on the<ulink
          url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/29/opensuse-edu-li-f-e-11-4-out-now/"> release
          announcement</ulink>.</para>
      <para>If you are using a previous release of Opensuse Edu and you want to upgrade to this new
        release, please <ulink
          url="http://www.unixmen.com/linux-tutorials/documentations-a-howto/1578-upgrade-opensuse-to-114"
          >check out previous post</ulink>.</para>
      <para><ulink url="http://www.youtube.com/v/6NWg8I2N_6U">openSUSE Edu: Li-f-e applications
          (Video)</ulink></para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Editors Note</emphasis>: Screenshots available in the Original
        Article.</para>
      <!--($ ld: 30.3.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://looksblo.wordpress.com/2011/03/30/german-subforum-on-forum-kde-org-opens-its-gates/"
          >Frederik Schwarzer: German subforum on forum.kde.org opens its gates</ulink></title>
      <para>A few minutes ago, a subforum was created on <ulink url="http://forum.kde.org/"
          >forum.kde.org</ulink> for all the German-speaking users out there (and yes, developers
        are users as well :)). So please come and make yourself at home, so it will grow and become
        the best and nicest German-speaking place to get help for those little itches KDE users
        sometimes have to scratch.</para>
      <para>On your mouse, get ready, <ulink url="http://forum.kde.org/viewforum.php?f=204"
          >Go!</ulink></para>
      <!--($ ld: 31.3.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://www.h-online.com/open/news/item/Linux-distributions-to-include-run-directory-1219006.html"
          >h-online: Linux distributions to include /run/ directory</ulink></title>
      <para>On the Fedora project's developer list, systemd developer Lennart Poettering has <ulink
          url="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.redhat.fedora.devel/146976">announced</ulink> the
        introduction of a /run directory in the root directory and provided detailed background
        explanations. Similar to the existing /var/run/ directory, the new directory is designed to
        allow applications to store the data they require in order to operate. This includes process
        IDs, socket information, lock files and other data which is required at run-time but can't
        be stored in /tmp/ because programs such as tmpwatch could potentially delete it from there. </para>
      <para>However, /var/run/ isn't a readily available choice for tools such as systemd, udev or
        mdadm that are required early in the boot process, because /var can be implemented as a
        separate file system to be mounted at a later stage in the start-up process. As a result,
        these programs have had to resort to such trickery as using the /dev/.udev, /dev/.mdadm,
        /dev/.systemd or /dev/.mount directories, even though the device directory isn't intended
        for such data. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 31.3.11 sm $) -->    
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://artax.karlin.mff.cuni.cz/~kendy/blog/archives/monthly/2011-03.html#2011-03-31T11_35_21.htm"
          >FOSDEM 2011: LibreOffice Online Help (Wikihelp)</ulink></title>
      <para>I realized I did not post my FOSDEM slides online; this blog post is to fix that ;-) So
        if you want to learn more about our approach to the on-line help, please have a look here: </para>
      <para><ulink
          url="http://artax.karlin.mff.cuni.cz/%7Ekendy/blog/pics/LibreOffice-wikihelp-FOSDEM2011.odp"
          >LibreOffice Online Help (Wikihelp)</ulink></para>
      <para> It talks briefly about what we have done to bring the <ulink
          url="http://help.libreoffice.org">LibreOffice help</ulink> online, and about the future
        steps. Talking of the future steps, in 3.4, the .xhp files are still the source of the help
        (check the presentation if you want to know what are the .xhp files), because we did not
        manage to do the 2nd step - converting the wiki markup back to the native help files. </para>
      <para> Actually - I would like to mentor a GSoC task for that: </para>
      <para><ulink
          url="http://wiki.documentfoundation.org/Development/Gsoc/Ideas#Convert_the_LibreOffice_web_help_.28wikihelp.29_to_platform_specific_help_files"
          >Convert LibreOffice Help to Platform Specific Help Files</ulink></para>
      <para> If you are a student interested in Free Software, with free summer, and Python or Perl
        knowledge (to bind to existing MediaWiki markup parsers), this might be a nice task for
        you!</para>
      <!--($ ld: 31.3.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://www.linux.com/learn/tutorials/426566:weekend-project-create-a-paperless-linux-office"
          >Linux.com/Nathan Willis: Weekend Project: Create a Paperless Linux Office</ulink></title>
      <para>The paperless office: whether to combat clutter or save the forests, it has been the
        dream of many a computer user ever since the first electronic record of, well, probably
        anything. But it remains elusive, in no small part because whatever your personal
        intentions, you just cannot control the actions of other people, and many businesses today
        still insist on sending you printed bills and receipts. You can at least dispense with the
        filing cabinets, however, by scanning in the documents you need as searchable, full-text
        PDFs. Fire up the scanner and the weekend.</para>
      <para>Clearly, you could just scan everything and save your documents as TIFF or JPEG files.
        Linux has solid support for USB desktop scanners (even all-in-one printer/fax/scan devices
        and those with sheet-feeders or other attachments) thanks to the <ulink
          url="http://www.sane-project.org/">SANE</ulink> project. There is also no shortage of
        quality scan applications, like <ulink url="http://kooka.kde.org/">Kooka</ulink>, <ulink
          url="http://www.xsane.org/">XSane</ulink>, or <ulink
          url="https://launchpad.net/simple-scan">Simple Scan</ulink>. But with images alone you
        lose the ability to search the text content of your documents — and remember, you can not
        only search within a particular document, but use GNU utilities to search your entire
        document collection. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 1.4.11 sm $) -->   
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://jeffhoogland.blogspot.com/2011/03/dialog-with-girlfriend.html">Jeff Hoogland: Dialog with the Girlfriend</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>About a year ago I <ulink url="http://jeffhoogland.blogspot.com/2010/03/minting-girlfriend.html">made a post</ulink> about installing Linux on my girlfriend&apos;s laptop. Just recently I was <ulink url="http://www.linuxinsider.com/rsstory/72103.html">quoted on Linux Insider</ulink> about how successful the installation had been a year later. I said that I believed it to have been a successful conversion of a Windows user to Linux. My descriptions were from my observations only, not my girlfriend&apos;s. I had not thought at that time to ask my girlfriend what she thought about the change of operating system on her computer.
        
      </para>
      <para>Last night I sat down with her and we talked a bit about what she thought of her penguin powered laptop. With her permission I am going to post some of her responses. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 2.4.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://www.petur.eu/blog/?p=349">Petur.eu: Linux can be hacked with an USB
          device</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>I have to admit, over the years I haven’t given openSUSE enough love or credit for being
        the outstanding Linux distribution is it. With that said, I wanted to give some attention to
        the latest release coming out of the openSUSE project. And, since the default desktop for
        openSUSE 11.4 is KDE, I will be giving a little extra attention to the KDE desktop. Since
        both might well gain some serious ground, when Ubuntu 11.04 is released, it will be nice for
        users to not only know of its existence, but to also know that openSUSE 11.4 is, in fact, a
        solid distribution worth giving a look. (...)</para>      
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>LOL</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://xkcd.com/874/">XKCD: Time Management</ulink></title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/time_management.png" width="50%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
          url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.5/">CC-BY-NC</ulink></para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
</sect1>
