<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
<!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://labs.qt.nokia.com/2011/10/21/the-qt-project-is-live/">The Qt Project is live!</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>I’m happy to announce that the Qt Project officially went live today. Starting today, development of Qt will be governed as a true open source project.</para>
      <para>We now have <ulink url="http://qt-project.org/">qt-project.org</ulink> – a website where all development of Qt will be centered, providing the same infrastructure and processes for everybody that wants to contribute to Qt. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 27.10.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
<!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.socallinuxexpo.org/blog/design-logo-scale-10x-win-trip-la">Design a logo for SCALE 10X, win a trip to LA!</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Want a free trip to SCALE 10X in Los Angeles this January?</emphasis></para>
      <para>In marking 10 years of the Southern California Linux Expo (SCALE) and 20 years of Linux, the SCALE team wants to incorporate an open-source approach to this year’s expo logo designs for publications and for swag. 

With this in mind, the SCALE team announces a contest to select the artwork for use on this year&apos;s t-shirts, attendee bags, and other conference materials.</para>
      <para>The designer of the winning submission will win a free pass to <ulink url="http://www.socallinuxexpo.org/scale10x/">SCALE 10x</ulink>, including airfare within the continental United States, as well as a three-night stay at the <ulink url="http://www.hilton.com/en/hi/groups/personalized/L/LAXAHHH-LNX-20120116/index.jhtml?WT.mc_id=POG%20target=">Hilton Los Angeles Airport</ulink>. (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.internetnews.com/blog/skerner/suse-builds-openstack-diablo-appliances.html">InternetNews.com/Sean Michael Kerner: SUSE Builds OpenStack Diablo Appliances</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>From the &apos;Cloud Rules&apos; files:</para>
      <para>You can add SUSE to the long list of vendors that with OpenStack solution.</para>
      <para>OpenStack is the open source cloud platform that now has well over 80 member companies participating. What SUSE is doing is interesting, in that they&apos;re making an OpenStack distribution available.</para>
      <para>So instead of just &apos;pledging&apos; to work with OpenStack and have some kind of OpenStack based solution, SUSE is actually providing OpenStack, running on SUSE Enterprise Linux. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 27.10.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/consumer-electronics-linux-initiative-starts/9820">ZDNet/Steven J. Vaughan-Nichols: Consumer Electronics Linux Initiative Starts</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Many people use Linux every day and never know it. Indeed, they’re often using Linux without even knowing they’re using a computing device. For years now, Linux has been the operating system of choice for Digital Video Recorders (DVR)s, DVD players, Smart TVs, Wi-Fi access points, GPS devices, and on and on. But, there’s never been a Linux kernel just for consumer electronics… until now.</para>
      <para>At <ulink url="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/linuxcon-europe">LinuxCon Europe</ulink> in Prague, Czech Republic, The <ulink url="http://www.linuxfoundation.org/">Linux Foundation</ulink>, the non-profit organization dedicated to promoting Linux, announced that it was hosting a new project created by its Consumer Electronics (CE) workgroup: the <ulink url="http://www.linuxfoundation.org/collaborate/workgroups/celf">Long Term Support Initiative (LTSI)</ulink>. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 27.10.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.readwriteweb.com/cloud/2011/10/red-vs-green-suse-backs-openst.php">ReadWriteCloud/Joe Brockmeier: Red Vs. Green: SUSE Backs OpenStack, Red Hat Stands Alone</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>This week, SUSE <ulink url="http://www.suse.com/blogs/suse-joins-openstack/">announced that it had joined OpenStack</ulink> and today the company announced <ulink url="http://susegallery.com/a/vszMWq/suse-cloud-powered-by-openstacktm">a development preview of SUSE Cloud</ulink> which is powered by OpenStack. With the green team at SUSE behind OpenStack, along with Canonical, does that make OpenStack the de facto open source cloud? Not so fast – I wouldn&apos;t count Red Hat out just yet.</para>
      <para><ulink url="http://www.openstack.org/">OpenStack</ulink>, the open source cloud infrastructure being developed by more than 125 organizations, should need no introduction. Red Hat is going its own way in the clouds, with <ulink url="http://www.redhat.com/solutions/cloud/cloudforms/">CloudForms</ulink> for its Infrastructure-as-a-Service (Iaas) offering, and <ulink url="http://www.redhat.com/solutions/cloud/openshift/">OpenShift</ulink> for its Platform-as-a-Service (PaaS) offering. (...)</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Related Articles</emphasis>: <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/open/news/item/SUSE-announces-OpenStack-based-cloud-solution-1367235.html">http://www.h-online.com/open/news/item/SUSE-announces-OpenStack-based-cloud-solution-1367235.html</ulink></para>
<!-- ($ Id: 27.10.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=MTAwNjY">Phoronix/Michael Larabel: Skype Publishes New Linux APIs w/ Video Support</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Skype, now <ulink url="http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OTQyNw">under the control of Microsoft</ulink>, has announced a new developer preview of SkypeKit. It surprisingly brings good news for Linux users.</para>
      <para>SkypeKit allows desktop applications to integrate Skype functionality into partner applications while the Skype desktop API allows developers to extend the functionality of the Skype client.</para>
      <para><ulink url="SkypeKit was originally rolled out in June">SkypeKit was originally rolled out in June</ulink> to help Skype in the consumer electronics industry. Skype developers have been working to improve SkypeKit since and today released a developer preview of SkypeKit 4.02. This new version does bring video APIs to &quot;SkypeKit for Desktop&quot;, so that developers can build in native Skype functionality into their own applications for handling video calls. There&apos;s also a new &quot;Skype App Directory&quot; that&apos;s being rolled out too.</para>
      <para>SkypeKit is available for Linux, Mac OS X, and Windows operating systems. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 28.10.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.networkworld.com/community/open-source-for-kids">Network World/Rikki Endsley: Open Source: You Know, For Kids!</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>A few years ago, when I was working as a print magazine editor, a young girl approached my booth at LinuxFest Northwest in Bellingham, Washington. She was probably 12- or 13-years old, and she gave me some of the best feedback I&apos;d ever had on our products.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Reason 1: You Will Learn</emphasis></para>
      <para>My new young friend told me what she liked about our articles, the art, and even our ads. She pointed out that one of our ads looked too much like an ad a hosting provider was running, and she was right. She told me that I needed to give out stickers for her and other attendees to put on their laptops, which I immediately ordered after the event. I thanked her for stopping and taking the time to make me look at our magazines from a fresh perspective. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 27.10.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://how-to.linuxcareer.com/how-can-you-help-the-linux-community">LinuxCareer/Reres Aioanei: How can you help the Linux community</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">1. Introduction</emphasis></para>
      <para>The whole Linux community is based on the concept of community and collaboration. Without it, Linus Torvalds&apos; e-mail sent out 20 years ago would have been forgotten and none of us would have known about Linux. As time went by, it became easier and easier for users, regardless of experience and knowledge, to contribute to his/her favorite distribution. While we&apos;re at it, it&apos;s a common misconception that you have to be a programmer in order to help the Linux community. Well, nothing could be further from the truth.  Anyone can help, provided he or she has Internet access, and, more importantly, the will to help. You are not expected to have any particular knowledge, just to have a few hours/week available for this. This article will not be specific to a distribution or another, because there are hundreds of them and anyway, the general concepts are the same. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 27.10.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.digitaltrends.com/web/spammers-create-and-launch-url-shortening-services-to-hide-links/">Digital Trends/Mike Flacy: Spammers create and launch URL shortening services to hide links</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">While spam continues to be a major problem for email providers and consumers, spammers have come up with a new way to hide links and slip through the spam filters.</emphasis></para>
      <para>According to new information from researchers at Symantec, a group of spammers have created a group of 87 spam-friendly, public URL shortening services and are actively using them to circumvent spam filters on popular sites. Using URL shortening scripts that are free and open source, the spammers are churning spam through the service and the public is also free to create links through the URL shorteners, perhaps an attempt to pass off the links as legitimate. All the URL shorteners are using the .info domain and are being operated through contacts in Moscow as well as a hosting company in the United Kingdom. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 28.10.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
<!--
  <sect2>
    <title>LOL</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://like-a-boss.org/2011/09/30/hacking-the-imperial-death-march/">like-a-boss.org: hacking the imperial death march</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>One of the great things about the original Star Wars trilogy, was the “lived in”, junky, hacked together aesthetic of the Star Wars universe. Everything was a bit trashed, as if real people actually lived there. Thankfully, that’s one of the things that George Lucas hasn’t tinkered with in his endless quest to ruin the childhood memories of a generation. So it’s heartening to see this tradition carried on with the playing of the imperial death march on miscellaneous hacked together hardware. Enjoy … (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> --></sect1>
