<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="tipsandtricks">
  <title>Tips and Tricks</title>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Desktop Users</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.muktware.com/articles/3038">Muktware/Swapnil Bhartiya: How To Install Restricted Drivers, Formats In openSUSE 12.1</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>OpeSUSE, like Fedora, doesn&apos;t support non-free/proprietary formats in the community version. So, if you want to use proprietary or restricted codecs you will have to install restricted formats. It&apos;s extremely easy using openSUSE KDE.

Just visit this <ulink url="http://opensuse-community.org/Restricted_formats/12.1">page</ulink> and select the easier <ulink url="http://opensuse-community.org/codecs-kde.ymp">1-click</ulink> installation. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 01.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.muktware.com/articles/3037">Muktware/Swapnil Bhartiya: How To Set Up Printers In openSUSE</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>I had to struggled a bit to connect my HP Photosmart Prem c410 printer on openSUSE. Coming from Ubuntu, I was used to &apos;add printer&apos; button and just follow the click-next procedure.</para>
      <para>Under openSUSE it&apos;s a bit different. openSUSE 12.1 comes with HPLIP Tool which makes it easier to install and configure HP printers. If your printer is connected through the wireless (as was mine), you can set it up using this tool.</para>
      <para>HPLIP wants the user to be added to several groups (I learned that after 3 failed attempts, so I am saving your time). Before firing the HP Tool, go to YaST and click on &apos;User and Group Management Accounts&apos;. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 01.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.muktware.com/articles/3039">Muktware/Swapnil Bhartiya: How To Setup Networking In openSUSE 12.1 KDE</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>There is a very tiny (extremely tiny, as tiny as a microbe) price you have to pay when you use a highly customizable desktop environment like KDE. I had issues with networking (which was more to do with my ignorance than KDE) under openSUSE KDE 12.1.</para>
      <para>While the live version showed the network icon in the tray, once I installed it on my desktop it was gone. There was no Internet.  I noticed this behavior only on the desktop, everything was fine on my laptop.</para>
      <para>The reason being KDE defaults to YaST&apos;s Network setting if it detects that you are running a desktop. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 01.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Commandline/Script Newbies</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://bashshell.net/script-of-the-week/using-diff-to-compare-directories/">BashShell.net/Mike: Using diff to Compare Directories</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The diff command compares two files or directories and returns the differences.  This provides you a way to monitor changes in an important directory like /etc which houses most configuration files on a Linux system.  In order for this to work properly you will need to create a file that lists the content of the /etc directory so that you can make a comparison. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 09.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Developers and Programmers</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://how-to.linuxcareer.com/c-development-on-linux-flow-control-iv">LinuxCareer.com/Rares Aioanei: C development on Linux - Flow Control - IV</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">1. Introduction</emphasis></para>
      <para>You have already been exposed to a small part of what flow control is in our <ulink url="http://how-to.linuxcareer.com/c-development-on-linux-types-variables-operators">previous part</ulink>, namely the section about relational operators. As you start writing more complex programs, you will feel the need to control the order in which your program executes various parts. Flow control is present in most programming languages in one form or another, and what you&apos;re about to read here is essential to writing C programs.Everything you might want to ask or discuss you can take to our new <ulink url="http://forum.linuxcareer.com/">forums</ulink>, as before. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 01.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://zoumpis.wordpress.com/2011/11/28/how-to-install-eclipse-3-7-indigo-sr1-in-opensuse-12-1-kde-only-within-10-steps/">Rousinopoulos Athanasios-Ilias: How-to Install Eclipse 3.7 (Indigo SR1) in openSUSE 12.1 (KDE) only within 10 Steps</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>This is my first blog post for the assignment “Development Tools” , so i could say that
        i am very happy with this matter!</para>
      <para>Well i use openSUSE Linux 12.1 and i am very proud of that! Sometimes i face problems
        like , lack of packages for programs, but this matter doesn’t mean that you cannot install
        the software you wish. In my case i installed Eclipse 3.7 (Indigo SR1) due to i have to use
        the <ulink url="http://marketplace.eclipse.org/">Eclipse Marketplace</ulink>. Eclipse
        Marketplace offers a thousand of plug-ins and extra features available for Eclipse platform.
        It is a truth that i searched a lot in order to find a package or a “one-click install” file
        but the result was an installation of 3.6.2 version. As we all know in FLOSS always there is
        a way to overcome problems and also fix them. Furthermore as a developer i have to use the
          “<ulink url="http://www.eclipse.org/downloads/packages/eclipse-ide-java-ee-developers/indigor">Eclipse IDE for Java EE Developers</ulink>“. Here are the instructions on how-to install
        (via terminal) this edition of Eclipse. (Some images are in greek language , due to the fact
        that i use the greek language as System language) (...)</para>
<!--($ Id: 02.12.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For System Administrators</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://beginlinux.com/desktop/opensuse/automate-install-with-autoyast-answer-files">BeginLinux.com: Automate Install With AutoYaST Answer Files</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>This is the final article on installing opensuse. To recap we&apos;ve covered <ulink url="http://beginlinux.com/desktop/opensuse/configuring-the-dhcp-server">Configuring the DHCP Server</ulink>, <ulink url="http://beginlinux.com/desktop/opensuse/installing-apache-on-opensuse">Installing Apache on OpenSUSE</ulink>, <ulink url="http://beginlinux.com/desktop/opensuse/opensuse-pxe-boot">OpenSUSE PXE Boot</ulink> and today we&apos;ll be tackling how to automate an install with AutoYaST answer files.</para>
      <para>The final part of our installation jigsaw puzzle is to create the answer file, in SUSE this is known as AutoYaST. If we were only ever to install one server or one desktop then maybe we could do without answer files; however where we need to install a few or many then AutoYaST provides us with an unattended installation:- a build script to create consistency and compliance we regulatory bodies governing security. In short we need answer files. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 09.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://blog.adityapatawari.com/2011/12/controlling-your-linux-server-using.html">Aditya Patawari: Controlling Your Linux Server Using Twitter</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Last weekend I wrote about &quot;<ulink url="http://blog.adityapatawari.com/2011/11/using-twitter-to-monitor-your-linux.html">Using Twitter To Monitor Your Linux Server</ulink>&quot; using a command line client &quot;<ulink url="http://myst.adityapatawari.com/">MYST</ulink>&quot;. I have added a new feature to MYST using which you can tell your server to execute commands by using DMs. Let us start configuration for the same. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 09.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://olex.openlogic.com/wazi/2011/shh-openssh-secrets-here/">Wazi/Carla Schroder: Shh! OpenSSH Secrets Here</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>If you routinely use multiple computers, it can be a challenge to keep your data files organized and to manage multiple login IDs. <ulink url="http://olex.openlogic.com/packages/openssh">OpenSSH</ulink> can help you with those tasks. It’s a powerful, secure tool that lets you share files without having to set up a file server, run applications remotely, and perform remote administration chores quickly and securely. You probably already know how to <ulink url="http://olex.openlogic.com/wazi/2011/stop-using-ftp-how-to-transfer-files-securely/">use OpenSSH for file transfers</ulink>. Here we’ll uncover some less well-known OpenSSH tricks that can make life easier for roaming computer users.</para>
      <para>To use the software, you should have the OpenSSH server and client installed and working on all the computers you need to access. In this article I use local for the computer we’re launching an OpenSSH session from, and remote to refer to the computer we’re logging into. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 09.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="https://www.linux.com/learn/tutorials/519933-embiggen-your-kvm-virtual-machines">Linux.com/Carla Schroder: Embiggen Your KVM Virtual Machines</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>When you provision virtual machines, you try to ensure that they have the storage that they need. But as we all know, storage needs tend to change over time. If you have KVM machines that need more space, we can up their storage with tools you already have handy.</para>
      <para>In <ulink url="https://www.linux.com/learn/tutorials/510124-managing-live-and-offline-migrations-with-linuxs-kvm">Managing Live and Offline Migrations with Linux&apos;s KVM</ulink> we learned how to migrate virtual machines, and how to manage disk storage. Today we&apos;ll learn how resize VMs and add storage space. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 09.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.ibm.com/developerworks/linux/library/os-python-kvm-scripting1/index.html">IBM developerWorks/Paul Ferrill: Scripting KVM with Python, Part 1: libvirt</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Virtualization is standard equipment with most server operating systems on the market today. In the Linux® world, there are two primary choices for server virtualization: the Kernel-based Virtual Machine (KVM) and Xen. KVM is the primary technology that Red Hat and others use. Although Citrix owns Xen, much of the core functionality remains in the public domain.</para>
      <para>The Virtual Machine Manager (VMM, or virt-manager) project provides a tool for managing the creation and running of both KVM and Xen virtual machine (VM) instances. VMM is written in Python using the GTK+ library for graphical user interface construction. The real work is done through the libvirt library, which is what you&apos;ll be using for this article series. Although libvirt is a Red Hat-sponsored effort, it remains an open source project available under the GNU Lesser General Public License.</para>
      <para>libvirt is made up of several different pieces, including the application programming interface (API) library, a daemon (libvirtd), and a default command-line utility (virsh). For the purposes of this article, all testing is done using Ubuntu Server version 11.04. The Installation and setup section covers everything I did to configure my server for developing the scripts presented here. Part 1 covers the basics of libvirt and Kernel-based Virtual Machine (KVM) virtualization along with a few command-line scripts to whet your appetite. Part 2 will dive deeper and show you how you can build your own virtualization management tools using libvirt, Python, and wxPython. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 09.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
