<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
  %myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="kernel">
  <title>Kernel Review</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
   <ulink
    url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/Kernel-Log-Coming-in-2-6-39-Part-1-Network-drivers-and-infrastructure-1227053.html"
    >h-online/Thorsten Leemhuis: Kernel Log: native KVM tool, new kernels galore</ulink>
  </title>
  <para><emphasis role="bold">Dissatisfied with the Qemu code, the developers have created a simple
    emulation tool for KVM. The latest drivers for Intel graphics chips improve the kernel's support
    for the video components of various current processors; a wealth of new long-term and stable
    kernels fix bugs and security holes.</emphasis></para>
  <para>In late March, Pekka Enberg <ulink url="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.kernel/1121307"
    >announced</ulink> on the LKML the development of a native KVM tool. This tool emulates some of
   the hardware components that guest systems access during operation; in KVM virtualisation, this
   task is nowadays mostly handled by a QEMU derivative, created and maintained as part of the KVM
   project. The KVM code within the kernel works in close co-operation with this emulation code,
   ensuring that the required processor resources are allocated; however, a few hardware components
   such as the interrupt controller are emulated by the KVM kernel code itself, because this
   considerably enhances performance.</para>
  <para>In his email, Enberg writes that his aim was to create a light-weight and clean KVM
   emulation implementation that can boot Linux guests. The developer said that the tool is "[...]
   just a hobby, won't be big and professional like QEMU [...]" – a play on the words Linus Torvalds
   used in his first email about the development of Linux. (..)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 21.4.11 sm $) -->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/Kernel-comment-Perseverance-pays-off-1232036.html"
        >h-online/Thorsten Leemhuis: Kernel comment: Perseverance pays off</ulink></title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Today, there are open source Linux drivers for all major Wi-Fi
        chips, which was unimaginable five years ago. The constant pressure for open source drivers
        has thus paid off, and this may also work in other areas in the long term.</emphasis></para>
    <para>"Buy a Centrino notebook, and then the Wi-Fi chipset will work with Linux." Five years
      ago, such simplifications were more common because a lot of the Wi-Fi components either did
      not run on Linux or took a lot of tweaking, say, with Ndiswrapper and Driverloader to get the
      NDIS drivers intended for use with Windows to run on Linux. Internet forums contained
      thousands of comments on these issues, and people repeatedly said that the Linux kernel needed
      a stable API for external drivers; otherwise, manufacturers would never offer proper Linux
      drivers for Wi-Fi hardware.</para>
    <para>We now know that such a step was not necessary, for all major manufacturers of Wi-Fi
      hardware for PCs and notebooks are currently working on open source drivers maintained within
      work on the Linux kernel.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 23.4.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
 <blockquote>
  <title><ulink url="http://schaiba.wordpress.com/2011/04/16/kernel-weekly-news-16-04-2011/">Rares
    Aioanei: kernel weekly news – 16.04.2011</ulink></title>
  <para>Rares finished his this weekly review from the Kernel.</para>
  <!--($ ld: 16.4.11 sm $)-->
 </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://article.gmane.org/gmane.linux.kernel/1128248">Linus Torvalds: Linux 2.6.39-rc4</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>So things have sadly not continued to calm down even further. We had
      more commits in -rc4 than we had in -rc3, and I sincerely hope that
      upward trend doesn&apos;t continue.
      
    </para>
    <para>That said, so far the only thing that has really caused problems this
      release cycle has been the block layer plugging changes, and as of
      -rc4 the issues we had with MD should hopefully now be behind us. So
      we&apos;re making progress on that front too.
      
    </para>
    <para>The plugging code still seems to trigger some issue with what looks
      like an infinite stream of disk-change notifications on CD-ROMs - but
      Jens is hopefully going to squish that problem soon. In the meantime,
      you can avoid the problem by either running SMP or having preemption
      enabled.
      
    </para>
    <para>Other than that? We may have a bit more commits than in -rc3, but it
      hasn&apos;t been _too_ bad. There&apos;s certainly nothing overly exciting:
      aside from the block/MD fixups, we&apos;ve got some filesystem updates
      (btrfs, cifs and ubifs) and some driver updates (the largest chunk of
      which is actually a duplicate driver removal). USB, some KMS, nothing
      really earthshaking.
      
    </para>
    <para>Shortlog appended for the curious. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 23.4.11 sat $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://article.gmane.org/gmane.linux.kernel.stable/9103">Paul Gortmaker: Linux 2.6.34.9 has been released</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>A new longterm 2.6.34.9 kernel has been released. This release contains
      security fixes and all 2.6.34 users are encouraged to update. This
      continues the 2.6.34 stable series under the new &quot;longterm&quot; name.
      
    </para>
    <para>Git:
      git://git.kernel.org/pub/scm/linux/kernel/git/longterm/linux-2.6.34.y.git
      
    </para>
    <para>Gitweb:
      http://git.kernel.org/?p=linux/kernel/git/longterm/linux-2.6.34.y.git
      
    </para>
    <para>Tarballs/patches:
      ftp://ftp.kernel.org/pub/linux/kernel/v2.6/longterm/v2.6.34/ (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 23.4.11 sat $)-->  </blockquote>
</sect1>
