<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/05/27/factory-progress/">Andreas Jaeger: Factory
        Progress</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>A lot of things are happening in our Factory distribution that will be released in
      November 2011 as openSUSE 12.1 and I’d like to point out a few things from the last few weeks
      that users and developers of factory shouldn’t miss.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="underline">Roadmap openSUSE
        12.1</emphasis></emphasis></para>
    <para>Stephan “Coolo” Kulow has updated the openSUSE 12.1 <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/Roadmap">Roadmap</ulink>, the next milestone is Milestone 1
      which is delayed and targeted now for release on Tuesday, 30th May. The next paragraphs
      highlight some of the updates for this versions.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">GCC 4.6</emphasis></para>
    <para>The GNU Compiler Collection has been updated to version 4.6, the list of <ulink
        url="http://gcc.gnu.org/gcc-4.6/changes.html">changes</ulink> includes the following new
      warning that will be visible while compiling packages for openSUSE Factory:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>“New -Wunused-but-set-variable and -Wunused-but-set-parameter warnings were added for
          C, C++, Objective-C and Objective-C++. These warnings diagnose variables respective
          parameters which are only set in the code and never otherwise used. Usually such variables
          are useless and often even the value assigned to them is computed needlessly, sometimes
          expensively. The -Wunused-but-set-variable warning is enabled by default by -Wall flag and
          -Wunused-but-set-parameter by -Wall -Wextra flags.”</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>Some packages have been failing by the new GCC due to new warnings and new optimizations
      and most have been fixed already but please double check that your packages are building and
      running fine.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">RPM 4.9</emphasis></para>
    <para>Michael Schröder <ulink
        url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-packaging/2011-05/msg00112.html"
        >announced</ulink><ulink url="http://rpm.org/wiki/Releases/4.9.0">RPM 4.9</ulink> for
      Factory. He explains the main packager visible changes as:<blockquote>
        <para>Besides some bug fixes and an update to a newer BerkeleyDB library rpm-4.9.0 contains
          plugin architecture for dependency generation. In older rpms, the internal dependency
          generator was pretty much hardcoded in C, so we always used the old external one to
          generate dependencies. With rpm-4.9.0, the internal generator has become flexible enough
          so that we can use it.</para>
        <para>This means for you, that rpm will no longer use the %__find_provides and
          %__find_requires macros. Some packages redefined those macros to be able to filter the
          generated dependencies.</para>
        <para>This will no longer work in rpm-4.9.0. Instead, support for dependency filtering was
          added to rpm…</para>
      </blockquote></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">GNOME3</emphasis></para>
    <para><ulink url="http://gnome3.org">GNOME 3</ulink> has now hit Factory as well and Vincent
      Untz <ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-packaging/2011-05/msg00006.html"
        >explained</ulink> how to fix failures due to the large push.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Linux Kernel 2.6.39</emphasis></para>
    <para>This update was a “boring” update – nothing broke AFAIK , so I hope it’s a solid version.
      Users will benefit from the<ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/Linux-Kernel-2-6-39-Tracking-1219728.html"> new
        features</ulink> in it. 2.6.39 is the first kernel without the Big Kernel Lock at
      all!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Packaging Changes</emphasis></para>
    <para>Besides new software, also new ways of handling it get introduced. The following catched
      my eyes:</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Rpmlint update</emphasis></para>
    <para>Ludwig Nussel updated rpmlint to version 1.2 and <ulink
        url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-packaging/2011-05/msg00118.html">explained</ulink>
      the new warnings about packaging of rpm packages – and what to do about them.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Changing the process of Factory submissions with the Open Build
        Service</emphasis></para>
    <para>Now with every submission to Factory scripts are run automatically that do two different
      reviews before the package goes to human check-in review:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>The “legal-auto” review checks the updated package for changes in licenses.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The “factory-auto” review checks that the updated package builds actually in the devel
          project – and if not, rejects it.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>The “legal-auto” review has quite a long backlog at the moment and Jýrgen is working on
      moving some of the checks to rpmlint or osc checks – so that the packager notices and fixes
      them before submission to Factory.</para>
    <para>Also, you can now submit packages to Factory even if you are not the maintainer of the
      package but in this case the maintainer (packager) gets a review request to review that the
      package really can go to factory and thus a plea to packagers to handle their review
      requests.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">openSUSE Conference</emphasis></para>
    <para>The <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/05/16/opensuse-conference-2011-to-be-creative-and-open/"
        >openSUSE Conference</ulink> is this year co-located with the SUSE Labs conference. Join us
      to present and discuss also Factory related topics. The <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/05/16/opensuse-conference-2011-to-be-creative-and-open/"
        >Call for papers</ulink> is open now!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="italic">I’m interested on feedback on this article – should I start a
        series?</emphasis></para>
<!--($ ld: 28.5.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://www.bryen.com/obs-renamespeaks_volumes/">Bryen Yunashko: OBS—The New Name
        Speaks Volumes</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>In May of 2010, fellow openSUSEan Andreas Jaeger (AJ) and I sat down to review how we can
      help promote the openSUSE Build Service, also known as OBS. It became quickly apparent to me
      that while theý service was called “openSUSE Build Service” the name didn’t give enough due
      credit. The build service’s capabilities meant so much more than simply creating a tool for
      the openSUSE distribution. Sporting an impressive list of supported distros and architectures
      that OBS could package for, this was clearly a tool that needed to be marketed beyond just the
      immediate openSUSE Project community. This was truly a tool for the masses.</para>
<!--($ ld: 28.5.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
</sect1>
