<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
  %myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="kernel">
  <title>Kernel Review</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/Kernel-Log-Wonder-patch-merged-improved-AMD-and-Intel-graphic-support-1166430.html"
        >Linux User and Developer/Jon Masters: Kernel Log: Wonder patch merged, improved AMD and
        Intel graphic support</ulink>
    </title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">For Linux 2.6.38, the kernel developers have integrated the
        much-discussed patch which considerably improves the response time of Linux desktops in
        certain situations. The AMD developers have extended their open source graphics drivers to
        support various Radeon HD 6000 graphics chips. A discussion was sparked by the tricky
        situation surrounding the graphics drivers for Intel's new processors. </emphasis></para>
    <para>After the <ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/What-s-new-in-Linux-2-6-37-1163376.html">release
        of Linux 2.6.37</ulink> on Wednesday morning, the first patches for kernel version 2.6.38
      appeared in the Linux main development branch late on Thursday night. Among Torvalds' first
      2,769 commits were the almost 600 patches for the network subsystem that had been <ulink
        url="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.network/183011">submitted</ulink> by its
      maintainer, David Miller. As expected, these patches have added the <ulink
        url="http://git.kernel.org/linus/0c8173385e549f95cd80c3fff5aab87b4f881d8d">rtl8192ce
        driver</ulink> for Realtek's RTL8192CE and RTL8188CE 802.11n Wi-Fi chips to the kernel. </para>
    <para>The first changes made for Linux 2.6.38 also include <ulink
        url="http://git.kernel.org/linus/5091faa449ee0b7d73bc296a93bca9540fc51d0a">the patch</ulink>
      that considerably improves the interactivity of desktop applications in situations where the
      CPU is fully utilised. This patch became known through such articles as <ulink
        url="http://bit.ly/fI6LyR"><quote>The ~200 Line Linux Kernel Patch That Does
        Wonders</quote></ulink> on the Phoronix web site; details of the patch's functionality as
      well as a description of an alternative, more flexible, approach can be found in a <ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/Kernel-Log-Fast-response-times-via-process-groups-1141390.html"
        >previous Kernel Log</ulink>. The maintainer of the process scheduler, Ingo Molnar, <ulink
        url="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.kernel/1084129">explicitly pointed out</ulink> this
      function in his Git-Pull request, calling it <quote>one of the biggest and most visible
        interactivity improvements achieved by the Linux scheduler</quote>.  (...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 11.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/What-s-new-in-Linux-2-6-37-1163376.html"
        >h-online/Thorsten Leemhuis: What&apos;s new in Linux 2.6.37 </ulink>
    </title>
    <para>After about eleven weeks of development, Linus Torvalds has released the Linux kernel
      2.6.37. The new version of the main development line has many improvements. Advances in the
      Ext4 file system mean it should be able to compete with XFS on larger systems and new discard
      functions can inform slow SSDs of vacant areas, without negatively affecting performance. </para>
    <para>This kernel also sees the first parts of the support for operation as a Xen host (Dom0).
      LZO compression will speed the transition into and out of hibernation and after years of work,
      almost all areas of the kernel are now without the Big Kernel Lock (BKL). Hundreds of new and
      revised drivers improve hardware support. New examples are the support for fast USB 3.0 disk
      with USB Attached SCSI Protocol (UASP) and various drivers for wireless hardware from Atheros,
      Broadcom and Realtek. The new kernel also has an audio loopback driver, extensions to deal
      with the Apple Magic Trackpad and support for 4 KByte logical sectors on hard drives. </para>
    <para>The following Kernel Log offers an overview of these and many further new features of
      Linux 2.6.37. These changes will eventually impact all Linux users as Linux distributions
      adopt the 2.6.37 kernel, or subsequent point releases, and make these improvements available
      to end users. At the end of this article, the Kernel Log will also take a peek at the advances
      that might make it into 2.6.38. (...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 5.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://news.softpedia.com/news/Linux-Kernel-2-6-37-Is-Available-for-Download-176428.shtml"
        >Softpedia/Marius Nestor: Linux Kernel 2.6.37 Is Available for Download</ulink>
    </title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Eariler today, January 5th, none other than Linus Torvalds, the
        father of Linux, proudly announced the release of Linux kernel 2.6.37.</emphasis></para>
    <para>Among the new features includes in Linux kernel 2.6.37 we can mention support for PPP over
      the IPv4 protocol, lots of enhancements to various important file systems, such as EXT4, XFS
      and Btrfs, support for I/O throttling, Perf probe improvements, and a Ceph-based network block
      device. (...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 8.1.11 sat $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
