<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.bryen.com/getting-articles-into-news-opensuse-org">Bryen Yunashko:
        Getting Articles into News.openSUSE.org</ulink></title>
    <para>At the recent 12.1 Marketing hackfest, we devised an editorial schedule and folks have
      begun writing articles for promoting 12.1.ý However, some of these articles haven’t been
      submitted yet.ý We suggest that in order to minimize confusion and reduce excessive pinging,
      you create an <ulink url="http://ietherpad.com">ietherpad</ulink> with your article and link
      to it in the editorial schedule at <ulink url="http://ietherpad.com/sked"
        >http://ietherpad.com/sked</ulink> or send your article directly to news@opensuse.org.
      (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 27.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://blog.cornelius-schumacher.de/2011/09/my-opensuse-conference.html">Raymond
    Wooninck: Chromium browser got accepted into openSUSE:Factory</ulink></title>
    <para>After maintaining the Chromium browser in the openSUSE Contrib repositories, the last few weeks things 
      got accelerated and as of this moment the Chromium browser has become officially part
      of openSUSE:Factory (the future 12.1).ý </para>
    <para>The first step wa taken about 3 – 4 weeks ago
    when a separate development project was created (network:chromium). From there onwards it was
    just a matter of getting the package in the right shape for Factory and making sure that all
    legal and security conditions were met. Those who are tracking the updates of Chromium in this
    devel repo, might have noticed that a number of rebuilds were triggered for the 16.0.880 version
    of Chromium. This all had to do to get a single spec-file that would satisfy both Factory
    requirements but also would be able to build for the older distributions. At this moment this
    special repository offers builds for 11.3, 11.4, Factory and also for Tumbleweed.ý</para>
    <para>I am quite
    proud on this fact and I hope that the openSUSE Chromium users will be happy with this fact.ýAt
    the moment I am preparing an update to the 16.0.891 version and hopefully sometime beginning of
    next week the new snapshot will become available.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 27.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.wafaa.eu/entry/growing-some-opensuse-arms-1-69.html">Bryen
        Yunashko: Take Geeko to the Races!</ulink></title>
    <para>Anyone who is part of the openSUSE Project knows that wherever you go, Geeko is with you.ý
      Geeko is that awesome mascot that brings the spirit of the openSUSE Community alive.ý
      Actually, Geeko isn’t just a mascot.ý Geeko lives within us all.ýý Are you a Geeko?</para>
    <para>Now you can take Geeko to the races.ý SuperTuxKart has a new addon, that includes Geeko,
      thanks toý Luke R.ý It’s pretty simple to install and then let your work pile up while you
      tryto win the races with Geeko at the wheel.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 27.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://blog.cboltz.de/archives/63-1001-bugs-or-the-golden-rules-of-bad-programming.html"
        >Christian Boltz: 1001 bugs - or: the golden rules of bad programming</ulink></title>
    <para>If you missed my talk at the openSUSE conference or want to see the slides (including
      notes) again - here we are:</para>
    <para><ulink
        url="http://blog.cboltz.de/uploads/1001-bugs-or-golden-rules-of-bad-programming.pdf">1001
        bugs - or: the golden rules of bad programming as PDF</ulink> (If you need an editable
      LibreOffice file, just drop me a note.)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 28.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://oyranos-cms.blogspot.com/2011/09/colour-correction-concepts-for-monitors.html"
        >Kai-Uwe Behrmann: Colour Correction Concepts for Monitors</ulink></title>
    <para>Colour management for the desktop is a long standing issue not only for Linux. The
      following text will concentrate on colour correction of monitors. This means the experience,
      when you switch your computer or handheld on and look on the screen. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Why colour correct the desktop? </emphasis></para>
    <para>People tend to compensate for quite a lot of different types of monitors. They are most
      often able to adapt to one full screen and see colours as they are intended to look like.
      Thats fine as long as they are concentrated on the visual event on that one display. But in
      this article we want to discuss how to compensate the monitor colours to our human visual
      needs in environments with various displays side by side, as is the typical situation for more
      and more people today. They take pictures with mobile phones or other digital cameras and look
      at them on laptops, tablets, picture frames, TV sets and printouts often side by side. Or we
      look at them over the internet and want to share the same visual impression with other people.
      Many people with uncorrected systems see quite a difference between various colour devices and
      try to figure out how to conveniently synchronise them. Colour management should help
      accomplish that task. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 28.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://blog.jospoortvliet.com/2011/09/tumbleweed-image-dream.html">Jos
        Poortvliet: Tumbleweed image dream</ulink></title>
    <para>At the (pretty cool) <ulink url="http://www.openmind.fi/">openMind conference in Tampere,
        Finland</ulink>, it came up that a big advantage of <ulink
        url="http://opensuse.org/Tumbleweed">Tumbleweed</ulink> is that it always has the latest
      hardware support. Thanks to the rolling release, Tumbleweed comes with the latest Linux kernel
      which plays a big part of the hardware support of a Linux distro. </para>
    <para>If your hardware does not work properly with the 'stable' release of openSUSE (or other
      distro's) trying the latest kernel can solve that. But that's hard to get on your system, even
      with stuff like <ulink url="http://kernel.opensuse.org">the openSUSE Kernel
        repositories</ulink> because it usually requires you to first <emphasis role="bold"
        >install</emphasis> something. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 28.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
