<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://log.or.cz/?p=108"
      >Petr Baudis: quick update</ulink></title>
    <para>Couple of things to blog about accumulated again, so I guess I will be posting bunch of articles soon. For such a long gap, a general update is in order, 
    I suppose.</para>
    <para>Aside of my studies, continuous MCTS (Go) research, grinding away on random glibc bugs and such, I most notably got involved in <emphasis role="bold">brmlab</emphasis> this summer – 
      the <ulink url="http://brmlab.cz/">Prague hackerspace</ulink>. We got a pretty thriving community there now, with various cool events, a lot of great projects (I’m involved in quite a few), and so on!</para>
    <para>Well, I wanted to mention more, but I can’t remember it right now. I suppose it will just come together. Oh, and seeing my last post – I have a new bike, this time 
      with insurance. ;-)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 28.12.10 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://log.or.cz/?p=110">Petr Baudis: Datasheet Translator</ulink></title>
    <para>As we (well, mostly other people than me) were dealing with a rather obscure micro-controller when hacking our laser projector in brmlab, the only datasheet we have found has been in Chinese. This is quite 
      often the case with obscure China-made parts (including event stuff like LEDs) and it’s annoying to deal with.</para>
    <para>So I hacked together a simple datasheet translator – you feed it a PDF with your datasheet, specify the source language, let it munch away for a minute and then it spews out a link to the 
    English translation!</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para><ulink url="http://datasheet-en.or.cz/">http://datasheet-en.or.cz</ulink></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Example: <ulink url="http://tinyurl.com/2bbq6o7">http://tinyurl.com/2bbq6o7</ulink></para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>Its user interface is extremely rudimentary, if someone wants to add an AJAXy progressbar and what-not, just let me know. :-)</para>
    <para>The “technology” is not much to mention either – thankfully, pdftohtml can do quite nifty stuff nowadays (just needs a lot of beating to properly zoom the documents), and Google Translate can do awesome 
      job with technical documents.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 28.12.10 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://sellingfreesoftwareforaliving.blogspot.com/2010/12/suse-linux-enterprise-wins-readers.html"
      >Han Wen Kam: SUSE Linux Enterprise Wins Readers' Choice Award 2010</ulink></title>
    <para>On 15th October 2010, Novell was presented a <ulink url="http://www.computerworld.com.sg/rca-2010/winners">Readers' Choice Award</ulink> from 
      <ulink url="http://mis-asia.com/magazines/computerworld_singapore">ComputerWorld Singapore</ulink> for winning in the Open Source Platforms/Operating Systems category. 
      It was a very proud moment for us in Novell Singapore and I'm sure it will pleased all SUSE supporters everywhere.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata width="45%" fileref="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_B1ti23BeShI/TRqM3yUwEuI/AAAAAAAAAl8/yu8tJctXuow/s1600/SUSE-Trophy.jpg"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Above is a photo of the trophy presented and its now sitting in a prominent place in the Novell Singapore office. :)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 29.12.10 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
      url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/12/23/rubygem-studio_api/">Josef
        Reidinger: Easy scripting actions with susestudio alias new rubygem
      studio_api</ulink></title>
    <para>Now I work for SLMS ( Suse Lifecycle Management Server ) project. It cooperate with SuSE
      studio and use its API. I get idea that more people could benefit from easy access to studio
      API from ruby so I extract functionality and improve behavior, documentation and testing and
      now there is new rubygem studio_api. Why you should use this gem?</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>ActiveResource Behavior</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Actively maintained ( and will be due to SLMS support )</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Tightly developed with guys from studio team</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Well documented with yard</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Good test coverage.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>I think then a lot of glory words is better to show example. It is example based on
      example from documentation. Example goal is simple. Create new appliance in studio, add own
      cool rpm and build appliance with it. It can be useful to test your new version of software in
      stable environment and have automatic appliance in which you can test it. (...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 23.12.10 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
