<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="community">
  <title>In the Community</title>
  <!--Put here things relevant to the openSUSE community maybe from * People of openSUSE or elections, votings 1 - 2 posts-->
  <sect2>
    <title>Postings from the Community</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://nowwhatthe.blogspot.com/2011/03/collaboration-imperative.html">Jos
          Poortvliet: The Collaboration Imperative</ulink></title>
      <para>As you might have noticed, there is a little bit of a brush-up between GNOME and
        Canonical with KDE involved from the sidelines (just read <ulink
          url="http://planet.gnome.org">Planet GNOME</ulink>). <ulink
          url="http://blogs.gnome.org/bolsh/2011/03/11/lessons-learned/">Dave wrote a reasonable
          summary of this</ulink> and <ulink
          url="http://bethesignal.org/blog/2011/03/12/relationship-between-canonical-gnome/">so did
          Jeff Waugh in his series on the relationship between Canonical and GNOME</ulink>. In three
        sentences:</para>
      <para><quote>Canonical gets a lot of criticism for creating a fork of the GNOME experience
          with Unity, instead of contributing upstream to GNOME Shell. Canonical responds that Unity
          was meant to be a GNOME project and their contributions are being blocked (giving
          libindicators as example). Suddenly Aaron Seigo from KDE weighted in, saying GNOME is
          indeed hard to work with.</quote></para>      
      <para>I've been reading up on it and to some extend participating in the discussion on <ulink
          url="http://identi.ca/conversation/65860477#notice-66972122">identi.ca</ulink>. As you
        know, I'm interested in the subject of collaboration and this is a case where it clearly
        didn't work out for a variety of reasons. In this blog I won't try to weight in on the topic
        itself but rather argue that the psychological construct of <quote>the fundamental
          attribution error</quote> can explain much of the conflict and how to avoid it.</para>
      <para>But let's start with a sample of the discussion.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">forming an opinion</emphasis></para>
      <para>I'm not exactly the type of person who makes up his mind easily. And the stories that
        came out of this debate were highly conflicting and confusing. According to <ulink
          url="http://aseigo.blogspot.com/2011/03/collaborations-demise.html?showComment=1299814706744#c1432139034199491817"
          >this</ulink>, Canonical discourages its employees from contributing upstream. However,
        Aaron claims <ulink
          url="http://aseigo.blogspot.com/2011/03/collaborations-demise.html?showComment=1299827142761#c4757710492378664655"
          >GNOME does not WANT to collaborate</ulink>. And Mark <ulink
          url="http://www.markshuttleworth.com/archives/661">blogs</ulink>:</para>
      <para><quote>Jeff also goes on to talk about Ted and Aurelien, who were proposing the app
          indicators work in GNOME and KDE respectively. KDE apps worked smoothly, Gnome rejected
          Ted’s proposal.</quote></para>
      <para>So GNOME is uncooperative? Or does Canonical not get it, as Dave claimed? Is KDE just
        pushing things without listening? Depends on your point of view - the facts are vague. Read
        for example <ulink url="http://lists.freedesktop.org/archives/xdg/2010-January/011228.html"
          >this thread on freedesktop.org about the StatusNotifier (systray) spec</ulink> - there is
        about a 50% chance you'll decide KDE is the uncooperative one... This thread was referenced
        several times as proof Party X was inflexible and rude - where X was sometimes GNOME and
        sometimes KDE!</para>
      <figure>
        <title>I say opinions are cool!</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2185/2402200306_f8c39a38c3.jpg"
              width="20%" align="right"/>
          </imageobject>          
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>      
      <para><emphasis role="italic">Makes you wonder what is going on...</emphasis></para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">So what is real?</emphasis></para>
      <para>A few days ago I had a call with <ulink url="http://bethesignal.org/">Jeff
        Waugh</ulink>. He <ulink url="http://identi.ca/notice/66923835">offered to talk in a
          dent</ulink> and I'm glad he did. Of course, as usual the whole situation is more
        complicated than what you can discuss in 140 characters on twitter. The talk was very
        enlightening and made me think of a psychological concept.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">The fundamental attribution error</emphasis></para>
      <figure>
        <title>Call it a family trait...</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2083/1917067112_07ff936211_m.jpg"
              width="15%" align="right"/>
          </imageobject>          
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>      
      <para>People tend to attribute what happens around us in the world to intentions. We believe
        things happen for a reason. This is quite a strong human tendency already present in very
        young children. Put a 3 year old in front of a room where stones are moved around by some
        invisible means like magnets. Ask the kid what is going on and he or she will describe the
        events in the room in terms of "the blue stone wants to talk to the reevd one". We know stones
        usually don't really want a lot - so why does the child perceive such intentions? This
        phenomenon not only forms the base of early religions (attributing 'intentions' to weather,
        trees or growth of crops) but also results in making conflicts worse. Psychologists call it
          <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fundamental_attribution_error">"the fundamental
          attribution error"</ulink> and it is fundamental (hence the name) to our perception of the
        world.</para>
      <para>So the reality is, besides that stones and trees don't have 'goals' and 'intentions',
        that often things happen for other reasons than someone having the intent to do that
        specific thing. Or in English, if a specification gets critical comments - maybe the
        respondent might have had other reasons than just wanting to be a jerk. Like being busy,
        tired or having misunderstood/missed a part of the discussion.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Reality applied</emphasis></para>
      <figure>
        <title>Reality?</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="http://farm1.static.flickr.com/48/172405687_6595d591d7.jpg"
              width="15%" align="right"/>
          </imageobject>          
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>      
      <para>The talk with Jeff made clear that the major reason for GNOME not supporting the
        systemtray spec was timing, not lack of interest The focus of the GNOME project right now is
        understandably narrow: get GNOME 3 out the door. Something like interoperability, no matter
        how important, is not on top of the agenda. Jeff said he expects the FD.o systray spec to be
        supported hopefully in GNOME 3.2! The lesson: sometimes things interfere with cooperation.
        And the 'other camp', blissfully unaware of the real reasons behind lack of response or rude
        behavior, attributes it to a lack of willingness and support.</para>
      <para>As another example, take the adoption of the Galago (notification) specification <ulink
          url="http://bethesignal.org/blog/2011/03/15/timeline-gnome-user-experience-hackfest-2008/#comment-6027"
          >and what went wrong according to this message by John Palmieri</ulink>. And about GNOME
        and Canonical having misunderstandings: <ulink
          url="http://www.asinen.org/2011/03/battling-misconceptions-what-is-kde/">Stuart Jarvis
          blogged how hard understanding a Free Software community can be.</ulink></para>
      <para>Now I'm not going to attempt to unravel all the events that led to this blog as that
        would simply be impossible. Nor will I attempt to figure out 'who is to blame' as that's
        pointless (and wrong anyway, as I argued above). What I can do is ask those involved to
          <emphasis role="bold">think about the fundamental attribution error: if someone looks
          funny at you, it doesn't mean they hate you</emphasis>. They might have something stuck in
        their eye!</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Action</emphasis></para>
      <para>Ok, so maybe the others don't hate you. That doesn't solve the problem - yet. We all
        need to step up and do something. What?</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Make collaboration an explicit focus</emphasis></para>
      <figure>
        <title>*snap*</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="http://farm1.static.flickr.com/156/355887968_b1647ac3c5.jpg"
              width="15%" align="right"/>
          </imageobject>          
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>      
      <para>I <ulink url="http://nowwhatthe.blogspot.com/2011/01/my-way-or-highway.html">wrote about
          collaboration before</ulink> and at FOSDEM there was a <ulink
          url="http://nowwhatthe.blogspot.com/2011/02/fosdem-2011.html">cross-distro-collaboration
          discussion</ulink>. As I said there, a big blocker for more openness is that we simply
        don't think about collaboration. We need to be aware of the opportunities for and benefits
        of collaboration. The whole discussion that I started this blog with might be negative and
        things are all a bit tense right now, but it shines the spotlight on something that needs
        attention! And positive initiatives like <ulink
          url="http://distributions.freedesktop.org/wiki/AppStream">Appstream </ulink> are
        happening. As <ulink
          url="http://seilo.geekyogre.com/2011/03/quick-update-from-the-world-of-zeitgeist/">Seif
          Lotfy</ulink> wrote on his blog:</para>
      <para><quote>And if you haven’t noticed we are working with GNOME Shell, Unity and KDE. So a
          sense of collaboration is possible ;)</quote></para>
      <para>It just needs us to take notice! So, Mark, maybe blog about Appstream? It's using Ubuntu
        Software Center for the GNOME side, after all... Let's also focus on the positive
        projects!</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Talk together face to face!</emphasis></para>
      <para>It is important to talk about concerns and frustrations. Considering the distance
        Brazil-Australia the best Jeff and I could do was a phone call but it was certainly
        enlightening. And I bet that you'll notice the same when you finally get to talk to those
        you've been fighting with on IRC and mailing lists for so long... Even then, realize that
        one single person does not define his or her whole project. Not everyone in KDE is as jumpy
        as Aaron; not everyone in GNOME is as French as Vincent Untz. It is important to share the
        results of a chat as well - blog about it (if your blog is aggregated on your projects'
        planet), or add results to a wiki or commit logs etcetera. Make sure the positive results
        persist!</para>
      <para>Allison <ulink url="http://allisonrandal.com/2011/03/12/a-little-help/">wrote he also
          wants to start a bit of a discussion</ulink> in the cross-desktop area which I welcome and
        support. Sounds like something which could make an impact and Allison, if you want my help,
        let me know what I can do.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Take advantage of events to meet</emphasis></para>
      <para>Don't overlook the opportunity to meet at events. For example, there is the Linux
        Foundation's <ulink url="http://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/collaboration-summit"
          >Collaboration Summit in San Fransisco</ulink> in a few weeks. It is <ulink
          url="http://dot.kde.org/2011/02/05/camp-kde-2011-announced">co-located</ulink> with <ulink
          url="http://camp.kde.org">Camp KDE</ulink> which seems to me an excellent opportunity for
        stakeholders to get together. Go a few days before the Collaboration Summit starts so you
        can get some face to face time with desktop folks.</para>
      <figure>
        <title>Time for a group hug?</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4115/4915241275_039b049bf6_m.jpg"
              align="right"/>
          </imageobject>          
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>      
      <para>Then of course in August, there is the <ulink url="http://desktopsummit.org">Desktop
          Summit</ulink>. I'm one of the organizers and while collaboration isn't always perfect,
        the team has a common goal: organize a great event! Like the previous Desktop Summit in Gran
        Canaria I hope we can make some steps forward. This Desktop Summit will have collaboration
        even higher on its agenda than the last one and I hope this will have positive
        effects.</para>
      <figure>
        <title>Gran Canaria Desktop Summit</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2527/3687474115_32e9ce920b.jpg"
              width="25%" align="right"/>
          </imageobject>          
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>      
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Doing more, moving forward</emphasis></para>
      <para>There certainly is more we can do to solve the conflicts. With apologies for the irony
        here, more blogs trying to analyze the whole thing may simply be fueling the flames more
        than extinguish them. Talking to people works better. I don't claim there was no talk,
          <ulink
          url="http://aseigo.blogspot.com/2011/03/shoot-messenger.html?showComment=1299953909118#c4811840744876232992"
          >there was</ulink>. However, much communication we do happens over the web. And as we are
        all aware, that can easily lead to misunderstandings. So the face to face meetings I
        suggest, as well as an awareness of biases like the fundamental attribution error, can
        contribute to solving these conflicts in a more effective manner. As long as the results get
        documented in a few (public!) places and as such don't get forgotten the results of such
        meetings can be good and long lasting!</para>
      <para>Personally, I'll stay away from the subject now - I've dented, tweeted and now blogged
        enough about it. I'll focus on the positive - including the Desktop Summit. And making sure
        the next openSUSE conference will have as much of a collaborative atmosphere as the last
        one!</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">CC-BY-SA</ulink></para>
      <!--($ ld: 23.3.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/03/23/chemnitzer-linuxtage-2011/">Klaas
          Freitag: Chemnitzer Linuxtage 2011</ulink></title>
      <para>Last weekend I spent on <ulink url="http://chemnitzer.linux-tage.de/2011/">Chemnitzer
          Linuxtage 2011</ulink> which is a popular linux event in Chemnitz, Germany. It was the
        first time I have been there and was very positively surprised. It is a very well organised
        event, in a building providing the perfect environment and a large amount of volunteers
        helping to make the whole weekend enjoyable and relaxed. Thanks for that, it really was fun
        to meet so many people in this all-inclusive atmosphere <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_surprised.gif"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="http://robert.fedorapeople.org/events/2011/chemnitzer-linux-tage/024.jpg"
            width="40%"/>
        </imageobject>        
      </mediaobject>
      <para>openSUSE had a booth there (thanks Fedora for the picture) and we were lucky enough to
        have brand new 11.4 promo DVDs there which were handed to interested people. openSUSE 11.4
        in general is very well received at most visitors, they were quite happy with our latest
        release. That is also true for the feelings for openSUSE all over: I heard so much positive
        feedback about what we do and how we do it, for example the OBS with the collaboration
        features, the distribution or the activity all over. People recognize our efforts.</para>
      <para>I gave a talk about <ulink url="http://volle-kraft-voraus.de">Kraft</ulink>, as people
        hinted me that there might be the right audience for the topic of Linux in the small
        business. The interest was huge, the room was more than full and people seemed to like the
        way I was approaching the challenge. Unfortunately I had to fight with the notebook/beamer
        phalanx in the beginning (I apologize for that) so that I had to skip the live demo of Kraft
        in the end. But still I got a lot of interesting discussions afterwards and got some nice
        contributions already. Thanks for that. </para>
      <para>On saturday noon there was a <quote>Distribution competition</quote> where I was pulled
        in to show openSUSE. It went ok for all distros taking part and was fun for us presenting <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject></para>
      <para>Booster Michal was giving a workshop about creating packages in the OBS for multiple
        distributions and a very well <quote>received whats new in 11.4?</quote> talk was given by
        Sirko in the beginners track. </para>
      <para>It was a great event, even though I quite exhausted arrived home late on sunday night. I
        will be there next year again.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
          url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GFDL 1.2</ulink></para>
      <!--($ ld: 23.3.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <!--
    <sect2>
    <title>People of openSUSE</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>This Week: xyz</title>
      <para>Good Guy. Glows in the night.</para>
    </blockquote>
    </sect2> -->
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Welcome new openSUSE Members</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/fcrozat">Frederic Crozat (fcrozat)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Very active in the openSUSE GNOME Team and Bugzilla.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/helen-au">Helen South
        (helen-au)</ulink></title>
      <para>Helen works inside Marketing and the Editor Team of news.opensuse.org.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/dominian">Matt Hayes
        (dominian)</ulink></title>
      <para>Active in Bugzilla, Wiki and Mailinglists.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/tsotsos">Angelos Tzotsos
        (tsotsos)</ulink></title>
      <para>Active inside the Greek Community and Marketing.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/bekun">Kai-Uwe Behrmann
        (bekun)</ulink></title>
      <para>Kai-Uwe serves as Speaker, Boothman and Developer for the openSUSE Project.</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Events &amp; Meetings</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Past</title>
<listitem>
<para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/15/opensuse-kde-team-meeting/">March 16, 2011 : openSUSE KDE Team Meeting</ulink></para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/16/opensuse-11-5-kde-team-planning-meeting/">March 17, 2011 : openSUSE 11.5 KDE Team planning meeting</ulink></para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/02/09/opensuse-project-meetings/">March 23, 2011 : Project Meeting</ulink></para>
</listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Upcoming</title>
      <listitem>
<para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/01/20/testing-core-team-meeting/">March 28, 2011 : Testing Core Team Meeting</ulink></para>
</listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <!-- ($ ld: 25.03.11 th $) -->
    <para>You can find more informations on other events at: <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/category/events/">openSUSE News/Events</ulink>. - <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Ambassadors_events">Local Events</ulink></para>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>openSUSE for your Ears</title>
    <para>The openSUSE Weekly News are available as livestream or podcast in German. You can hear it
      or download it on <ulink url="http://blog.radiotux.de/podcast">Radiotux</ulink>. </para>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>From Ambassadors</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://www.bryen.com/opensuse-11-4-arrives-in-san-diego/">openSUSE 11.4 Arrives in San Diego</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The latest release of openSUSE 11.4 on Thursday proved to be a very good release day for
        us around the world. And in celebrating the release day, several of us came to visit San
        Diego’s Kernel Panic Linux User Group (<ulink url="http://www.kernel-panic.org/"
          >KPLUG</ulink>). It was a good crowd at the event with the members of KPLUG and friends
        some of us invited to join the festivities and learn about openSUSE.</para>
      <para>Representing openSUSE were local openSUSE guru Tony Su, Brazilian Ambassadors Carlos
        Ribeiro and Izabel Valverde (In town for the recent SCALE and openSUSE Marketing Hackfest in
        Los Angeles) and myself.</para>
      <figure>
        <title>Opening presentation statements</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://www.bryen.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/DSC00641-KPLUG-Tony-Bryen-300x199.png"
            />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>As most people present weren’t users of openSUSE, we decided to focus our message not
        just on what is so cool and awesome about openSUSE, but rather on how openSUSE complements
        the Project itself. I started out by giving a brief overview of what openSUSE represents as
        a Project and the various things we do in the Project. Tony then continued by giving a live
        demonstration of KDE and then moved on to an in-depth look at YaST. Occasionally, Carlos
        also offered useful information about the various features of openSUSE and even helped out
        with a couple of users after the presentation.</para>
      <figure>
        <title>Tony extolls the virtues of YaST</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://www.bryen.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/DSC00648-Tony-KPLUG-300x199.png"
            />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>A lot of good questions were generated by the audience, and we saw questions focusing on
        our OBS ervice, SUSE Studio and virtualization. Additionally, people asked questions about
        the Project itself and how it is sponsored. I think people were generally impressed to learn
        and understand that our openSUSE Project is truly a community-driven project and that our
        relationship with our sponsors are collaborative rather than managed.</para>
      <para>Afterwards, in the grand tradition of openSUSE Launch Parties, we gave out cake and DVDs
        as well as a bunch of stickers. As I kept near the DVDs to answer questions, I was genuinely
        pleased to see people not only took DVDs for themselves, but asked if they could also take
        extra copies to give to their friends.</para>
      <figure>
        <title>Every green morsel was delicious!</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://www.bryen.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/DSC00628-KPLUG-Cake-300x199.png"
            />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>I have to say that the KPLUG folks were truly a nice group of people, and their
        backgrounds truly very interesting, ranging from systems administrators to piano teacher to
        retiree who can’t quite give up his love for Linux. It was also a pleasure to meet with
        Neil, the president of KPLUG.</para>
      <para>Cake was definitely delish. I only wish I had extra days in San Diego before the KPLUG
        event so I could have ordered a proper openSUSE photo cake with logo and all. But, once it
        gets in your stomach, I guess it really doesn’t matter. :-)</para>
      <para>Hope to have a chance to visit the guys at KPLUG again, the next time I visit San Diego.
        If you live in the San Diego area, check them out. Next month, they’re doing a presentation
        of MythTV. Should be very interesting!</para>
      <para>Next stop, representnin’ GNOME Foundation Accessibility at the CSUN Assistive Technology
        conference in San Diego this week. I’ll update you all on what happens there.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 14.03.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://opensuseambassadors.blogspot.com/2011/03/opensuse-114-release-party-next-day.html">Greek openSUSE Ambassadors: openSUSE 11.4 Release Party-The Next day</ulink></title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/_EX6cn8rqip4/TX1ywq6uNSI/AAAAAAAAAyU/AV-VhjC4u1k/s320/SAM_0746.JPG"
          />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>Last night the first Release Party for 11.4 of the Greek openSUSE Community took place.
        We had every reason to celebrate since we have this great distribution that attracted
        peoples attention from the first day of it's release.</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/_EX6cn8rqip4/TX1z1A1LVlI/AAAAAAAAAy8/g5RDT6EdV98/s320/SAM_0754.JPG"
          />
        </imageobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/_EX6cn8rqip4/TX10_m1oTnI/AAAAAAAAAzk/0HiGhXLldHY/s320/SAM_0760.JPG"
          />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>The Party was once again awesome. Many beautiful people gathered to Rock 'n' Roll and
        celebrate the arrival of openSUSE 11.4. Of course The ambassadors and the other members of
        the community talked to people about the greatness of the openSUSE Project.</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/_EX6cn8rqip4/TX11Fq8uePI/AAAAAAAAAzs/s0Rwf8ocSBw/s320/SAM_0761.JPG"
          />
        </imageobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/_EX6cn8rqip4/TX10Mh_SFqI/AAAAAAAAAzM/SAPtsONGfYs/s320/SAM_0756.JPG"
          />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>We had all kind of freebies for the people to take. We had some serious party equipment
        like balloons and whistles. Of course we also had 11.3 DVD with instructions stickers for
        upgrade on. Also we burned a few 11.4 and we had stickers, openSUSE cheat-cubes, openSUSE
        Calendars and various other openSUSE stuff.</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/_EX6cn8rqip4/TX10ljqk9TI/AAAAAAAAAzc/FmoXgjojklI/s320/SAM_0758.JPG"
          />
        </imageobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/_EX6cn8rqip4/TX19HDLZS0I/AAAAAAAAA3w/yn6dK1vHwaE/s320/SAM_0805.JPG"
          />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>All attendants were given a number and in the end of the night we had a draw and gave
        away 3 openSUSE t-shirts. Also at the end of the night we all sign an openSUSE poster as
        something for the community to remember from that wild night.</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/_EX6cn8rqip4/TX1-uhteigI/AAAAAAAAA4w/DXSpksZLWus/s320/SAM_0815.JPG"
          />
        </imageobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/_EX6cn8rqip4/TX1wt2uhucI/AAAAAAAAAxI/GUjMOAI3DsM/s320/SAM_0733.JPG"
          />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>We proved once again that openSUSE people most of all have fun because openSUSE is more
        than a more than a product.</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/_EX6cn8rqip4/TX12q0B7xNI/AAAAAAAAA0g/TPsSuzwxOAg/s320/SAM_0769.JPG"
          />
        </imageobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/_EX6cn8rqip4/TX13b7eTrvI/AAAAAAAAA04/zXjC0tsHX_w/s320/SAM_0774.JPG"
          />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>Unfortunately it is impossible to fit all photos from the party here so if you like to
        see some more go to: <ulink
          url="https://picasaweb.google.com/warlordfff/OpenSUSE114ReleaseParty#"
          >https://picasaweb.google.com/warlordfff/OpenSUSE114ReleaseParty#</ulink></para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
          url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">CC-BY-SA</ulink></para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 15.03.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Communication</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/">The Mailinglists</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org">The openSUSE Forums</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Contributors</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://users.opensuse.org">The User Directory</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
