<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="tipsandtricks">
  <title>Tips and Tricks</title>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Desktop Users</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/12/21/easy-use-of-webyast-for-opensuse-11-3/"
          >Stefan Schubert: Easy use of WebYaST for OpenSuSE 11.3</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Have you ever tried WebYaST ? No ? Then it is time for.</emphasis>
      </para>
      <para>We have noticed that WebYaST is not really known in the OpenSuSE community. One reason
        for is that WebYaST is not really user friendly regarding the installation.</para>
      <para>So we have investigate here some effort. Lets see….</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Installation</emphasis></para>
      <para>The simplest way is the one-click installation which is already installed on your
        OpenSuSE 11.3.</para>
      <para>Just use a web browser (like firefox) with the url: <ulink
          url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/YaST:/Web/openSUSE_11.3/webyast.ymp"
          >http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/YaST:/Web/openSUSE_11.3/webyast.ymp</ulink></para>
      <para>The browser will ask you to start the installation via the one-click installation. Start
        the installation and go through the installation workflow.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Starting and managing WebYaST</emphasis></para>
      <para>WebYaST is a web application which runs on two http servers on your system. For starting
        and managing these servers Thomas Goettlicher has written a nice Qt-applet which can be
        started e.g. in KDE:</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/qwebyast1.jpeg"
            width="25%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>After starting the WebYaST applet the WebYaST icon appears on the right edge of the
        frame :</para>
      <informaltable frame="none">
        <tgroup cols="2">
          <colspec colwidth="0.5in"/>
          <colspec colwidth="0.5in"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <mediaobject>
                  <imageobject>
                    <imagedata
                      fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/qwebyast-disabled.png"
                    /></imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
              </entry>
              <entry>WebYaST is disabled</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <mediaobject>
                  <imageobject><imagedata
                      fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/qwebyast-enabled.png"
                    /></imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
              </entry>
              <entry>WebYaST is enabled</entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </informaltable>
      <para>With the right mouse click you can manage WebYaST:</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/qwebyast21.jpeg"
            width="25%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>With this applet you can start WebYaST in your browser too. After accepting the GPG-key
        please login with your <quote>root</quote> account.</para>
      <para>And that’s WebYaST:</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/webyast.png"
            width="25%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>That’s all.</para>
      <para>(Yes, I know that sentence is written almost in every post here. Even in posts where
        problems just starting after the sentence has been read. :-) )But I think that should be
        really all. If not, please use bugzilla and blame us ! Have fun ! </para>
      <para>(Yes, I know that’s the second sentence which should be in every blog :-) )</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 22.12.10 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://www.tuxarena.com/?p=508">8 More Bash Tips for Working Faster With
          the Shell (Part 2 of 2)</ulink></title>
      <para>My last post was about converting audio files in Linux with GStreamer. In that post I
        showed how to convert FLAC files to Ogg Vorbis files and retain the audio tags. You may
        however, have an audio player that does not support playing Ogg Vorbis audio files and you
        want to convert your files to MP3 instead.</para>
      <para>The following commands will work as long as you have the appropriate GStreamer plugins
        installed along with the LAME package.</para>
      <para>This command will encode to MP3 using LAME's defaults.</para>
      <screen>gst-launch filesrc location=file.flac ! flacdec ! audioconvert ! lamemp3enc ! id3v2mux ! filesink location=file.mp3</screen>
      <para>If you want to encode your files with VBR at a higher quality level, you can do
        something like this.</para>
      <screen>gst-launch filesrc location=file.flac ! flacdec ! audioconvert ! lamemp3enc target=quality quality=2 ! id3v2mux ! filesink location=file.mp3</screen>
      <!-- ($ ld: 18.12.10 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://www.linux.com/learn/tutorials/390966:creating-and-reading-ebooks-on-linux-with-calibre"
          >Linux.com/Joe Brockmeier: Creating and Reading eBooks on Linux with
        Calibre</ulink></title>
      <para>Many of us are hoping for an eBook reader under the tree. A Kindle, a Nook, or perhaps
        just an Android device that runs eBook software. But if you don't get the gadget of your
        choice, or if you want to create content to fill one, you'll find plenty of eBook software
        for Linux as well as open source software to publish your own. The best of the lot? Calibre,
        a one stop solution for all your e-book needs. I didn't coin that term for Calibre — that's
        their motto. How accurate is it? Very. Calibre handles library management, format
        conversion, syncing to your device, and more. Oh, and it also lets you read your books too.
        Nice, eh?</para>
      <figure id="fig.calibre">
        <title>Viewing the Linux.com RSS Feed as eBook</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://www.linux.com/images/stories/screenshot-e-book%20viewer%20-%20linux.com.png"
              width="25%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Formats and DRM</emphasis> If you're new to eBooks, you might be
        wondering what I'm babbling about with regards to format conversions. Just as video and
        digital audio have a lot of formats to choose from, so do eBooks. Annoyingly, they not only
        offer many formats, but also several DRM schemes too. </para>
      <para>One of the problems with eBooks, or some eBooks, is Digital Restriction Management
        (DRM). Yes, the industry likes to call it Digital Right's Management, but that's really not
        what's going on. When you buy books from Amazon, Barnes and Noble, Apple, etc.the books are
        encrypted with DRM so that you can't open them on multiple devices or competing devices —
        even if they support the same format. For example, ePub is a widely supported format that
        can be read by a number of eBook devices like Barnes and Noble's Nook and iBooks on iOS. If
        you have an ePub book without DRM, you can read it anywhere. </para>
      <para>But ePub supports an optional DRM scheme, so publishers can add DRM to it and restrict
        it to one player or one type of DRM format. I don't find it upsetting that publishers are
        trying to find a way to limit sharing of eBooks, but the side effect is that users really
        lack options when it comes to acquiring books. If you want access to new books, you're stuck
        choosing one of the major vendors (Amazon, Apple, Barnes and Noble, etc.) and then as you
        acquire more material, you get locked into those vendors and their readers. </para>
      <para>Unfortunately, I don't have a good answer to that if you want access to the latest books
        via electronic formats. But if you want to read classics or publish your own books, you have
        lots of great options with open source. </para>
      <para>You'll find quite a few eBook formats, but the ones that matter the most for the most
        popular devices (Kindle, Nook, and iBooks on iOS) are ePub and Mobipocket. You'll also find
        a lot of support for PDF and plain text, too, but those are well-understood and handled
        formats within open source already. The ePub format is supported via Nook and iBooks,
        Mobipocket on Kindle. You can produce both ePub and Mobipocket with Calibre. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 17.12.10 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/12/17/adobe-flash-64-bits-under-opensuse-64bits-11-211-311-4factory/"
          >Bruno Friedmann: Adobe Flash 64 bits under openSUSE 64bits
          (11.2,11.3,11.4,factory)</ulink></title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Non Free </emphasis></para>
      <para>Dear readers, we sometimes have to use non-free software. This post will learn you how
        to get the latest flash player supporting natively your favorite openSUSE Linux 64 bits
        distribution. Keep in mind that it is preview software, actually pre-release code quality,
        and with it you will not receive any security updates. Keep an eyes on it, and refresh it
        manually if newer version are published So why to try that software ? My answer is simple :
        it’s a native 64bits plug-in. So it’s interaction with your native 64bits browser, should
        give you a better stability. My experience using it in the last 4 months is pretty good, no
        Firefox crash due to flash. (Several pro week or day with the 32bits 10.0 version) </para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Get ready</emphasis></para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Remove any installed 32bits packages </emphasis>First things to
        do, remove all actual 32bits flash installed. </para>
      <para><screen>zypper rm flash-player pullin-flash-player</screen><emphasis role="bold">Get the
          lastest Flash square preview </emphasis></para>
      <para>Go the main project page Square </para>
      <para>Read the informations, and the Adobe License you implicitly accept by using this
        software. </para>
      <para>Then Download the tar.gz </para>
      <para>
        <screen>cd /tmp wget http://download.macromedia.com/pub/labs/flashplayer10/flashplayer10_2_p3_64bit_linux_111710.tar.gz</screen>
      </para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Uncompress &amp; Install</emphasis></para>
      <para>
        <screen>tar -xvzf flashplayer10_2_p3_64bit_linux_111710.tar.gz</screen>
      </para>
      <para>
        <screen>sudo chown root:root libflashplayer.so</screen>
      </para>
      <para>
        <screen>sudo cp libflashplayer.so /usr/lib64/browser-plugins/libflashplayer.so</screen>
      </para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Test </emphasis></para>
      <para>Close any firefox or konqueror running, and restart them under firefox, launch the
        about:plugins uri and you should <emphasis role="bold">see Shockwave Flash File:
          libflashplayer.so Version: Shockwave Flash 10.3 d162</emphasis> Have a nice surfing
        session, if you like flash website .</para>
      <para><!-- ($ ld: 17.12.10 sm $) --></para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Commandline/Script Newbies</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://www.tuxarena.com/?p=508">Tuxarena/Craciun Dan: 8 More Bash Tips for
          Working Faster With the Shell (Part 2 of 2)</ulink></title>
      <para>This is the second article in this series, and brings eight additional tips for working
        faster with the shell. <ulink url="http://www.tuxarena.com/?p=257">Here</ulink> is the first
        article of the series, containing 10 tips. (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>For Developers and Programmers</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>super article</title>
      <para>bin/sh</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
  <sect2>
    <title>For System Administrators</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://saschpe.wordpress.com/2010/12/20/reclaim-me-blocks/">Sascha
          Peilicke: Reclaim me blocks!</ulink></title>
      <para>Ever wondered why your filesystems fill up so quickly and why those new discs aren’t as
        big as advertised? While the latter may have several reasons (measuring units, the metric
        system or just damn lies), it may also be just an overly precautious default filesystem
        setting. On Linux, every filesystem gets some 5% of the available blocks reserved for the
        root user. This way, you can still work on your machine even if you forgot to rotate your
        log files Changing this default to something more realistic on today’s big hard discs may
        come with a nice surprises. Here’s my laptops root partition before:</para>
      <screen>saschpe@minime:~% df -h
        Filesystem Size Used Avail Use% Mounted on
        /dev/sda1 168G 144G 16G 91% /</screen>
      <para>Now let’s do a courageous tune2fs changing this to 0.2% (more than enough to be able to
        login and remove logfiles):</para>
      <screen>sudo tune2fs -m 0.2 /dev/sda1</screen>
      <para>And check again:</para>
      <screen>saschpe@minime:~/download% df -h
        Filesystem Size Used Avail Use% Mounted on
        /dev/sda1 168G 144G 24G 86% /</screen>
      <para>How neat, 8 fresh new gigs of storage :-)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 21.12.10 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
