<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="tipsandtricks">
  <title>Tips and Tricks</title>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Desktop Users</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.banym.de/security/use-ssh-for-more-secure-browsing-in-public-networks">Dominik Zajac: Use SSH for more secure browsing in public networks</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>In the time of free wifi and free internet connections in every hotel, bar or cafe you should be sure your connections are secure. In some cases you can’t trust the connection but you need to go online and read some mails or share some documents. In this case some basic tools like SSH and Firefox can help you to build an secure connection to an known computer in the internet you can trust (for example your own root server).</para>
      <para>To make more clear what I am talking about i created this small diagram to make it more easy for me to explain what I am doing with this SSH connection and how I can benefit from it. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 5.8.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://olex.openlogic.com/wazi/2011/how-to-create-an-ebook-with-openoffice-org/">Wazi/Dmitry Kaglik: How To Create an Ebook with OpenOffice.org</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Do you want to see your name on the front page of a book? It’s easier than you might think. First, write the book. Next, follow these simple steps to prepare an ebook using the free OpenOffice.org desktop publishing application.</para>
      <para>Publishing ebooks today can be a DIY business. If you write for a specific audience, you can create a successful book without the help of big companies, and get your work into the hands of readers who can download ebooks from popular sites such as Amazon CreateSpace, Lulu, or Lightning Source.</para>
      <para>Let’s assume you’ve already written the book you want to publish. Your work might be in plain text format or written using a word processing application. No matter where it starts out, import it into OOo Writer and use that program’s rich set of tools to create a file for publication. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 5.8.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linux.com/learn/tutorials/477968-advanced-layering-techniques-on-linux-with-gimp">Linux.com/Jack Wallen: Advanced Layering Techniques on Linux with GIMP</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The <ulink url="http://www.gimp.org/">GNU Image Manipulation Program</ulink> (GIMP) is one of the most powerful image editing tools available. It is, effectively, the Photoshop of the open source world; and with that kind of title comes a level of power most never take advantage of. One feature that should be a must-use for all digital artists is the layer. Using layers not only makes work easier, it gives digital art more depth and more flexibility.</para>
      <para>What I want to do is to illustrate some of the more advanced methods for using layering in GIMP. Once these techniques have been mastered, creating and editing digital masterpieces will be so much easier. I will assume the basics of layers is understood (such as how to add, copy, and delete layers), so the 101-level layer steps will not be discussed.(...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 5.8.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Commandline/Script Newbies</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://bashshell.net/utilities/line-addressing-in-sed/">BashShell.net/Mike: Line Addressing in sed</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Line Addressing</emphasis></para>
      <para>Line addressing allows you to select the lines that you want to work with.  Addressing can use regular expressions to determine the lines or list numbers for the lines in the format of a number.  If two numbers are used separated by a comma then it becomes a range.(...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 5.8.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://linuxaria.com/pills/be-nice-with-your-process-on-linux?lang=en">Linuxaria: Be nice with your process on Linux</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>On Linux there is a way to set/change the priority of processes, the user can act to give greater or lesser priority to its own processes.</para>
      <para>For example you are running a backup with rsync or doing a tar, but you do not want these processes use all your CPU, in these cases you can make use of the nice command. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 5.8.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://flossstuff.wordpress.com/2011/07/09/how-bash-shell-interprets-a-command/">Ankur Aggarwal: How Bash Shell interprets a command ??</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>In this previous part of this article we learned about  types of shells . In most of the Linux distributions , bash shell is the default shell. So we are going to discuss the working of bash shell in this article . Fasten your seat belts and get ready for the bash ride :D (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
<!--
  <sect2>
    <title>For Developers and Programmers</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.techradar.com/news/software/operating-systems/19-ways-to-do-your-bit-for-open-source-980764">techradar/Neil Bothwick:19 ways to do your bit for open source</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>It&apos;s undoubtedly good to give back to a community you take so much from.</para>
      <para>And in doing so, you can also help improve the software that you use every day, both for
        your benefit and for everyone else.</para>
      <para>Here are 19 ways you can help open source projects.</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->  <sect2>
    <title>For System Administrators</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.serverwatch.com/tutorials/article.php/3937996/Try-collectlfor-System-Monitoring.htm">ServerWatch/Joe Brockmeier: Try collectl for System Monitoring</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Most Linux system administrators are familiar with sar for collecting system status data. However, there&apos;s a few ways that sar shows its age and doesn&apos;t quite live up to expectations. If you&apos;re looking for a newer utility that also handles NFS, Slab data and sub-second intervals, <ulink url="http://collectl.sourceforge.net/">collectl</ulink> may better fit the bill.</para>
      <para>The collectl utility was written by Mark Seger, and it is dual-licensed under the Artistic License and GNU General Public License (GPL). It&apos;s written in Perl and does a bit more than <ulink url="http://collectl.sourceforge.net/Architecture.html">just read from /proc and copy data to the terminal</ulink>. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 5.8.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
