<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="tipsandtricks">
  <title>Tips and Tricks</title>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Desktop Users</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="nbprashanth.wordpress.com/2011/10/01/customizing-gnome3/">N.B.Prashanth:
          Customizing GNOME3</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>GNOME3 and the GNOME Shell are no doubt, major improvements. They bring in usability and
        quite a bit of eye candy (in a different way compared to compiz) while at the same time, a
        few features went missing in 3.0 release – like Emblems, for instance. Nevertheless, GNOME3
        is a great release and has been extremely stable so far (Yes, i have been using it since
        it’s release in April.). </para>
      <para>One major complaint that I hear from people is that GNOME3 is not as easy to customize
        as 2.x. A lot of people seem to think that they are “stuck” with the blue-black theme that
        comes by default. Ofcourse this is not the case. In this post, I ll explain a few ways in
        which we can customize GNOME3 and the GNOME Shell. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 02.10.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://scribblesandsnaps.wordpress.com/2011/09/26/five-quick-digikam-tricks/">Dmitri Popov: Open Source Photography Tools Five Quick digiKam Tricks</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Tip #1</para>
      <para>To quickly adjust thumbnail size in the Album view, press and hold the Ctrl key, then use the mouse scroll wheel to make the thumbnails larger or smaller.</para>
      <para>Tip #2</para>
      <para>With the Non-Destructive editing and Versioning feature enabled, digiKam automatically hides originals and displays the latest modified versions of the photos. For example, if you process a NEF file and save it in the JPEG format, digiKam hides the original RAW file and shows only the JPEG photo. To disable this feature, choose <emphasis role="bold">Settings</emphasis> → <emphasis role="bold">Configure digiKam</emphasis> → <emphasis role="bold">Editing Images</emphasis> and make sure that the <emphasis role="bold">Always show original images</emphasis> option in the In main view section is enabled. To keep things tidy, you can then group the original and all its versions. To do this, select the photos you want to group, right-click on the selection, and choose <emphasis role="bold">Group</emphasis> → <emphasis role="bold">Group Selected Here</emphasis>. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 30.9.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Commandline/Script Newbies</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://linuxaria.com/article/pipes-linux?lang=en">Linuxaria: Pipes – what are they and Example of Use</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Unix based operating systems like Linux offer a unique approach to join two commands on the terminal, with it you can take the output of the first command and use it as input of the second command, this is the concept of pipe or | . Pipes allow two separate process to communicate with each other also if they were not created to do it, so this open an infinite series of opportunity. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 30.9.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.eracc.com/content/custom-weekly-backup-tar">Home ERA Computers &amp; Consulting: Custom Weekly Backup with tar</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>This page describes one method of backing up data from one&apos;s Linux or Unix based system to an external medium using a bash script and tar. Here is the script for the impatient ones who &quot;Just want some code!&quot;: (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 30.9.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Developers and Programmers</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.misfitgeek.com/2011/09/avascript-developer-tools-for-linux-2/">Joe Stagner: Selecting and Installing JavaScript Developer Tools for Linux</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Choosing an editor or IDE for development is a personal thing, like choosing a car. What is a perfect ride for one person offers no interest at all to another. Personally, I was never happy with only one car and usually want different ones in the garage so that I can choose the one that most closely matches my mood or the kind of driving that I need to do.</para>
      <para>Some folks like the help and tooling of a fully integrated environment like Visual Studio. Others like the hardcore elitism of EMACS or Vi. I’m a pragmatist, I like tools that just help me get the job done. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 30.9.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For System Administrators</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxjournal.com/content/playterm-platform-gurus">IBM Developer
          Works/Tracy Bost: Learn Linux, 302 (Mixed environments): Internationalization</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>If you work in a mixed environment in which non-English characters are used, you need to
        understand character codes and code pages as they relate to your locale. You also need to
        understand Linux and Windows environments differ when interpreting name spaces. Although
        Samba supports internationalization, if you work with older Windows clients , Samba 2.x
        versions, or otherwise need to use a specific character set other than Unicode, you'll need
        to do a bit of configuration tuning. Depending upon the environment's locale in use,
        building and patching conversion libraries may also be necessary. In this article, learn how
        to handle internationalization in your Linux environment. (...)</para>
<!--($ Id: 05.10.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.ibm.com/developerworks/linux/library/l-lpic3-312-5/index.html?ca=drs-"
          >ZDNET/Steven J. Vaughan-Nichols: How to lock down Linux</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Linux is, by design, a very secure operating system, but so what? You can have the best
        security system in the world on your house, but if you leave your front-door open anyone can
        still walk in. Even people who know better, like Linux kernel developers, blow it sometimes.
        That’s what happened to the <ulink url="http://www.linuxfoundation.org">Linux
          Foundation</ulink>’s constellation of sites. <ulink
          url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/some-linux-foundation-crack-attack-details-emerge/9535"
          >Multiple important Linux sites were down for weeks</ulink> and as of October 3rd, <ulink
          url="http://http://kernel.org">kernel.org</ulink> is still down. This doesn’t have to
        happen to you. Here are a few simple suggestions from me, and some more advanced ones from
          <ulink url="http://www.kroah.com/log/">Greg Kroah-Hartman</ulink>, one of Linux’s lead
        developers. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 05.10.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://beginlinux.com/desktop/opensuse/opensuse-pxe-boot">BeginLinux: OpenSUSE PXE Boot</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>What we will look at</para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>What is PXELinux</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>DHCP Configuration</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Confirm the Installation Server Source</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Installing PXE and TFTP</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Populate the TFTP Directory</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Configure and Test PXE
(...)</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
<!-- ($ Id: 30.9.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
