<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/02/22/opensuse-participates-in-the-google-summer-of-code-2011/"
        >openSUSE participates in the Google Summer of Code 2011</ulink></title>
    <note>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is Licensed under the <ulink
            url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/fdl.txt">GNU Free Documentation
          License.</ulink></emphasis></para>
    </note>
    <para>In about a week Google will accept applications from Free Software projects to be part of
      Google’s Summer of Code. This great project enables students who want to spend their summer
      time working on Free Software instead of a regular summer job the opportunity to do. Commonly
      called GSOC, the program helps students by paying them cash for their code. A successful
      project makes the student about USD 5000 which certainly is not bad for a summer job. </para>
    <para>The students get mentored and the project itself receives another donation of USD500 per
      successful student project. Of course GSOC is not just about the money: it is about learning
      and making a difference for the students; it is about having fun and learning for the mentors
      too; and the project often gains valuable new contributors!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Why and for whom?</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>GSOC has shown to be successful in its goal of bringing new contributors to Free Software.
      Over the years many students continued to be involved in the projects they have participated
      in through GSOC. If you are a student and want to contribute and even make a career in Free
      Software we definitely advice you to think about being part of a GSOC program. </para>
    <para>But also if you are already an openSUSE contributor and you would love an opportunity to
      spend 8 weeks full time on your favorite project, this is for you! Many great applications and
      initiatives have been started as GSOC programs in the past like Cheese and Empathy. Many
      students who started with Free Software thanks to GSOC have been able to turn it into a great
      career, all that while having fun. </para>
    <para>openSUSE has unfortunately not been able to participate in GSOC last year. This year we do
      want to do better and for that we need help. We need people from our community to step up and
      be mentors, we need ideas for students to execute and of course we need students to submit
      proposals! </para>
    <para>Women, don’t forget you are very welcome to be part of openSUSE. We are a community which
      embraces diversity. We want everyone to have fun, no matter your, skill level, gender, race,
      cultural background or where you’re from. Everyone deserves an opportunity like this, so join
      us!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Information </emphasis></para>
    <para>You can find openSUSE’s <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:GSOC_2011">wiki
        page</ulink> on GSOC 2011 here and our <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:GSOC_2011_Ideas">list of ideas here</ulink>. Many
      people have already submitted ideas but more are very welcome.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 22.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
