<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://michal.hrusecky.net/2011/08/libyui-in-gentoo/">Michal Hrušecký: libyui
        in Gentoo</ulink></title>
    <para>Some time ago I wrote a blog post about <ulink
        url="http://michal.hrusecky.net/2011/06/osc-client-in-gentoo/">osc in Gentoo</ulink>. As I
      already stated there, we’ve got some pretty cool technologies in openSUSE and I would like to
      promote them everywhere. And as I’m also partially Gentoo user and I have many Gentoo friends,
      I’m trying to make some of the coolest openSUSE technologies available on Gentoo. One of the
      cool things we’ve got is libYUI. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 18.08.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/08/19/opensuse-lxde-logo-contest-starting-now/">Andrea
        Florio: openSUSE-LXDE logo contest starting now!</ulink></title>
    <para>As recently announced <ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/08/12/looking-for-artists-artworks-and-graphics-for-lxde/"
        >here</ulink>, the LXDE team is looking for graphics contributors. Trying to involve as much
      people as possible i created a graphic contest! Is time for you, cool graphics, to create a
      logo for the openSUSE-LXDE team!</para>
    <para>The contest will start tomorrow, everyone is welcome to join! All the rules are in <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:LXDE_Logo_Contest">our wiki</ulink>! </para>
    <para>So? what are you waiting for??? </para>
    <para>Is just the right time to <emphasis role="bold">Have a lot of fun…</emphasis></para>
    <!--($ ld: 19.08.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.marques.so/2011/08/a-brief-update-on-things/">Nelson Marques: A
        brief update on things…</ulink></title>
    <para>I’ve been a bit away from openSUSE in the last months (mainly this summer) and this is
      related to several things that are happening in my personal life. During this time I’ve kept a
      look in several packages I maintain for GNOME, but haven’t been doing anything related to
      openSUSE.</para>
    <para>As many people know, the international pressures in Portugal are placing much demanding
      things on every citizen, mainly on the working force. I still don’t see the shackles around my
      hands, but it’s pretty much obvious they exist and they are around my wrists. It’s time to
      rethink the strategy for the life I wanted to live and move out to living it.</para>
    <para>No changes to be announced except that some weight I shouldered is going to be dropped,
      this is the case of GNOME:Ayatana, which I will discuss with Vincent once he’s around, but
      from my side the proposal is simple, salvage all the packages that are requirements to other
      packages and might have some utility in the distro, all the others, just a plain and simple
      nuke them. It served it’s purposes, but I no longer have the time or will to continue
      maintaining stuff, some that worked, others that never worked. In a way I was wrong, openSUSE
      users are far better with the traditional choices, ex: GNOME, than with other alternative
      choices.</para>
    <!--$ ld: 20.08.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://vizzzion.org/blog/2011/08/release-team-changes/">Sebastian Kügler: Release Team Changes</ulink>
    </title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Release Team Changes</emphasis></para>
    <para>During the Desktop Summit in Berlin, we had a session in which we had a good look at
      how KDE’s release team performs, which points we can improve on, how, and who will
      implement these changes. For example: <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Make our output more predictable and thus downstreams’ lives easier</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Reduce the risk of something going wrong, the <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bus_number">bus number problem</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Make our work more efficient</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>Let’s take a step back first, though.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">A bit of history: from Coolo &amp; Dirk to TWG to Release Team</emphasis></para>
    <para>In KDE 3, Coolo and Dirk managed KDE’s releases. When KDE4 was started, we also wanted
      to promote this in a more suitable fashion, we started doing more proactive PR work, and
      generally improved our communication to our users (potential or not). In 2005, the
      Technical Working Group was conceived, which was meant to handle the releases of KDE4. The
      Technical Working Group didn’t quite work out since it didn’t bring the structural changes
      we needed in order to release KDE4. In late 2006 we we decided that it didn’t work,
      disbanded the TWG and conceived the release team, a self-organized team of volunteers.
      Conceptually, the release team started as a place for people to go who wanted to make
      releases happen. We found module maintainers for our released modules who would coordinate
      towards the app teams and, and a few core people who know how all that stuff works to put
      things together. We got our release process on the rails again. Interestingly, the release
      team is very informal, we never ended up appointing anyone release manager, or
      end-responsible — it has also never been necessary, it seems. Lesson here: shared
      responsibility works well for us.</para>
    <para>A quick unscientific count of the whole KDE 4 series (including pre-releases) brought
      me to 88 releases done by the release team in its current form.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 16.8.11 sm $)-->      </blockquote>
</sect1>
