<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
  <!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
  %myentities;
]>
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://nowwhatthe.blogspot.com/2010/11/catching-up.html">Jos Poortvliet:
        catching up</ulink></title>
    <para>Hi! It feels like ages since I blogged, so here goes. A lot has happened since my last
      blog - Latinoware is over (and was frickin' awesome), I had a week off which I enjoyed in
      Brazil and now I'm at the Nuremberg offices due to Michl who just left. We had some catching
      up to do before he went - same with AJ who has decided to enjoy some parental leave. And
      Jaqueline who will have to fill the shoes of these two fine gentlemen. Meanwhile I am trying
      to catch up to mail and news - there is a lot of both. Mail catching up has been limited quite
      a bit by the KDE Factory OBS repository for 11.3 upgrading to KDE's 4.6 release of platform
      (Akonadi!), apps (KMail2) and desktop workspace. The two I mentioned (Akonadi &amp; kmail2)
      have been a royal pain in the ass, to be honest. The migration of my old accounts took a night
      (>100.000 mails) but didn't actually import those mails. Hence they had to be downloaded from
      gmail. With the VERY frequent disconnections and regular hanging of the Akonadi resource this
      has taken a while to say the least - lots of babysitting (restarting Akonadi etc) required. I
      hope the KDE Pim* dudes and dudettes can get this stable (and faster!) before the release...
      Oh, and Virtuoso-t keeps hogging 100% CPU untill I decide to just kill it - after which I
      don't notice any bad or strange behavior. Maybe I should auto-kill it on login ;-) but in the
      end, it's all working reasonably well now, albeit a bit slower than KMail1.x. Yay yay.  (...)
      (EDITMARK)</para>
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
