<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/06/27/facebook-bans-kdes-photo-uploaded-all-uploaded-content-inaccessible/"
        >Will Stephenson: Facebook bans KDE’s photo uploader; all uploaded content
        inaccessible.</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>So in my head there’s a little Walter Sobchak beating on my conscience and shouting “This
      is what you get when you trust Facebook with your data, Will”. </para>
    <para>The reason is that I upload photos to Facebook using KDE’s shared uploader and this has
      fallen victim to the whims of FB’s purge of its app biosphere. Unless the original developer
      can convince them that the app is not spammy, offering a bad experience or having the wrong
      attitude, the app, my photos (all archived elsewhere of course), but most importantly, all the
      kind comments from my friends and contacts that represent FB’s only value, get sent to the
      farm. </para>
    <para>This is what you get when you trust one company with stuff you care about. Will.</para>
<!--($ ld: 28.6.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://obsforandroid.wordpress.com/2011/06/21/opensuse-buildservice-101/"
        >Justine Leng: openSUSE buildservice 101</ulink></title>
    <para>One of the reasons that Novell created this community-based openSUSE project was to invite
      contributions from independent developers. It also unveiled a new online service that
      automatically builds binary packages from source code. The openSUSE buildservice initially
      focused on building packages for the SUSE variants — openSUSE, SLES, and SLED — but the tool
      was later extended to support packages for other major distributions, such as Red Hat, Fedora,
      Mandriva, Debian, and Ubuntu. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 22.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://anditosan.blogspot.com/2011/06/custom-setups-for-revolutionized.html"
        >Andres Silva: Custom Setups for Revolutionized Desktop</ulink></title>
    <para>Ok my friends. Here is the thing: An idea came up recently in the artwork mailing list to
      make openSUSE a little different than other times in the graphical aspect. The idea would be
      to add different default plasma widgets, as well as to make subtle changes to the panels. A
      friend also suggested that it would be cool to create a more socially integrated widget. I
      thought of one that was included in the Kickoff menu. Added to one of the tabs in there, there
      could exist a simple update tracker for different social networks, such as Facebook, Twitter,
      or Google Blogs. Whatever the service that may be, it doesn't matter. The main idea is to add
      something social to the default desktop in KDE under the new release of openSUSE. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 24.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
