<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <important>
    <para>The Articles inside this Section are in full. If you are already knowing the stuff in
      news.opensuse.org, then you can skip this section through using the TOC.</para>
  </important>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/20/opensuse-summer-camp-greece-2011/"
        >openSUSE Summer Camp Greece 2011</ulink></title>
    <para><inlinegraphic fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/Geekocamp.jpg"
      /></para>
    <para>Summer in Greece! Is the weather too hot for you to code or contribute to your favorite
      FOSS project? Do you need some motivation and a refreshing swim? Come to our Summer
      Camp!</para>
    <para>The Greek openSUSE community is organizing its first openSUSE Summer Camp, in central
      Greece at Grand Platon Hotel at Olympiaki akti. This is is the beach of the city of Katerini.
      The doors will be open from the 15th to the 17th of July 2011, at the Heart of Summer!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Sounds awesome, I’ll book my tickets.</emphasis></para>
    <para>So, you’ll be there. What can you expect?</para>
    <para>Our goal is to bring FOSS communities closer and encourage people to contribute to their
      favorite projects.</para>
    <para>A lot of people, with little to a lot of experience can benefit from the workshops
      included in our program, during which we will work on things like translation, wiki usage,
      coding, packaging and much more, showing how to work inside a community and how to collaborate
      with others!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Hmmm. But I could go swimming…</emphasis></para>
    <para>There will be relaxing and swimming of course! But hey, we have a common passion, don’t
      we?</para>
    <para>We love what we do, we are having fun contributing to FOSS and we hate doing it alone in
      our rooms during Summer time. Besides coding, translating and all other ‘working stuff’ there
      will also be plenty of sun and beach, a large swimming pool and plenty of beers – all paid by
      you since we only sponsor the sun, the fun and all the other free stuff…</para>
    <para>We are looking forward to seeing you at the openSUSE Summer Camp Greece!</para>
    <!--($ ld: 21.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
