<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="tipsandtricks">
  <title>Tips and Tricks</title>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Desktop Users</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxjournal.com/video/get-firefox-menu-button-linux">Linux Journal/Shawn Powers: Get Firefox Menu Button in Linux</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The Windows version of Firefox comes with a fancy menu button in the title bar. Linux doesn&apos;t have that exact feature, but you can come close. Shawn Powers shows us how.</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 23.9.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
<!--
  <sect2>
    <title>For Commandline/Script Newbies</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://elevenislouder.blogspot.com/2011/08/introduction-to-find.html">Eleven is Louder: An Introduction to Find</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Learning find can seem daunting at first, but it is worth learning. There is no single more useful search tool for UNIX like systems. You could almost consider find a very primitive scripting language in itself as find can find the files you request and then perform tasks. (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->  <sect2>
    <title>For Developers and Programmers</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://log.or.cz/?p=213">Petr Baudis: Realtime Signal Analysis in Perl</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>About a month ago, we were working on <ulink url="http://brmlab.cz/project/fluffyball">the Fluffy Ball project</ulink> – a computer input device that can react to fondling and
        punching. Thanks to a nice idea on the brmlab mailing list, we use a microphone and process
        the noise coming from the ball’s scratchy stuffing and an embedded jingle. The sounds from
        the outside are almost entirely dampened by the stuffing and for a human, the noise of
        fondling and punching is easily distinguishable.</para>
      <para>It turns out that trivial spectrum-based rules can be used to achieve reasonably high
        detection accuracy for a computer too (especially when the user is allowed to “train” her
        input based on feedback); I had big plans to use ANN and all the nifty things I have learned
        in our AI classes, but it turned out to be simply an overkill. The input signal is
        transformed to a frequency spectrum (see box) using <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Discrete_Fourier_transform">real discrete FFT</ulink>. (...)</para>
<!--($ Id: 24.9.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For System Administrators</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.ibm.com/developerworks/linux/library/l-lpic1-v3-101-2/index.html?ca=drs-"
          >All about Linux: Learn Linux Commands The Easy Way</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>There are hundreds of command line tools in Linux. For a person who has just started
        using Linux, learning the various commands could at times, be a chore. But not any more, if
        you see what this website has achieved. </para>
      <para>Playterm is a site which hosts videos of commands / tasks executed in the Linux
        terminal. (...)</para>
<!--($ Id: 27.9.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.ibm.com/developerworks/linux/library/l-lpic3-312-5/index.html?ca=drs-">IBM
          Developer Works/Roderick W. Smith: Learn Linux, 302 (Mixed environments): SWAT
          configuration</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The Samba Web Administration Tool (SWAT) is a web-based administration tool for Samba,
        enabling GUI configuration from any computer with a web browser. SWAT is a server in its own
        right, and like all servers, it requires at least minimal configuration. In this article,
        learn how to install and configure SWAT itself and how to use SWAT to manage Samba.
        (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 27.9.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
