<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="forums">
  <title>openSUSE Forums</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/community/general-chit-chat/451854-christmas-theme-login.html">
	Christmas login theme
	</ulink></title>
    <para>
      This thread is about the annually returning phenomenon of the cute little penguins taking over the GRUB boot menu appearance. New users suspect virus infections, worms et cetera. In the thread you will learn, that it's not. Not a Christmas theme either, just a winter theme, given to us by the GRUB developpers.
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-help-here/applications/451886-11-2-partition-isolation-issue.html">
      Partition isolation issue on openSUSE 11.2
      </ulink></title>
    <para>
      Many times we meet issues on how to mount partitions. Here we have the opposite going on: how to keep end-users from mounting partitions the administrator does not want them to mount, for example partitions containing other operating systems. Filemanagers like Dolphin on KDE show these partitions as "Places" that can be accessed, where the administrator does not want these "places" to be exposed to end-user access. Various options to achieve this "isolation of partitions" are shown.
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-help-here/install-boot-login/451891-speed-up-boot-time.html">
      Speed up boot time
      </ulink></title>
    <para>
      A returning issue. With a lot of new technologies to speed up the boot time, some of them already in use on other distros, this question/issue arises. The thread starter found a difference in boot time speed between the latest Linux Mint and openSUSE. Read how members jump in to explain about the many improvements, that will definitely come to openSUSE as well.
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>This week's subforum: <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/forums-feedback/how-use-forums/">
      How to use the forums
      </ulink></title>
    <para>
      One of the main issues for the Forums Team is to make the forums access fast and easy. Some users prefer NNTP (newsgroup) to read and post, others prefer the web interface. In this subforum you may find instructions on how to make things even better for you by using the forums software's features, there's threads to help you to use NNTP, explanations of the legenda etc. 
    </para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 07.12.10 gl $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
