<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
  %myentities;
]>
<sect1 role="updates">
  <title>New/Updated Applications @ openSUSE</title>
<!--* Gnome
* KDE
* XYZ 

Version should be available at packman or software.opensuse.org/search max. 4 posts. -->  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://hermes.opensuse.org/messages/6195364">OBS openSUSE:11.3:Update/clamav r2
        commited </ulink></title>
    <para>Updated to clamav-0.96.4. </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/2010/11/30/smb-traffic-analyzer-1-2-1-released/">Holger
        Hetterich: SMB Traffic Analyzer 1.2.1 released</ulink></title>
    <para>The team is happy to announce the release of SMB Traffic Analyzer (SMBTA in the following)
      version 1.2.1. This is a very important release, as many fixes have been done for the build,
      making both smbtad and smbtatools much more portable. Also, the build has been adapted to work
      with libraries that are not installed at the usual places on the system (bnc#654930). On the
      feature side, we have two really cool things to say. First off, we are introducing rrddriver
      with this release. It is an interface to rrdtool, and allows to build a round robin database
      from the data smbtad is receiving, in real time. Having data in a rrdtool database allows you
      to create all the fancy graphics SMBTA was missing until today (bnc#655149). (...) </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://packman.links2linux.org/package/handbrake-unstable">Packman:
        handbrake-unstable 0.9.4+3697-0</ulink></title>
    <para>HandBrake is an open-source, GPL-licensed, multiplatform, multithreaded video
      transcoder.</para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://packman.links2linux.org/package/lightspark">Packman: lightspark
        0.4.4-0.pm.1.6</ulink></title>
    <para>Lightspark is a FLOSS Flash player entirely rewritten from scratch based on Adobe's
      released SWF documentation. Lightspark features: <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>JIT compilation of Actionscript to native x86 bytecode using LLVM.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Hardware accelerated rendering using OpenGL Shaders (GLSL).</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Very good and robust support for current-generation Actionscript3.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>A new, clean, codebase exploiting multithreading and optimized for modern hardware.
            Designed from scratch after the official Flash documentation was released.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://packman.links2linux.org/package/FrostWire">Packman: FrostWire
        4.20.6_svn1467-0.pm.1.9</ulink></title>
    <para>FrostWire is a gnutella client written in Java. It supports a number of advanced features
      like ultrapeers (like FastTrack's supernodes), automatic download retries, freeloader
      punishment, etc. FrostWire is a fork of the very popular LimeWire Gnutella client. The purpose
      of FrostWire is to keep and maintain the freedoms that LimeWire LLC may be forced to withdraw.
    </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://packman.links2linux.org/package/vlc">Packman: vlc
        1.1.5-1.pm.3.13</ulink></title>
    <para>VLC media player is a highly portable multimedia player for various audio and video
      formats (MPEG-1, MPEG-2, MPEG-4, DivX, mp3, ogg, ...) as well as DVDs, VCDs, and various
      streaming protocols. It can also be used as a server to stream in unicast or multicast in IPv4
      or IPv6 on a high-bandwidth network.</para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://packman.links2linux.org/package/Scrabble">Packman: Scrabble
        3.1.0rc8-0.pm.1.3</ulink></title>
    <para>Play Scrabble against computer, other local or network connected player. Full
      configurable, different languages available and user editable, user defined libraries etc.
      Basically designed to develop a 3D version of the well known board game. </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://packman.links2linux.org/package/frinika/195819">Packman: frinika
        0.6.0-0.pm.2.14</ulink></title>
    <para>Frinika is a free, complete music workstation software for Linux, Windows, Mac OSX Tiger
      and other operating systems running Java 1.5. It features sequencer, soft-synths, realtime
      effects and audio recording. Frinika is compact, self-contained and simple - yet powerful
      enough to boost your musical creativity.</para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://hermes.opensuse.org/messages/6369500">OBS
        openSUSE:11.3:Update/java-1_6_0-openjdk r3 commited</ulink></title>
    <para>Updated to icedtea6-1.9.2 (EDITMARK)</para>
  </blockquote>
  
  <itemizedlist>
    <title>You can find other interesting Packages at:</title>
    <listitem>
      <para><ulink url="http://packman.links2linux.de/rdf/packman_en.rdf">Packman</ulink></para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para><ulink url="https://hermes.opensuse.org/feeds/66367.rdf">openSUSE Build
        Service</ulink></para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</sect1>
