<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/28/opensuse-at-and-with-fosdem-2011/">openSUSE at
        and with FOSDEM 2011</ulink>
    </title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata width="25%"
          fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/openSUSEboothfosdemrhlim-300x200.jpg"
        />
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Next years <ulink url="http://www.fosdem.org/2011/">FOSDEM</ulink> takes place again in
      Brussels on Feb 5th and 6th 2011 and openSUSE will be present as usual!</para>
    <para>Apart of the well known high level open Source tech conference there will be for the 2nd
      time the Distribution <ulink url="http://www.fosdem.org/2011/distrominiconf">Miniconf</ulink>.
      The Miniconf provides the perfect place for different projects to share ideas, talk about
      challenges each project has and to foster collaboration – and as openSUSE is all about
      collaboration we want to play a major role there.</para>
    <para>The Miniconf is open for every project. For more information please subscribe on the
      Miniconf <ulink url="http://lists.fosdem.org/mailman/listinfo/dist2011">mailinglist</ulink>.
      We are looking for talks about cross-distro collaboration and presentations on openSUSE
      technology – like OBS, openFATE but also where we are going – things like Tumbleweed!</para>
    <para>Our contact with FOSDEM is <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/User:Hennevogel">Henne
        Vogelsang</ulink>, if you think about giving a talk, contact him.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 28.12.10 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/28/the-first-marketing-collaboration-days-are-over-but-more-will-come/"
        >The first Marketing Collaboration days are over but more will come!</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>On the 6th of December, the openSUSE marketing team held the first of three Collaboration Days. The goal of these days was to get on IRC together and get some tasks 
      done. Each day was organized by a team of two volunteers who build up a list of possible task which on the day itself were to be picked up by the attendees.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Results</emphasis></para>
    <para>Before talking about the material results, an important note: while indeed it was great to get so many things done, the most important was something else. Working 
      together like this was fun. Really, the team spirit was great and everyone involved deserves a big kudos for simply being such a great person! During the 24 hours that 
      the event took, some members were online for a much longer time than you could expect anyone to stay – true dedication! The meetings really showed what the spirit of 
      Free Software and openSUSE means – making a difference together. Because we made a difference.</para>
    <para>Among other things, the following things were accomplished:</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Documentation created and updated</emphasis>: organizing booths and launch parties; Ambassador documentation; Talking points; example Letters 
      of Sponsorship; and a general WIKI reorganization and cleanup.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Totally new</emphasis>: two short presentations, one about SUSE Studio and one on OBS; short descriptions of openSUSE to be used in marketing 
      materials; a series of keywords associated to openSUSE for SEO usage; a photo gallery showing openSUSE related images;</para>
    <para>We also made significant strides in the feature list for openSUSE 11.4, which we hope to turn into an informative and fun to read feature guide for the release! Based 
      on the work on short descriptions of openSUSE and the latest state of our Strategy, two folders are now in development: one for potential openSUSE users and one for 
      potential contributors. Anyone interested in helping out: please contact us!</para>
    <para>Moreover two short presentations on SUSE Studio and OBS were created which can be used in presentations from the Ambassadors. Already some Greek ambassadors are using 
      them and they promised to contribute back translated versions.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Thanks all!</emphasis></para>
    <para>We would like to thank the whole marketing team and everyone else who joined for a great job. We made a few significant steps forward and surely there will be more 
      collaboration days in the future!</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata width="45%" fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/openSUSECollaborationDayCertificate-300x212.jpg"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Thanks especially to the volunteers who prepared the Collaboration days:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>Review of Ambassador materials: Kostas Koudaras and Carlos Ribeiro</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Marketing Review: Chuck Payne and Bryen Yunashko</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Social Media: Manu Gupta and Jos Poortvliet</para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <!-- ($ ld: 29.12.10 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/23/opensuse-announces-fifth-development-milestone-with-kernel-interactivity-patch/"
        >openSUSE Announces Fifth Development Milestone with Kernel Interactivity Patch</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>The openSUSE project released the fifth of six milestones in the development of openSUSE
      11.4 some days ago. <emphasis role="bold">Milestone 5 (M5)</emphasis> brings a wide range of
      updates, both major and minor. As usual, you can get it <ulink
        url="http://software.opensuse.org/developer/en">here</ulink>.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Major Features</emphasis>:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Kernel 2.6.37rc5-12 is the basis of M5, including the famous “200 line” per tty task
          groups patch to improve desktop interactivity, and featuring the almost-complete removal
          of the so-called ‘Big Kernel Lock’, which should improve scalability. This kernel supports
          new drivers, including Broadcom wireless and updated open-source graphics drivers, and a
          host of the usual other improvements.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Libzypp 8.10.2 adds improved support and fixes for metalinks, the multiple download
          URL specification.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>On the desktop, the KDE Platform makes the leap to version 4.6 beta with many
          improvements in the UI and underlying infrastructure. This includes a complete rewrite of
          Kontact and is undergoing heavy testing. There is a serious chance KDE PIM 4.6 will not
          make it into the final openSUSE 11.4 release, testing and development is needed!</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>KOffice is updated to 2.3 RC superseding beta1, including the exciting Krita natural
          media painting app. Meanwhile OpenOffice.org is removed, having been succeeded by
          LibreOffice which is updated to 3.3.0.1.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>GNOME 2.32.1 is now available as the 2.32.2 is the final version planned for openSUSE
          11.4, which is notable for being the last stable release before GNOME 3 in March.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>GNUCash 2.4 RC comes with a new complete dress-up.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Pidgin updates fixes several MSN and ICQ issues.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>In the Virtualization area, available now are kernel-xen 2.5.37 features and
          kernel-ec2 2.6.37 with improvements for cloud sync services and Virtual Box 4 Beta
          including USB devices support and more than 2GB RAM support on 32 bit guest, Intel HD
          Audio, asynchronous I/O for iSCSI, VMDK, VHD and Parallels image support.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>systemd 15 provides aggressive parallelization capabilities to start multiple daemons
          at the same time with dependencies which offers improvements to the boot times on some
          systems. More testing (and porting of init scripts) is still needed for systemd, which
          will most likely make it into 11.4 as experimental and optional feature.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Get it!</emphasis></para>
    <para>A list of most annoying bugs is being compiled; please check it before installing. We look
      forward to your bug reports and test experiences! Automated testing and the openSUSE Factory
      team have been very active to ensure that your download of M5 will be at least minimally
      functional, thanks for that! now go and <ulink url="http://software.opensuse.org/developer/en"
        >download it!</ulink></para>
    <para>The next milestone is scheduled for Thursday, Jan 20 2011, and will be the openSUSE 11.4
      Milestone 6 release. The final openSUSE 11.4 is planned to be released in March 2011.</para>
    <para>Other Souces: <ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/open/news/item/openSUSE-11-4-Milestone-5-released-1158848.html"
        > h-online</ulink>
      <ulink
        url="http://www.linux.com/news/enterprise/biz-enterprise/392669:opensuse-114-milestone-5-released"
        >Linux.com</ulink></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 23.12.10 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
