ev<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="community">
  <title>In the Community</title>
<!--Put here things relevant to the openSUSE community maybe from * People of openSUSE or elections, votings 1 - 2 posts-->  
  <sect2>
    <title>Postings from the Community</title>
    <blockquote>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <!--  
  <sect2>
    <title>People of openSUSE</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>This Week: xyz</title>
      <para>Good Guy. Glows in the night.</para>
    </blockquote>
    </sect2> -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Welcome new openSUSE Members</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/cyberiad">New Member: Stephan Barth (cyberiad)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>He is involved in some openSUSE Build Service Projects, he is active in Bugreporting and
        is active in Wiki and IRC. OLD</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Events &amp; Meetings</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Past</title>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/03/24/opensuse-board-meeting/">December 01, 2010: openSUSE Board Meeting"</ulink></para>
        <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/01/opensuse-greek-community-meeting/">December 04, 2010: openSUSE Greek Community Meeting"</ulink></para>
        <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/02/ambassador-support-review/">December 06, 2010: Marketing Collaboration Day - Ambassador Support Review"</ulink></para>
        <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/05/30/german-wiki-team-meeting-2/">December 08, 2010: German Wiki Team Meeting"</ulink></para>
        <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/05/13/%ef%bb%bfopensuse-kde-team-meeting/">December 09, 2010: ﻿openSUSE KDE Team meeting"</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
(EDIT MARK)
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Upcoming</title>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/02/marketing-materials-review/">December 13, 2010: Marketing Collaboration Day - Marketing Materials Review</ulink></para>
        <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/10/05/opensuse-marketing-team-meeting-8/">December 14, 2010: openSUSE Marketing Team Meeting</ulink></para>
        <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/03/24/opensuse-board-meeting/">December 15, 2010: openSUSE Board Meeting</ulink></para>
        <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/02/pr-social-media-review/">December 21, 2010: Marketing Collaboration Day - PR and Social Media Review</ulink></para>
        <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/05/30/german-wiki-team-meeting-2/">December 22, 2010: German Wiki Team Meeting</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
(EDIT MARK)
    <para>You can find more informations on other events at: <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/category/events/">openSUSE News/Events</ulink>. - <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Ambassadors_events">Local Events</ulink></para>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>openSUSE for your Ears</title>
    <para>The openSUSE Weekly News are available as livestream or podcast in German. You can hear it
      or download it on <ulink url="http://blog.radiotux.de/podcast">Radiotux</ulink>. </para>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>From Ambassadors</title>
    <figure id="fig.bras">
      <title>Braselieros</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/openSUSE-Brasil-Group-DSC00240-300x159.jpg" width="25%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/07/opensuse-makes-a-splash-at-latinoware/">openSUSE makes a splash at Latinoware</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The openSUSE Brasileiros!
        A few weeks ago, Latinoware offered an opportunity for the Brazilian openSUSE ambassadors to organize an ambassador meeting, combined with a great showing at the Latinoware event itself. The ambassadors gave a series of talks and workshops while answering questions at the booth and helping users with the installation of openSUSE. International visitors Bryen Yushenko and Jos Poortvliet flew in to attend the ambassador meeting, get to know the team and give keynotes about the importance of accessibility and the openSUSE community itself. It is safe to say that the event was hugely successful and of course a lot of fun! <xref linkend="fig.bras"/></para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Venue</emphasis> Many semi-government organizations or
        government-run companies in Brazil, operating important communal services, have a dual
        purpose. A library provides books and a Museum shows it’s guests the beauty of art. But they
        have other goals too like creating jobs or improving welfare. Latinoware itself is an
        example as it is hosted by Itaipu. Itaipu is ‘s worlds largest hydroelectric dam located
        across the Brazil-Paraguay border (also close to Argentina) and near to Foz do Iguaçu, a
        city with about 500.000 inhabitants. Foz do Iguaçu is a very touristy place, as it features
        the world largest water fall (Cataratas do Iguaçu in English is Iguassu Falls, the water
        falls of Foz do Iguaçu). It used to feature an even larger waterfall – the building of the
        worlds largest hydro-electric dam has however turned the worlds second largest waterfall
        into the biggest. This collaborative effort between the two countries generates about 19% of
        Brazil’s and almost 90% of Paraguay’s annual electricity needs. Itaipu invests heavily in
        social programs to decrease social inequality, build schools and care for the environment.
        And it organizes Latinoware – an attempt to increase education and support the local
        economy. I don’t have to argue with you why Free Software is far better for the local
        economy than proprietary – great to see this is recognized by Itaipu. Itaipu itself makes
        heavy use of Free Software, running thousands of openSUSE and SUSE Enterprise systems. John
        “Maddog” Hall explained on the bus to the conference location: they have a long term
        investment here. When they started building the dams, software was new – and so were
        software businesses. Even now, the time needed to recoup the building costs (and hence the
        minimum life expectancy of the project) exceeds that of most software companies. Imagine the
        damage if Itaipu would suddenly be stuck with unsupported software running some of it’s most
        crucial infrastructure! Itaipu wisely decided to go for a more long-term, durable solution
        build on Linux. This provides them with software which is maintained by a huge international
        community of large and small businesses and individuals – and even if they would fail to
        maintain it, Itaipu has the freedom to do it by themselves as they have access to the source
        code.</para>
      <figure id="fig.brasjos">
        <title>Jos Poortvliet gives a keynote at the Conference</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/Jos-DSC00137-300x208.jpg" width="50%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">The conference</emphasis> Latinoware is a big conference with
        thousands of visitors and many simultaneous tracks accompanied by a large exposition area.
        Many prominent Free Software projects gave presentations and featured a booth, as did the
        openSUSE team. Most of the openSUSE ambassadors arrived late on the night before the
        conference so the breakfast at the hotel turned into a meet-and-greet. At the conference the
        team quickly set up the booth and started to prepare for the talks and workshops which were
        scheduled. There was quite a turnout and unfortunately the supply of openSUSE DVD’s provided
        a serious stumbling block – customs had stopped a shipping of 1000 DVD’s at the border so
        there were only a hundred or so to give away. The ambassadors mitigated the issue by
        performing openSUSE installations at the booth, thus ‘sharing’ the DVD’s in true Free
        Software fashion. The first day ended with a party including a rock band at conference
        venue, openSUSE people fueling party spirit with Bryen Yushenko in the lead and yours truly
        bouncing around as well.<xref linkend="fig.brasjos"/></para>
      <figure id="fig.brasmeet">
        <title>openSUSE Brasil Meeting</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/oS-Brazil-meeting-DSC00235-300x96.jpg" width="50%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>The second day had two keynotes given by openSUSE visitors.
        Bryen Yushenko talked about how thinking about accessibility impacts common software
        development and your writer spoke about the open and collaborative atmosphere in openSUSE
        which has resulted in such innovative technologies as the openSUSE Build Service, KIWI and
        upcoming projects like Bretzn. Like the first day there were other talks and workshops, same
        as the third day. Friday the openSUSE team further organized an ambassador meeting with over
        20 people attending. We did a round of introductions and spoke about the future of openSUSE
        in Brazil and South America in general. The ambassadors who volunteered at Latinoware to
        help out received some cool rewards including openSUSE branded soap, courtesy of the
        creative brain of Carlos Ribeiro.<xref linkend="fig.brasmeet"/></para>
      <figure id="fig.brasedu">
        <title>Carlos Ribeiro introduces openSUSE Edu-L-Ife to Latinoware</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/Carlos-DSC00197-300x219.jpg" width="25%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Finishing things</emphasis> up Friday night the openSUSE team
        invited people from the KDE, GNOME and Latinoware event teams at the hotel together for a
        party. A few ambassadors went out to get Pizza and Beer, and upon their return the 25 FOSS
        enthusiasts enjoyed some quality time together. Rest assured that the openSUSE team in
        Brazil is very much alive and kickin’ and has great plans for the future. A big thank you
        for the invitation from openSUSE ambassadors Carlos and Izabel – and extra special hugs for
        Izabel who organized both the openSUSE and the GNOME booth, took care of hotel, travel – in
        short, without her Latinoware would have missed two excellent projects ;-)<xref
          linkend="fig.brasedu"/></para>
      <figure id="fig.brasbooth">
        <title>Izabel Valverde discusses openSUSE at our booth</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/Izabel-DSC00063-300x290.jpg" width="25%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">openSUSE Everywhere</emphasis> At the end of the event, we heard
        many visitors say that it seemed like openSUSE was everywhere. Many other stands like the
        GNOME and KDE booths but also TV-Radio Latinoware featured openSUSE desktops; the openSUSE
        ambassadors organized a large number of well-attended talks and workshops; there was the
        openSUSE keynote; and at the booth many visitors brought their laptops to be equipped with a
        fresh openSUSE installation. In short, we made quite an impact at the conference and brought
        fun with us!<xref linkend="fig.brasbooth"/> ($ ld: 10.12.10 sm $)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Communication</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/">The Mailinglists</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org">The openSUSE Forums</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Contributors</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://users.opensuse.org">The User Directory</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
