<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 id="gsoc" role="gsoc">
  <title>Google Summer of Code</title>
  <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
      <imagedata width="20%" align="center" fileref="http://michal.hrusecky.net/wp-content/uploads/GSoC2011_300x200.png"/>
    </imageobject>
  </mediaobject>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://rxvl.in/post/7967401920/gsoc-2011-ssc-week-9">Ratan Sebastian: GSOC 2011:
        ssc Week 9</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>Tasks completed this week:<orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Replacing of ArgumentParser with Thor. I’d given a mid-week update about <ulink
              url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-project/2011-07/msg00098.html">this</ulink> on
            the mailing list. Please check there for complete details.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Implementing the general commands (checkout, commit and status). As a direct
            consequence of using thor for the command line parsing, we get to use the invoke method
            to call other actions. This made writing these commands quite easy.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Started on refactoring the DirectoryManager module. The NewDirectoryManager is
            currently in use in the general commands and will gradually replace the older version
            which is a mess of helper functions right now. There will be separate classes for
            handling each of the local storage files (for software, repositories and files) deriving
            from a parent LocalStorageFile class which implements the
            generic #read and#save methods.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>The gem is now hosted on rubygems.org . So, you can install it with gem install ssc.
            Use the fantastic thor generated usage instructions to help you use the app.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist></para>
    <para>The tasks for next week are:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Write integration tests</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Implement a command to get information about installed packages from the currently
            run system.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Commands for Appliance building and build status reporting.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>If you have any suggestions for features. Please do write in on the studio-users mailing
      list.</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 24.7.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/07/17/gsoc-osc-code-cleanup-–-summary-of-week-8/"
        >Marcus Hüwe: osc code cleanup – summary of week 8</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>Here’s a small summary of the 8th (coding) week. This week I spentmost of my time with
      rewriting the working copy code.</para>
    <para>Done:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>added support to add and delete packages</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>added some “abstractions” for the tracking file format:currently packages and files
            are tracked in a xml file</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>thought about the package update algorithm. Basicallyit’ll work like this (verfy
            simplified version):<itemizedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>perform update in a tmpdir (phase 1)</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>if the tmp update finished, copy/rename all files tothe wc (phase 2)</para>
                <para>Advantage:If the update is interrupted in phase 1 the wc wasn’t touchedat all
                  and nothing should be broken.If the update is interrupted in phase 2 the wc is
                  _inconsistent_but a subsequent “update” call can resume the update and
                  everythingshould be consistent afterwards (in this case only files
                  arecopied/renamed)</para>
              </listitem>
            </itemizedlist></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>TODO:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>implement update + commit algorithm</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>If everything works as expected most parts of working copy codecleanup should be finished
      after this week.</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 18.7.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://cbounta.wordpress.com/2011/07/22/a-utility-for-merging-configuration-sysconfig-files-week-9-report/"
        >Christos Bountalis: A utility for merging configuration / sysconfig files – Week 9
        Report</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>Exciting news for the project this week. After solving the problem with the comments and
      the tree representation of the sysconfig files in Augeas, there was a big leap in the
      project’s progress. By having test data and through debugging i was able to complete the match
      algorithm.The program is now able to traverse through two trees / files, make the necessary
      matches between the nodes of these two trees and provide the appropriate information to the
      later stages. That of merging.</para>
    <para>What exactly have been done in the previous week:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Tree representation of sysconfig files</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Matching between two trees nodes completed</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Sorting of labels (Small Fixes)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>tree_compare function complete</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Tree traversal of aug_process_trees ( revisited)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>What is for next week:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Finish merging functions for aug_process_trees ( I feel optimistic that i will
            surely complete this next week due to the reason that matching was completed)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Create first beta packages</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Test Test Test</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Improve code</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
<!-- ($ ld: 23.7.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://redache.wordpress.com/2011/07/23/entomologist-ui-changes-weekly-report-9/"
        >David Williams: Entomologist UI Changes - Weekly Report #9</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>This week I’ve been working on finishing up the ToDo Lists, which did entail writing a new
      Item Delegate for the list as the previous method of checking which widget had been clicked
      was less than optimal!. I have finished the ToDo List and it will hopefully be merged on
      Monday into an experimental branch that I can go through and ensure that everything works as
      expected. This will then all be pulled together as a possible version 1.0 of Entomologist,
      which is great news!.</para>
    <para>I am currently researching possibilities for integrating Cloud Services into the ToDo List
      and I plan on targeting an iCal/WebDAV compatible format export to begin with. Once this basic
      step is in place I can then look at integrating with various web services and generic
      iCal/WebDAV support for servers that use these.</para>
    <para>This all leads on to how long I have left of my GSoC, which by my count is 5 weeks(!) of
      GSoC Time,but I would like to stick to the soft pencils down date as much as possible so the
      final week can be spent ensuring everything works properly. I want to look at the addition of
      QML after I’ve integrated some Cloud Sync aspects as I think this would be a really excellent
      feature to have.</para>
    <para>Here’s a screenshot of the ToDo List on OS X Lion (Which also shows that nothing has to be
      done to Entomologist’s code base to make it compatible):</para>
    <para><inlinegraphic
        fileref="http://redache.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/screen-shot-2011-07-23-at-02-21-41.png"
        width="30%"/></para>
<!-- ($ ld: 23.7.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
</sect1>
