<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
  %myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="kernel">
  <title>Kernel Review</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/Kernel-Log-Coming-in-3-0-Part-4-Drivers-1276887.html"
        >h-online/Thorsten Leemhuis: Kernel Log: Coming in 3.0 (Part 4) - Drivers</ulink>
    </title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Along with better support for new chipsets and graphics cores from
        AMD and Intel, not to mention drivers for Microsoft's Kinect and DVB-T2, Linux 3.0 once
        again offers a number of workarounds for a wide range of hardware
      problems.</emphasis></para>
    <para>In the opening minutes of Tuesday morning, Linus Torvalds released another pre-release
      version of Linux 3.0. In his release mail, Linus says that "Things have been pretty quiet, but
      there's enough new stuff here that I wanted to do another -rc". The developer had previously
      said that the sixth release candidate might perhaps have been the last.</para>
    <para>Should Torvalds not issue another rc, Linux 3.0 could appear later this week or early next
      week. As Linux 3.0 slowly nears completion, the kernel log finishes the "Coming in 3.0"
      mini-series with a description of changes to drivers, including those for audio, graphics,
      multimedia, and storage hardware. The first part of the series dealt with changes to network
      drivers and infrastructure, while the second part focused on filesystems, and the
      third discussed platform-specific code, virtualisation, and general infrastructure.</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 13.7.11 sm $) -->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="https://lkml.org/lkml/2011/7/11/427">Linus Torvalds: Linux
      3.0-rc7</ulink></title>
    <para>I think I said -rc6 might be the last -rc. I lied.</para>
    <para>Things have been pretty quiet, but there's enough new stuff here thatI wanted to do
      another -rc, and we still have some issues with the RCUchanges causing problems when RCU
      events happen before the schedulerhas been fully initialized etc. So -rc7 is out there,
      although itmight not have mirrored out to the public sites quite yet.</para>
    <para>I also ended up re-generating the -rc6 files (fat-fingered the releasescript), so the -rc6
      patches and tar-balls look all brand spanking newtoo! Two releases for the price of
      one!</para>
    <para>There's not a whole lot to say about it - the appended shortlog givesa reasonable
      overview. Random drivers (we're back to the usual "twothirds drivers" statistics), some media
      and cifs updates, and somevmscan corner case improvements. Linus</para>
    <!--($ ld: 13.7.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://schaiba.wordpress.com/2011/07/16/kernel-weekly-news-16-07-2011/">Rares
        Aioanei: kernel weekly news – 16.07.2011</ulink></title>
    <para>Rares gives his weekly Kernel Review.</para>
    <!--$ ld: 16.7.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
