<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="tipsandtricks">
  <title>Tips and Tricks</title>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Desktop Users</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://nbprashanth.wordpress.com/2011/11/03/gnome-shell-themes/">N.B.Prashanth: GNOME Shell Themes</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>As a follow up to my previous post about customizing your GNOME Shell, here are a few
        themes I had recently come across. <ulink url="http://www.omgubuntu.co.uk/2011/10/five-pretty-awesome-gnome-shell-themes/">http://www.omgubuntu.co.uk/2011/10/five-pretty-awesome-gnome-shell-themes/</ulink> (opens
        in a new window). Other than smooth inset, which has been doing the rounds on the internet
        since GNOME 3 first arrived, the other themes look pretty new to me. </para>
      <para>Have fun customizing!</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 04.11.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Commandline/Script Newbies</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://bashshell.net/commands/understanding-the-cat-command/">BashShell.net/Mike: Understanding the cat Command</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">cat</emphasis></para>
      <para>Cat is  used to either view, create, or join multiple text files together.  (In fact, the term “cat” is short for catenate, which is a fancy way of saying “to join two things together, end-to-end”.)</para>
      <para>By default, stdin for cat is the keyboard, and stdout is the computer screen.  If you just type “cat” at the command prompt, you’ll be able to type in text, and make it echo back to you as soon as you hit Enter.  It will keep doing this until you press Ctrl-d to end it. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 5.11.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Developers and Programmers</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://olex.openlogic.com/wazi/2011/jquery-and-ajax-error-detection-and-handling/">Wazi/W. Jason Gilmore: jQuery and Ajax Error Detection and Handling</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Website development duties were once assigned to different individuals with two distinct roles: A designer focused on the all matters related to the front-end HTML and CSS, and a developer was responsible for the server-side code. JavaScript’s meteoric rise to first-class citizen status has blurred these traditional lines, forcing developers into what was once considered taboo territory. The results have been spectacular, with frameworks such as <ulink url="http://olex.openlogic.com/packages/jquery">jQuery</ulink> significantly streamlining JavaScript’s often unwieldy native syntax, and programming techniques such as <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ajax_%28programming%29">Ajax</ulink> bringing highly responsive user interfaces to the browser. The marrying of jQuery and Ajax has been particularly impactful, providing developers with a powerful solution to the problem of asynchronously interacting with and updating parts of a web page. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 5.11.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For System Administrators</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://linuxaria.com/recensioni/protect-your-server-with-sshguard?lang=en">Linuxaria: Protect your server with SSHGuard</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>I’ve already talked about <ulink url="http://linuxaria.com/howto/fail2ban-brute-force-attacks">fail2ban</ulink> and <ulink url="http://linuxaria.com/pills/logcheck-scan-your-logs-and-warns-you">logcheck</ulink>, 2 tools that can scan your logs and do actions, based on rules that you can give/modify, usually modify your <ulink url="http://linuxaria.com/tag/iptables">iptables</ulink> rules to stop active attacks against your server or simply send you a warning if some thing is found in the logs.</para>
      <para>Today we’ll see a similar tool, <ulink url="http://www.sshguard.net/">sshguard</ulink>, it is different from the other two in that it is written in C, so it’s uses less memory and CPU while running, but still achiving the same results. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 5.11.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
