<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1>
  <title>openSUSE Conference 2011</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://dev-loki.blogspot.com/2011/08/my-talks-at-opensuse-conference-2011.html">Pascal
        Bleser: My talks at the openSUSE Conference 2011</ulink></title>
    <para>Big mistake, big mistake. At the call for papers deadline, we ended up with not having any
      sessions about packaging at all except <ulink
        url="http://conference.opensuse.org/indico//contributionDisplay.py?contribId=46&amp;sessionId=7&amp;confId=2"
        >one by Jan Engelhardt</ulink>.</para>
    <para>Now, that would have been quite a ludicrous situation, as our core activity is precisely
      to build packages, without which it wouldn't be a distribution in the first place.</para>
    <para>So I picked up an early email from Lars Vogdt who proposed a few sessions on the topic of
      packaging. Unfortunately, it was really early in the call for papers phase and we weren't
      quite organized yet, which caused his proposal to remain unanswered for a few weeks. I tried
      to contact him by email a few times, but he didn't reply (until now, that is), and I
      nevertheless took it up on myself to do a few packaging related sessions at the conference.
      (...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 29.08.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://dev-loki.blogspot.com/2011/08/on-communication-cultural-differences.html">Pascal
        Bleser: On communication, cultural differences, and the openSUSE Conference</ulink></title>
    <para>Disclaimer: the next paragraphs may sound presumptuous, but they're not. I swear.</para>
    <para>It has occurred to me, time and time again, that some people consider others as semi-gods.
      People who are highly active e.g. in open source projects, and are sometimes even regarded for
      their work. Well, it sucks.</para>
    <para>I know that this has happened to me a few times (being seen as a semi-god, that is), and I
      hate it. Not only does it not have any ground for being, we're just folks like everyone else,
      and while hard and good work should be appreciated, and while a simple "thank you" is way too
      rare and rewarding, taking it to that level is a very-bad-thing (tm) (...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 29.08.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/08/25/osc11-android-app/">Honey, your
        conference is on the phone!</ulink></title>
    <para>As we continue to work towards making this years <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/category/project/events/osc/">conference</ulink> the best
      ever, there’s one cool new thing we’ve never done before: Introducing the <ulink
        url="https://market.android.com/details?id=org.opensuse.conference.osc11">openSUSE
        Conference App</ulink> for your Android phone. With this app you’ll be able to:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Look at the daily timetable of sessions</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Read the abstracts for each session</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Mark the ones you want to attend and/or set an alarm to remind you</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Get a refreshed version of the schedule whenever you want (...)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 26.8.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/08/22/osc11-fun/">Fun, fun, fun at
        OSC11</ulink></title>
    <para>The Zentrifuge, our <ulink url="http://conference.opensuse.org/location">conference
        location</ulink> this year, is build in an old factory that was used for the production of
      washing machines (centrifuge, get it?). The bridging between technology and art is an
      important concern for them and thus our conference, as a technology conference, tries to cross
      that bridge too. Of course we also follow our motto <emphasis role="italic"><emphasis
          role="bold">Have a lot of fun…</emphasis></emphasis>in this endeavor and throw a little
      party into the mix as well. So here is our blend of social events at OSC11. (...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 28.8.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <!-- More entries here... -->
</sect1>
