<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
  %myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="kernel">
  <title>Kernel Review</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/Kernel-Log-Consistent-names-for-network-interfaces-1180510.html"
        >h-online/Thorsten Lemmhuis: Kernel Log: Consistent names for network interfaces</ulink>
    </title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Future distributions will use a consistent, predictable scheme to
        name network interfaces, using names such as "em1" and "pci2#1" instead of "eth0" and "eth1"
        to provide more transparency for server administrators. As various new kernels have recently
        been introduced, the Kernel Log will provide an overview of the most important Stable and
        Longterm kernel series.</emphasis></para>
    <para><ulink url="http://domsch.com/linux/lpc2010/lpc2010-network-device-naming.pdf">For
        years</ulink>, Matt Domsch has advocated solutions which provide reliable and predictable
      network port names – in systems with multiple network sockets, the driver loading sequence and
      hardware response times influence whether a certain port will be called eth0 or eth1. Now, the
      Dell technology strategist and DKMS contributor seems to have taken a big step towards his
      goal. <ulink url="http://domsch.com/blog/?p=455">On his blog</ulink>, Domsch, who also
      contributes to the Fedora project, explains that Fedora 15 – expected in May – will <ulink
        url="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Features/ConsistentNetworkDeviceNaming">use</ulink> a
      device naming scheme that he helped develop, in which udev accesses <quote><ulink
          url="http://linux.dell.com/files/biosdevname/">biosdevname</ulink></quote>, a program
      mainly developed by Dell employees, to allocate network device names. The developer says that
      other distributions are also likely to adopt this solution. </para>
    <para>This naming scheme will make udev allocate the device name <quote>em1</quote> to the
      motherboard's first network port, <quote>em</quote> being short for <quote>embedded</quote>;
      network cards will be named according to the pattern <quote>pci&lt;slot>#&lt;port></quote>
      (such as pci2#1), which should always make the ports on a network card accessible under the
      same name as long as the card, or a substitute, is inserted in the same slot. The
      sub-functions of network cards that can be partitioned (NPAR) and the sub-functions of cards
      with SR-IOV virtualisation support are given an added underscore and a number. As before, vlan
      functions are separated by a dot, and aliases by a colon. </para>
    <para>When allocating names, biosdevname accesses the information available in PCI firmware
      specification 3.1; if this information is unavailable, it will try to retrieve values using
      smbios. This is designed to match the numbers behind the <quote>em</quote> with those printed
      on the housing or board – and considerably help network admins with their cabling, especially
      on servers with a large number of network sockets. If biosdevname can't retrieve any
      information this way, the program uses the PCI IRQ routing table and will allocate the numbers
      according to the card's position in the device hierarchy. Biosdevname doesn't handle USB
      network interfaces, which will continue to be given such names as <quote>eth0</quote>.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 1.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
