<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.wafaa.eu/entry/arming-opensuse---111011-1-72.html">Andrew Wafaa:
        ARMing openSUSE - 111011</ulink></title>
    <para>So HackWeek VII has been and gone, but work has not stopped in getting our beloved Geeko
      some ARMs.</para>
    <para>Now I'll be the first to admit, things have been a wee bit scrappy in places. This isn't
      anyone's fault, it's just that we want to get things rolling ASAP. Thing is, we need more
      haste less speed; we need to be somewhat more concerted with our efforts. So instead of trying
      to get everything to build in one hit (would be great if that was possible), we are going to
      target patterns of packages. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 13.10.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://lslezak.blogspot.com/2011/10/opensuse-hackweek-vii-hacking-usb.html"
        >Ladislav Slezak: OpenSUSE Hackweek VII - Hacking USB Joysticks in YaST</ulink></title>
    <para>This <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Hackweek">hackweek</ulink> I spent playing
      with joysticks in <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:YaST">YaST</ulink> and hwinfo
      (libhd). YaST already has a module for configuring joysticks, but I only supported <ulink
        url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gameport">Gameport</ulink> joysticks which are quite
      obsoleted these days. </para>
    <para>AFAIK all recent mainboards do not have gamport connectors (just a pin header) or the
      gameport is completely missing. And if you want to buy a joystick you will find only USB
      models anyway. </para>
    <para>There was a note in the YaST module that it only supports Gameport joysticks but some
      users find it confusing. </para>
    <para>So I decided to change the situation and do something interesting during my Hackweek
      project - to add USB joystick support to YaST. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 13.10.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://ungethym.blogspot.com/2011/10/2-days-to-go-and-kde-turns-15.html"
        >Thomas Thym: 2 days to go and KDE turns 15!</ulink></title>
    <para>Whoooo. Just 2 more days until KDE can celebrate the 15th birthday. Have you prepered your
      presents ;-) And even more important: Are you ready to party? </para>
    <para>Find more information on the dot. <ulink
        url="http://dot.kde.org/2011/10/05/freedom-15-years-party"
        >http://dot.kde.org/2011/10/05/freedom-15-years-party</ulink></para>
    <!--($ ld: 13.10.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://blog.cornelius-schumacher.de/2011/10/demise-of-windows-platform.html"
        >Cornelius Schumacher: The demise of the Windows platform</ulink></title>
    <para>I bought a Windows <ulink url="http://www.rage.com/">game</ulink> last week. What I got
      was a scenic tour through the demise of the Windows platform. I knew that Windows as gaming
      platform was <ulink url="http://blogs.kde.org/node/3104">troublesome</ulink>, but it never was
      as clear that it's actually <ulink
        url="http://kotaku.com/5847761/why-was-the-pc-launch-of-rage-such-a-cluster">moving towards
        irrelevance</ulink>. If you ever have seriously played games on Windows you know this
      cocktail of driver updates, googling error messages, entering illegiible cryptic codes from
      stickers hidden in game boxes, waiting for online activation, going through update popups of
      various origins, and what not. It took me something like two hours before I was even able to
      start the game. I love games, and I have played quite some games on Windows, but I might be
      done with this now.</para>
    <para><!--($ ld: 15.10.11 sm $)--></para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://vizzzion.org/blog/2011/10/plasma-active-perspective-the-user-story/"
        >Sebastian Kügler: Plasma Active Perspective: The User Story</ulink></title>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="italic"><ulink url="http://plasma-active.org">Plasma Active</ulink> brings a
        flexible, elegant, activity-driven user experience to a spectrum of devices. This article is
        part of a <ulink url="http://vizzzion.org/blog/2011/10/plasma-active-perspectives/">series
          of articles</ulink> about different perspectives on Plasma Active. This installment looks
        at the user story, and aims at answering the questions “what does Plasma Active bring me as
        a user?”, what are the underlying concepts and how do we plan to achieve these
        goals.</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>For the user who wants to enjoy the Internet, multimedia and data away from his laptop or
      desktop, right now choices are rather slim. This means, for example, that you will choose a
      platform with some sort of critical mass, meaning that your favourite 3rd party apps are
      available, enough services supported, etc.. A Free software platform has to bring a lot to the
      table for users: There’s a lot of cool software available, systems such as Plasma Active offer
      a system without lock-in to a single vendor, but rather being able to take apps across vendors
      and devices. Plasma Active already comes with a good amount of interesting widgets, new ones
      are being developed all the time, the development platform is proven to be stable and working
      in real world use, and it’s easy for 3rd parties to develop and bring support for (even “4th”
      party) services. Plasma Active extends the Free software ecosystem into user experiences for
      devices, bringing a critical mass with it. </para>
    <para>I personally use Plasma Active almost every day, I prefer the tablet form factor for
      “light reading”, checking on news, social networks, the blogosphere. For me it’s an ideal “on
      the couch in the living room” device, although I tend to use it in trains for reading and
      watching movies as well. With its powerful email client Kontact Touch it allows me quite
      conveniently read longer email threads. The virtual keyboard works well enough for entering
      short texts. For longer texts, I usually either plug in a keyboard and put the tablet into a
      stand, so it feels more like a ‘stationary laptop’. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 15.10.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://michal.hrusecky.net/2011/10/how-to-contribute-in-opensuse-build-service/">Michal
        Hrušecký: How to contribute in openSUSE Build Service</ulink></title>
    <para>I promised that I’ll write a post about how you can contribute. There are several ways how
      to contribute to MySQL, but most of it means modifying packages. And as everything in openSUSE
      is built using openSUSE Build service, first post will be actually pretty general obs and osc
      howto. In the next posts, I’ll go deeper into specific details of MySQL packaging.
      (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 15.10.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://michal.hrusecky.net/2011/10/how-to-create-patches-using-quilt/">Michal
        Hrušecký: How to create patches using quilt</ulink></title>
    <para><ulink
        url="http://michal.hrusecky.net/2011/10/how-to-contribute-in-opensuse-build-service/">Last
        time</ulink> I described how to contribute quite to any package in openSUSE Build Service.
      But I left out the most important part. I haven’t shown how to change anything. This time I
      want to show you, how to create patches, if you need them, easily. Let’s start start with
      package we checked out from obs. Creating patch for anything is different only in first few
      steps.</para>
    <para> First we got to the directory where do we have the package checked out. We run</para>
    <programlisting>quilt setup</programlisting>
    <para>This command will parse the .spec file, unpack tarball and prepare all quilt stuff. Now is
      time for patching, so let’s enter the newly created directory and try following command</para>
    <programlisting>quilt push</programlisting>
    <!--($ ld: 15.10.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://blog.cornelius-schumacher.de/2011/10/fifteen-years-of-kde.html"
        >Cornelius Schumacher: Fifteen years of KDE</ulink></title>
    <para>Fifteen years ago <ulink
        url="http://dot.kde.org/2009/11/06/matthias-ettrich-receives-german-federal-cross-merit"
        >Matthias Ettrich</ulink> started the <ulink url="http://kde.org/">KDE</ulink> community. On
      14th October 1996 he wrote his <ulink url="http://www.kde.org/announcements/announcement.php"
        >famous email</ulink> to the de.comp.os.linux.misc group on Usenet. He called for other
      programmers to join him to create a free desktop environment for Linux targeted at end users.
      Many, many people joined. <ulink url="http://blogs.fsfe.org/padams/?p=247">Thousands of
        developers </ulink>wrote <ulink
        url="http://blog.cornelius-schumacher.de/2009/10/4273291-lines-of-code.html">millions lines
        of code</ulink>. We did <ulink url="http://www.kde.org/announcements/">90 stable
        releases</ulink> of our core set of applications alone, not counting all additional stuff
      and the <ulink url="http://kde-apps.org/">thousands of 3rd party applications</ulink>.
      (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 15.10.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
