<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="forums">
  <title>openSUSE Forums: A big hand for the release of openSUSE 12.1 !</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/how-faq-forums/new-user-how-faq-read-only/467087-new-users-opensuse-12-1-pre-installation-please-read.html">NEW Users - openSUSE-12.1 Pre-installation - PLEASE READ</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>
      Keeping this one up for another week. openSUSE 12.1 is new, we like to draw your attention to this article in the New User HOWTO/FAQ subforums. Like with every openSUSE release our admin oldcpu has prepared a document for new users to read before starting to install openSUSE 12.1. If you're new to openSUSE, this is a must-read, if you're already an openSUSE user, even very experienced, the article still deserves your attention. 
    </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
    <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/install-boot-login/468836-no-acceleration-ati-proprietary-driver-opensuse-12-1-a.html">No acceleration with ATI proprietary driver - Opensuse 12.1</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>
    These days openSUSE, or rather linux in general, has good open source support for ATI and NVIDIA based video cards. Yet, to get the full blast out of your video card, you still need to install the ATI or NVIDIA proprietary driver. This thread is started by a member who's having difficulties getting his ATI video card to use it's full capabilities. In the thread we find that our member please_try_again discovers a bug in the ATI updater, delivering a fix at the same time. If you're experiencing trouble installing the ATI driver, please read this thread, it may help you solve your trouble.
    </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
    <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/tumbleweed/">The Tumbleweed subforum</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>
      Some attention for the Tumbleweed -openSUSE's rolling release- subforum. My personal advice is to read our admin swerdna's instructions on how to move to Tumbleweed. The various threads in the subforum will probably provide answers to most questions related to Tumbleweed.
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      openSUSE Language specific subforums:
    </title>
    <para>We now host the following language specific subforums under the umbrella of the openSUSE Forums:
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/">Main forums, english</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/ae-ae-chinese/">中文(Chinese)</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/nederlands-dutch/">Nederlands (Dutch)</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/frana-ais-french/">Français (French)</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/deutsch-german/">Deutsch (German)</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/greek/">Ελληνικό (Greek)</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/magyar-hungarian/">Magyar (Hungarian)</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/japanese/">日本語 (Japanese)</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/portuguese/">Portuguese</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/p-russian/">Pусский (Russian)</ulink>
      </para>
<!-- ($ ld: 09.12.2011 gl $) -->  </blockquote>
</sect1>
