<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
  %myentities;
]>
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
<!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->  
  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://dot.kde.org/2010/12/02/december-updates-stabilize-kde-45-further"
          >KDE News: Search this site: December Updates Further Stabilize KDE's 4.5
        Series</ulink></title>
      <para>As of today, the latest release in KDE's 4.5 series is <ulink
          url="http://kde.org/announcements/announce-4.5.4.php">4.5.4</ulink>, which adds a bunch of
        stabilization and translation updates on top of 4.5. Users in general are encouraged to
        upgrade to 4.5.4. The <ulink
          url="http://www.kde.org/announcements/changelogs/changelog4_5_3to4_5_4.php"
          >changelog</ulink> has more details about some of the changes that went into this release.
        Enjoy upgrading!</para>
    </blockquote>
    
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>gfg</title>
      <para>...</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink 
          url="http://www.linuxplanet.com/linuxplanet/reports/7233/1/"
          > Linux Planet/Sean Michael Kerner: Yes, Novell Owns Unix-Unix Ownership Settled</ulink></title>
      <para>When Novell first announced that it was being acquired by Attachmate for $2.2 billion,
        the question of who would retain ownership over Unix copyrights was an open issue. As part
        of the Novell sale, the company also revealed that it is selling 882 patents to a
        Microsoft-led technology consortium for $450 million. Potential ownership of Unix by the
        Microsoft-led group could have led to a new round of patent battles between Microsoft and
        the open source community. In a terse statement, Novell has now publicly stated that it will
        not be selling Unix as part of the patent sale. </para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://itmanagement.earthweb.com/osrc/article.php/3914701/Seven-Improvements-Needed-in-KDE.htm"
          >Datamation/Bruce Byfield Seven Improvements Needed in KDE</ulink></title>
      <para>For the past eighteen months, KDE has been my primary desktop. I use it about two-thirds
        of the time, with the rest of my desktop usage divided between GNOME, Xfce, and occasionally
        other desktops like LXDE. You could call me a generally happy user -- but, as with any
        desktop not designed for me personally, KDE has one or two quirks or deficiencies that make
        my computing less than ideal. To be sure, KDE has made many improvements since the last time
        I complained about its shortcomings, in 2008. </para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink 
          url="http://www.neowin.net/news/a-history-of-viruses-on-linux"
          >Neowin/Brandon Boyce: A history of viruses on Linux</ulink></title>
      <para>We recently gave you a brief history of viruses on the Mac and as requested by a user we
        wanted to give you a history of viruses on Linux. Given the tight security integrated into
        Linux, it is difficult to take advantage of a vulnerability on the computer, but some
        programmers have found ways around the security measures. There are several free options for
        anti-virus on Linux that you really should use, even if it isn't always running - a weekly
        or monthly scan doesn't hurt. Free anti-virus solutions include: ClamAV, AVG, Avast and
        F-Prot.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://ostatic.com/blog/opensuse-to-offer-a-rolling-release-repo"
          >ostatic/Susan Linton: openSUSE to Offer a Rolling Release Repo</ulink></title>
      <para>Although news of <ulink url="http://ostatic.com/blog/ubuntu-to-become-a-rolling-release"
          >Ubuntu's switch</ulink> to rolling release was denied, it seems another distribution
        thinks it just may be a good idea. Greg Kroah-Hartman, openSUSE kernel developer, today
        announced "openSUSE Tumbleweed." </para>
      <para>Greg K-H, as he is commonly known, described openSUSE Tumbleweed as, "a repo that is a
        rolling updated version of openSUSE containing the latest "stable" versions of packages for
        people to use." In a <ulink
          url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-project/2010-11/msg00206.html">post</ulink> to the
        opensuse-project mailing list Kroah-Hartman offered further information in the form of a Q
        &amp; A (EDITMARK). </para>
      </blockquote>
      <blockquote>
        <title><ulink
          url="http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/32569/f/491734/s/102d97fd/l/0L0Sh0Eonline0N0Copen0Cnews0Citem0CFree0ELinux0Eclient0Ereleased0Efor0ERyzom0EMMORPG0Egame0E11453560Bhtml0Cfrom0Crss/story01.htm"
          >h-online/Free Linux client released for Ryzom MMORPG game</ulink></title>
        <para>A free Linux client for the<ulink url="http://www.ryzom.com/"> Ryzom</ulink>
          <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Massively_multiplayer_online_role-playing_game"
            >massively multi-player online role-laying game</ulink> (MMORPG) is now available for
          <ulink url="http://dev.ryzom.com/wiki/ryzom/OfficialRyzomClientLinux">downloading</ulink>.
          The program's development was supported by the <ulink url="http://www.fsf.org/">Free
            Software Foundation</ulink> after games vendor Winch Gate released the source code of the
          server and Windows client under the <ulink url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/agpl-3.0.html"
            >Affero General Public Licence</ulink> back in May. </para>
        <para>Winch Gate says it hopes that as many gamers as possible will try out the Linux client,
          which is available to download in binary and in source code form, and has launched an
          in-game contest as an incentive. The contest will close on the 10th of January. Participants
          who manage to find all seven Linux Steles that are scattered around the start island of
          Silan will be entered in a draw for a <ulink url="http://zareason.com/shop/Terra-HD.html"
            >ZaReason Linux Terra-HD Netbook</ulink> worth $450 (£289) or its equivalent in
          cash.</para>
      </blockquote>
      <blockquote>
        <title><ulink
          url="http://www.h-online.com/open/news/item/Mozilla-Firefox-4-Beta-8-coming-next-Tuesday-1145550.html"
          >h-online/Mozilla: Firefox 4 Beta 8 coming next Tuesday</ulink></title>
        <para>Originally <ulink url="https://wiki.mozilla.org/Releases">scheduled</ulink> to arrive on
          the 30th of November, the <ulink url="http://www.mozilla.org/">Mozilla</ulink> Project has
          confirmed that it plans to ship the eighth beta for version 4 of its open source Firefox web
          browser on Tuesday, the 7th of December. According to Mozilla's <ulink
            url="https://wiki.mozilla.org/Platform/2010-11-23">Platform Meeting Minutes</ulink>, the
          developers criteria for release for <ulink
            url="https://wiki.mozilla.org/Releases/Firefox_4.0b8">Firefox 4 Beta 8</ulink> is "no
          stability regressions from previous beta". Mozilla says that Firefox 4 Beta 8 will ship at
          the same time as Firefox 4 Beta 3 for Mobile devices "in order to align on some sync
          changes" and that beta 8 will include stability fixes for graphics, JavaScript optimisations
          and various UI fixes related to the Add-ons manager. Based on the <ulink
            url="https://wiki.mozilla.org/WeeklyUpdates/2010-11-29#Firefox_4">meeting notes</ulink>
          from the 29th of November, the eight beta was being held by 29 blocker bugs. At the time of
          this writing, that number is <ulink
            url="https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/buglist.cgi?quicksearch=blocking2.0%3Abeta8">now
            18</ulink>, two of them rated as critical. (...)</para>
      </blockquote>
      <blockquote>
        <title><ulink
          url="http://www.h-online.com/open/news/item/Flock-3-5-social-web-browser-arrives-1145337.html"
          >h-online/Flock 3.5 social web browser arrives</ulink></title>
        <para>The <ulink url="http://www.flock.com/">Flock</ulink> developers have <ulink
          url="http://twitter.com/Flock/status/9650158010638336">announced</ulink> the release of
          version 3.5 of their social web browser based on Google's open source Chromium platform –
          versions previous to the 3.x branch were based on Firefox. Flock is a popular cross-platform
          browser that automatically manages updates and media from several popular social services,
          including MySpace, Facebook, Bebo, Digg, YouTube and Twitter. </para>
        <para>Flock 3.5 is based on the 7.x branch of Chromium and features updates to new account
          creation, as well as support for the business-oriented <ulink url="http://www.linkedin.com/"
            >LinkedIn</ulink> social networking site. Also new in this version is support for Mac OS X
          – the previous version (3.0) was only available for Windows systems. Version 2.6.1 still
          seems to be available for Linux users, but Flock does not promote or support it.
          (...)</para>
      </blockquote>
      <!--EDITMARK-->
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>ert</title>
      <para>...</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>dangerous games</title>
      <para>...</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>LOL</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>would you like to laugh? Look this</title>
      <para>hihi :-)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
