<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
<!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! --><!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://labs.qt.nokia.com/2011/10/21/the-qt-project-is-live/">The Qt Project is live!</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>I’m happy to announce that the Qt Project officially went live today. Starting today, development of Qt will be governed as a true open source project.</para>
      <para>We now have <ulink url="http://qt-project.org/">qt-project.org</ulink> – a website where all development of Qt will be centered, providing the same infrastructure and processes for everybody that wants to contribute to Qt. (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.socallinuxexpo.org/blog/scale-next-generation-invitation-participation">SCALE: The Next Generation - Invitation for Participation</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The Southern California Linux Expo is proud to announce a conference for the next generation of free and open source community enthusiasts. “SCALE: The Next Generation” — lets the FOSS community leaders of tomorrow spotlight their talents and ideas today. Open to kids 10 and older, the goal of conference is to be as “kid driven” as possible, offering a unique opportunity to see and experience the inner workings of planning a conference. Kids will be able to determine the content and help steer the direction that this mini-conference will take. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 01.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.itworld.com/it-managementstrategy/231609/suse-global-linux-jobs-rise">ITworld/Brian Proffitt: SUSE: Global Linux jobs on the rise</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Even as the <ulink url="http://www.itworld.com/it-managementstrategy/230747/dowsing-linux-jobs-and-skills">Linux Foundation reports on Linux jobs in the U.S.</ulink>, the global picture seems to be even more encouraging.</para>
      <para>That&apos;s the take away from my conversation with Ralf Flaxa, SUSE&apos;s VP of Linux Engineering, who paints a pretty strong picture of worldwide job hiring on the part of SUSE and, presumably, other non-U.S. firms.</para>
      <para>As the person primarily responsible for hiring engineers for SUSE, Flaxa has a unique position on the outlook for Linux careers, especially in the European market. While Flaxa certainly recognizes the importance of the Linux Foundation&apos;s recent infographic for the U.S., &quot;my point of view looks a bit different.&quot; (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 09.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.datamation.com/open-source/xamarin-brings-mono-to-icecream-sandwich.html">Datamation/Sean Michael Kerner: Xamarin Brings Mono to IceCream Sandwich</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>2011 has been a year of significant changes for the Mono community. For the most part those changes have resulted in new development momentum. Today Mono startup Xamarin is announcing Mono for Android 4, providing support for Google&apos;s latest Android release.</para>
      <para>Mono was originally started by Novell as an open source implementation of the Microsoft .NET framework. After Novell was acquired by Attachmate, the lead mono developers, including project founder Miguel de Icaza, left to startup a company called Xamarin, which is focused on mobile development. In July, SUSE Linux <ulink url="http://www.datamation.com/open-source/suse-joins-xamarin-for-mono.html">partnered with Xamarin</ulink> to provide support to Novell/SUSE customers. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 09.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/finding-a-linux-job/9966">ZDNet/Steven J. Vaughan-Nichols: Finding a Linux Job</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>So you want a Linux job do you? Well, according to <ulink url="http://www.linuxfoundation.org/">The Linux Foundation</ulink>, the jobs are out there. Specifically, Linux jobs are divided up almost evenly between developer, 53% and system administrator. 47%, jobs.</para>
      <para>Amanda McPherson, the Linux Foundation’s vice president of marketing and developer programs, told me, “The Linux jobs market is booming, and we’re doing a variety of things to understand what skills are most in demand and how we can help address that opportunity for our corporate and individual members and with things like our <ulink url="https://training.linuxfoundation.org/courses">Linux Training courses</ulink>. The data we’ve surfaced from our <ulink url="http://jobs.linux.com/">Jobs Board</ulink> really reflects the importance of common programming languages, as well as areas of great success for Linux–such as Android. Mobile and embedded development skills are extremely valuable in today’s market. If you can work on security, power management and integration at the device level, you’re well prepared for this burgeoning area of Linux development.” (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 09.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.esecurityplanet.com/network-security/apache-server-hit-by-reverse-proxy.html">eSecurityPlanet/Sean Michael Kerner: Apache Server Hit by Reverse Proxy</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The open source Apache HTTP Web Server is at risk from a reverse proxy flaw that is currently unpatched. The flaw was disclosed Qualys security researcher Purtha Parikh late last week and is related to a flaw that Apache first attempted to fix in October.</para>
      <para>&quot;While reviewing the patch for the older issue CVE-2011-3368, it appeared that it was still possible to make use of a crafted request that could exploit a fully patched Apache Web Server (Apache 2.2.21 with CVE-2011-3368 patch applied) to allow access to internal systems if the reverse proxy rules are configured incorrectly, Parikh <ulink url="https://community.qualys.com/blogs/securitylabs/2011/11/23/apache-reverse-proxy-bypass-issue">reported</ulink>. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 01.12.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
<!--<sect2>
  <title>LOL</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://like-a-boss.org/2011/09/30/hacking-the-imperial-death-march/">like-a-boss.org: hacking the imperial death march</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>One of the great things about the original Star Wars trilogy, was the “lived in”, junky, hacked together aesthetic of the Star Wars universe. Everything was a bit trashed, as if real people actually lived there. Thankfully, that’s one of the things that George Lucas hasn’t tinkered with in his endless quest to ruin the childhood memories of a generation. So it’s heartening to see this tradition carried on with the playing of the imperial death march on miscellaneous hacked together hardware. Enjoy … (...)</para>
  </blockquote>
</sect2>--></sect1>
