<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/28/opensuse-at-and-with-fosdem-2011/">openSUSE at
        and with FOSDEM 2011</ulink>
    </title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata width="25%"
          fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/openSUSEboothfosdemrhlim-300x200.jpg"
        />
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Next years <ulink url="http://www.fosdem.org/2011/">FOSDEM</ulink> takes place again in
      Brussels on Feb 5th and 6th 2011 and openSUSE will be present as usual!</para>
    <para>Apart of the well known high level open Source tech conference there will be for the 2nd
      time the Distribution <ulink url="http://www.fosdem.org/2011/distrominiconf">Miniconf</ulink>.
      The Miniconf provides the perfect place for different projects to share ideas, talk about
      challenges each project has and to foster collaboration – and as openSUSE is all about
      collaboration we want to play a major role there.</para>
    <para>The Miniconf is open for every project. For more information please subscribe on the
      Miniconf <ulink url="http://lists.fosdem.org/mailman/listinfo/dist2011">mailinglist</ulink>.
      We are looking for talks about cross-distro collaboration and presentations on openSUSE
      technology – like OBS, openFATE but also where we are going – things like Tumbleweed!</para>
    <para>Our contact with FOSDEM is <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/User:Hennevogel">Henne
        Vogelsang</ulink>, if you think about giving a talk, contact him.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 28.12.10 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/28/the-first-marketing-collaboration-days-are-over-but-more-will-come/"
        >The first Marketing Collaboration days are over but more will come!</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>On the 6th of December, the openSUSE marketing team held the first of three Collaboration
      Days. The goal of these days was to get on IRC together and get some tasks done. Each day was
      organized by a team of two volunteers who build up a list of possible task which on the day
      itself were to be picked up by the attendees.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Results</emphasis></para>
    <para>Before talking about the material results, an important note: while indeed it was great to
      get so many things done, the most important was something else. Working together like this was
      fun. Really, the team spirit was great and everyone involved deserves a big kudos for simply
      being such a great person! During the 24 hours that the event took, some members were online
      for a much longer time than you could expect anyone to stay – true dedication! The meetings
      really showed what the spirit of Free Software and openSUSE means – making a difference
      together. Because we made a difference.</para>
    <para>Among other things, the following things were accomplished:</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Documentation created and updated</emphasis>: organizing booths and
      launch parties; Ambassador documentation; Talking points; example Letters of Sponsorship; and
      a general WIKI reorganization and cleanup.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Totally new</emphasis>: two short presentations, one about SUSE
      Studio and one on OBS; short descriptions of openSUSE to be used in marketing materials; a
      series of keywords associated to openSUSE for SEO usage; a photo gallery showing openSUSE
      related images;</para>
    <para>We also made significant strides in the feature list for openSUSE 11.4, which we hope to
      turn into an informative and fun to read feature guide for the release! Based on the work on
      short descriptions of openSUSE and the latest state of our Strategy, two folders are now in
      development: one for potential openSUSE users and one for potential contributors. Anyone
      interested in helping out: please contact us!</para>
    <para>Moreover two short presentations on SUSE Studio and OBS were created which can be used in
      presentations from the Ambassadors. Already some Greek ambassadors are using them and they
      promised to contribute back translated versions.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Thanks all!</emphasis></para>
    <para>We would like to thank the whole marketing team and everyone else who joined for a great
      job. We made a few significant steps forward and surely there will be more collaboration days
      in the future!</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata width="45%"
          fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/openSUSECollaborationDayCertificate-300x212.jpg"
        />
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Thanks especially to the volunteers who prepared the Collaboration days:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Review of Ambassador materials: Kostas Koudaras and Carlos Ribeiro</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Marketing Review: Chuck Payne and Bryen Yunashko</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Social Media: Manu Gupta and Jos Poortvliet</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <!-- ($ ld: 29.12.10 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/29/opensuse-boosters-year-2010/">openSUSE
        Boosters Year 2010</ulink>
    </title>
    <figure id="fig.boosters">
      <title>The elusive Thirsty Thirteen</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata width="25%"
            fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/Opensuse-boosters-300x200.jpg"
          />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>At the end of the year it is the time for reviews and the openSUSE Booster <xref linkend="fig.boosters"/> team did not
      want to let that opportunity slip. So what was important in 2010 from an openSUSE Boosters
      perspective? What happened, what progress was made, how did the boosters help openSUSE? A
      report from Klaas Freitag.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Who are the Boosters</emphasis></para>
    <para>For those who do not know who <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Boosters_team"
        >the Boosters</ulink> are: We’re not Tuxies favorite boy group, but a bunch of people
      dedicated to help the openSUSE Project in any way we can. The team consists of 13 people (BTW:
      widely known as the thirsty thirteen) with skills ranging from low level C hackery over Ruby
      on Rails mastering to Graphical Design or Project Management. Our team picks milestones and
      works on them in a agile fashion while always following our mantra: Grow community by enabling
      community. You can meet us at the usual places like IRC, the mailinglists or events were we
      show up and spread the word about openSUSE. We’re there to make contributors life easier and
      more fun, so if you have anything do not hesitate to talk to us. We’re here for you.</para>
    <para role="bold"><emphasis role="bold">Events in 2010</emphasis></para>
    <para>So let’s quickly fly over the year of 2010 and see what was nice and important.</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>FOSDEM</para>
        <para>Lets start with a very important event, FOSDEM in Brussels in February. We traveled
          there by coach the first time. That was remarkable because there were some push back
          against before (long journey) but we did it because it is cheaper, which means more people
          can go. The result was that we all were quite pleased by the coach trip as it was
          comfortable and fun, and finally not so much longer than the flight. And yes, consider how
          much carbon dioxide was saved? Since that trip I am constantly nagging for budget for an
          openSUSE Coach…</para>
        <para>I held a talk about Hermes at FOSDEM which was, well, not a great success, that thing
          seems hard to market. That happens, others were more succesfull, like Christopher with his
          talk about image building with Kiwi. Michal had a meeting with MySQL packagers from all
          over the world at FOSDEM, which was probably the first real initiative to collaborate on
          cross distro topics. I also bought a GNOME T-Shirt, met tons of old friends, had cherry
          beer and got a cold as usual on FOSDEM.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Dev meeting</para>
        <para>Also in February, we hosted a dev meeting of 25 KDE hackers here in the Nuremberg
          office. They worked on the highly rated plasma workspace for KDE 4.5. I still wonder how
          Will managed to get around with definitely no sleep for days.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Bento and wiki work</para>
        <para>At home, at the beginning of the year we worked on projects called “Integrate all
          Infrastructure under one Umbrella” which resulted in the Bento web theme nowadays at all
          openSUSE sites use. It provides short ways from one site to another by thought through and
          pretty menus. Robert did a real great job with that and we got a lot of external
          recognition for it. At the same time the Wiki project started which was a huge project the
          Wiki community was pulling together with Henne and Tom. The decision was to create a new
          Wiki from scratch, implement reviewing features and transfer all relevant content into the
          new one while making sure to not transfer stuff nobody needs and maintains any more. That
          was a big thing and caused a lot of discussion. Today we can look back and say that we now
          have a well structured Wiki with valuable content. Fortune favors the bold :-)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>OBS</para>
        <para>In parallel to that, Coolo and Tom were contributing to the new BuildService <ulink
            url="http://build.opensuse.org">web interface</ulink>. After long working hours we
          finally came out with a great web interface for OBS which was a big bum for the whole
          project, as it makes working in OBS much more fun. I remember that whole thing being
          started as a sprint called “Factory status”, aiming to provide a good <ulink
            url="https://build.opensuse.org/projectstatus?project=openSUSE%3AFactory">overview
            page</ulink> for the Factory project in OBS. It grew a bit more ambitions, but, well,
          that’s how it goes if things are in movement ;-)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>LinuxTag</para>
        <para>In June, there was LinuxTag in Berlin where most of us participated with talks in the
          free program or workshops on our booth. We educated a lot of people how to contribute to
          openSUSE in various ways. From submitting code fixes through the Build Service to creating
          great Geeko graphics with Inkscape to how to twist their own Geeko out of pipe
          cleaners.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>openSUSE 11.3</para>
        <para>In July, openSUSE 11.3 was released. That was lots of work beforehand with quite some
          boosters involvement, as Mr. Distro Coolo is part of the team. However not only he is
          contributing to the distribution, we all have our shares in it. 11.3 was a good one, it
          got good press and showed that we as a community are doing great. All over the world
          release parties were organized, some Boosters took over the one here in Nürnberg. <ulink
            url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/07/16/opensuse-11-3-launch-party-in-nurnberg/"
            >Nice party</ulink> with some talks, along with BBQ and beer. The latter ran out at 7pm,
          because many community members showed up. Cool, I love that kind of stress to organize
          food and beer quickly to let the party go on :-)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>GNOME and KDE conferences</para>
        <para>Also in Summer, GUADEC as well as Akademy took place for our desktop Boosters. Vincent
          rocked GUADEC and gave away Geekos and stuff and advertised openSUSE as a good platform
          for the upcoming GNOME3. Will could not go to Akademy this year for a very good reason
          called Anna :-)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>openSUSE conference</para>
        <para>In autumn, the for me most exciting event of the year took place, the second <ulink
            url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Conference">openSUSE Conference</ulink>. We were
          heavily involved in organizing, program committee work, giving talks and presentations and
          all what is involved with that kind of large event. It was a huge success, as a very
          active and passionate community showed up. Discussions went from a “This is what we did”
          in the last year to a “this is what we could do” which is so great to see as that is
          resulting in innovation for the whole project. As a result some very concrete sub projects
          were created such as “Project Brezn” and openSUSE Invis which slowly evolves.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>openFATE, Connect and more</para>
        <para>After the conference and the release of 11.3 we started to dig into milestones again
          with <ulink url="http://features.opensuse.org">openFATE</ulink> and <ulink
            url="http://connect.opensuse.org">Connect</ulink>. Since a couple of weeks we have a
          nice looking openFATE that has the features that make it possible for the feature
          screening team to work on one of our most important tasks in our project: Looking into the
          future of the distribution with feature evaluation. We also implemented the future of the
          user/group handling for all the openSUSE services with a social twist: Connect. Our own
          instance of a social network that makes it possible to connect the people that make this
          project what it is and at the same time makes it possible to centralize the user
          data.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Busy 2010</emphasis></para>
    <para>So all in all the boosters had a very busy and prosperous year 2010. All of us carried
      their individual share of work in the various areas of the openSUSE project we participate in,
      be it in the openSUSE KDE and GNOME Teams, the openSUSE Distribution, the openSUSE tools or
      the openSUSE Board. We attended a lot of events and organized a couple of our own with great
      success. And we worked together on the most pressing milestones we saw for contributor growth
      in a fun and clever way. All in all we helped a lot of contributors to stand up, take
      responsibility and do get their hands dirty for the openSUSE Project. That makes us proud and
      we will do this smarter, faster, better and stronger in 2011. Promised!</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 31.12.10 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/30/winner-of-opensuse-2010-survey-got-his-chumby/">Winner of openSUSE 2010 survey got his Chumby!</ulink></title>
    <figure id="fig.chumby">
      <title>The elusive Thirsty Thirteen</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata width="25%"
            fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/chumby_info1-300x219.jpg"
          />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>In February 2010 openSUSE held the openSUSE survey 2010 to find out more about the community. Who are the openSUSE users? What do they want? Who are our contributors? 
      What motivates them? How can openSUSE improve? These questions and more have, to some extend, been answered by the over 27.000 participants in the three months the survey 
      was live. Just before the end of the year we finally managed to get the winner of the Chumby <xref linkend="fig.chumby"/> his prize. Konrad Schlichtherle from Dortmund, Germany, is the lucky winner. 
      Read on for more!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Winners</emphasis></para>
    <para>The winners of the prizes we gave away were, in no particular order:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>Yosef Peretz from Jerusalem Israel</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Carlos Gárzon from Colombia</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Mityunin Alexander Vladimirovich from Russia</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Dong Xiaoyan from China</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Mar’yan Rachynskyy from Ukraine</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Roland Ortmann from Germany</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Sergey Goncharuk from Russia</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Wolodja Pskowskaja from Russia</para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>And the main prize, the Chumby, went to <emphasis role="bold">Konrad Schlichtherle</emphasis> from Germany.</para>
    <para>We managed to catch Konrad on IRC – he is currently not involved with Free Software but looking to change that so tips for him are welcome!</para>
    <screen>
      News.o.o: So, Konrad, you got the Chumby?
      Konrad: yes, i got it on the 27th. Many thanks for it. Its a nice gadget!
      News.o.o: So it’s working for you?
      Konrad: Yes, what else can I say about the Chumby? He stands beside me and plays music. I have to say, I use Linux since one year and have a lot to learn. I hope to 
      use the Chumby with some other useful things so I can learn more about Linux.
    </screen>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Survey results</emphasis></para>
    <para>The survey results are available as <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/images/3/3a/SurveySummary_03012010.pdf">pdf file</ulink> and on the openSUSE Survey 
      2010 <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Survey_2010">wiki page</ulink> an extensive analysis has been made. The results have helped make project 
      decisions, be it technical, marketing or otherwise – and we call upon all openSUSE community members to keep using these numbers to back up their choices! We want to be 
      close to ourselves and the opinions of 27,000 users and contributors is nothing to be sneezed at.</para>
    <para>We’d like to thank everyone who answered the questionnaire again for their time and efforts and wish the winners a lot of fun with their prizes and their future 
      endeavors in the world of Free Software! And as usual, if you’re looking into getting involved, you can simply contact anyone on IRC or mail – that includes me, your 
      humble writer. Find me on IRC <ulink url="http://webchat.freenode.net/">(freenode.net in the openSUSE channels like #opensuse-project)</ulink> under the 
      nick jospoortvliet!</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 31.12.10 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
