<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="tipsandtricks">
  <title>Tips and Tricks</title>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Desktop Users</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/12/21/easy-use-of-webyast-for-opensuse-11-3/"
          >Stefan Schubert: Easy use of WebYaST for OpenSuSE 11.3</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Have you ever tried WebYaST ? No ? Then it is time for.</emphasis>
      </para>
      <para>We have noticed that WebYaST is not really known in the OpenSuSE community. One reason
        for is that WebYaST is not really user friendly regarding the installation.</para>
      <para>So we have investigate here some effort. Lets see….</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Installation</emphasis></para>
      <para>The simplest way is the one-click installation which is already installed on your
        OpenSuSE 11.3.</para>
      <para>Just use a web browser (like firefox) with the url: <ulink
          url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/YaST:/Web/openSUSE_11.3/webyast.ymp"
          >http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/YaST:/Web/openSUSE_11.3/webyast.ymp</ulink></para>
      <para>The browser will ask you to start the installation via the one-click installation. Start
        the installation and go through the installation workflow.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Starting and managing WebYaST</emphasis></para>
      <para>WebYaST is a web application which runs on two http servers on your system. For starting
        and managing these servers Thomas Goettlicher has written a nice Qt-applet which can be
        started e.g. in KDE:</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata width="25%"
            fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/qwebyast1.jpeg"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>After starting the WebYaST applet the WebYaST icon appears on the right edge of the
        frame :</para>
      <informaltable frame="none">
        <tgroup cols="2">
          <colspec colwidth="0.5in"/>
          <colspec colwidth="0.5in"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <mediaobject>
                  <imageobject>
                    <imagedata
                      fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/qwebyast-disabled.png"
                    />
                  </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
              </entry>
              <entry>WebYaST is disabled</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <mediaobject>
                  <imageobject>
                    <imagedata
                      fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/qwebyast-enabled.png"
                    />
                  </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
              </entry>
              <entry>WebYaST is enabled</entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </informaltable>
      <para>With the right mouse click you can manage WebYaST:</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata width="25%"
            fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/qwebyast21.jpeg"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>With this applet you can start WebYaST in your browser too. After accepting the GPG-key
        please login with your <quote>root</quote> account.</para>
      <para>And that’s WebYaST:</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata width="25%"
            fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/webyast.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>That’s all.</para>
      <para>(Yes, I know that sentence is written almost in every post here. Even in posts where
        problems just starting after the sentence has been read. :-) )But I think that should be
        really all. If not, please use bugzilla and blame us ! Have fun ! </para>
      <para>(Yes, I know that’s the second sentence which should be in every blog :-) )</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 22.12.10 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://maketecheasier.com/change-linux-displays-on-the-fly-with-disper/2010/12/22"
          >Make Tech Easier/Tavis J. Hampton: How to Change Linux Displays on the Fly with
          Disper</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Using Linux on a laptop has always been a hit and miss affair. With sometimes obscure
        proprietary hardware, many laptop manufacturers have showed no interest in supporting the
        free operating system. Nevertheless, through hard work by developers and support from some
        hardware manufacturers, Linux now supports a wide variety of laptops and netbooks.
        (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
    <!-- ($ ld: 25.12.10 sat $) -->
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Commandline/Script Newbies</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.computerworld.com/s/article/9202538/12_Commands_Every_Linux_Newbie_Should_Learn"
          >Computerworld/Katherine Noyes: 12 Commands Every Linux Newbie Should Learn</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>PC World - It's a testament to how far <ulink
          url="http://www.pcworld.com/businesscenter/article/207479/linux_is_on_the_rise_for_business.html?tk=rel_news"
          >Linux</ulink> has come that users today don't typically have to use the command line if
        they don't want to. Such is the quality of the graphical user interfaces in many modern
          <ulink
          url="http://www.pcworld.com/businesscenter/article/204767/a_guide_to_todays_top_10_linux_distributions.html?tk=rel_news"
          >Linux distributions</ulink> that there's simply no need, in general.</para>
      <para>Yet the command line can be a highly efficient way of getting things done in the Linux
        world--it's often a much simpler, easier and more direct method than clicking through all
        the menu choices, in fact.</para>
      <para>I believe fear of the command line is one of the <ulink
          url="http://www.pcworld.com/businesscenter/article/207739/top_5_mistakes_made_by_linux_firsttimers.html?tk=rel_news"
          >top mistakes</ulink> newcomers to Linux sometimes make. For that reason, let's look at
        some of the main commands any Linux user should know. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 27.12.10 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Developers and Programmers</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.developer.com/open/10-ways-git-version-control-can-streamline-your-writing-projects.html"
          >Developer.com/Jason Gilmore: 10 Ways Git Version Control Can Streamline Your Writing
          Projects</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Establishing a rigorous version control process is a standard part of any software
        project, and <ulink url="http://git-scm.com/">Git</ulink> is a powerful system for enabling
        such version control. But Git&apos;s advantages extend beyond just software development. For
        instance, I use Git to manage all of my writing projects, including <ulink
          url="http://www.wjgilmore.com/">books</ulink> and my articles published on Developer.com
        (including this one). Git offers writers a fantastic set of features for producing material
        in an impressively fast, efficient and organized manner. In this article I&apos;ll introduce
        you to 10 Git tips and tricks I regularly apply within my own writing projects! Even if
        you&apos;re using Git solely for software development, you&apos;ll still be able to apply
        these tips to your projects! (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 25.12.10 sat $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For System Administrators</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://vavai.net/2010/12/domainkeysdkim-implementation-on-zimbrasles-11-sp1-with-opendkim/"
          >Masim Sugianto: DomainKeys/DKIM Implementation on Zimbra+SLES 11 SP1 with
          OpenDKIM</ulink>
      </title>
      <figure id="fig.zimbra">
        <title>Zimbra</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="http://vavai.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/zimbra-logo32.jpg"
              width="25%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>Following tutorial will covers DomainKeys/DKIM implementation using OpenDKIM on SLES or
        openSUSE. Domain Keys Identified Mail (DKIM) is a technology designed to make it difficult
        or impossible for criminals to steal the identities of legitimate organizations. This
        authentication technology allows good senders to “sign” a message to prove that it really
        did come from them..</para>
      <para>DKIM originally written as sender authentication protocol developed in order to address
        the problem of forged email messages. Yahoo! released the DomainKeys specification and Cisco
        released the Internet Identified Mail specification. Both methods are based on cryptographic
        message signing. The two efforts have been merged, and the combined specification is known
        as DomainKeys Identified Mail (DKIM).</para>
      <para>These are various options for implementing DomainKeys Signature : by using DK-Filter,
        DKIM-milter, OpenDKIM and also by using Amavisd-new DKIM implementation. Don’t be confused
        with all the terms. All method have similar function, signing your email as “trusted” or
        legitimate email. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 27.12.10 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.howtoforge.com/postgresql-ssl-certificates">HowtoForge/thebrain.ca:
          SSL Certificates For PostgreSQL</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>This describes how to set up ssl certificates to enable encrypted connections from
        PgAdmin on some client machine to postgresql on a server machine. The assumption is that
        postgresql (compiled with ssl support) and openssl are already installed and functional on
        the server (Linux). PgAdmin is already installed on the client (either Windows or Linux).
        (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
    <!-- ($ ld: 25.12.10 sat $) -->
  </sect2>
</sect1>
