<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="forums">
  <title>openSUSE Forums</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/install-boot-login/453441-grub-higher-resolutions.html">
	GRUB at higher resolutions
	</ulink></title>
    <para>
      Many of us today have larger monitors with higher resolutions, than we used to have. This thread is started by a member that has a full HD resolution monitor, yet he cannot seem to find a proper resolution setting to make GRUB look good on new large widescreen monitor. Read and see if it all can be done. 
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/other-forums/news-announcements/tech-news/453886-we-would-like-support-feature.html">
      We would like support for this feature
      </ulink></title>
    <para>
      Maybe we should see this more often, it's an example of how the community can contribute to the development of the distro. Through openSUSE's openFATE a feature request is done to improve certain aspects of the package- and repositorymanagement. Now support for the request is asked in the forums. By voting for the feature request, users can support this.
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/other-forums/news-announcements/tech-news/453301-kde4-6-get-release-46-repository.html">
      KDE to get Release:46 Repository
      </ulink></title>
    <para>
      Recently <ulink url="http://kde.org/">KDE</ulink> released KDE4 4.6.0, this thread announces the creation of a repository for this KDE version, like at the time of release of KDE4 4.5.0 a Release:45 repo has been created. The repo will follow the KDE4 monthly releases. In short: not bleeding edge, just updated released stable packages. For those users, who want to keep their desktop environment up-to-date, yet don't want to use the Factory, let alone the UNSTABLE repos.
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>This week's subforum: <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/multimedia/">
      Multimedia
      </ulink></title>
    <para>
      The word "muldimedia" covers a lot, and so does this forum. To start, you'll find <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/multimedia/452884-multimedia-one-click.html">Multimedia in one click</ulink>, but there's more. About installing codecs (covered in mentioned sticky post), about using HDMI output on various videocards, about sound issues and so on and so on. Short instructions, as well as long threads to help out members with multimedia related trouble.
      </para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 9.2.11 gl $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
