<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="updates">
    <title>New/Updated Applications @ openSUSE</title>
    <!--* Gnome
* KDE
* XYZ http://oyranos-cms.blogspot.com/2011/05/openicc-and-basiccolor-profile-packages.html

Version should be available at packman or software.opensuse.org/search max. 4 posts. -->
    <blockquote>
        <title>
            <ulink
                url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/11/21/atiamd-fglrx-8-911-catalyst-11-11-rpm-available-for-opensuse-11-3-11-4-12-1/"
                >Bruno Friedmann: ATI/AMD fglrx 8.911 Catalyst 11.11 rpm available for openSUSE
                11.3, 11.4, 12.1</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>Several of you has all kind of non feature (mostly called bugs) with Gnome3.2 and kde4
            etc…</para>
        <para>I will just copy/google translate/paste here the comment made by Sebastian Siebert on
            his blog</para>
        <para> Okay, now that was a long night for me was. ﷽ I’ve researched intensively since
            yesterday evening after the problem of GNOME 3.2 and the XvBA hardware acceleration on
            openSUSE 12.1. Here, a blog reader has pointed out that the direct installation of the
            AMD Catalyst could solve the problem. However, I think the direct installation of
            anything since like AMD will move the existing files, and thus endangering the integrity
            of files. But I had to start somewhere and so did the RPM package and direct install AMD
            compared. I could detect no difference in principle, except that some files were
            installed in a different directory, where they had really nothing to be related. I could
            at first make any sense why the RPM installation failed. To me a very banal story is
            remembered. A specific search path ld.so.conf could possibly be kicked out in openSUSE
            12.1. I have my current openSUSE 11.4 /etc/ld.so.conf compared with that of openSUSE
            12.1 and lo and behold some search paths were removed. I have the necessary path to
            /usr/X11R6/lib/ or created and /usr/X11R6/lib64 in /etc/ld.so.conf.d/fglrx.conf for the
            fglrx driver, and lo and behold “vainfo” tells me that everything is in order. Now comes
            the interesting question: Is the problem fixed with GNOME 3.2 now? The answer: YES! ﷽
            So, dear people, you invite the makerpm-ati-down script with the updated packaging
            script installs the driver as usual and have fun with the new openSUSE 12.1 and the AMD
            Catalyst driver. (...)</para>
        <!-- ($ ld: 22.11.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
</sect1>
