<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://duncan.mac-vicar.com/2011/09/19/proprietary-drivers-broken-with-factory/">Duncan
        Mac-Vicar Prett: proprietary drivers broken with Factory</ulink></title>
    <para>ld.so.conf seems to have changed to include /etc/ld.so.conf.d/*.conf.</para>
    <para>Unfortunately, proprietary drivers like the NVIDIA installed a file without the .conf
      extension. Therefore XOrg did not find the custom openGL library included by the
      driver.</para>
    <para>Tracked as <ulink url="http://bugzilla.novell.com/718734">bug 718734</ulink>.</para>
    <para><ulink
        url="https://build.opensuse.org/project/show?project=home%3Admacvicar%3Abranches%3AX11%3ADrivers%3AVideo"
        >home:dmacvicar:branches:X11:Drivers:Video</ulink> contains a fixed nvidia-gfxG02 (Also
      updated to 280.13).</para>
    <!--($ ld: 21.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://oyranos-cms.blogspot.com/2011/04/google-summer-of-code-2011-students.html"
        >Kai-Uwe Behrmann: Google Summer of Code 2011 Students</ulink></title>
    <para>Several students proposed this year to specific colour management themes. Unfortunately
      not all could be accepted for the stipends, even though the quality of the proposals where
      generally high for the themes and response was very lifely. The mentors made their decision
      and picked the following three proposals and students. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 23.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://blog.cornelius-schumacher.de/2011/09/my-opensuse-conference.html"
        >Cornelius Schumacher: My openSUSE conference </ulink></title>
    <para>Last week was the <ulink url="http://conference.opensuse.org/">openSUSE conference</ulink>
      in Nýrnberg. Here are some of my impressions. I loved the relaxed, crazy atmosphere, mixing so
      many different people with so many different backgrounds, skills, interests, and fascinating
      projects. This spans quite a broad range of topics, not only on the software side from kernel
      to office suite, but also in other areas from cheese over quadrocopters to self-replicating
      machines. This community is seriously rocking the boat. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 23.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/09/22/happy-pony-opensuse/">Susanne
        Oberhauser: “Happy Pony” openSUSE?</ulink></title>
    <para>At the openSUSE conference last week, Lydia Pintscher from the KDE Community Working Group
      led a BoF on “women in openSUSE”. This is what we (Stella, Bruno, Lydia, Pascal, Susanne,
      Greg) worked out:</para>
    <para>There are very few women in openSUSE for a variety of reasons. In our perceiption, despite
      the good efforts of moderators on IRC, forums and mailing-lists, some attitudes there still
      persist, and we believe these are a key issue that keeps women away. To further address this
      as a small group, we decided to start at just one place, opensuse-project@. Here’s why and
      how:</para>
    <para>There is quite some research on why there is so few “women in FLOSS” in general. One of
      the recurring topics there, and one that we also quickly came to in the BoF, was the
      ‘flaming’, or more generally, the negative possibilities of the direct, unfiltered yet
      anonymous communication on IRC, forums and mail.</para>
    <para>We all value the speed and positive directness of those forms of communication — however
      it’s cutting off facial expression and physical reaction. So it’s very easy to miss the tone,
      without even noticing. To more sensitive souls, this is creating a barrier of entry that
      especially women do not want to cross, or if it hits you unprepared, will reject you, often
      with no return. Nota bene: this effect is not limited to women! It just happens to reject
      women more than men.(...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 23.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.wafaa.eu/entry/growing-some-opensuse-arms-1-69.html">Andrew Wafaa:
        Growing some openSUSE ARMs</ulink></title>
    <para>One of the things that came out of the recent <ulink url="http://conference.opensuse.org"
        >Geeko Love-In</ulink> for me was a new project to immerse myself in within openSUSE. Yeah I
      know, we have enough existing projects already so why create a new one? Simples! Believe it or
      not but openSUSE is behind the curve in a specific segment, and that segment has yet to
      explode to its full potential. That segment is ARM. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 23.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
