<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="updates">
  <title>New/Updated Applications @ openSUSE</title>
  <!--* Gnome
* KDE
* XYZ 

Version should be available at packman or software.opensuse.org/search max. 4 posts. -->
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/05/26/7393/">Klaas Freitag: Kraft
    updated</ulink></title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/kraft_helps-300x192.png"
          width="10%"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Yesterday I did a new release of <ulink url="http://volle-kraft-voraus.de">Kraft</ulink>,
      the KDE application to create and manage business documents in the small enterprise. It is
        <ulink url="http://volle-kraft-voraus.de/Releases">version 0.43</ulink>, the former one was
      0.42, release in april 2011. Both releases, where the latter is a kind of maintenance release
      of the first are the result of a comparable high development effort of the underlying code in
      catalog handling and document lists in Kraft.</para>
    <para>The document lists consisting of a latest, complete and time sorted view are now fully
      based on one Qt interview model feeding the views. That was a step because the original code
      was based on Qt3′s treewidget code. The result is convincing: the time needed to build up all
      views with a couple of thousand documents went down from around 20 seconds with the old
      implementation (which of course was not optimized) to almost nothing now. A nice
      result.</para>
    <para>The catalog management got also a fundamental change, it can handle an arbitrary depth of
      catalog chapters now instead of only one. That makes a catalog chapter hirarchie in which
      templates can be moved around by drag and drop. Complete sub chapters can now be moved now
      from the catalog to the document quickly to speed up the assembly of documents covering
      standard workflows. Moreover this change in the underlying catalog data structure was an
      important prerequisite to implement reading of standard catalog formats such as DATANORM in
      later releases.</para>
    <para>Krafts development is still going slowly, but steadily. There are quite some ideas on how
      to move on with Kraft:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Kraft Mobile – spin off a mobile app working on the new form factors providing useful
          functionality</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>support for DATANORM and friends, which would allow reading standard template catalogs
          provided by suppliers.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://techbase.kde.org/Projects/KdeFinance/Alkimia">Alkimia</ulink>
          support which would head into accounting functionality together with the other KDE
          financial applications</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>continue on <ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/01/25/share-your-kraft/"
            >shared Kraft</ulink>, which utilizes the <ulink url="http://www.owncloud.org">Owncloud
            project</ulink> as a document and catalog sharing platform</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>support sub documents and more structured documents in Kraft</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>more project management capabilities in Kraft</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>All of these ideas are interesting and quite some work. I haven’t decided yet. If you
      think you want to influence Krafts future, let me know your arguments, most preferably on the
        <ulink url="http://sourceforge.net/mailarchive/forum.php?forum_name=kraft-user">Kraft
        mailinglist</ulink>. If you even feel like you want to work on an interesting KDE
      application, please let me know, I’d be happy to share everything <inlinemediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif"
          />
        </imageobject>
      </inlinemediaobject></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 10.5.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/2011/05/08/smb-traffic-analyzer-1-2-4-supports-multiple-databases-and-delivers-websmbta/"
        >Holger Hetterich: SMB Traffic Analyzer 1.2.4 supports multiple databases and delivers
        webSMBTA</ulink></title>
    <para>If you don’t have a clue what you are reading here, this article is about the<emphasis
        role="bold"> SMB Traffic Analyzer</emphasis> project, check it’s <ulink
        url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/smb-traffic-analyzer/">homepage</ulink> for more
      information about it.</para>
    <para>The development team is proud to announce the release of <emphasis role="bold">version
        1.2.4 of SMB Traffic Analyzer</emphasis>. With a much longer development cycle than usual,
      we took the time to do real ground work on<emphasis role="bold"> SMBTA</emphasis>, and
      reworked the whole database handling. As a result, SMBTA will from now on access it’s
      databases via <ulink url="http://libdbi.sourceforge.net/">libDBI</ulink>, a generic database
      layer. Via libDBI, <emphasis role="bold">SMBTA</emphasis> is potientially able to run with
        <emphasis role="bold">sqlite, MySQL, and postgresql</emphasis> as database backend. Since
      both, smbtad and smbtatools have been rewritten to use the libDBI layer, smbtaquery can know
      run completely independent from smbtad, as it uses<emphasis role="bold"> libDBI</emphasis>
      directly to access the database (<emphasis role="bold">bso#8065</emphasis>). We have tried
      hard to crash smbtad in test suites since we made the move to <emphasis role="bold"
        >libDBI</emphasis>, and moved <emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="bold">several tens of
          terabyte</emphasis></emphasis> over samba shares without getting smbtad to fall (we are
      currently using<emphasis role="bold"> postgresql</emphasis> as database). We strongly believe,
      since smbtad does not have to function as a network gateway to the database for the clients
      any more, the move to libDBI will make SMB Traffic Analyzer much more stable. SMB Traffic
      Analyzer 1.2.4 provides an upgrade path if the user wants to use the sqlite database that has
      been created with SMBTA version &lt;= 1.2.3.</para>
    <figure id="fig.websmbta">
      <title>The object selector of webSMBTA</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://holger123.files.wordpress.com/2011/05/bildschirmfoto.png"
            width="30%"/>
        </imageobject>        
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>    
    <para>Furthermore,<emphasis role="bold"> SMB Traffic Analyzer 1.2.4</emphasis> debuts <emphasis
        role="italic"><emphasis role="bold">Benjamin Brunner’s</emphasis></emphasis> work on
        <emphasis role="bold">webSMBTA</emphasis>, a web
      interface to all functions of the <emphasis role="bold">smbtaquery</emphasis> program. It is a
      modern, rails3 based, intuitive interface, that <emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="bold"
          >reduces</emphasis></emphasis> object selection <emphasis role="italic"><emphasis
          role="bold">to a few mouse clicks</emphasis></emphasis>, and makes running statistic
      functions on the objects a breeze. <emphasis role="bold">webSMBTA</emphasis> automatically
      retrieves all the objects known in your Samba network, and displays them in a way that gives
      an idea of the network structure. Out of these lists, you click the object you want to run a
      function on, and get a descriptive dialog for the function’s options. The output of functions
      is HTML rendered, and attached to the webSMBTA main page. Our ground work on XML in smbtaquery
      finally pays off, as <emphasis role="bold">webSMBTA</emphasis> is consuming <emphasis
        role="italic"><emphasis role="bold">HTML output</emphasis></emphasis> of smbtaquery
      directly. Once a function has been chosen, it can easily be re-run by clicking it’s reload
        button,<emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="bold"/></emphasis> or removed from the
      page.</para>
    <para>We have added a new chapter for the documentation on <emphasis role="bold"
        >webSMBTA,</emphasis> as well as to the <emphasis role="bold">libDBI</emphasis>
      change.</para>
    <para>All of smbtatools can now use a single configuration file, serving all of them (<emphasis
        role="bold">bso#8097</emphasis>). The “top” function of smbtaquery can now operate
      descending as well as ascending. (<emphasis role="bold">bso#8095</emphasis>).</para>
    <para>You can download <emphasis role="bold">SMB Traffic Analyzer</emphasis> from the <ulink
        url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/smb-traffic-analyzer/smb-traffic-analyzer-download/"
        >download page</ulink>. Please be aware that currently binary packages of smbtatools 1.2.4
      do <emphasis role="bold">not</emphasis> contain the code for webSMBTA, as webSMBTA is in Beta,
      has not yet been employed with Apache, and is not ready for being packaged. Of course, the
      1.2.4 source tarball of smbtatools does contain the webSMBTA sources. Nevertheless, you can
      find a README file in the smbtatools tarball, describing how to run the webinterface by using
      the internal rails webserver. For more information on <emphasis role="bold">SMB Traffic
        Analyzer</emphasis>, check it’s<ulink
        url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/smb-traffic-analyzer/"> homepage</ulink>. </para>
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
