<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
  %myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="kernel">
  <title>Kernel Review</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/Kernel-Log-First-release-candidate-for-Linux-3-1-1319559.html"
        >h-online/Thorsten Leemhuis: Kernel Log: First release candidate for Linux 3.1</ulink>
    </title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Expected to be released in about two months, the next kernel version
        will offer optimised virtualisation, add bad block management components to the software
        RAID code and include an extended Nouveau driver for NVIDIA's Fermi graphics chips. Several
        developers have been criticised for their clumsy use of Git in this development
        cycle.</emphasis></para>
    <para>Linus Torvalds has issued the first release candidate of Linux 3.1, closing the merge
      window of this version, whose final release is expected in late September or early October, 17
      days after the release of Linux 3.0. Therefore, the first phase in the Linux development cycle
      was three days longer than usual. This was caused by the diving holiday Torvalds is currently
      taking in Hawaii; he is providing an impression of his trip on Google Plus.</para>
    <para>Kernel development has now entered the stabilising phase, which Torvalds and his
      co-developers mainly use to fix bugs; no further major changes are usually integrated in this
      phase, and the most important advancements of Linux 3.1 can therefore already be outlined. For
      instance, the code for software RAIDs will, on some RAID levels, be able to handle media that
      contain defective blocks. (...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 9.8.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://schaiba.wordpress.com/2011/08/13/kernel-weekly-news-13-08-2011/">Rares
        Aioanei: kernel weekly news – 13.08.2011</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>Rares gives his weekly Kernel Review with openSUSE Flavor.</para>
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
