<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
 <!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
 %myentities;
]>
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-project/2010-11/msg00206.html">Announcing
        openSUSE Tumbleweed project</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>There's been many discussions over the past years about a "rolling update" version of
      openSUSE on lots of different mailing lists and in person a different conferences. So the time
      now is to stop talking about it, and actually trying to do it :) So, I'd like to propose
      "openSUSE Tumbleweed" a repo that is a rolling updated version of openSUSE containing the
      latest "stable" versions of packages for people to use. (...)</para>
    <para>Other Sources: <ulink url="http://lwn.net/Articles/417946/rss">LWN</ulink>
      <ulink url="http://www.linuxjournal.com/content/opensuse-and-ubuntu-rollercoasters"
        >LinuxJournal</ulink>
      <ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/open/news/item/openSUSE-Rolling-release-project-Tumbleweed-proposed-1146308.html"
        >h-online</ulink></para>
  </blockquote>
  <figure id="fig.geeko">
    <title>Geeko wants you</title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject role="html">
        <imagedata fileref="http://zonker.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2008/09/uncle_geeko.jpg" width="15%"/>
      </imageobject>
      <imageobject role="fo">
        <imagedata fileref="http://zonker.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2008/09/uncle_geeko.jpg" width="15%"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </figure>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/01/third-opensuse-board-election-2010/"
        >Third openSUSE Board Election 2010</ulink></title>
    <para>We are pleased to announce the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board_election_2010">openSUSE Board Election
        2010</ulink>! The Election Committee this year is staffed by: geeko wants you <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/User:Diamond_gr">Stathis Iosifidis</ulink> , <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/User:saigkill">Sascha Manns</ulink>, <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/User:HeliosReds">Satoru Matsumoto</ulink>, <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/User:Digitaltomm">Thomas Schmidt</ulink> The Committee has
      prepared the timeline for this year’s election. As last year the election process consists of
      3 phases: (...)<xref linkend="fig.geeko"/></para>
  </blockquote>
  <figure id="fig.fate">
    <title>openFATE Picture</title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject role="html">
        <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/Screenshot-300x169.png"/>
      </imageobject>
      <imageobject role="fo">
        <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/Screenshot-300x169.png"/>
      </imageobject>     
    </mediaobject>
  </figure>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
      url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/11/30/feature-handling-for-opensuse-reworked/"
      >Feature handling for openSUSE reworked</ulink></title>
    <para>openFATE, the feature tracking tool used in openSUSE has been completely reworked and the
      new version is live now on features.opensuse.org. A team has started driving the handling of
      features and we’d like to update you with the current state and invite you to participate. The
      new version is now live and contains a long list of new features so that features can be
      handled completely with the new web user interface. The interface uses the new openSUSE Bento
      theme to fit in better in the openSUSE site family, has several search options to allow the
      screening team to find features easily, it’s possible to edit all fields and also the product
      states. Thanks to the openSUSE boosters, especially to Thomas Schmidt, for the new version.
      The new team has defined a workflow to handle features and described it in the openSUSE wiki.
        <xref linkend="fig.fate"/></para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/02/opensuse-announces-fourth-development-milestone-with-kernel-interactivity-patch/"
        >openSUSE Announces Fourth Development Milestone with Kernel Interactivity Patch</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>On Monday, the openSUSE project released the fourth of six milestones in the development
      of openSUSE 11.4. Milestone 4 (M4) brings a wide range of updates, both major and
      minor.</para>
    <para>Kernel 2.6.37rc3 is the basis of M4, including the famous “200 line” per tty task groups
      patch to improve desktop interactivity, and featuring the removal of the so-called ‘Big Kernel
      Lock’ that will improve scalability. </para>
    <para>NetworkManager was updated to 0.8.2, seeing several last minute fixes in cooperation with
      upstream developers. </para>
    <para>Libzypp 8.8 adds support for metalinks, the multiple download URL specification. </para>
    <para>On the desktops, KDE makes the leap to version 4.6 beta 1. This includes a complete
      rewrite of Kontact and is undergoing heavy testing. GNOME 2.32.2 is the final version planned
      for openSUSE 11.4, which is notable for being the last stable release before GNOME 3 in March.
      Zeitgeist, the activity tracker, is updated to 0.6. KOffice is updated to 2.3beta1, bringing
      the exciting Krita natural media painting app to M4, while OpenOffice.org is removed, having
      been succeeded by LibreOffice in M3. Qt 4.7.1 and Qt Creator 2.1beta2 will allow improved Qt
      Quick development. Other major updates include the addition of the Midori lightweight browser,
      the Rosegarden musical notation editor in version 10.10 and monodevelop 2.4. Gnash, the free
      Flash viewer, comes in version 0.8.8, which has “100% Youtube support” and supports hardware
      acceleration. </para>
    <para>And finally, the prize for biggest version number leap goes to xmahjong, which went from
      2006.8.10 to 2010.11.8. xmahjong fans will be happy to hear that the version bump is only due
      to a packaging change removing build support for SUSE versions earlier than 9.1. The graphics
      and gameplay remain as they were in 1990. </para>
    <para>A <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Most_annoying_bugs_11.4_dev#openSUSE_11.4_Milestone_4_of_6"
        >list of most annoying bugs</ulink> is being compiled; please check it before installing. We
      look forward to <ulink url="http://bit.ly/el1dv8">your bug reports</ulink> and test
      experiences too. Automated testing and the openSUSE Factory team have been active to ensure
      that your download of M4 will be at least minimally functional. </para>
    <para>The next milestone is scheduled for December 16. openSUSE 11.4 is planned to be released
      in March 2011.</para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/02/marketing-collaboration-days/">Marketing
        Collaboration Days</ulink></title>
    <para>The openSUSE Marketing Team is proud to host Collaboration Days during the month of
      December. Each designated day, we will focus on a specifc area related to marketing. The
      purpose of this is to get some work done on that topic to strengthen our ability to promote
      openSUSE to the world. It is a day that is meant to be busy and productive for the team as
      well as an opportunity for non-team members to stop by and offer their perspectives and help
      out as we hack away. As this is an open process, we encourage everyone to come join us, even
      if you are not directly related to openSUSE. All perspectives are important and we welcome you
      all. (EDITMARK)..</para>
  </blockquote></sect1>
