<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
<!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://dot.kde.org/2011/03/03/qt-and-future-kde">KDE News/Cornelius Schumacher: Qt and the Future of KDE</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Following <ulink url="http://conversations.nokia.com/2011/02/11/open-letter-from-ceo-stephen-elop-nokia-and-ceo-steve-ballmer-microsoft/">Nokia&apos;s recent announcement</ulink> about its future smart phone development strategy,
        KDE has received a lot of questions. Many of these questions have been related to the future
        of KDE and KDE&apos;s commitment to the Qt framework. In this statement we set out what we see as
        a bright future for Qt and KDE software.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Qt</emphasis></para>
      <para>We chose Qt in 1996 because it offered the best software development framework. Today,
        it still does. Over the last fifteen years, KDE has worked to ensure that Qt will always be
        available, leading to the creation of agreements such as that which underpins the <ulink url="http://www.kde.org/community/whatiskde/kdefreeqtfoundation.php">KDE Free Qt Foundation</ulink>. The future of Qt has been further strengthened in recent years by
        Nokia&apos;s decisions to release it under the LGPL and begin the process of giving the community
        greater influence through Open Governance. We are working with our partners to speed up this
        process and make <ulink url="http://qt-labs.org/index.php/Main_Page">Open Governance</ulink>
        a reality. In the meantime, we welcome Nokia&apos;s ongoing commitment to Qt, as well as their
        continued support of KDE, as <ulink url="http://ev.kde.org/supporting-members.php">a Patron</ulink> and as a sponsor of our annual conference.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">KDE</emphasis></para>
      <para>Today, KDE faces new challenges and opportunities. Traditional desktop and laptop
        computers are no longer the only means for users to work on documents, entertain themselves
        and interact socially. Innovations such as netbooks, tablets and increasingly capable smart
        phones have changed computer use, introducing new form factors and new use cases. For the
        first time since KDE was founded, we have the chance to shape the nature of computer use,
        rather than competing with established computing paradigms.</para>
      <para>Our Plasma framework puts us in a strong position to develop innovative and beautiful
        user interfaces for smart phones, in-vehicle systems, desktop computers, portable computers,
        home media centers and more. Few, if any, of our competitors have an application and user
        interface framework that is as portable, attractive and easy to develop with as ours. At the
        heart of Plasma and the portability of our applications is Qt. Code developed for one
        platform can run with minimal changes on legacy platforms such as Microsoft Windows and Max
        OS X and, crucially, on Linux and other free platforms that can scale from the handheld
        device to the desktop powerhouse. Recent innovations in Qt, such as Qt Quick, make it easier
        than ever for designers as well as developers to turn their ideas into applications and
        offer them to users. KDE is only just beginning to take advantage of these new
        opportunities.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">The Future</emphasis></para>
      <para>Qt remains the strong, cross-platform foundation of everything we do. Combined with KDE
        technologies, we believe Qt is the compelling framework for cross-platform software
        development. There has never been a better time to shape the future of computing. <ulink url="http://www.kde.org/community/getinvolved/">Join us</ulink> and make that future a
        future that is free.</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 4.3.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
<!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://camp.kde.org/">Welcome to Camp KDE 2011!</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The 3rd annual Camp KDE will be held on the 4th and 5th of April, 2011 in San Francisco,
        California at <ulink url="http://www.jdvhotels.com/hotels/kabuki">Hotel Kabuki</ulink>. Held
        annually in the United States, Camp KDE provides a regional opportunity for KDE contributors
        and enthusiasts to gather, learn about the latest KDE happenings and share their
        experiences. The event will feature in-depth talks by core KDE developers. </para>
      <para>This year Camp KDE is co-located with the <ulink
          url="http://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/collaboration-summit">Linux Foundation
          Collaboration Summit</ulink>, which takes place April 6-8, 2011. Co-location with the
        Collaboration Summit will allow Camp KDE attendees a unique opportunity to learn from and
        share their experiences with members of many other successful Free and Open Source software
        projects and companies. All Camp KDE attendees are invited to attend the Collaboration
        Summit. (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/open/news/item/X-org-completes-X-Server-1-10-1199226.html">h-online/Chris von Eitzen: X.org completes X Server 1.10</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>X development veteran Keith Packard has <ulink url="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.comp.freedesktop.xorg.announce/1342">released</ulink>
        version 1.10 of X.org&apos;s <ulink url="http://www.x.org/wiki/XServer">X Server</ulink>. A list
        of all changes, mostly minor improvements and bug fixes, are included in the release email.
        The most prominent new feature is the Fence interface, which was <ulink url="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.comp.freedesktop.xorg.devel/15993/">contributed by NVIDIA developers</ulink> and improves the synchronisation between OpenGL-based and X
        rendering contexts. (...)</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Copyright:</emphasis><link linkend="extcopyright">2</link></para>
<!-- ($ ld: 1.3.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.serverwatch.com/news/article.php/3926526/IBM-DB2-Novell-Partner-for-Linux-Software-Appliances.htm">ServerWatch/Sean Michael Kerner: IBM DB2, Novell Partner for Linux Software Appliances</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>&quot;Novell is expanding its SUSE Studio Linux appliance technology today with the addition of new templates for IBM&apos;s DB2 database.</para>
      <para>SUSE Studio is a Linux appliance building service that enables users to build software appliances powered by Novell&apos;s SUSE Linux products. There are two 
        elements to the IBM Novell partnership for DB2 appliances: DB2 is now available as a software appliance in the SUSE Gallery of Linux appliances, and SUSE Studio users 
        also now can more easily build appliances with DB2 with new integrated templates.  (...)&quot;</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Copyright</emphasis>: <link linkend="extcopyright">4</link></para>
<!-- ($ ld: 5.3.11 sat $) Copyright notice: Copyright 2011 QuinStreet Inc. All Rights Reserved.-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linux.com/news/featured-blogs/185:jennifer-cloer/414794:-ask-the-experts-how-to-get-involved-in-the-community">Linux.com/Jennifer Cloer: Ask the Experts: How to Get Involved in the Community</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>&quot;In <ulink url="http://www.linux.com/news/featured-blogs/185-jennifer-cloer/398699-ask-the-experts-how-to-get-paid-to-work-on-linux">last month&apos;s Ask the Experts</ulink> column, we talked to insiders about how to get paid to work on Linux. The experts replied with a variety of useful tips but one piece of advice was 
        common among all of their comments: get involved in the community. So, this month we&apos;ve reached out to another group of experts to learn what exactly are the best 
        ways to contribute and/or participate in the Linux and open source software communities. (...)&quot;</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Copyright</emphasis>: <link linkend="extcopyright">5</link></para>
<!-- ($ ld: 5.3.11 sat $) Copyright © 2011 Linux.com. All Rights Reserved. Linux.com.-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
<!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.net-security.org/secworld.php?id=10544">HELP NET SECURITY: USB
          autorun attacks against Linux</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Many people think that Linux is immune to the type of Autorun attacks that have plagued
        Windows systems with malware over the years. However, there have been many advances in the
        usability of Linux as a desktop OS - including the addition of features that can allow
        Autorun attacks.</para>
      <para>This Shmoocon presentation by Jon Larimer from IBM X-Force starts off with a definition
        of autorun vulnerabilities and some examples from Windows, then jumps straight into the
        Linux side of things. (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
  <sect2>
    <title>LOL</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://xkcd.com/869/">XKCD: Server Attention Span</ulink>
      </title>
      <note><para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is licensed under the <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.5/">Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 2.5 Generic (CC BY-NC 2.5)</ulink></emphasis>.</para>
      </note>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/server_attention_span.png"/>
        </imageobject>                  
      </mediaobject>      
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> 
</sect1>
