<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
<!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->  
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://labs.qt.nokia.com/2011/05/09/thoughts-about-qt-5/">QT Labs/Lars Knoll:
          Thoughts about Qt 5</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Qt 4.0 was released in June 2005, almost six years ago. A lot has changed in the
        software industry over these years. While application development back then happened mostly
        on desktop systems, mobile devices connected to the web have become increasingly popular.
        User interface technology has moved from static widgets to a fluid touch based experience.
        Since Qt 4.0 we have released seven minor versions of Qt to stay ahead of development needs,
        for example by releasing Qt Quick. Within the growing Qt user base, we have had a strong
        up-take and new needs from embedded and mobile app and UI developers.</para>
      <para>To also, in the future, be a leading edge development framework across multiple
        industries, Qt needs to continue to renew itself. Qt 4 has been an evolution, and I have
        been thinking about what future Qt versions might look like from a technical perspective.
        Over the last years we have been working on laying the foundations for the next major
        release. I see Qt Quick, QML Scenegraph and Project Lighthouse– combined with an increased
        focus on Qt Webkit – as the foundation which we plan to use to move towards a new major
        release of Qt.</para>
      <para>Given that Qt is moving into open governance mode in the upcoming months, I wanted to
        share my thinking with the Qt community in order to kick off the discussions about what I
        see as the technical architecture for Qt 5. (...)</para>
          </blockquote> 
  </sect2>-->
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxfoundation.org/collaborate/workgroups/lsb/fhs">The Filesystem Hierarchy Standard (FHS)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The LSB workgroup is preparing FHS 3.0, which will be the first FHS release since 2004. As part of that release, we are soliciting contributions from all interested parties.

</para>
      <para>Our goal is to release FHS 3.0 by July 1 if possible. (...)</para>
  </blockquote> 
  </sect2> -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.h-online.com/security/news/item/Getting-a-grip-on-Flash-cookies-Adobe-publishes-Flash-10-3-1242645.html"
          >h-online: Getting a grip on Flash cookies: Adobe publishes Flash 10.3 </ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Adobe has <ulink
          url="http://kb2.adobe.com/cps/901/cpsid_90194.html?cjsku=47050364&amp;PID=3848922"
          >published</ulink> version 10.3 of its <ulink url="http://get.adobe.com/flashplayer/"
          >Flash Player</ulink> for all platforms. This version finally gives users control of their
        Flash cookies, but only if one of the currently supported web browsers is used: <ulink
          url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/What-s-new-in-Firefox-4-0-1212755.html"
          >Firefoxý4</ulink>, <ulink
          url="http://www.h-online.com/news/item/Chrome-11-Google-s-web-browser-learns-to-listen-1233908.html"
          >Chromeý11</ulink>, Internet Explorerý8 (or higher) and, soon, Safari. The new
        ClearSiteData API allows the browser to <ulink
          url="http://www.h-online.com/news/item/Chrome-12-Beta-brings-Flash-cookie-protection-1240386.html"
          >take care</ulink> of Flash cookies (LSOs – Local Shared Objects), which it can manage as
        though they were normal cookies. Up until this release, users had to visit the <ulink
          url="http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html"
          >Settings Manager</ulink> on Adobe's website to handle the stubborn Flash cookies.</para>
      <para>Under Windows, Flash cookies can also be managed via a new entry in the control panel.
        Here, users will also find all of the settings that concern security and privacy. Flashý10.3
        now also alerts Mac OSýX users about updates automatically. Developers of VoIP applications
        can now access echo and noise suppression. Adobe has integrated the Media Measurement
        analysis function that provides developers with detailed usage statistics in combination
        with <ulink url="http://www.omniture.com/en/products/online_analytics/sitecatalyst"
          >SiteCatalyst</ulink>. The update for <ulink
          url="http://labs.adobe.com/technologies/flashplatformruntimes/incubator/features/">Flash
          Player Incubator</ulink>, Adobe's test bed for new functions, will be of interest for
        developers with its JSON support and secure random number generator.</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 16.5.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://kdepepo.wordpress.com/2011/05/11/troubleshooting-kded4-bugs/">Christoph Feck: Troubleshooting kded4 Bugs</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Not just recently, but as long as KDE exists, we are getting bug reports for the KDE
        process “kded4“. These include:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>kded4 crashes</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>kded4 leaks memory</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>kded4 eats 100% CPU</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>kded4 &lt;defunct&gt; process</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>Before I dive into troubleshooting those problems, let me explain what kded4 does and
        how it works. (...)</para>
      <!--($ ld: 11.5.11 sm $)-->      </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/return-of-the-linux-quiz/8843">ZDNet/Steven J. Vaughan-Nichols: Return of the Linux Quiz</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Hi there, it’s Steven J. Vaughan-Nichols again, ZDNet’s resident Linux expert, with yet another Linux quiz. This test is purely for your amusement and should not be used to determine if you’re ready for your RHCE exam.

</para>
      <para>Instructions: Click on your answer and then see how many others agree with you. Then click to see the answer and the next question. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 14.5.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://itmanagement.earthweb.com/osrc/article.php/3933061/Are-Usability-Studies-Hurting-the-Free-Desktop.htm">Datamation/Bruce Byfield: Are Usability Studies Hurting the Free Desktop?</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The recent history of new interfaces on the free desktop is not a happy one. Three years ago, the release of KDE 4.0 resulted in a user revolt whose like had never been seen. This year, the <ulink url="http://itmanagement.earthweb.com/osrc/article.php/3930571/Ubuntu-Unity-vs-GNOME-3-Which-is-Better.htm">releases</ulink> of GNOME 3 and Ubuntu&apos;s Unity have produced similar revolts, but on a smaller scale.

</para>
      <para>Looking at these reactions, I am starting to wonder: Are the developers of free desktops become obsessed with design principles at the expense of what users actually want? (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 14.5.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://labs.qt.nokia.com/2011/05/09/thoughts-about-qt-5/">QT Labs/Lars Knoll:
          Thoughts about Qt 5</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Qt 4.0 was released in June 2005, almost six years ago. A lot has changed in the
        software industry over these years. While application development back then happened mostly
        on desktop systems, mobile devices connected to the web have become increasingly popular.
        User interface technology has moved from static widgets to a fluid touch based experience.
        Since Qt 4.0 we have released seven minor versions of Qt to stay ahead of development needs,
        for example by releasing Qt Quick. Within the growing Qt user base, we have had a strong
        up-take and new needs from embedded and mobile app and UI developers.</para>
      <para>To also, in the future, be a leading edge development framework across multiple
        industries, Qt needs to continue to renew itself. Qt 4 has been an evolution, and I have
        been thinking about what future Qt versions might look like from a technical perspective.
        Over the last years we have been working on laying the foundations for the next major
        release. I see Qt Quick, QML Scenegraph and Project Lighthouse– combined with an increased
        focus on Qt Webkit – as the foundation which we plan to use to move towards a new major
        release of Qt.</para>
      <para>Given that Qt is moving into open governance mode in the upcoming months, I wanted to
        share my thinking with the Qt community in order to kick off the discussions about what I
        see as the technical architecture for Qt 5. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 10.5.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blog.jprosevear.org/2011/05/13/webgl-security/">JP Rosevear:
        WebGL</ulink></title>
      <para>Recently Context Information Security Limited gathered a lot of attention for <ulink
        url="http://contextis.co.uk/resources/blog/webgl/">a blog post on the state of WebGL
        security</ulink>. For Mozilla, <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WebGL"
          >WebGL</ulink> was first released in Firefox 4, and there are implementations in Chrome,
        Safari and Opera as well. The blog post outlines an abstract concern that WebGL is
        inherently insecure because it allows fairly direct access to the hardware, along with two
        specific attacks, a Denial of Service and a Cross-Domain Image Theft.</para>
      <para>The Denial of Service attack does not generally endanger user data or privacy, but it
        can be highly annoying for users, not unlike sites that pop up multiple dialogs or have
        long-running javascript that hangs the browser. The Khronos WebGL working group has been
        aware of this type of issue for some time and has discussed it openly. Shader validation can
        help somewhat, as can <ulink url="http://www.opengl.org/registry/specs/ARB/robustness.txt"
          >GL_ARB_robustness</ulink>, but the forthcoming GL_ARB_robustness_2 extension will help
        even more. There are also user confirmation approaches available as well depending on what
        real world data we uncover over time. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 14.5.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>    
  </sect2> 
<!--<sect2>
  <title>LOL</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://xkcd.com/874/">XKCD: Time Management</ulink>
    </title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/time_management.png" width="50%"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.5/">CC-BY-NC</ulink></para>
  </blockquote>
</sect2>--></sect1>
