<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
  %myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="kernel">
  <title>Kernel Review</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://www.linuxuser.co.uk/opinion/the-kernel-column-95-by-jon-masters/">Linux User and Developer/Jon Masters: The kernel column #95 by Jon Masters</ulink>
    </title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Jon Masters talks about features in the 2.6.37 Linux kernel and describes debugging a kernel problem using the Git bisection feature… </emphasis></para>
    <para>We’re now free of the Big Kernel Lock (in many configurations – it’s a config option that will hide other not-yet-compatible options when used) and I have been running 
      systems BKL-free for some time now. Arnd Bergman and others have done an excellent job to rid us of this last vestige of truly ancient non-scalable Linux and unless you need 
      a V4L (Video-4-Linux – TV tuner, webcam etc) device, you can probably run BKL-free today too. It is hoped that V4L will be fixed soon, maybe in time for 2.6.37. You probably 
      won’t notice a huge performance benefit of running without the BKL unless you happen to have something more high end than a desktop, but it’s still pretty cool to know that 
      you could get higher performance if only you could afford to have a system with dozens of CPUs to take advantage of it.</para>
    <para>calability is great on the high end, but another more impressive feature for those working with more down-to-earth systems is (at last) near-complete support for running 
      as a Xen ‘Dom0’ (or host kernel) under the Xen hypervisor. For years, the support for Xen host kernels lived in patches separate from the mainline kernel and had to be added 
      separately. This constrained which Xen kernels could be used and made life more difficult for those using it in their virtualisation setups. It’s not (yet) possible to fully 
      run an official Linus kernel without any patches as a Dom0 host kernel, but the remaining extra driver pieces and other work should be complete in time for 2.6.38. This 
      incidentally prompted some folks in the Fedora kernel community to wonder about scheduling. They would like this to land in Fedora 15 (for those who want to use Xen instead 
      of hardware-based KVM virtualisation) but are unwilling to accept large patches for things not yet in the official kernel (especially given historical experiences with having 
      to maintain large patches for Xen). Only time can tell what will happen there. (...)</para>
    <para><emphasis role="italic">This article originally appeared in <ulink url="http://www.linuxuser.co.uk/magazine-issues/linux-user-developer-issue-95-is-out-now/">issue 95</ulink> of <ulink url="http://www.linuxuser.co.uk/">Linux User &amp; Developer</ulink> magazine.The kernel column #95 by Jon Masters Subscribe and save more than 30% and receive our exclusive money back guarantee – click <ulink url="https://imagine.subscribeonline.co.uk/all-titles/linux-user-&amp;-developer?offer=WEB100">here</ulink> to find out more.</emphasis></para>
  </blockquote>
<!-- ($ ld: 29.12.10 sm $) -->  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/Kernel-Log-Coming-in-2-6-37-Part-5-Drivers-1158991.html">h-online/Thorsten Leemhuis: Kernel Log: Coming in 2.6.37 (Part 5) - Drivers</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>Support for fast USB 3.0 storage devices with USB Attached SCSI Protocol (UASP), an audio loopback driver plus extensions to support Apple&apos;s Magic Trackpad are only 
      some of the advances that improve the hardware support of the forthcoming Linux kernel version 2.6.37; final release is expected in January. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 31.12.10 sat $) -->  </blockquote>
</sect1>
