<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.bryen.com/getting-articles-into-news-opensuse-org">Nelson Marques:
        openSUSE 12.1 delivers GTK+ 3.2 with Broadway backend!</ulink></title>
    <para>On the 25th of September 2001, <ulink url="http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/User:Mclasen"
        >Mathias Clasen</ulink> announces the <ulink
        url="http://mail.gnome.org/archives/gtk-devel-list/2011-September/msg00175.html">release of
        GTK+ 3.2.0</ulink>. This release includes delivers:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Many improvements to the CSS theming support;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Width-for-height support in many more widgets (ex: GtkPanel, GtkMenuBar,
            GtkNotebook, etc);</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>New experimental Wayland and <emphasis role="bold">HTML5 ‘Broadway’
              backeds</emphasis>;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>GtkFileChooser and GtkAssistant received face-lifts;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>New widgets (ex: GtkLockButton and GtkOverlay, etc);</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <!--($ ld: 03.10.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://tittiatcoke.wordpress.com/2011/09/24/chromium-browser-got-accepted-into-opensusefactory/"
        >Raymond Wooninck: Chromium browser got accepted into openSUSE:Factory</ulink></title>
    <para>After maintaining the Chromium browser in the openSUSE Contrib repositories, the last few
      weeks things got accelerated and as of this moment the Chromium browser has become officially
      part of openSUSE:Factory (the future 12.1).  </para>
    <para>The first step wa taken about 3 – 4 weeks ago when a separate development project was
      created (network:chromium). From there onwards it was just a matter of getting the package in
      the right shape for Factory and making sure that all legal and security conditions were met.
      Those who are tracking the updates of Chromium in this devel repo, might have noticed that a
      number of rebuilds were triggered for the 16.0.880 version of Chromium. This all had to do to
      get a single spec-file that would satisfy both Factory requirements but also would be able to
      build for the older distributions. At this moment this special repository offers builds for
      11.3, 11.4, Factory and also for Tumbleweed. </para>
    <para>I am quite proud on this fact and I hope that the openSUSE Chromium users will be happy
      with this fact. At the moment I am preparing an update to the 16.0.891 version and hopefully
      sometime beginning of next week the new snapshot will become available.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 27.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.bryen.com/take-geeko-to-the-races">Bryen Yunashko: Take Geeko to
        the Races!</ulink></title>
    <para>Anyone who is part of the openSUSE Project knows that wherever you go, Geeko is with you.
      Geeko is that awesome mascot that brings the spirit of the openSUSE Community alive.
      Actually, Geeko isn’t just a mascot.  Geeko lives within us all.   Are you a Geeko?</para>
    <para>Now you can take Geeko to the races.  SuperTuxKart has a new addon, that includes Geeko,
      thanks to  Luke R.  It’s pretty simple to install and then let your work pile up while you
      tryto win the races with Geeko at the wheel.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 27.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://blog.cboltz.de/archives/63-1001-bugs-or-the-golden-rules-of-bad-programming.html"
        >Christian Boltz: 1001 bugs - or: the golden rules of bad programming</ulink></title>
    <para>If you missed my talk at the openSUSE conference or want to see the slides (including
      notes) again - here we are:</para>
    <para><ulink
        url="http://blog.cboltz.de/uploads/1001-bugs-or-golden-rules-of-bad-programming.pdf">1001
        bugs - or: the golden rules of bad programming as PDF</ulink> (If you need an editable
      LibreOffice file, just drop me a note.)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 28.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://oyranos-cms.blogspot.com/2011/09/colour-correction-concepts-for-monitors.html"
        >Kai-Uwe Behrmann: Colour Correction Concepts for Monitors</ulink></title>
    <para>Colour management for the desktop is a long standing issue not only for Linux. The
      following text will concentrate on colour correction of monitors. This means the experience,
      when you switch your computer or handheld on and look on the screen. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Why colour correct the desktop? </emphasis></para>
    <para>People tend to compensate for quite a lot of different types of monitors. They are most
      often able to adapt to one full screen and see colours as they are intended to look like.
      Thats fine as long as they are concentrated on the visual event on that one display. But in
      this article we want to discuss how to compensate the monitor colours to our human visual
      needs in environments with various displays side by side, as is the typical situation for more
      and more people today. They take pictures with mobile phones or other digital cameras and look
      at them on laptops, tablets, picture frames, TV sets and printouts often side by side. Or we
      look at them over the internet and want to share the same visual impression with other people.
      Many people with uncorrected systems see quite a difference between various colour devices and
      try to figure out how to conveniently synchronise them. Colour management should help
      accomplish that task. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 28.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://blog.jospoortvliet.com/2011/09/tumbleweed-image-dream.html">Jos
        Poortvliet: Tumbleweed image dream</ulink></title>
    <para>At the (pretty cool) <ulink url="http://www.openmind.fi/">openMind conference in Tampere,
        Finland</ulink>, it came up that a big advantage of <ulink
        url="http://opensuse.org/Tumbleweed">Tumbleweed</ulink> is that it always has the latest
      hardware support. Thanks to the rolling release, Tumbleweed comes with the latest Linux kernel
      which plays a big part of the hardware support of a Linux distro. </para>
    <para>If your hardware does not work properly with the 'stable' release of openSUSE (or other
      distro's) trying the latest kernel can solve that. But that's hard to get on your system, even
      with stuff like <ulink url="http://kernel.opensuse.org">the openSUSE Kernel
        repositories</ulink> because it usually requires you to first <emphasis role="bold"
        >install</emphasis> something. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 28.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.bryen.com/the-video-bof">Bryen Yunashko: The Video
      BoF</ulink></title>
    <para>So, one of the Birds of a Feather (BoF) sessions at the Conference that I organized was a
      Video BoF.  Specifically, the BoF was meant to start coming up with storyboarding to create
      some cool openSUSE promotional videos (ala commercials.)  There’s a number of us with some
      great creative ideas and varying levels of exertise in this area and we just haven’t gotten
      off the ground yet on how to approach some of these ideas.  For me, (relying on “old school”
      classes I took from when I was a film major) storyboarding would have helped to define exactly
      the steps we needed in order to complete and execute the ideas many of us have.</para>
    <para>However, the general discussion quickly went in another direction, and one that I think is
      equally as important and I’m glad that conversation took place as well… (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 30.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://blog.jospoortvliet.com/2011/09/meego-and-opensuse-invitation.html">Jos
        Poortvliet: MeeGo and openSUSE - an invitation</ulink></title>
    <para>Yesterday a <ulink
        url="http://www.meegoexperts.com/2011/09/linux-foundation-limo-foundation-announce-project-tizen/"
        >big announcement was made</ulink> by Intel and Samsung. It entails another big change of
      directions for Moblin/Maemo/MeeGo.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Where to go Next</emphasis></para>
    <para>Many people in your community <ulink
        url="https://meego.com/community/blogs/imad/2011/whats-next-meego">wonder where to go
        now</ulink>. Yesterday, at a MeeGo meet in Tampere, many wondered if Intel will let the
      community contribute to Tizen. Will Samsung work in the open? Intel and Linux Foundation
      didn't build a great track record with MeeGo and some said they simply didn't believe in it
      anymore. Many clearly care about the great community which was build over the last years and
      are afraid it will break up. </para>
    <para>Aaron Seigo spoke some wise words. He said: "don't rely on what big companies might or
      might not do. Find out what YOU want and how to get there!" And indeed, community is about
      making your choices together. Not depending on corporate players acting as ADHD kids in a
      candy store, tasting every candy then dropping it. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 30.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.wafaa.eu/entry/target-arm-hardware-1-70.html">Andrew Wafaa: Target
        ARM Hardware</ulink></title>
    <para>I just sent this into the <ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-arm">-arm mailing
        list</ulink>.</para>
    <para>This is a hot topic, and one that seems to generate the most noise.</para>
    <para>I've had a discussion with several people about target hardware, and I've also looked at
      what our peers are doing and saying. At the same time I've been trying to see what options we
      have for getting some sponsorship for hardware. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 01.10.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://kfreitag.tumblr.com/post/10848737554/where-do-you-put-your-data">Klaas
        Freitag: Where do you put your data?</ulink></title>
    <para>This week is <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/09/22/suse-hackweek-7-next-week/"
        >openSUSE hackweek</ulink>, as you might know, and we do fun stuff. A couple of people, I
      was one of them, were investigating in the very promising project called <ulink
        url="http://owncloud.org">ownCloud</ulink>. We were working on a better integration in the
      openSUSE desktop in upcoming releases.</para>
    <para>Why do we like ownCloud so much? </para>
    <para>Well, thats easy: ownCloud is a solution that is under the full control of the user and as
      a result very transparent. The server, were you push your data to is owned by you. You start,
      stop, erase or open it how ever you want. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 01.10.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
