<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
<!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxfoundation.org/news-media/announcements/2011/07/basyskom-codero-gluster-and-nixu-open-join-linux-foundation">Linux Foundation: basysKom, Codero, Gluster and Nixu Open Join The Linux Foundation</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Linux Foundation’s newest members represent Linux’s ubiquity and adaptability across
        industries</para>
      <para>SAN FRANCISCO, Calif., July 13 2011 – The Linux Foundation, the nonprofit organization
        dedicated to accelerating the growth of Linux, today announced that four new members are
        joining the organization: basysKom, Codero, Gluster and Nixu Open.</para>
      <para>These four companies represent the diverse environments in which Linux is accelerating
        technology innovation. The Linux operating system today powers the majority of the world’s
        stock exchanges, websites and supercomputers. It is also the foundation for next-generation
        mobile devices and embedded systems, while enabling new innovations such as the smart grid
        and highly visible technology advancements such as IBM’s Watson Supercomputer.</para>
      <para>Today’s new Linux Foundation members represent three distinct opportunities for the
        Linux operating system: to ensure security and application development across mobile and
        embedded systems, as a key component of hosted IT and web services, and as the foundation
        for storage in today’s maturing enterprise. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 14.7.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.mikogo.com/company/press/pr-2011/mikogo-announces-linux-open-beta-release/">Remote Desktop Software for Linux Community – Mikogo Announces Open Beta Release</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="italic">The renowned remote desktop sharing application, Mikogo, makes the move to its third platform with the announcement of its native Linux client. This release now enables businesses to host and join free desktop sharing sessions from any three of the major platforms – Linux, Windows and Mac computers.</emphasis></para>
      <para>Mannheim, GERMANY July 13, 2011 – The free desktop sharing application, Mikogo, today releases the first open beta version of its software for Linux computers enabling users on Linux computers to start or join desktop sharing sessions. A significant milestone for Mikogo and desktop sharing as whole, this release now provides businesses with a free and easy-to-use application for online meetings, web presentations as well as remote support sessions, available on the three major operating system platforms.</para>
      <para>For the last two weeks, the Mikogo Linux version has been in a closed beta stage, as it was thoroughly tested by a group of beta testers. Following positive feedback and a successful closed stage, Mikogo releases its new software openly making it available for any individual or business looking to start or join online meetings from a Linux computer. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 15.7.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
<!--<sect2>
  <title>Call for participation</title>
  <blockquote><title>
      <ulink url="http://blog.worldlabel.com/2011/tux-paint-kids-summer-drawing-contest.html">Tux Paint Kids Summer Drawing Contest</ulink>
    </title><para><emphasis role="bold">Grab <ulink url="http://www.tuxpaint.org/">Tux Paint</ulink>, make a cool drawing, win one of 3 <ulink url="http://one.laptop.org/">OLPC laptops</ulink>, one of 10 <ulink url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Sugar_on_a_Stick">Sugar-on-a-stick</ulink> and other awesome prizes!</emphasis></para><para>The 2011 <ulink url="http://www.tuxpaint.org/">Tux Paint</ulink> Summer Drawing Contest is sponsored by Worldlabel.com and is open to all children aged 3 to 12 who live anywhere in the World!

Here’s a chance to show off your talent using a great drawing program made especially for kids. Tux Paint is an award-winning drawing program you can download to your computer. Tux Paint was recently awarded <ulink url="http://sourceforge.net/blog/potm-201106/">SourceForge.net Project of the Month</ulink>. It will run on all versions of Windows (including Tablet PC), Mac OS X 10.4 and up, Linux, FreeBSD and NetBSD. And it’s FREE! (...)</para> ($ ld: 2.7.11 sat $) </blockquote>
</sect2>-->  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.datamation.com/open-source/choosing-the-best-linux-desktop-kde-unity-gnome-1.html">Datamation/Bruce Byfield: Choosing the Best Linux Desktop: KDE, Unity, GNOME</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The perfect desktop would be the one you design yourself. Failing that, which of the
        main Linux desktops is right for you?</para>
      <para>A few months ago, this question came to a choice between GNOME and KDE. Now, with the
        introduction of GNOME 3 and Ubuntu&apos;s Unity, the question has become more complex.</para>
      <para>Should you accept the latest innovation, or go with a desktop that proves itself? A
        simple desktop, or a complex one with all sorts of customization? One that doesn&apos;t change,
        regardless of whether you are using a mobile device or a workstation, or one that changes to
        fit the limitations or advantages of each computing device? (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 14.7.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://labs.qt.nokia.com/2011/07/14/qtquick-particles-2-0/">Qt Labs: QtQuick.Particles 2.0</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Some people may remember the old Qt.labs.particles module. It was left in labs because
        we thought we could create a better particle system later, and didn’t want to tie ourselves
        into that first attempt (but of course, we had to have a particle system somewhere; it’s a
        modern essential!). With the graphical power of scenegraph, the shader fairies are now
        creating that better system. As it’s in the unreleased and unstable Qt5 though, it’s still
        only labs quality – but that doesn’t stop me from sharing it on labs&#160;<mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="http://labs.qt.nokia.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>&#160;Check out the image of Plasma Patrol below to get a feel for some of its
        capabilities (and checkout qt5.git to see it in action). (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 14.7.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://blog.gapinthecloud.com/2011/07/13/gsoc-copy-cut-and-paste-shared-files-in-owncloud/">Michael Gapczynski: GSoC: Copy, Cut, and Paste Shared Files in ownCloud</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>As usual I ran into a couple more issues this past week that prevented me from
        completing many of the items on my Todo list. I also forgot to finish a couple of things
        like copying files, because it isn’t part of the web frontend.</para>
      <para>First, I’d like to take some time responding to Lukas’s&#160;comment&#160;to last week’s post.
        I’ve spent a while debating whether or not to store all file records in the database or
        continue with the current solution with only recording folders and any files that differ
        compared to their parent folder. I’ve decided that it is best to stick with current solution
        because ownCloud isn’t designed nor wants to support a large number of users, but only small
        groups. Lukas also suggested some additional permissions or rules instead of the current
        read or write. Well, protected files are what every user has in their own directory. Private
        files with links are what the public link app can already do using a token for the link.
        Eventually this will be part of sharing files and offer the same functionality in one
        interface. Shared files right now are pulled directly out of the owner’s file system, but
        you have limited power when dealing with those files and can’t physically delete them, only
        unshare the files from yourself. Creating copies of the files would require a huge rewrite
        and it doesn’t seem to be worth the effort. If you’re still confused about how sharing files
        work and where your files are going please continue to ask questions. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 14.7.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://digitizor.com/2011/07/14/flash-11-64-bit-linux/">Digitizor/Ricky: Adobe Releases Flash Player 11 – Finally Delivers 64-bit Flash Player For Linux</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Adobe has been taking quite a bashing from Linux supporters of late. First, there was the issue of them <ulink url="http://techie-buzz.com/foss/adobe-drops-linux-desktop.html">dropping AIR for Linux</ulink> and then came the bashing because of the lack of updates on the experimental 64-bit Flash Player for Linux.</para>
      <para>Well, guess what! They have just released Flash Player 11 and it includes native 64-bit support for Linux as well. When they discontinued their experimental 64-bit Flash Player earlier this year, Adobe promised to release a 64-bit version of Flash Player for Linux when they release the next major version. They have kept that promise. (...)</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Editors note</emphasis>: You can get Flash Player 11 Beta from <ulink url="http://labs.adobe.com/downloads/flashplayer11.html">Adobe&apos;s site</ulink>.</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 15.7.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linux.com/learn/tutorials/469003:the-five-best-linux-netbook-distributions-2011-edition">Linux.com/Joe Brockmeier: The Five Best Linux Netbook Distributions: 2011 Edition</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Though netbooks have waned a bit in favor of tablet devices, there&apos;s still a lot of
        demand for netbooks and netbook-friendly Linux distros in certain circles. Whether you&apos;re
        looking for a brand-new netbook or to keep an older device current, there&apos;s plenty of
        options for the Linux crowd. Let&apos;s take a look at the top five netbook Linux distros.</para>
      <para>A lot has happened in the last year for netbook distributions, and there have been quite
        a few changes in our selection for 2011 compared to&#160;<ulink url="http://www.linux.com/news/embedded-mobile/netbooks/308465-five-best-linux-netbook-oses-for-now">the 2010 line-up of best Linux netbooks.</ulink></para>
      <para>What happened? Well, a couple of releases that weren&apos;t quite ready for release yet
        finally hit the shelves. On top of that, a few releases sort of disappeared. The&#160;<ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GOS_%28operating_system%29">gOS release</ulink>&#160;went
        offline and is now considered discontinued. Puppy Linux is still going strong, but with the
        current crop of netbook releases, it didn&apos;t look quite as attractive this year as one of the
        suggestions.</para>
      <para>Ready for this year&apos;s list? Let&apos;s get started with the most likely suspect, Ubuntu.
        (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 15.7.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.debian.org/reports/patent-faq">Debian.org: Community Distribution Patent Policy FAQ</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Introduction</emphasis></para>
      <para>For whom is this document intended?</para>
      <para>This document presents information about patents and patent liability useful for developers working on community distributions of Free and Open Source Software (FOSS). By community distributions, we mean collections of free software packages maintained and distributed by organizations composed of volunteers, where neither the organization nor the volunteers seek to make a profit from the activity. Such community-based distributions may sell as well as give away their work product, possibly on CDs or USB storage media or by paid-for downloads as well as by gratis distribution. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 15.7.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://linuxaria.com/article/game-editor-linux?lang=en">Linuxaria/linuxari: Game Editor to create your game, on Linux</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Thanks to a great <ulink url="http://www.itworld.com/software/180043/10-best-open-source-apps-you-never-heard?page=0,0">application list</ulink> made by Carla Schroder I’ve discovered this software: <ulink url="http://game-editor.com/">Game Editor</ulink>.</para>
      <para>Game Editor is the open source game design software that gives you the power to create the games of your dreams, and, unlike other game creation tools, gives you the chance to get and change the source code of the game creator and design and develop 2D games for personal computers as well as mobile devices. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 15.7.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
<!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://omgsuse.com/content/yet-another-flash-player-security-update">OMG!SUSE! team: Yet another Flash Player security update</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Security Team member <ulink url="http://www.suse.de/~thomas/">Thomas Biege</ulink>
        published an advisory this morning more critical security updates in..you guessed it:
        <emphasis role="bold">flash-player</emphasis>.</para>
      <para>According to the security announcement this package update affects openSUSE 11.3, 11.4
        as well as SUSE Enterprise Linux Desktop 10 SP4 and 11 SP1. This announcement also mentions
        that this is a <emphasis role="bold">remote code execution</emphasis> vulnerability, which
        means not updating to the latest flash-player package will leave you open to attackers
        running programs and exploits on your machine!</para>
      <para>Adobe has posted more <ulink url="http://www.adobe.com/support/security/bulletins/apsb11-12.html">details on this bulletin on their site</ulink> if you&apos;re <emphasis role="italic">that</emphasis>
        interested in the different issues this fix addresses.</para>
      <para>For most users, you&apos;ll just need to follow these steps:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Open up <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/YaST2-GTK">Yast2</ulink><emphasis role="bold">or</emphasis> click on the &quot;Online Update&quot; applet running in your GNOME or
            KDE panels</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Select the flash-player update and install it</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Make sure you restart <emphasis role="bold">
            <emphasis role="italic">all</emphasis>
          </emphasis> of your browsers, this will ensure that no program is
            running the older vulnerable flash-player package</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Relax with a Long Island Ice Tea</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
          </blockquote>
  </sect2> --><!--<sect2>
  <title>LOL</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://xkcd.com/874/">XKCD: Time Management</ulink>
    </title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/time_management.png" width="50%"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.5/">CC-BY-NC</ulink></para>
  </blockquote>
</sect2>--></sect1>
