<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/2011/10/30/teradata-partners-conference-novell-brainshare-smb-traffic-analyzer-development-status/"
        >Holger Hetterich: Teradata Partners Conference / Novell Brainshare / SMB Traffic Analyzer /
        Development status</ulink></title>
    <para>Well last weeks have been pretty busy. With a 10 hours flight, we arrived at <ulink
        url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/San_Francisco">San Francisco</ulink> to get to <ulink
        url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/San_Diego">San Diego</ulink> to visit the <ulink
        url="http://www.teradata-partners.com/Conference">Teradata Partners conference</ulink>, an
      excellent event that included good discussions and lots of acceptance and recognition for
        <ulink url="http://www.suse.com">SUSE Linux</ulink>. I liked the way talks have been
      organized, or to say it in other words it was a matter of downloading an Android app to always
      have the overview.</para>
    <para>We served the SUSE booth at the conference, got involved into lots of discussions about
      the OS, and I was even happier in the moments when people asked questions on <ulink
        url="http://www.opensuse.org">openSUSE</ulink> – <emphasis role="italic"><emphasis
          role="bold">this is showing clearly that the project is well known!
      </emphasis></emphasis>To leave some words on San Diego is very simple:<ulink
        url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gaslamp_Quarter,_San_Diego,_California"> Gaslamp
        Quarter</ulink>, I’ll be back<emphasis role="bold">, </emphasis>and have a few more beers
        at<ulink url="http://www.rockbottom.com/"> Rock Bottom!</ulink></para>
    <!--($ ld: 02.11.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://blog.cornelius-schumacher.de/2011/10/introducing-inqlude-qt-library-archive.html"
        >Cornelius Schumacher: Introducing Inqlude, the Qt library archive</ulink></title>
    <para>Today I would like to introduce you to <ulink url="http://inqlude.org/">Inqlude</ulink>,
      the Qt library archive. The goal of this project is to provide a comprehensive listing of all
      existing libraries for developers of Qt applications. So if you are creating applications
      using the <ulink url="http://qt-project.org/">Qt toolkit</ulink>, and are looking for
      libraries, components or modules to use, Inqlude is meant to be the place where you find all
      information and pointers to get started.</para>
    <para><inlinegraphic
        fileref="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-OlDauS1xh-o/TqlYqnvZHRI/AAAAAAAAAT0/W9OY3LLS3o0/s1600/inqlude-home.png"
        width="20%"/></para>
    <!--($ ld: 28.10.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/10/26/coffee-talk-with-michael-miller/">Coffee
      talk with Michael Miller</ulink></title>
    <para>Friday 16.09, while working on the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:12.1"
      >openSUSE 12.1</ulink> marketing actions during the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:12.1_Marketing_Hackfest">Marketing Hackfest</ulink>,
      two of us had the spontaneous idea to suggest an interview to Michael Miller(<ulink
        url="http://www.suse.com/company/executive-management/">Vice President of Global Alliances
        &amp; Marketing for SUSE</ulink>), asking him a few questions we could have in the openSUSE
      community. We did not have the time to go around, to find the FAQ or to choose the “best
      questions”. It was kind of “shall we do that, around a cup of coffee ? Why not ?”. And Michael
      Miller accepted our proposition, without any objection or any “joker’s need”. (...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 26.10.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/10/25/internet-at-opensuse-conference-2011/"
        >Internet at openSUSE Conference 2011</ulink></title>
    <para>At the openSUSE conference 2011, there was especially one area that caused us the previous
      years some trouble and this year nobody spoke about since it just worked fine: Wireless
      internet access.</para>
    <para>So, what have we done right this year? It was basically wiring internet ourselves to the
      location and setting up the wifi controllers sponsored by Aeroaccess.</para>
    <para>We were lucky that SUSE’s internet provider M-Net had a fibre channel cable in the cellar
      of the building and negotiated a special short-term package with 100 MBit/s for the
      conference. (...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 29.10.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
