<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 id="gsoc" role="gsoc">
  <title>Google Summer of Code</title>
  <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
      <imagedata fileref="http://michal.hrusecky.net/wp-content/uploads/GSoC2011_300x200.png"
        width="20%" align="center"/>
    </imageobject>
  </mediaobject>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/05/23/gsoc-new-osc-user-interface-proposal/"
        >Marcus Hüwe: GSoC – new osc user interface proposal</ulink></title>
    <para>as a part of our Google Summer of Code Project to cleanup osc our first task was to define
      a new commandline user interface for osc. The current user interface is quite “inconsistent”
      (with regard to the expected arguments for different commands) and has some other “flaws”.
      Here are some examples to show some flaws of the current user interface: (...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 24.5.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://rxvl.in/post/5826361873/gsoc-2011-ssc-week-1">Ratan Sebastian: GSOC
        2011: ssc - Week 1</ulink></title>
    <para>My proposal for a command-line client for Suse Studio has been accepted for this year’s
      Google Summer of Code. You can see the full proposal <ulink
        url="http://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/proposal/review/google/gsoc2011/ratan/1"
        >here</ulink>. In short, the project is pretty self-evident from the title. In case you
      don’t know what Suse Studio is, its a web service that allows you to design custom ISOs of
      linux distributions. As you can imagine, designing a custom variant of a linux distro will
      involve a lot of configuration. This tool aims to ease the hassles involved with using the web
      interface to make these customisations. The most common use case for this tool as I see it
      will be modifying default configuration files. The tool will allow you to make all the
      modifications you want locally in an appliance directory and push the changes when you’re
      ready. If you want a more thorough view of how it will work please do read the <ulink
        url="http://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/proposal/review/google/gsoc2011/ratan/1">complete
        proposal</ulink>.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 28.5.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://cbounta.wordpress.com/2011/05/27/a-utility-for-merging-configuration-sysconfig-files-week-1-report/"
        >Christos Bountalis: A utility for merging configuration / sysconfig files – Week 1
        Report</ulink></title>
    <para>It’s less than a week, that GSoC 2011 coding period have begun. This is my first report
      for the project.Every Friday I will make a report in this blog to share with you the progress
      I am making on the project.So what did I do during these first days?</para>
    <para>First of all I created an online repo on GitHub and I forked the Augeas project. That will
      permit me to use version control of my project “GIT” during the implementation and retain an
      online repo where I can commit my changes to, while experimenting with the source code. This
      gave me the opportunity to practice more with git, create branches merge commit changes etc. I
      have to admit that until now, I didn’t used a version control system much, but i really don’t
      know why?!?! Really git is awesome and can save the developer valuable and useful time.</para>
    <para>Next, I continued with trying out OBS for the first time, the openSUSE Build Service, that
      just renamed to Open Build Service. Even thought i faced some troubles in the start finding my
      way around (packaging was a new thing for me, and after using obs I have to say that it is not
      as hard as I initially believed), with the help of my mentor I think I can understand now
      better the service and use it. But why use OBS to package so early in the project? Well we
      thought that by using obs we will be able to create packages (please care they are
      experimental ) with the changes i make, so other people can try them out if they are
      interested and maybe help with future debugging.</para>
    <para>Finally among my initial experiments with Augeas source code, I have created a branch
      “helloworld” on my git repo, whether i added a simple hw – Hello world command in the augtool
      that is contained within Augeas. That command prints as you may have guessed <inlinemediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="http://s2.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif?m=1256405099g"/>
        </imageobject>
      </inlinemediaobject> , a hello world message on screen. Then i compiled the project by using
      the sources of the specific branch, and at the end i used obs to create some packages that can
      be found on my obs repo <inlinemediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif?m=1256405099g"/>
        </imageobject>
      </inlinemediaobject> .</para>
    <para>As I had not any important experience with building software and packages, I occupied
      myself this week mainly with administration actions. Which however, will help the community
      and of course everyone interested in my gsoc project, to follow the changes, make suggestions,
      and contribute with new ideas, but will also help in the latter phase of integrating</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Conclusion</emphasis></para>
    <para>The progress of the week 1 in bullets:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>created git repo online through GitHub</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>practice with git</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>compiling packages from git sources</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Learn the basics about using OBS</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>experimenting with augeas code, and creating a small command as a test</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>creating openSUSE packages through OBS</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>The GSoC have just begun, and I have already learned many new and very exciting things.
      This summer will be very interesting for sure!!! Now i will focus on the actual coding and
      specifically in the merging procedure that will used in Augeas. Till the next report,</para>
    <para>Best Regards, Christos Bountalis</para>
    <para>[1] <ulink url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/home:/mpounta/openSUSE_11.4/"
        >http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/home:/mpounta/openSUSE_11.4/</ulink></para>
    <para><emphasis role="italic">Notice: This is the first time I compile and package a project
        with obs, therefore the packages inside the repo are highly experimental and only for
        testing purposes.</emphasis></para>
    <!--($ ld: 28.5.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
