<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
  %myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="kernel">
  <title>Kernel Review</title>
    <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://www.pcworld.com/businesscenter/article/224955/7_free_security_tools_for_linux.html"
        >h-online/Thorsten Leemhuis: Kernel Log: Coming in 2.6.39 (Part 1) - Network drivers and
        infrastructure</ulink>
    </title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">The addition of ipset support makes it easier to run a firewall, as
        it means that only one table needs to be modified in order to block a specific IP address.
        The situation with regard to drivers for WLAN chips continues to improve, with Ralink and
        Realtek now actively involved in developing the Linux kernel drivers.</emphasis></para>
    <para>Linus Torvalds' release emails for the <ulink
        url="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.kernel/1123040">second</ulink> and <ulink
        url="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.kernel/1124982">third</ulink> pre-release versions
      of Linux kernel 2.6.39 both note a comparative lack of changes. The calm prior to the RC2
      release even prompted him to speculate whether the kernel developers were "up to something".
      More jocularity of this ilk was evident on the release of RC3 on Tuesday, but both emails make
      it clear that he welcomes the tranquillity and is looking forward to a quiet development
      cycle.</para>
    <para>As usual, the bulk of the changes in the next major kernel revision found their way into
      the main development tree during the merge window. Kernel Log is therefore already in a
      position to offer a comprehensive overview of the major changes in kernel 2.6.39, scheduled
      for release in mid to late May. A range of articles will deal with different functional areas
      of the kernel in turn. The "Coming in 2.6.39" series opens here with the major changes in the
      network stack and associated drivers. Over the next few weeks, this will be followed by
      articles covering graphics drivers, storage support, file systems, architecture code,
      infrastructure and drivers for other hardware. (...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 15.4.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://schaiba.wordpress.com/2011/04/02/kernle-weekly-news-02-04-2011/">Rares Aioanei: kernel weekly news – 02.04.2011</ulink></title>
    <para>Rares published the Kernel Review for this Week. Thanks for working on it :-)</para> 
    <!--($ ld: 2.4.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
