<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/09/01/and-the-milestones-keep-on-coming/">And the
        Milestones Keep On Coming!</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>Fire up your virtual machines, get your test machines motoring, and start tweaking your
      fingers. It’s testing time!</para>
    <para>openSUSE 12.1′s next milestone 5 is now ready for download. Thanks to the men and women of
      openSUSE Factory who kept their eye on the ball with all the wonderful flurry of activities
      going on in our Project these days, they never lost sight and we’ll be sure to have an awesome
      final release in November. </para>
    <para>There’s a lot of interesting updates to the 12.1 release and some cool new technologies
      including GNOME 3 and SystemD. You’ll definitely want to take this milestone for a spin and
      see what you can expect in 12.1. And if you’ve never tested before, its easy if you follow
        <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/VirtualBox">these instructions</ulink>. Being a tester is
      one of the great ways of contributing to the free software movement, and there’s plenty of
      room for testers in openSUSE Project. (...)</para>
    <para><!-- ($ ld: 03.09.11 sm $)--></para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/09/02/drone-on/">Drone On!</ulink></title>
    <para>Among other things, the openSUSE project is about “having a lot of fun”. In that spirit we
      would like to add a bit of diversion and an extra incentive for everyone to register and
      attend the openSUSE conference.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Join the Drone On! contest and have a lot of fun.</emphasis></para>
    <para>We’ve purchased an <ulink url="http://ardrone.parrot.com/parrot-ar-drone/">AR
        Drone</ulink>, small flying aircraft which can be controlled by a computer or mobile phone
      over wifi, to be given away at the openSUSE Conference. There is an open sourced SDK for
      Linux. The SDK site provides the software and shows how to guide the drone from a Linux
      workstation; with a console to show the drone operating parameters. Let’s get it up and
      running on openSUSE for the fun of it! (...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 03.09.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
