<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
<!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->  
  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://dot.kde.org/2010/12/06/kde-announces-calligra-suite"
        >KDE News: KDE Announces the Calligra Suite</ulink></title>
      <para>The KDE community today announces the start of the <ulink
          url="http://www.calligra-suite.org/">Calligra Suite</ulink> project, a continuation of the
        KOffice project. The new name reflects the wider value of the KOffice technology platform
        beyond just desktop office applications. With a new name for the Suite and new names for the
        productivity applications, the Calligra community welcomes a new stage in the development of
        free productivity and creativity applications for desktop and mobile devices. ($ ld:
        10.12.10 sm $)</para>
    </blockquote>
    
  </sect2>
  <!--  
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>gfg</title>
      <para>...</para>
    </blockquote>
    </sect2> -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/open/news/item/Amarok-2-4-Beta-1-adds-new-features-1149453.html">Amarok 2.4 Beta 1 adds new features</ulink></title>
      <para>The <ulink url="http://amarok.kde.org/">Amarok</ulink> development team has released a first beta for version 2.4 of the open source music player for the KDE desktop, code named "Closer". According to the developers, the first beta is aimed at developers and early adopters and includes a number of new features that require "a lot of testing to make sure they are top-notch for final release at the beginning of 2011".
      </para>
      <para>The 2.4 Beta 1 release features a completely re-written collection scanner that better detects compilations, the option to have Amarok write statistics and album covers back to the files directly and the inclusion of <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transcoding">transcoding</ulink> support – the developers note that transcoding will be expanded to media devices in a future release. A new applet for guitar and bass tab information, map and calendar views for the upcoming events applet, and the new Playdar collection that allows users to listen to music provided by a local Playdar service have also been added. Other changes include an option to show and hide the menu bar, a mass-tagging user interface using the <ulink url="http://musicbrainz.org/">Musicbrainz</ulink> open content music database and support for the third generation iPod Touch.
      </para>
      <para>As with all development releases, use in production environments and on mission critical systems is not advised. Users testing the release are encouraged to provide feedback and <ulink url="http://bugs.kde.org/">report</ulink> any bugs that they encounter.
      </para>
      <para>Further information about the development preview, including a full list of changes and
        new features, can be found in the <ulink url="http://amarok.kde.org/en/releases/2.4/beta/1"
          >official release announcement</ulink>. Amarok 2.4 Beta 1 is available to <ulink
          url="http://amarok.kde.org/wiki/Download">download</ulink> from the project's web site and
        is licensed under version 2 of the GNU General Public License (GPLv2). The latest stable
        release of Amarok is <ulink
          url="http://www.h-online.com/news/item/Amarok-2-3-2-with-enhanced-search-podcast-management-1082697.html"
          >version 2.3.2</ulink> from the 20th of September. ($ ld: 10.12.10 sm $)</para>      
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>ert</title>
      <para>...</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>dangerous games</title>
      <para>...</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>LOL</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>would you like to laugh? Look this</title>
      <para>hihi :-)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
</sect1>
