<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
<!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxfoundation.org/news-media/announcements/2011/05/linux-foundation-announces-linuxcon-japan-keynotes-support-tsunami-">The Linux Foundation Announces LinuxCon Japan Keynotes, Support for Tsunami Relief</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>• Linux creator Linus Torvalds tops LinuxCon Japan agenda, will share his thoughts on the 20th Anniversary of Linux

</para>
      <para>• A dedicated day titled, “Open Forum: Power of Collaboration in Crisis,” will facilitate collaboration among open source project leaders working on technology to address crisis

</para>
      <para>• The Linux Foundation to donate program funds to tsunami relief efforts (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 7.5.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxfoundation.org/collaborate/workgroups/lsb/fhs">The Filesystem Hierarchy Standard (FHS)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The LSB workgroup is preparing FHS 3.0, which will be the first FHS release since 2004. As part of that release, we are soliciting contributions from all interested parties.

</para>
      <para>Our goal is to release FHS 3.0 by July 1 if possible. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 7.5.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxjournal.com/article/10935">LinuxJournal/Ibrahim Haddad: Run with MeeGo</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">What&apos;s new in 1.1?</emphasis>
      </para>
      <para>The MeeGo Project has had multiple releases and has progressed significantly since its
        announcement in February 2010. This article provides an overview of the MeeGo Project for
        newcomers, a review of the benefits MeeGo provides to the players in the mobile ecosystem,
        and discusses the features in the latest MeeGo 1.1 release, announced October 28, 2010.  </para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Introduction to MeeGo </emphasis></para>
      <para>MeeGo is an open, collaborative project between the project founders (Nokia and Intel),
        the Open Source community and various commercial and noncommercial partners with the goals
        of accelerating the adoption of Linux on a magnitude of client devices and enriching the
        technical Linux platform as the platform of choice for mobile computing devices.
        (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 1.5.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://blog.martin-graesslin.com/blog/2011/05/things-i-want-to-see-in-kwin/">Martin Grässlin: What Would Be A Win For KWin In KDE</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Now with the GSoC application timeline ended, I feel like blogging about some more ideas
        what I want to see in KWin in our next releases, but are not enough for a GSoC. Nevertheless
        most of it is in the scope that it can also be handled by new developers. But some parts
        have to be done by KWin/Plasma developers. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 2.5.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>i<ulink url="http://blog.internetnews.com/skerner/2011/05/attachmate-lays-off-mono-emplo.html">nternetnews/Sean Michael Kerner: Attachmate lays off Mono employees</ulink></title>
      <para>Attachmate is moving swiftly to re-organize the Novell business it acquired for $2.2
        billion.</para>
      <para>Today Attachmate laid off an unknown number of U.S. based Novell developers that were
        working on the open source Mono project.</para>
      <para>Mono is the Novell led effort to provide an open source implementation of the Microsoft
        .NET framework on Linux. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 4.5.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/security/news/item/The-Tor-Project-plans-a-Firefox-fork-1237745.html">h-online: The Tor Project plans a Firefox fork</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The <ulink url="https://www.torproject.org/">Tor project</ulink> has announced that it
        is to launch its own fork of Firefox that will include Tor integration. At present, users
        who want to use the decentralised Tor network to browse the internet anonymously install the
        Firefox extension <ulink url="https://www.torproject.org/torbutton/index.html.en">Torbutton</ulink> and additional Tor software. As developer Mike Perry has written on the
          <ulink url="https://blog.torproject.org/blog/toggle-or-not-toggle-end-torbutton">project blog</ulink>, the need to install additional software creates an unnecessary and
        complicating hurdle for many users. They also often find the toggle system for turning
        anonymity on and off confusing. Users would also often not remember in which mode certain
        tabs were opened, thereby putting anonymity and privacy at risk. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 5.5.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/security/news/item/Free-Software-Foundation-organises-Day-Against-DRM-1237347.html">h-online: Free Software Foundation organises &quot;Day Against DRM&quot; </ulink>
      </title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata width="10%" fileref="http://www.h-online.com/imgs/43/6/6/1/3/3/0/Dadrm2011-yellow-triangle-d508e44f9d741662.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>On its <ulink url="http://www.DefectiveByDesign.org">DefectiveByDesign.org</ulink>
        campaign page, the <ulink url="http://www.fsf.org/">Free Software Foundation</ulink> (FSF)
        has announced that 4 May (today) will be this year&apos;s &quot;Day Against DRM&quot;. With this day of
        action, the organisation wants to focus the public&apos;s attention on the risks of what it
        considers to be an anti-social technology. The FSF has created a <ulink url="http://libreplanet.org/wiki/Group%3ADefectiveByDesign/Day_Against_DRM_2011">wiki page</ulink> which allows users to swap campaign banners and event ideas. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 5.5.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.geek.com/articles/games/game-developer-david-braben-creates-a-usb-stick-pc-for-25-2011055/">geek.com/Matthew Humphries: Game developer David Braben creates a USB stick PC for $25</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>David Braben is a very well-known game developer who runs the UK development studio Frontier Developments, but is just as well known for being the co-developer of <emphasis role="italic">Elite</emphasis>.</para>
      <para>(...)</para>
      <para>Braben has developed a tiny USB stick PC that has a HDMI port in one end and a USB port on the other. You plug it into a HDMI socket and then connect a keyboard via the USB port giving you a fully functioning machine running a version of Linux. The cost? $25. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 7.5.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://linuxblog.darkduck.com/2011/04/what-if-prince-william-and-kate.html">DarkDuck: What If Prince William And Kate Middleton Were Linux Fans</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Today is great day in the UK. Day of another Royal Wedding.
Not only because this is just another Bank Holiday in this country. But also because this day continues monarchy. Hopefully Prince William and Kate Middleton will have baby soon, who can inherit British throne.
I actually don&apos;t know if William and Kate are Linux fans or not. Maybe they even have not heard about this great operation system.
</para>
      <para>But let&apos;s imagine they are great Linux lovers.
</para>
      <para>How can this change Royal Wedding ceremony? (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 7.5.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.makeuseof.com/tag/banshee-20-comprehensive-media-player-streamer-podcast-tool-linux/">MakeUseOf/Tim Brookes: Banshee 2.0 – A Comprehensive Media Player, Streamer &amp; Podcast Tool</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The <ulink url="http://banshee.fm/">Banshee</ulink> media player was first released in
        early 2005 and has since come on leaps and bounds. Probably the closest thing Linux has to
          <ulink url="http://www.makeuseof.com/tags/itunes">iTunes</ulink>, Banshee comes with an
        integrated music store, Internet radio, podcasting and compatibility with Apple’s range of
        media players, including the iPhone. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 5.5.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/is-mono-dead-is-novell-dying/8821">ZDNet/Steven J. Vaughan-Nichols: Is Mono dead? Is Novell dying?</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Well, that didn’t take long. I had thought that after <ulink url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/novell-deals-done/8755">Attachmate bought Novell</ulink> it would be keeping its open-source teams working. Indeed, Attachmate CEO
        Jeff Hawn had told me that, <quote>Business will operate as usual</quote>. While Attachmate
        will be keeping SUSE Linux as a spin-off company, <ulink url="http://www.mono-project.com/Main_Page">Mono</ulink>, the open-source implementation
        of Windows’ .NET, is being shut down and there have been hundreds of additional Novell
        layoffs. So much for business as usual.</para>
      <para>In a statement, Hawn told me, <quote>We have re-established Nuremburg [Germany] as the headquarters of our <ulink url="http://www.novell.com/linux/">SUSE business unit</ulink> and the prioritization and resourcing of certain development efforts–including Mono–will now be determined by the business unit leaders there. This change led to the release of some US based employees today. As previously stated, all technology road-maps remain intact with resources being added to those in a manner commensurate with customer demand.</quote></para>
<!-- ($ Id: 5.5.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://www.geek.com/articles/games/psn-was-running-on-unpatched-apache-server-with-no-firewall-2011055/">geek.com/Matthew Humphries: PSN was running on unpatched Apache server with no firewal</ulink>l</title>
      <para>Few gamers will be feeling sorry for Sony and the mess caused with this PSN hacking debacle. But if you were just annoyed by what has happened, be prepared to now start getting a bit angry.

</para>
      <para>Dr. Gene Spafford, <ulink url="http://www.cerias.purdue.edu/site/people/faculty/view/1">CERIAS Fellow</ulink> and professor of Computer Science at Purdue University, has been talking at a hearing about the PSN security breach held by the House Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade. He explained that independent security experts monitor Sony’s systems such as PSN, Qriocity, and SOE and report in an open forum Sony employees view about anything they find.

</para>
      <para>Those security experts apparently reported some major failings with Sony’s servers some three months before the April 17 hack occurred. These weren’t small issues, they are blatant oversights and laziness on the part of Sony’s engineering team. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 7.5.11 sat $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
<!--<sect2>
  <title>LOL</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://xkcd.com/874/">XKCD: Time Management</ulink>
    </title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/time_management.png" width="50%"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.5/">CC-BY-NC</ulink></para>
  </blockquote>
</sect2>--></sect1>
