<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
  %myentities;
]>
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
<!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->  
  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>test</title>
      <para>...</para>
    </blockquote>
    
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>gfg</title>
      <para>...</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink 
          url="http://www.linuxplanet.com/linuxplanet/reports/7233/1/"
          > Linux Planet/Sean Michael Kerner: Yes, Novell Owns Unix-Unix Ownership Settled</ulink></title>
      <para>When Novell first announced that it was being acquired by Attachmate for $2.2 billion,
        the question of who would retain ownership over Unix copyrights was an open issue. As part
        of the Novell sale, the company also revealed that it is selling 882 patents to a
        Microsoft-led technology consortium for $450 million. Potential ownership of Unix by the
        Microsoft-led group could have led to a new round of patent battles between Microsoft and
        the open source community. In a terse statement, Novell has now publicly stated that it will
        not be selling Unix as part of the patent sale. </para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://itmanagement.earthweb.com/osrc/article.php/3914701/Seven-Improvements-Needed-in-KDE.htm"
          >Datamation/Bruce Byfield Seven Improvements Needed in KDE</ulink></title>
      <para>For the past eighteen months, KDE has been my primary desktop. I use it about two-thirds
        of the time, with the rest of my desktop usage divided between GNOME, Xfce, and occasionally
        other desktops like LXDE. You could call me a generally happy user -- but, as with any
        desktop not designed for me personally, KDE has one or two quirks or deficiencies that make
        my computing less than ideal. To be sure, KDE has made many improvements since the last time
        I complained about its shortcomings, in 2008. </para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink 
          url="http://www.neowin.net/news/a-history-of-viruses-on-linux"
          >Neowin/Brandon Boyce: A history of viruses on Linux</ulink></title>
      <para>We recently gave you a brief history of viruses on the Mac and as requested by a user we
        wanted to give you a history of viruses on Linux. Given the tight security integrated into
        Linux, it is difficult to take advantage of a vulnerability on the computer, but some
        programmers have found ways around the security measures. There are several free options for
        anti-virus on Linux that you really should use, even if it isn't always running - a weekly
        or monthly scan doesn't hurt. Free anti-virus solutions include: ClamAV, AVG, Avast and
        F-Prot.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <!--EDITMARK-->
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>ert</title>
      <para>...</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>dangerous games</title>
      <para>...</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>LOL</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>would you like to laugh? Look this</title>
      <para>hihi :-)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
