<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://jimmac.musichall.cz/log/?p=1181">Jakub Steiner: Killing Mode Switch</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>As Allan already mentioned in one of his useful summaries, I’ve been pondering how how to
      improve the layout of the application picker in shell’s overview. While the mockup he showed
      does address the small click target problem, it still felt out of place with relation to the
      dash. I tried to apply different lipstick on it, but there was something inherently wrong with
      the layout and the overview lost its clean, “no boxes” feel.</para>
    <para>The reason for the windows/applications toggle was easy extensibility. We thought of using
      shell to access people/contacts in the same way as we access applications. We thought to
      present documents in a better way without exposing the filesystem here as well. We thought the
      orthogonal arrangement ala Sony’s XMB would be fun on touch devices. Over time, I have come to
      the conclusion that extending the scope of shell might do more harm than good. I’ve never been
      a fan of all-in-one solutions ala iTunes. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 16.6.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://my.opera.com/miki100/blog/show.dml/30928312">Mikolaj Siuda: Sonar
        color scheme for KDE</ulink></title>
    <para>I always thought why GNOME in openSUSE has (and had) green theme(Sonar), while KDE sticks
      with default color scheme, which isn't bad, but...We could also change it to integrate with
      the openSUSE style.I made a quick Sonar color scheme and here is what it looks like:</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://files.myopera.com/miki100/blog/KDE_Sonar.jpg"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>You can find my Sonar color scheme here: <ulink url="http://pastebin.com/BiapkPxn">http://pastebin.com/BiapkPxn</ulink> . Save it as
      "Sonar.colors" and import in "System settings". I know that it isn't perfect, but it matches
      original pretty good (you can see Gimp in the screnshot).Hope you like it!</para>
    <!--($ ld: 6.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://blog.jospoortvliet.com/2011/06/on-value-of-contributing-opinions.html"
        >Jos Poortvliet: On the value of contributing opinions</ulink></title>
    <para>I recently read <ulink
        url="http://lists.kde.org/?l=kde-core-devel&amp;m=130559953811420&amp;w=2">a mail on the KDE
        core-devel mailinglist by Eike Hein</ulink>. It was quite a good description of the value of
      opinions and ideas for a FOSS project - something I've been thinking about quite a bit lately.
      What is the value of an idea, suggestion or opinion? That is a much harder question to answer
      than it might seem. Free Software projects solicit user feedback in a variety of ways. For
      example via a bug tracker or comments on announcements. Users are sometimes asked to
      participate in mailing lists or on forums. Interestingly, both users and developers often
      complain about the process and results. Users feel they are not heard, developers say the
      comments are unfriendly, de-motivating or useless. In Eike's case, he commented that the user
      was <blockquote>
        <para>sort of implying that the current placement of things in workspace isn't already the
          result of a thought and decision process, while not actually having done your homework yet
          on what the purpose of the components in question is</para>
      </blockquote>So, he felt attacked a bit - the user makes it seem like the developers just did
      something at random. And the user didn’t bother to inform himself, so the comments aren’t
      useful either. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 9.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
