<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/28/opensuse-at-and-with-fosdem-2011/">openSUSE at
        and with FOSDEM 2011</ulink>
    </title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata width="25%"
          fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/openSUSEboothfosdemrhlim-300x200.jpg"
        />
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Next years <ulink url="http://www.fosdem.org/2011/">FOSDEM</ulink> takes place again in
      Brussels on Feb 5th and 6th 2011 and openSUSE will be present as usual!</para>
    <para>Apart of the well known high level open Source tech conference there will be for the 2nd
      time the Distribution <ulink url="http://www.fosdem.org/2011/distrominiconf">Miniconf</ulink>.
      The Miniconf provides the perfect place for different projects to share ideas, talk about
      challenges each project has and to foster collaboration – and as openSUSE is all about
      collaboration we want to play a major role there.</para>
    <para>The Miniconf is open for every project. For more information please subscribe on the
      Miniconf <ulink url="http://lists.fosdem.org/mailman/listinfo/dist2011">mailinglist</ulink>.
      We are looking for talks about cross-distro collaboration and presentations on openSUSE
      technology – like OBS, openFATE but also where we are going – things like Tumbleweed!</para>
    <para>Our contact with FOSDEM is <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/User:Hennevogel">Henne
        Vogelsang</ulink>, if you think about giving a talk, contact him.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 28.12.10 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/21/board-meeting-summary-15-december-2010/">Board
        Meeting Summary 15 December 2010</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>For the full transcript of the last openSUSE Board meeting, see our <ulink
        url="http://community.opensuse.org/meetings/opensuse-project/2010/opensuse-project.2010-12-15-19.01.log.html"
        >logs</ulink>. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Introduction of new openSUSE Board Chairman – Alan Clark
      </emphasis></para>
    <para>We opened with an introduction to new Board Chairman, Alan Clark who answered general
      questions from the community about his role and goals. To the question of what Clark’s goals
      are he answered:<orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>The top goal is as a Board to get the Foundation up and operational. As we continue
            to work towards this, I’m sure that we will uncover other issues that we will need to
            address</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Grow the Community</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Is a personal goal: Tune up my decoder ring for all these alias cloaking and get to
            know as many people as possible -simply because that is the fun part of being in a
            community.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Let people get their work done; er <quote>have a lot of fun</quote></para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist></para>
    <para>Alan also provided his background experience with open source projects, both within Novell
      and outside Novell. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Foundation Creation</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>Several board members expressed a desire to develop a more open and transparent process in
      communicating the development of the openSUSE Foundation than what currently exists. Some
      believe there has been a disconnect in how we become aware of what everyone is doing and
      keeping the momentum of the process going forward, as well as ensuring that all those with a
      vested interest are able to participate in the process.</para>
    <para>We all agreed that we must begin to identify who are the stakeholders and take steps
      immediately to open up the process. To that end, a new open mailing list will be created and
      Alan will create a wiki page where we will collect all the relevant information for the
      foundation creation. Relevant points and concerns of the stakeholders will be listed and the
      progress of the creation will be documented.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Membership Approval Concerns</emphasis></para>
    <para>Membership approval team members expressed concern about the clarity of the rules for
      consideration and eligibility.</para>
    <para>In the current rules, it states that a membership application is processed after receiving
      four votes. It was unclear whether that meant four votes in sum or four votes of either
      positive or negative. With a minor edit of the rules, we stated that an application is
      considered processed once it has received either four positive votes or four negative
      votes.</para>
    <para>Additionally, there was concern about a recent email request to process a particular
      application expeditiously. Team members felt this was an inappropriate breach of protocol and
      that all applications are equal and that no single application should be placed ahead of
      existing applications. We agreed and declared that henceforth, such requests should not be
      honored.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Where do we fail?</emphasis></para>
    <para>Our regular topic to identify areas where we fail and can quickly remedy brought up a
      topic of concern regarding communication. To this, we agreed that the Board will begin
      regularly posting summaries of meetings (which is what you are reading now.)</para>
    <para>We also took a general board action item to review <ulink
        url="https://features.opensuse.org/statistic/product/opensuse.org">opensuse.org product
        category in openFATE</ulink> to ensure we stay on top of “Where do we fail?” concerns that
      are not brought up during board meetings.</para>
    <para>Read here for the <ulink
        url="http://community.opensuse.org/meetings/opensuse-project/2010/opensuse-project.2010-12-15-19.01.log.html"
        >full meeting transcript</ulink>.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Next Meeting</emphasis></para>
    <para>With the holidays coming up, we will have our next Board meeting on 12 January,
      2011.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 22.12.10 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/23/opensuse-announces-fifth-development-milestone-with-kernel-interactivity-patch/"
        >openSUSE Announces Fifth Development Milestone with Kernel Interactivity Patch</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>The openSUSE project released the fifth of six milestones in the development of openSUSE
      11.4 some days ago. <emphasis role="bold">Milestone 5 (M5)</emphasis> brings a wide range of
      updates, both major and minor. As usual, you can get it <ulink
        url="http://software.opensuse.org/developer/en">here</ulink>.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Major Features</emphasis>:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Kernel 2.6.37rc5-12 is the basis of M5, including the famous “200 line” per tty task
          groups patch to improve desktop interactivity, and featuring the almost-complete removal
          of the so-called ‘Big Kernel Lock’, which should improve scalability. This kernel supports
          new drivers, including Broadcom wireless and updated open-source graphics drivers, and a
          host of the usual other improvements.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Libzypp 8.10.2 adds improved support and fixes for metalinks, the multiple download
          URL specification.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>On the desktop, the KDE Platform makes the leap to version 4.6 beta with many
          improvements in the UI and underlying infrastructure. This includes a complete rewrite of
          Kontact and is undergoing heavy testing. There is a serious chance KDE PIM 4.6 will not
          make it into the final openSUSE 11.4 release, testing and development is needed!</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>KOffice is updated to 2.3 RC superseding beta1, including the exciting Krita natural
          media painting app. Meanwhile OpenOffice.org is removed, having been succeeded by
          LibreOffice which is updated to 3.3.0.1.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>GNOME 2.32.1 is now available as the 2.32.2 is the final version planned for openSUSE
          11.4, which is notable for being the last stable release before GNOME 3 in March.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>GNUCash 2.4 RC comes with a new complete dress-up.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Pidgin updates fixes several MSN and ICQ issues.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>In the Virtualization area, available now are kernel-xen 2.5.37 features and
          kernel-ec2 2.6.37 with improvements for cloud sync services and Virtual Box 4 Beta
          including USB devices support and more than 2GB RAM support on 32 bit guest, Intel HD
          Audio, asynchronous I/O for iSCSI, VMDK, VHD and Parallels image support.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>systemd 15 provides aggressive parallelization capabilities to start multiple daemons
          at the same time with dependencies which offers improvements to the boot times on some
          systems. More testing (and porting of init scripts) is still needed for systemd, which
          will most likely make it into 11.4 as experimental and optional feature.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Get it!</emphasis></para>
    <para>A list of most annoying bugs is being compiled; please check it before installing. We look
      forward to your bug reports and test experiences! Automated testing and the openSUSE Factory
      team have been very active to ensure that your download of M5 will be at least minimally
      functional, thanks for that! now go and <ulink url="http://software.opensuse.org/developer/en"
        >download it!</ulink></para>
    <para>The next milestone is scheduled for Thursday, Jan 20 2011, and will be the openSUSE 11.4
      Milestone 6 release. The final openSUSE 11.4 is planned to be released in March 2011.</para>
    <para>Other Souces: <ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/open/news/item/openSUSE-11-4-Milestone-5-released-1158848.html"
        > h-online</ulink>
      <ulink
        url="http://www.linux.com/news/enterprise/biz-enterprise/392669:opensuse-114-milestone-5-released"
        >Linux.com</ulink></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 23.12.10 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
