<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://andreasjaeger.blogspot.com/2010/12/fixing-smugbatch-for-new-smugmug-api.html"
        >Fixing smugbatch for new smugmug API</ulink></title>
    <para>I'm using smugmug to share my photos and have used the <ulink
        url="http://ajaeger.smugmug.com/">smugbatch</ulink> command line tool to upload photos
      directly to albums at smugmug. Recently smugmug made some changes to the API so that the
      command line tool did not work anymore. Now it needs the _su cookie to be send back with each
      request. I enhanced the tool, submitted the fixes back and now they are awaiting for the
      review by Greg KH at <ulink url="https://github.com/gregkh/smugbatch/pull/1">github</ulink>. </para>
    <para>I also packaged smugbatch with the changes in the<ulink url="http://build.opensuse.org/">
        openSUSE Build Service</ulink> and submitted the fix to the Contrib repository so that
      others can use the package as well. </para>
    <para>P.S. The primary reason for writing this is to evaluate the Blogilo blog editor. I wanted
      to know how it works - and will now test it some more and then write about that as
      well.</para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="https://saschpe.wordpress.com/2010/12/12/braindead-python-packaging/">Sascha
        Peilicke: Braindead Python packaging</ulink></title>
    <para>As you all know, distributing and building packages with the <ulink
        url="https://build.opensuse.org/">openSUSE Build Service</ulink> is easy and fun. The only
      party pooper is that you have to write a spec file to get your RPMs out there. Thanks to
        <ulink url="http://nordisch.org/">darix</ulink>, we have a decent solution at least for Ruby
      packages: gem2rpm, a script which auto-generates RPM spec files for Ruby gems. Ever wondered
      why we don’t have something similar for Python? Well, I did so too. Thus, after a half a week
      of hackery, I’d like to introduce <ulink url="http://pypi.python.org/pypi/py2pack"
        >py2pack</ulink>, my take on braindead Python packaging. Here’s how it goes: </para>
    <para>Lets suppose you want to package <ulink url="http://pypi.python.org/pypi/zope.interface"
        >zope.interface</ulink> and you don’t know how it is named exactly or where to download
      from. First of all, you can search for it and download the source tarball automatically if you
      found the correct module:</para>
    <para><screen>$ py2pack search zope.interface
 searching for module zope.interface...
 found zope.interface-3.6.1
 $ py2pack fetch zope.interface
 downloading package zope.interface-3.6.1...
 from http://pypi.python.org/packages/source/z/zope.interface/zope.interface-3.6.1.tar.gz</screen></para>
    <para>(...)</para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/12/13/last-indicator-builds/">Nelson
        Marques: Last Indicator builds!</ulink></title>
    <para>Finally… the last of the indicators builds and works properly… fun thing… works out of the
      box with Banshee! Two pics… one from the indicator-sound and another from the messaging
      indicator with empathy and evolution support.</para>
    <figure id="fig.indic">
      <title>Picture 1</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/Screenshot2.png" width="50%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <figure id="fig.indic2">
      <title>Picture 2</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/Screenshot-12.png" width="50%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://jeffreystedfast.blogspot.com/2010/12/assignment-apologize-to-someone-you.html"
        >Jeffrey Stedfast: Assignment: Apologize to someone you have wronged</ulink></title>
    <para>This past Friday, on our walk back from lunch, <ulink url="http://tirania.org/blog"
        >Miguel</ulink> told me about the latest assignment given to him by his teacher and mentor,
        <ulink url="http://www.benjaminzander.com/">Benjamin Zander</ulink>, the conductor of the
        <ulink url="http://www.bostonphil.org/">Boston Philharmonic</ulink>. The assignment was to
      pick someone you have wronged and apologize to them. </para>
    <para>For those who don't know, Benjamin Zander is the author of the book, The Art of
      Possibility, a book which I have been reading the past week or so. The idea of this book is to
      change your perspective on life by teaching you to see things in a positive light and thus
      present you with a world of possibility where you can accomplish anything you set your mind to
      because you are no longer held back by negative thinking (fear of failure, criticism from
      others, and most importantly, criticism from yourself). </para>
    <para>To continue on with my story, as I was laying in bed last night after having read a few
      more chapters in <ulink url="http://amzn.to/fi53Qj">The Art of Possibility</ulink>, I was
      reminded of Miguel's assignment and I began to wonder: if I was given this assignment, who
      would I apologize to? </para>
    <para>I thought of 1 person in particular and a community of users and decided to apologize to
      them all. (...)</para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://psankar.blogspot.com/2010/12/meego-naming-conflicts-controversies.html">Sankar
        P: MeeGo - Naming Conflicts / Controversies</ulink></title>
    <para>Some of you might remember the <ulink
        url="http://www.wafaa.eu/entry/disappointment-at-the-linux-foundation-and-meego-project-1-46.html"
        >Naming Controversy</ulink> behind Meego. There is a<ulink
        url="http://www.wafaa.eu/entry/disappointment-at-the-linux-foundation-and-meego-project-1-46.html"
        > new blog</ulink> post by Andrew on this matter and since he is not on Planet GNOME, I am
      just linking here, for the interested people. In case you want to know what the issue is all
      about, read further. </para>
    <para>There were Maemo and Moblin platforms from Nokia and Intel respectively. They both merged
      to form the Meego project under the governance of the <emphasis role="bold">Linux
        Foundation</emphasis>. Distributions such as openSUSE, Fedora, Debian tried to spin off
      Meego based derivatives and faced a lot of troubles. </para>
    <para>Well known openSUSE rockstar <emphasis role="bold">Andrew Wafaa</emphasis>, overcame some
      of these troubles and did a distro release using these Meego packages on top of an openSUSE
      image. He named this distro "<emphasis role="bold">Smeegol" => SuSE + Meego</emphasis>. This
      effort by Andrew (and other distros) is a step in bringing the cool, shiny features of MeeGo
      to the masses, by riding on the large user-base of the existing distros. However, this has not
      went well with the linux foundation and they have asked to change the name of the project.
      They were afraid that Andrew using "Smeegol" will dilute the brand image of Meego. </para>
    <para>Let us take a different case. "<emphasis role="bold">Linux</emphasis> " is a registered
      trademark of <emphasis role="bold">Linus Torvalds</emphasis>. If he has decided that nobody
      should be using the name "Linux" in their projects, We may not be able to use names such as
        "<emphasis role="bold">RedHat Enterprise Linux (RHEL)</emphasis>", "<emphasis role="bold"
        >SUSE Linux Enterprise (SLED/S)</emphasis>" etc. Allowing other people to use the name
      "Linux" (with due credits of course) has given it a widespread popularity. The Linux
      Foundation seems to be missing this point altogether and insists <emphasis role="italic">to
        move away from using {M,m}-e-e-{G,g}-o or any subset of those letters or sounds in that
        order, alone or in combination with other letters, words or marks that would tend to cause
        someone to make a reasonable connection of the reference with the MeeGo mark.</emphasis>
      (...)</para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://nowwhatthe.blogspot.com/2010/12/good-news.html">Jos Poortvliet: good
        news!</ulink></title>
    <para>Hello world, Some good news. </para>
    <para>First of all, the dutch Linux Starter I blogged about a few days ago is now <ulink
        url="http://www.hubstore.nl/informatie.asp?LN=STLIN2010">available online</ulink>. So if
      you're dutch and want to try out openSUSE - go and get it! </para>
    <para>And second of all, the board has just announced that Alan Clark has been appointed by
      Novell as new chair of the board. Most of you probably don't know him, I do as I have been
      working with him for the last few months on the openSUSE Foundation and some other things.
      He's in my humble opinion one of those people who gets Free Software and a pleasure to work
      with. Only after this announcement I discovered he was pretty "high in the tree" as we in NL
      say - being on the Senior Leadership team of Markus, his experience in the Linux Foundation
      and other organizations... But while working with me he had a simple "let's get this done and
      do it well" attitude. Still an engineer on the inside - something you actually see a lot in
      Novell and something I appreciate greatly.</para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://www.wafaa.eu/entry/fed-up-of-fud-against-novell-suse--opensuse-1-47.html">Andrew
        Wafaa: Blogged about: Fed up of FUD against Novell, SUSE</ulink></title>
    <para>tl;dr – To all you doomsday FUD mongers about Novell/SUSE/openSUSE STFU &amp; let us show
      you what we can and will do!! </para>
    <para>For those living under a rock, yes Novell has agreed to be acquired. Welcome to the world
      of business, and especially in software this sort of thing is very common. </para>
    <para>Now for some reason a whole heap of people seem to think that this spells doom for Novell,
      SUSE and openSUSE. Why? I really can't answer that. What I do know is that all their negative
      speculation is at best counter productive, at worst foolish and damaging. </para>
    <para>As with any form of speculation there are no facts to back up what they reckon is going to
      happen – hence the speculation. If there is enough negative talk, negative things will happen.
      Current customers will look at switching from Novell products whether they be SUSE based or
      not, purely based on all the negativity that is being generated. </para>
    <para>No-one is giving Attachemate a chance to prove what they have openly said – Novell, SUSE
      and openSUSE's contribution to the wider community will continue and that it is business as
      usual. If you look at when Oracle bought Sun they said sod all about OpenSolaris and the rest
      of Sun. This is different. The new overlords are actually communicating – maybe not as much as
      we would like, but hey it's a bloody good step in the right direction. </para>
    <para>The latest negative piece comes from the <ulink
        url="http://blogs.the451group.com/opensource/2010/12/08/linux-kernel-solid-but-what-will-become-of-novell-contribution"
        >451 Group</ulink>. Why the frig would Novell's purchase change their kernel contributions?
      Why the frig would Novell's purchase change any of their current contributions to the vast
      array of projects including GNOME/KDE/Banshee/LibreOffice/Systemd and a whole heap of others?
      Simple, it doesn't. </para>
    <para>Don't get me wrong Novell has screwed up big time in the past, but we are working together
      as a community to learn from these mistakes. All this negative noise is counter productive and
      just gets in the way. If you want to see Novell, SUSE and openSUSE flourish hows about you
      roll your sleeves up and get stuck in? If you don't want to chip in STFU and wait and see if
      something does happen. Then you can berate us and tell us how and where we went wrong.</para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/12/15/verein-computerspende-hamburg-and-opensuse/"
        >Klaas Freitag: Verein Computerspende Hamburg and openSUSE</ulink></title>
    <para>This <ulink url="http://www.spiegel.de/netzwelt/netzpolitik/0,1518,706047,00.html"
        >article</ulink> of the German news magazine <ulink url="http://www.spiegel.de/">Der
        Spiegel</ulink> made me aware of the <ulink url="http://www.computerspendehamburg.de/"
        >Verein Computerspende Hamburg</ulink>. A German verein is a non profit association, there
      are lots in Germany for sports, culture and these kind of stuff. </para>
    <para>The Verein Computerspende Hamburg does something very useful: It takes used computer parts
      that other people do not longer need and refurbish them to working computers again. These
      computers are handed to people who happen to be in a difficult situation in life. They have to
      live from Hartz IV which is a kind German social security, following the unemployment benefit
      which ends after a short period. Hartz IV means very, very little money the people have to
      make their lives from, too little to buy a new computer. </para>
    <para>On the other hand, an increasing amount of the job offerings are posted on the web, so
      people currently unemployed basically have to search the web, not speaking about preparing the
      resumes to apply for a job. So how would one do that without a computer? </para>
    <para>Computing is not only hardware and well known operating systems and applications are far
      away from free, so it’s obvious that our great project is a perfect partner here: Not that we
      only offer a user friendly, easy to install, secure, feature rich and last but not least
      completely free <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Distribution">Linux
        Distribution</ulink>, we as a community are also able to help if problems come up,
      regardless if somebody has money or not and what kind of problem it might be. This is another
      very concrete example where free software and the FOSS communities help your neighbor, or you
      – as it is very easy to get into a difficult situation in life. </para>
    <para>We sent 500 openSUSE 11.3 DVDs to Hamburg with our warm invitation and welcome to all new
      users to show up and join our community. So be aware of new kids on the block :-) </para>
    <para>And if you are in Hamburg or around and want to help, I am sure <ulink
        url="http://www.computerspendehamburg.de/">Verein Computerspende</ulink> can make use of the
      help of more Geekos, such as installation, first hand user support and probably much more. And
      if you know of a similar interested initiative, let me know, I am sure I will find more DVDs
      ;-) </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/12/16/10-minutes-of-your-time/">Nelson
        Marques: 10 minutes of YOUR time…</ulink></title>
    <figure id="fig.pirate">
      <title>Be a pirate</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="http://www.openclipart.org/image/800px/svg_to_png/Clue_Calico_Jack_pirate_logo.png" width="15%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>Fellow openSUSE Contributor, I am not as gifted as Mizmo, so I can’t really present some
      cool metaphore in the form of a cartoon… Nevertheless I will try my best.<xref linkend="fig.pirate"/></para>
    <para>During the OSC2010 in Nürnberg I tried without much success to pass on the word that
      Marketing isn’t about a Team, but comes also down to us. This in an awesome time to
      demonstrate that on practice… Right now with an important release on the horizon, your
      Marketing team is starting a process to gather information to promote the features of the next
      release. Speaking for myself, I don’t feel confortable in taking an assingment of gathering
      features for example about the Kernel. As I won’t feel confortable producing contents about
      KDE which I barelly know… Nevertheless if those contents aren’t provided to us…. we have to
      dig for them… sometimes not even having a clue of the extention of their importance. </para>
    <para>Many times I’ve heard the ultimate excuse ‘Marketing is for Ubuntu, because they are just
      Marketing and nothing else’… and things on that line… Well… think again… who’s fault is this
      that only them care about Marketing ? I see a good opportunity for you all to achieve some
      things in the next days… with only 10 minutes of your time… and why could be nice it happened
      this way:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>You run a project that is on Factory… cool… Please take 10 minutes, make a small
            list of 10 features that are really cool on the next release… make a 7/15 lines text on
            how your project changed and the benefit of the improvements for our users (if you don’t
            know your users, then write it as if you were talking about yourself)… This way you save
            your Marketing Team ‘wild goose chase’ on a stack of Changelogs we might not understand…
            even worst, we might even pass on the wrong stuff….</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>By doing this… you are doing Marketing… you are promoting your own project within
            openSUSE, giving it more visibility and with 10 mins of your time… you will pass on the
            right word to the Marketing Team and help them. Instead of spending 50 hours searching
            for stuff and taking some hard decisions that might not work out in the best way for
            YOUR project, we have 50 mins more to work your information and make sure it is better
            used for the interests of YOUR project.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para> If Marketing takes 3 features to write an article or make Marketing materials… and
            just lists the other 7… If like at least we get contributions in this form from: Kernel,
            GNOME, KDE and Ambassadors (yes, people should also be on the release)… thats 3×4 = 12
            featured articles for the release and a feature list of 40 new exciting
            features….</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>Now… does this seem so surreal to ask 10 minutes of your time to help out your
      Marketing Team and make the best release ever! Oh! And have a lot of fun! </para>
    <para>Someone said that I was crazy… and that projects and developers would never comply and
      would most likely laugh on my face after proposing such thing… I might be crazy… or I might
      very well on the wrong track. I’ve decided not to back down from facing the ‘mob’, and still
      risking to be laughed upon, I brought this to your attention.</para>
    <para>Become a openSUSE Pirate ? <ulink url="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JiPnuuE60r8"
        >You-are-a-pirate</ulink> Youtube Video.</para>
  </blockquote>
  <!-- ($ ld: 17.12.10 sm $) -->
</sect1>
