<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://dominique.leuenberger.net/blog/?p=149">Dominique Leuenberger: VLC /
        openSUSE 11.0 repository to be removed</ulink>
    </title>
    <note>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is licensed under the <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">Creatice Commons
        Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License</ulink></emphasis>.</para>
    </note>
    <para>openSUSE 11.0 has been End-Of_life for a good while already, but the VLC Repository kept
      on being available for the users still relying on it. There have not been any updates and
      rebuilds for a long time (maintaining new versions became a nightmare, as underlying libraries
      started to be outdated). </para>
    <para>For this reason I’m hereby announcing that the 11.0 repositories will be removed from the
      videolan download infrastructure by <emphasis role="bold">March 1st 2011</emphasis> ! If you
      rely on having the packages available for your personal installations, please make sure to
      create a local copy of the FTP tree. </para>
    <para>On the bright side though: the 11.4 repository has just been uploaded. It is built against
      the latest snapshot of 11.4, which is somewhat between RC1 and RC2. Most likely not much is
      changing that would affect stability of the VLC packages. And like always of course: Factory
      package keep on existing. But they did for a long time already.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 20.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://log.or.cz/?p=119">Petr Baudis: Arduino Software Tone
      Generator</ulink></title>
    <note>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is licensed under the <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">Creatice Commons
          Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License</ulink></emphasis>.</para>
    </note>
    <para>This is something really trivial, but I have not actually googled out a recipe so I
      thought I’d post it anyway for the googlers out there. Sometimes, you discover the Arduino
      tune() function does not really work – in our case, it was since we have ethernet shield
      attached and apparently, some other piece of the software drives the timer (not surprising at
      all) – besides, the tune() function may silently abuse other pins than the chosen one, AIUI,
      due to its timer usage.</para>
    <para>Therefore, it may be useful to manually generate sounds. The code snippet really is
      simple, with play-by-melody code thrown in for good measure
      too:<screen>#include "pitches.h"
 
/* Cue Star Wars - Darth Vader theme, opening notes! */
int melody_nak[] = { NOTE_G5, NOTE_G5, NOTE_G5, NOTE_DS5, NOTE_AS5, NOTE_G5, NOTE_DS5, NOTE_AS5, NOTE_G5};
int noteDurations_nak[] = { 330, 330, 330, 250, 120, 330, 250, 120, 500 };
 
int melody_ack[] = { NOTE_D6, NOTE_A6, NOTE_C7, NOTE_A6 };
int noteDurations_ack[] = { 120, 500, 120, 500 };
 
void toneManual(int pin, int frequency, int duration)
{
  unsigned long period = 1000000/frequency;
  unsigned long length;
  boolean state = false;
  for (length = 0; length &lt; (long) duration * 1000; length += period) {
    state = !state;
    digitalWrite(pin, state);
    /* The 50uS correspond to the time the rest of the loop body takes.
     * It seems about right, but has not been tuned precisely for
     * a 16MHz ATMega. */
    delayMicroseconds(period - 50);
  }
}
 
void playMelody(int *melody, int *noteDurations, int notes)
{
  int i;
  for (i = 0; i &lt; notes; i++) {
    toneManual(8, melody[i], noteDurations[i]);
    delay(noteDurations[i] * 6/10);
  }
}
 
void playMelodyAck()
{ playMelody(melody_ack, noteDurations_ack, sizeof(melody_ack)/sizeof(melody_ack[0])); }
void playMelodyNak()
{ playMelody(melody_nak, noteDurations_nak, sizeof(melody_nak)/sizeof(melody_nak[0])); }</screen></para>
    <para>Grab pitches.h from the digital -> tone generator example sketches, i.e. <emphasis
        role="italic">/usr/share/arduino*/examples/2.Digital/toneMelody/pitches.h</emphasis>. </para>
    <para>There is one important point. With tone(), you did not need to correctly set pin mode of
      the pin to output – you <emphasis role="bold">do need to do that</emphasis> with this routine!
      This took me quite a while to debug…</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 20.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://ungethym.blogspot.com/2011/02/gsoc-mentors-wanted-elegant-display.html">Thomas
        Thym: GSoC: Mentors wanted! - Elegant display settings for presentations</ulink></title>
    <note><para>ATM no License set</para></note>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-gyZKgILFwj4/TWDqR2A4SuI/AAAAAAAAAC0/cvVPRXHTlP8/s1600/computer-laptop_and_video-projector.png"
          width="20%"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>I recently mentored some students during the Google Code In project. Now the <ulink
        url="http://linuxgrandma.blogspot.com/2011/02/gsoc-2011-start-your-engines.html"
        >preparations for Google Summer of Code have begun</ulink>. Unfortunately I am not a hacker,
      I am a promo guy and I can't mentor here. Nevertheless I have some <ulink
        url="http://community.kde.org/GSoC/2011/Ideas">ideas for GSoC</ulink> and I hope to scratch
      somebodies itch so she or he will mentor that idea. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Idea 1: (More elegant) Display settings for presentations
      </emphasis></para>
    <para>Application/component: Plasma </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Brief explanation:</emphasis> The handling of multiple screens has
      continuously improved during the last releases. The handling of a stationary setting of two
      screens seems to be rather good. When it comes to presentation-mode with a projector I would
      be delighted to see even more elegance (simplicity).</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Expected results:</emphasis> When doing presentations there is in
      general only one question to decide. The presentation mode:<orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>The same picture of both screens or </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>The notes on the notebook, the presentation on the projector. </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist></para>
    <para>To 1: Autodetect the smallest max. resolution of the two displays. Instead of scaling the
      picture to full screen it would be nicer to keep the ration and leave some space blank on the
      left and right notebook screen. </para>
    <para>To 2: Autodetect the max. resolution of each of the two displays and set those different
      resolutions. The panel, all the widgets and all the open windows should stay on the notebook
      screen. The projector screen shows only the wallpaper. It does not matter if the projector
      “screen” is located above or on the right or wherever of the notebook screen. </para>
    <para>It would be very useful to link that dialog to the keyboard shortcut (e.g. Fn+F7) or to
      start it automatically when a projector is attached. (At the moment I have to start krandrtray
      from krunner first or have the symbol in the taskbar all the time. I am not sure if a new
      users could work that out in a couple of seconds.) </para>
    <para>Save the display/plasma settings (esp. widget positions etc.) to restore them when the
      projector is detached. (Perhaps that could be solved with activities.) </para>
    <para>Extra points: It is possible to save the standard settings. In a second step different
      screen setting profiles could be saved and loaded (like in powerdevil). Presentation-mode 1
      and 2 could be such profiles and a user could modify them (e.g. projector on top or right) if
      it is necessary. </para>
    <para>So what do you think. Is that scratching your itch? Can you imagine how cool this would be
      to have? At least for me as a presenter that would really rock.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 21.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://dev-loki.blogspot.com/2011/02/packman-service-interruption-and.html"
        >Pascal Bleser: Packman service interruption and migration</ulink></title>
    <note><para>ATM no License set.</para></note>
    <para>The <ulink url="http://packman.links2linux.org/">Packman</ulink> website and <ulink
        url="http://packman.inode.at/suse/">repositories</ulink> are going to be broken and in the
      works for several days (possibly up to a week) starting tonight at 20:00 CET, during which the
      following services will not be available, or only sporadically: <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>the Packman website itself: <ulink url="http://packman.links2linux.org/"
              >http://packman.links2linux.org</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>the Packman repositories, except "Essentials" (see "new repository layout"
            below)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>The reason is that we are performing a major migration of our services to <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>the latest version of the openSUSE Build Service (we were still using an old
            version)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>a new layout of our repositories, to enable a more fine-grained control over what
            parts of Packman should be used (see below)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>In order to try to keep a minimum service going during that time, you may use and point
      people to our new repositories, that already contain the "Essentials" part, which are almost
      complete with the bare minimum everyone needs (mplayer, vlc, libraries, ...). The URLs for the
      new repositories are as follows: <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://packman.inode.at/suse/openSUSE_11.3/"
              >http://packman.inode.at/suse/openSUSE_11.3/</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://packman.inode.at/suse/openSUSE_11.2/"
              >http://packman.inode.at/suse/openSUSE_11.2/</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://packman.inode.at/suse/Factory/"
              >http://packman.inode.at/suse/Factory/</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://packman.inode.at/suse/SLE_11/"
              >http://packman.inode.at/suse/SLE_11/</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>There are no .repo files there yet, so adding one of these is done as
      follows:<screen>zypper ar -n packman http://packman.inode.at/suse/openSUSE_11.3/ packman</screen></para>
    <para>(obviously adapt the URL to your openSUSE version). You may also use one of our mirror
      sites, as they already have our new repositories: <ulink
        url="ftp://packman.links2linux.de/pub/packman/MIRRORS"
        >ftp://packman.links2linux.de/pub/packman/MIRRORS.</ulink></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">New repository layout</emphasis></para>
    <para>As has been announced (including here), we have had a discussion back in December about
      whether and how we should reorganize the layout of our repositories. Up to now, and for many
      years, it has always been "one big repository", which had pros and cons: <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="underline">good</emphasis>: easy to use, just add onr repository and
            be done with it</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="underline">good</emphasis>: easy for us to manage</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="underline">bad</emphasis>: you get everything and the kitchen sink,
            including packages that are duplications of stuff from other repositories, specifically
            from build.opensuse.org (which didn't exist when Packman was created), and potential
            conflicts with those</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="underline">bad</emphasis>: large metadata files to synchronise
            (although zypper has become pretty fast at that)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>We came up with a solution to this, as more and more people requested having split
      repositories, in order to control whatthey want to use from Packman: <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>we will have four repositories instead of one: Essentials, Multimedia, Games and
            Extras</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Essentials will be the bare minimum to get your multimedia experience on openSUSE
            going (libraries, MPlayer, vlc, ffmpeg, ...)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Multimedia will contain additional applications that are not available for openSUSE
            or only in a crippled build, such as avidemux, etc...</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Games are, well, games, although we will try to move most of what may be hosted on
            build.opensuse.org to the games project there</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Extras is all the rest</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>In order to provide the best of both worlds or, rather, still provide you with the old
      option of adding everything, we are using a little trick and are running "createrepo" on the
      top-level directory, which results in having repository metadata that contains all the
      packages from all the above mentioned repositories without having to duplicate the RPM files
      on our server (and mirrors). </para>
    <para>Hence, to make it short and less technical, you can still also use the "old way"
      too.</para>
    <para>As an example of what needs to be added to zypper, once the migration is complete and
      .repo files are available too: <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>add the Essentials
            repository:<screen>zypper ar -r http://packman.inode.at/suse/openSUSE_11.3/Essentials/Essentials.repo</screen></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>add the "everything"
            repository:<screen>zypper ar -r http://packman.inode.at/suse/openSUSE_11.3/packman.repo</screen></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>I will announce our progress <ulink url="http://dev-loki.blogspot.com/">on my blog</ulink>
      (which is also aggregated on <ulink url="http://planet.opensuse.org/">Planet openSUSE</ulink>)
      and will obviously post another announcement here once our migration is complete. </para>
    <para>In advance, sorry for the inconvenience, and thank you for your understanding. We are
      convinced that our move will not only provide us with a better infrastructure, but also
      improve your experience with Packman and openSUSE.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 21.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="https://saschpe.wordpress.com/2011/02/21/summer-of-code-approaches/">Sascha
        Peilicke: Summer of Code approaches</ulink></title>
    <note><para>ATM no License set.</para></note>
    <para>As in the past years, <ulink url="http://code.google.com/soc/">Google’s Summer of
        Code</ulink> is going to happen again and we’re currently collecting ideas for <ulink
        url="http://www.opensuse.org/en/">openSUSE</ulink>. So if you want to support your favorite
      distribution or seek a way to getting involved more deeply, be sure to check out our <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:GSOC_2011">GSoC info page</ulink>. </para>
    <para>Or, if you want it cross-distro, the awesome <ulink
        url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OpenSUSE_Build_Service">Build Service</ulink> always needs
      some helping hands that are curious on how to expand it’s massive feature set :-) . This
      includes adding support for currently unsupported distros like <ulink
        url="http://www.archlinux.org/">Arch Linux</ulink> or <ulink
        url="http://www.pardus.org.tr/eng/">Pardus</ulink> as well as making it’s web user interface
      more social. </para>
    <para>Feel free to add you ideas to <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:GSOC_2011_Ideas"
        >our list</ulink> and discuss them on our IRC channel (#opensuse-project on FreeNode). </para>
    <!--($ ld: 22.2.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://ungethym.blogspot.com/2011/02/gsoc-idea-2-improved-more-elegant.html"
        >Thomas Thym: GSoC idea 2: Improved (more elegant) keygeneration in
      KMail/Kleopatra</ulink></title>
    <note><para>ATM no License set.</para></note>
    <para>As I mentioned in my <ulink
        url="http://ungethym.blogspot.com/2011/02/gsoc-mentors-wanted-elegant-display.html">previous
        post</ulink> I can't mentor GSoC students myself and therefore are looking for a developer
      to jump in for me. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">GSoC idea 2: Improved (more elegant) keygeneration in
        KMail/Kleopatra </emphasis></para>
    <para>Application/component: <emphasis role="italic">KDEPIM/KMail and
      Kleopatra</emphasis></para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-cf3L8CKxspY/TWFKcHk9iYI/AAAAAAAAAC4/1leB6C1GIEY/s1600/kmail2-kleopatra.png"
          width="20%"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Brief explanation: </emphasis></para>
    <para>Signing and encrypting emails is very old, however only a minority is using it. One reason
      might be, that it is not easy enough for regular users to use it. The importance for private
      and business users is still high. Private companies started to sell proprietary, secure e-mail
      services (e.g. in Germany DE-Mail and e-brief). There are good key creation, signing and other
      key management functions present in KDE software. The goal of this proposal is to make it easy
      and fast to work with signed and encrypted emails.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Expected results:</emphasis><orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Analyze and optimize the key creation, signing etc processes,
              make it dumb easy to create and use a key/signature</emphasis>. One way could be to
            add a button “Generate Key” (next to “Change”) in the KMail – Identity settings –
            Cryptographie; start the key creation wizard from Kleopatra and take the name and email
            address from that identity (at the moment you have to enter them manually). The user
            just has to enter the passphrase and is done. Offer a button “Save private key and
            revoke key on usb” or something like this and “send public key to server” / “Make key
            public”. Add the key creation (or import possibilities) into the identity / account
            creation wizard of KMail. Add the possibility to create revoke keys within the gui (when
            sending the key to the server, there is an information message yet.) </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Guide the user through the whole process of signing and
              encrypting/decrypting emails.</emphasis> Offer possibilities to learn about the topic
            in an easy and fast way (offline help, online help / wiki, videos, tutorials etc). Show
            how they use the keys, how they get their keys signed, how they sign other keys etc.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Integrate other free/open services</emphasis> like CAcert.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist></para>
    <para>These are just some ideas. If there is someone interested I could go more into details if
      necessary.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 22.2.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/02/22/10-good-reasons-for-upgrading-to-opensuse-11-4/"
        >Nelson Marques: 10 good reasons for upgrading to openSUSE 11.4</ulink></title>
    <para>
      <note>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is licensed under the GNU Free Documentation
            License.</emphasis></para>
      </note>
    </para>
    <para>DISCLAIMER: Based on personal preferences, and deeply personal. Other people might have
      different views, this is mine<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Artwork</emphasis> – openSUSE 11.4 ships with ‘Stripes’
            artwork. I love specially the console terminal which offers very good contrast. The boot
            splash images are visually attractive and provide a pleasant boot experience.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Wine</emphasis> – openSUSE 11.4 ships with Wine 1.3.10 which
            works very good for me. I’ve tried Lord of the Rings Online (flawlessly out of the box)
            and World of Warcraft. From the tested products, I feel that openSUSE promotion needs a
            bit more of effort on highlighting Wine. Marcus must be proud, and I’m for sure thankful
            for his great work!</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Repository Management </emphasis>– One of the main reason why
            I love openSUSE is because it works like “Lego”. You can keep adding/removing software
            repositories and have a hell of a kick ass experience. Success on this tasks require
            some brains, but an expert tinker can perform great things with openSUSE
            repositories!</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">“Out of the Box” Factor</emphasis> – It just works… even with
            my problematic ATI. This is one important point for me. I don’t really like to install a
            Linux distribution and spend hours tinkering it for my needs. With openSUSE it’s done
            fast and clean.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Default Software Patterns</emphasis> – The default software
            patterns on openSUSE are awesome and they fulfill all the needs for my daily computing
            tasks.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Security and Stability</emphasis> – Without doubt the calling
            card from openSUSE. There’s isn’t really much to say, except it inspires trust!</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">YaST Installer</emphasis> – Not being a technical person, I
            have to remove my hat before openSUSE installer. It ‘speaks’ normal user language, it
            provides outstanding features for advanced and starters. It inspires total supremacy of
            man over machine!</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Featured upstream Projects</emphasis> – The most known
            upstream projects are present! GNOME, KDE, LXDE and friends, even IceWM made his way
            into 11.4. Banshee, VLC, you name it… Everything can run on openSUSE, even community
            repos such as GNOME:Ayatana! Whatever software you are looking for, it’s for sure in a
            openSUSE repository!</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">GNOME</emphasis> – Does it need an introduction? NO! It’s
            mature, stable, rock solid and will provide a powerful Desktop experience for any user!
            OpenSUSE 11.4 is a must for people who want to hang around with GNOME2 for a bit more,
            and for all the GNOME3 fans through an additional repository. GNOME3 is something you
            can’t miss! openSUSE 11.4 will enable you that feature later on!</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Community</emphasis> – A strong and helpful community in which
            our users can rely. Swift on bug fixing, helpful when one is in trouble and commited to
            bring our users the best Linux experience possible. It’s all about faces and human
            interaction, it’s all about being human in charge of the machine! And most of us will
            speak your language!</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <!--($ ld: 23.2.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://ungethym.blogspot.com/2011/02/gsoc-idea-3-store-annotations-within.html">Thomas
        Thym: GSoC idea 3: Store annotations within PDF</ulink></title>
    <note><para>ATM no License set.</para></note>
    <para>As I mentioned in my <ulink
        url="http://ungethym.blogspot.com/2011/02/gsoc-mentors-wanted-elegant-display.html">previous
        post</ulink> I can't mentor GSoC students myself and therefore are looking for a developer
      to jump in for me. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">GSoC idea 3: Store annotations in PDF file </emphasis></para>
    <para>Application/component: Okular/Poppler </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Brief explanation</emphasis>: It is possible to store annotations
      with Okular. They are saved in separat files. One of the most wanted bugs is <ulink
        url="https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=151614">151614</ulink> (123 comments, 739 votes).
      It would be awsome to have that feature in our wonderful Okular. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Expected results</emphasis>:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Store annotations in the PDF file.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>If that is not enough apped support to modify the PDF (insert, delete pages
            etc.)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>In my next life I will become a developer and the I could mentor that project myself.
      Until this happens I am really hoping someone else steps up.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 23.2.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://blog.karlitschek.de/2011/02/owncloud-update.html">online communities
        and free desktops /Frank Karlitscheck: ownCloud update</ulink>
    </title>
    <note>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is licensed under the <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">Creatice Commons
        Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License</ulink></emphasis>.</para>
    </note>
    <para><note>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is licensed under the Creatice Commons
            Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License</emphasis>.</para>
      </note>A lot of cool stuff is happening around ownCloud at the moment. François is working on
      a super cool new webinterface. It looks really nice.<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Login: <ulink url="Login: http://www.kubler.org/owncloud-mockups/login.html"
              >http://www.kubler.org/owncloud-mockups/login.html</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Files : <ulink url="http://www.kubler.org/owncloud-mockups/"
              >http://www.kubler.org/owncloud-mockups/</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Logs : <ulink url="http://www.kubler.org/owncloud-mockups/logs.html"
              >http://www.kubler.org/owncloud-mockups/logs.html</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>User settings : <ulink
              url="http://www.kubler.org/owncloud-mockups/user_settings.html"
              >http://www.kubler.org/owncloud-mockups/user_settings.html</ulink>
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>We have a cool new audioplayer so people have easy access to their media from all their
      devices. This works with Amarok or just your browser. Several people are working on a syncing
      client for KDE. Is important to have offlice access to your files. This is super cool. I´m
      totaly amazed by the speed we are moving forward. </para>
    <para>Another cool thing is that we have a first provider to offer hosted ownCloud services if
      you don´t have webspace to host it yourself. PackageCloud offers a free ownCloud installation
      for 100MB and an installation with unlimited storage and traffic for 5,- EUR per month. I
      think this is a very nice offer. Completely free software and more affordable than other cloud
      solutions. Try it here if you don´t have your own server. <ulink
        url="https://www.packagecloud.com/?au=owncloud">https://www.packagecloud.com/?au=owncloud
      </ulink></para>
    <para>We will participate in this years Google Summer of code again. So if you have ideas add
      them to the brainstorming page here: <ulink
        url="http://community.kde.org/GSoC/2011/Ideas#ownCloud"
        >http://community.kde.org/GSoC/2011/Ideas#ownCloud</ulink>
    </para>
    <para>We are also planing the first ownCloud developer meeting. It will take place between 15.
      and 18. of April in Stuttgart, Germany. <ulink
        url="http://community.kde.org/Sprints/ownCloud2011"
        >http://community.kde.org/Sprints/ownCloud2011</ulink> We will hack on ownCloud and plan the
      next releases. </para>
    <para>Please send me an email if you want to join the meeting and help working on ownCloud.
      Cheers Frank</para>
    <!--($ ld: 23.2.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://michal.hrusecky.net/2011/02/gsoc-2011-ideas-sax-3/">Michal Hrusecky:
        GSoC 2011 ideas – SaX 3</ulink></title>
    <note><para>This Article is licensed under the <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/">Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported</ulink>
    </para></note>
    <para>You must already heard about this from everybody. Google Summer of Code 2011 is nearby and
      openSUSE wants to participate. Currently we are collecting ideas and mentors and we are going
      to apply. I also came up with few projects and volunteered to mentor them. I saw Thomas Thym
      introducing his GSoC ideas and I think it’s great to write a blog posts that introduce
      projects. So I’ll join and here comes the first project that many of you were waiting for –
      SaX 3.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">SaX 3</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>I guess I don’t have to explain what was SaX 2 good for. It is one of the most voted
      features in openFATE – bring SaX back to live. SaX 2 was the tool to configure X server.
      Whenever your X didn’t behave correctly, whenever you needed to tweak any settings, SaX 2 was
      there for you. Unfortunately it worked only with xorg.conf file. Nowadays X are much better.
      We’ve got auto detection of everything which works most of the time. Some little tweaks can be
      added to /etc/X11/xorg.conf.d directory and every tweak can be in separate file. It’s much
      better than before, easier to take care of, easier to understand and maintain. But as already
      mentioned, SaX2 can’t handle current situation. That is why I propose creating SaX 3 as a part
      of GSoC.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Features</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>Main feature is that it should be able to configure X. That means to force them to use
      different mode that your monitor claims to support, force it to use different graphic card
      driver or change default resolution. Also some little tweaks like per mouse drivers with
      specific settings (I have pretty different settings for my trackpoint than for my external
      mouse) or default keyboard layout. I guess we all expect this basic functionality from SaX. </para>
    <para>From coding point of view, we need to keep it as small as possible. As it will be one of
      the basic administration tool, we don’t want it to pull in several frameworks just to
      configure X. And if I can’t get X working I still want to use this tool. So that makes it
      obvious that ncurses UI is a must. On the other hand, once I have X running, I don’t want to
      see any ugly ncurses anymore, but nice Qt/GTK. So it should also support at least some toolkit
      for nice and shiny X window UI. But as this might pull in some dependencies and pulling Qt to
      your minimalistic PekWM desktop might sound terrifying, it should be optional and SaX should
      be able to detect whether it is installed and X are running so it can use it or not. </para>
    <para>One feature that is also a little bit important is to make it distribution independent to
      make it easy for other distributions to use it, improve it and contribute back, so we will
      make a world better place for all of us ;-)</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Student? </emphasis></para>
    <para>I wrote it on the wiki and yesterday I already received an e-mail from interested student,
      who is considering it! So if openSUSE and SaX3 get selected, there is a pretty good chance
      that we will have it!</para>
    <!--($ ld: 25.2.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://dev-loki.blogspot.com/2011/02/packman-removing-111.html">Pascal
        Bleser: Packman: removing 11.1</ulink></title>
    <note><para>ATM no License set.</para></note>
    <para><ulink url="http://packman.links2linux.org">We</ulink>'re going to remove the <ulink
        url="http://www.opensuse.org">openSUSE</ulink> 11.1 <ulink
        url="http://packman.links2linux.org">Packman</ulink> repositories from our primary server
      and, hence, also our <ulink url="http://packman.links2linux.de/MIRRORS.html">mirrors</ulink>. </para>
    <para>If you would like to keep a copy (for whatever reason, as they're unmaintained), make sure
      to pull the tree <emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="underline">before
        Monday</emphasis></emphasis> (2011-02-28). </para>
    <para>The reason, obviously, is that <ulink
        url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-security-announce/2011-01/msg00005.html">openSUSE
        11.1 has gone End-Of-Life since mid-January</ulink>, and as we're <ulink
        url="http://dev-loki.blogspot.com/2011/02/packman-service-interruption-and.html"
        >restructuring our repositories</ulink>, we do need quite some extra space right now and
      don't want to put too much of a burden on our <ulink
        url="http://packman.links2linux.de/MIRRORS.html">mirrors</ulink> (there are a few <ulink
        url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rsync">rsync</ulink> mirrors in there too).</para>
    <!--($ ld: 25.2.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://log.or.cz/?p=122">Petr Baudis: KMS vs Radeon 7000</ulink>
    </title>
    <note>
      <para><citation role="bold">This Article is licensed under the Creatice Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License</citation></para>
    </note>
    <para>Just a quick note for those googlers out there again. My sister has my old and trusty
      Radeon 7000 (RV100) GPU in her machine and after distro upgrade, we had trouble getting it
      working with respectable performance; DRI etc. was all fine after the usual installation
      round of firmware-linux, but heavy 2D blipping work (e.g. moving windows, OpenTTD,
      darkening/lightening whole screen in various applications) was taking awful amounts of CPU
      within Xorg and things were really choppy. </para>
    <para>It seems that there are some bugs lurking within the KMS; <emphasis role="italic">radeon.modeset=0</emphasis> on the kernel commandline has a good shot at curing things
      like this!</para>
    <!--($ ld: 21.2.11 sm $) -->      </blockquote>
</sect1>
