<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="tipsandtricks">
  <title>Tips and Tricks</title>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Desktop Users</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.linux.com/learn/tutorials/459107-weekend-project-use-rapid-photo-downloader-for-photo-management"
          > Linux.com/Nathan Willis: Weekend Project: Use Rapid Photo Downloader for Photo
          Management </ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Often the most impressive thing about the open source community is getting to watch
        someone step up to work on a task that's far from fun or glamorous in the traditional sense.
        A good example of that phenomenon is Damon Lynch's <ulink
          url="http://www.damonlynch.net/rapid/index.html">Rapid Photo Downloader</ulink> (RPD), a
        utility that takes the pain out of what many projects overlook: getting your newly shot
        material off of the camera's memory card and into your computer. Despite the name, RPD
        handles both photos and video, and although its speed <emphasis role="italic">is</emphasis>
        impressive, how it really makes your life easier is by keeping you and your storage
        organized. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 19.6.11 sm $)-->    
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxjournal.com/content/tweaking-text-scribus">LinuxJournal/Bruce Byfield: Tweaking text in Scribus</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>In word processors, users generally settle for an appearance that is good enough. By
        contrast, in a design application like Scribus, you have the tools to adjust the layout
        until it is exactly the way you want.</para>
      <para>That is especially true for text. Scribus not only provides tools for general management
        of the available fonts, but also for micro-managing everything from the size and shape of
        fonts to the spaces between characters and words and how a word is hyphenated at the end of
        a line. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 16.6.11 sm $)-->    
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/16/opensuse-and-online-services/">Jos
          Poortvliet: openSUSE and online services</ulink></title>
    <para>The ‘cloud’ has been a buzzword for quite a while. While some are still rather cynical
      towards the concept, products like mobile phones with Android have shown the value of putting
      your data in that huge, amorphous network of servers somewhere. Apple recently introduced
      their new cloud service and Microsoft has their cloud too. So with the other major players
      talking cloudy, what does Linux have?</para>
    <para><inlinegraphic fileref="http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1165/644335254_4b8a712be5_m.jpg"
        align="right"/></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Variety</emphasis></para>
    <para>Let’s define Cloud technology as ‘related to putting data online &amp; sharing among
      devices’ which is a reasonable definition for our purposes. There is a huge number of
      technologies connecting openSUSE users to online services. However there is a distinction to
      be made between commercial or proprietary operating systems and ours. We don’t create a vendor
      lock-in scenario because we focus on tools that freely connect you to your choice of publicly
      available services. This is a key distinction because we’re not owning or controlling the
      cloud that you place your data in. You, the user, get to decide the place where it best fits
      your needs and comfort level. Today and tomorrow we will highlight some of them here, starting
      with integration in our every day applications.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Integration with online services</emphasis></para>
    <para>openSUSE brings online services like <ulink url="http://facebook.com">Facebook</ulink>,
        <ulink url="http://flickr.com">Flickr</ulink> and <ulink url="http://youtube.com"
        >Youtube</ulink> to your desktop in a variety of applications. New applications like <ulink
        url="http://www.umplayer.com/">UMPlayer</ulink> and <ulink url="http://tomahawk-player.org/"
        >Tomahawk</ulink> go out of their way to deeply integrate <ulink url="http://twitter.com"
        >twitter</ulink> or <ulink url="http://last.fm">last.fm</ulink>, with Tomahawk even able to
      play music over a jabber (google-talk) chat connection. Of course, old-timers like <ulink
        url="http://banshee.fm/">Banshee</ulink> and Amarok also feature music from music stores,
      pod casts and other on-line services.</para>
      <para>
        <table frame="all">
          <title>Install Tomahawk</title>
          <tgroup cols="2">
            <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.02*"/>
            <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry>
                <ulink
                  url="http://software.opensuse.org/ymp/home:pansenmann:tomahawk-player/openSUSE_11.4/tomahawk.ymp">
                  <inlinemediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                      <imagedata fileref="http://files.opensuse.org/opensuse/en/f/f1/Oneclick.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                  </inlinemediaobject>
                </ulink>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">openSUSE 11.4</emphasis></para></entry>
                <entry>
                <ulink
                  url="http://software.opensuse.org/ymp/home:pansenmann:tomahawk-player/openSUSE_11.3/tomahawk.ymp">
                  <inlinemediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                      <imagedata fileref="http://files.opensuse.org/opensuse/en/f/f1/Oneclick.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                  </inlinemediaobject></ulink>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">openSUSE 11.3</emphasis></para></entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table>
      </para>
    <para>
      <table frame="all">
        <title>Install UMPlayer</title>
        <tgroup cols="2">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
          <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <ulink url="http://software.opensuse.org/ymp/home:stecue/openSUSE_11.4/umplayer.ymp">
                  <inlinemediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                      <imagedata fileref="http://files.opensuse.org/opensuse/en/f/f1/Oneclick.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                  </inlinemediaobject>
                </ulink>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">openSUSE 11.4</emphasis></para></entry>
              <entry>
                <ulink url="http://software.opensuse.org/ymp/home:stecue/openSUSE_11.3/umplayer.ymp">
                  <inlinemediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                      <imagedata fileref="http://files.opensuse.org/opensuse/en/f/f1/Oneclick.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                  </inlinemediaobject>
                </ulink>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">openSUSE 11.3</emphasis></para></entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
    </para>
    <para>Image viewers have engaged online services for a while. <ulink
        url="http://f-spot.org/Features">F-Spot</ulink> can export to <ulink
        url="http://www.flickr.com/">Flickr</ulink>, <ulink url="http://www.23hq.com/">23</ulink>,
        <ulink url="http://picasaweb.google.com/">Picasa Web</ulink> or <ulink
        url="http://www.smugmug.com/">SmugMug</ulink>. <ulink url="http://yorba.org/shotwell/"
        >Shotwell</ulink> can even export to Youtube. KDE applications <ulink
        url="http://www.digikam.org/drupal/about/features9x">Digikam</ulink> and it’s companion
      Showfoto add <ulink url="http://facebook.com">Facebook</ulink>, <ulink
        url="http://piwigo.org/">piwigo</ulink>, <ulink url="http://www.shwup.com/">shwup</ulink>,
        <ulink url="http://www.zooomr.com/">zooomr</ulink> and some other sites to the list. They
      can also export to a HTML gallery and put the images with the locations they were taken at on
      Google Maps. This is shared KDE infrastructure so you can expect image viewer <ulink
        url="http://gwenview.sourceforge.net/">Gwenview</ulink> and even screenshot application
        <ulink url="http://www.elpauer.org/?p=509">ksnapshot</ulink> to be able to directly share
      over these services.</para>
    <para>It’s not just media tools which integrate with online services. <ulink
        url="http://www.libreoffice.org/">LibreOffice</ulink> can export and import documents from
      online office suites like <ulink url="http://docs.google.com">Google Docs</ulink> and <ulink
        url="http://zoho.com">Zoho</ulink>. And of course, mail/agenda/news clients like <ulink
        url="http://projects.gnome.org/evolution">Evolution</ulink> and <ulink
        url="http://pim.kde.org">KDE PIM</ulink> have offered integration with online services like
      mail or calendaring forever. Feed readers like <ulink url="http://liferea.sourceforge.net/"
        >Liferea</ulink> offer syncing your news feed with <ulink url="http://www.google.com/reader"
        >Google Reader</ulink> and <ulink url="http://tt-rss.org/">TinyTinyRSS</ulink>.</para>
    <para>Besides integrating with existing services, Free Software projects are starting their own.
      Prominent examples are GNOME’s <ulink url="http://projects.gnome.org/tomboy/">Tomboy</ulink>
      which synchronizes your notes between instances using an online service.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">More</emphasis></para>
    <para>But there is more available for openSUSE. There are several file sharing and syncing
      services out there. Look for an article about those tomorrow!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GFDL 1.2</ulink></para>
    <!--($ ld: 16.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/17/opensuse-and-your-own-cloud/">Jos
          Poortvliet: openSUSE and online storage and syncing</ulink></title>
    <para>The ‘cloud’ has been a buzzword for quite a while. While some are still rather cynical
      towards the concept, products like <ulink url="http://www.android.com/">mobile phones with
        Android</ulink> have shown the value of putting your data in that <ulink
        url="http://xkcd.com/908/">huge, amorphous network of servers somewhere</ulink>. Apple
      recently <ulink url="http://www.apple.com/icloud/">introduced their new cloud service</ulink>
      and Microsoft has their <ulink url="http://www.microsoft.com/cloud">cloud</ulink> too. So with
      the other major players talking cloudy, what does Linux have?</para>
    <para><inlinegraphic fileref="http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1165/644335254_4b8a712be5_m.jpg"
      /></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Variety</emphasis></para>
    <para>Let’s define Cloud technology as ‘related to putting data online &amp; sharing among
      devices’ which is a reasonable definition for our purposes. There is a huge number of
      technologies connecting openSUSE users to online services. However there is a distinction to
      be made between commercial or proprietary operating systems and ours. We don’t create a vendor
      lock-in scenario because we focus on tools that freely connect you to your choice of publicly
      available services. This is a key distinction because we’re not owning or controlling the
      cloud that you place your data in. You, the user, get to decide the place where it best fits
      your needs and comfort level. Yesterday we <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/16/opensuse-and-online-services/">highlighted
        integration in our every day applications</ulink>. Today we focus on file syncing services
      and especially the cool Free Software project ownCloud!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">File sharing and syncing services</emphasis></para>
    <para>A file sharing and syncing service helps you keep the files on several computers in sync
      and allows you to share such files with others on the web. This is indeed what Apple recently
      introduced, but others have gone before.</para>
    <para><ulink url="https://spideroak.com/">SpiderOak</ulink> offers such an online space for
      synchronizing files. Just drop the files in a specific folder on your drive and you can share
      them between your computers, mobile devices and even with other people. SpiderOak is included
      in the openSUSE repositories since openSUSE 11.3.</para>
    <para>The popular <ulink url="http://dropbox.com">Dropbox</ulink> service offers a similar
      online space, and even comes with integration in the <ulink
        url="http://live.gnome.org/Nautilus">Nautilus file manager</ulink>!</para>
    <para>But both services depend on proprietary server components and need a proprietary daemon to
      run on your system. Dropbox also doesn’t encrypt the data on the server, something Spideroak
      at least does. SpiderOak also promised to at some point open source their client software.
      Still, the server side and web interface will remain closed. Luckily there are Free Software
      solutions out there, two of them I’ll talk about here.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Introducing iFolder</emphasis></para>
    <para><inlinegraphic
        fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/iFolder2clean_filmgrain_picture-300x212.png"
      /></para>
    <para><ulink url="http://www.kablink.org/ifolder">iFolder</ulink> is a Free Software file
      storage, backup and sharing solution written in C# and Mono. iFolder comes with a desktop
      client which allows you to manage your iFolders. iFolders can be located on any number of
      servers, each having a number of folders which you can manage independently. Each folder can
      be your own or shared with others and files dropped or modified in them will be synced right
      away. iFolder, like Dropbox and SpiderOak, has clients for Windows, Mac and Linux and new is a
      web interface so you can access your files anywhere and share them with others on-line.</para>
    <para>iFolder does have some powerful capabilities, especially for corporate environments. For
      example, unlike most competing solutions it only transfers modified portions of files instead
      of the whole file, saving you some bandwidth. iFolder also offers integration with LDAP, disk
      quotas, and limits to the number of iFolders each user has. It integrates in the Desktop with
      a Nautilus plugin which allows you to turn any folder into a shared iFolder and iFolder has
      fully encypted file transfer and storage. Finally, a big plus of iFolder is the excellent
      documentation which you can find <ulink url="http://ifolder.com/ifolder/documentation"
        >here</ulink>.</para>
    <para>So unlike Dropbox and SpiderOak, iFolder is fully Free Software and the source is <ulink
        url="http://community.ifolder.com/ssf/a/c/p_name/ss_forum/p_action/1/action/view_permalink/entityType/folderEntry/entryId/4244"
        >hosted on sourceforge</ulink> and can be found <ulink
        url="http://sourceforge.net/projects/ifolder/">here</ulink>. With 9 commits in the last 2
      months it is not a hugely active project and the last release is from November 2009. Still bug
      fixes are being added and lots of improvements were landed in 2010. You can find more
      up-to-date versions by <ulink
        url="http://software.opensuse.org/search?q=ifolder&amp;baseproject=ALL&amp;lang=en"
        >searching on OBS</ulink>. And it should be noted that this <emphasis role="italic"
        >‘old’</emphasis> version of iFolder has been offering all the features of Dropbox and
      SpiderOak, fully open and free, for years!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">introducing ownCloud</emphasis></para>
    <para><inlinegraphic
        fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/owncloud-logo-300x148.png"
        width="20%"/></para>
    <para><ulink url="http://owncloud.org/">ownCloud</ulink> is an exciting and much more active
      project, developing file synchronization technology on a Free Software base. However, ownCloud
      is far more ambitious as you can read in <ulink
        url="http://blog.karlitschek.de/2011/06/yesterday-apple-announced-their-new.html">this
        recent blogpost</ulink> by lead developer Frank Karlitschek. Frank welcomed Apple to the
      Cloud, giving a feature comparision between ownCloud and their cloud offering. He mentioned
      that:</para>
    <blockquote>
      <para>Apple finally [has] features which are essential for people who live in a connected
        world and have more than one device</para>
    </blockquote>
    <para>Furthermore, after having a look at what Apple came up with, he concludes:</para>
    <blockquote>
      <para>It seems that we support everything iCloud is doing and a bit more if you look into the
        feature set. And we have a fundamentally more advanced vision and architecture.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <para>ownCloud offers all the basics of accessing files via a variety of means including a web
      interface and WebDAV. WebDAV support means integration in both <ulink
        url="http://live.gnome.org/Nautilus">Nautilus</ulink> and <ulink
        url="http://dolphin.kde.org/">Dolphin</ulink>, as well as all KDE and most GNOME
      applications. ownCloud can synchronize application data like Bookmarks and settings and allows
      you to listen to your online music collection in a few ways including from <ulink
        url="http://ampache.org/">Ampache</ulink> and via the web interface. The same goes for
      movies and photo’s while PIM syncing is in the works.</para>
    <para><inlinegraphic
        fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/ownCloud_Login-300x173.jpg"
      /></para>
    <para>Above and beyond iCloud, work is going on in ownCloud to offer versioning of all files
      through it’s git backend and the ability to share your files with whomever you want. More
      importantly, ownCloud is extensible. It is possible to write addons to ownCloud like RSS
      readers, todo lists and note syncing or even collaborative gaming. And ownCloud doesn’t limit
      you with DRM or digital fingerprints, allowing you to put your music and movies online without
      restrictions. Finally, where Apple’s cloud just works with Apple devices (as we’ve come to
      expect from them), ownCloud is not so picky, working with Windows, Mac and Linux as well as
      Android, MeeGo and of course the iPhone. This is possible because ownCloud uses open standards
      and works with Free Software where possible, including the mentioned webDav, HTML5, <ulink
        url="http://www.freedesktop.org/wiki/Specifications/open-collaboration-services">Open
        Collaboration Services</ulink> and <ulink url="http://ampache.org/">Ampache</ulink>. An
      access library for applications, to offer better integration with ownCloud, is already
      available and part of the latest openSUSE.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Upcoming</emphasis></para>
    <para>And more is <ulink
        url="http://owncloudtest.blogspot.com/2011/06/owncloud-20-just-merged-with.html">coming in
        ownCloud 2.0</ulink>, scheduled for later this year. The UI has been completely redesigned
      and there is now media support to play audio and video via the web interface. The mentioned
      Ampache support, developed by Robin Appelman, will have a nice effect: the awesome <ulink
        url="http://tomahawk-player.org/">Tomahawk music player</ulink> we <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/16/opensuse-and-online-services/">mentioned
        yesterday</ulink> has Ampache support and thus will be able to play music directly from your
      ownCloud 2.0 server!</para>
    <para>Moreover, user management has been improved as well, and you will be able to extend
      ownCloud with new functionality via apps and plugins! Finally, ownCloud aims to support not
      only Chromium and Firefox but also lesser used browsers like Konqueror. A really exciting
      feature is being worked on by a <ulink url="http://code.google.com/soc/">GSOC</ulink> student:
      git versioning of files! There is some UI work to be done, which will then allow you to go
      back in time and see earlier versions of your files.</para>
    <para>Aaron, one of the ownCloud developers, gives <ulink
        url="http://owncloudtest.blogspot.com/2011/06/owncloud-20-just-merged-with.html">his
        thoughts</ulink> on where ownCLoud should go:</para>
    <blockquote>
      <para>With this, we can not only compete with Apple &amp; Google, we can leave them behind or
        integrate with them from our own camp. There’s no reason you shouldn’t be able to play your
        music from the cloud in Amarok or Tomahawk, view your calendar events on your iPhone and in
        Kontact and access all of your files from Android or webOS or Gnome or Windows or OS X. You
        should also be able to back up your home directory and keep it in sync between multiple
        computers</para>
    </blockquote>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Control</emphasis></para>
    <para>The most important feature of ownCloud, however, is control. In Frank’s words:</para>
    <blockquote>
      <para>You don't have to put your private data into the hosting center of a big company</para>
    </blockquote>
    <para>You can install ownCloud on your own server, your desktop at home, a company server but
      also at a hosting provider supporting PHP, or run it as appliance in some cloud service under
      your direct control. Because it is Free Software, you fully own your data and only <emphasis
        role="italic">you</emphasis> can determine what happens with it.</para>
    <para>All this doesn’t have to mean ownCloud is hard to set up. The upcoming 2.0 version will
      make it drastically easier to deploy but the current 1.2 release can also be had in a number
      of very easy ways.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Get ownCloud</emphasis></para>
    <para>You can install owncloud on your own server or even desktop using the <ulink
        url="http://software.opensuse.org/search?q=owncloud&amp;baseproject=ALL">openSUSE
        repositories on OBS</ulink>. Be sure to read <ulink
        url="http://owncloud.org/index.php/Installation#openSUSE">the documentation</ulink> on
      starting and managing your ownCloud. You can also use the how-to on <ulink
        url="http://owncloudtest.blogspot.com/2011/06/getting-your-owncloud.html">Aaron’s
        blog</ulink> to get the latest and freshest version installed from source! After following
      the basic installation steps, you just have to go to <ulink
        url="http://127.0.0.1/owncloud/index.php">127.0.0.1</ulink> in your browser to complete the
      setup from the web interface.</para>
    <para>However, your ownCloud can be had easier. You can use the excellent <ulink
        url="http://susegallery.com/a/TadMax/owncloud-in-a-box">ownCloud-in-a-box SUSE Studio
        image</ulink> to download a virtual image of ownCloud and start running it right away. It
      gets even more interesting with the <ulink url="http://aws.amazon.com/ec2/">Amazon Elastic
        Cloud Computing</ulink> support of SUSE Studio. Deploying your image on the Amazon cloud
        <ulink url="http://blog.susestudio.com/2011/05/its-never-been-so-ec2-access-cloud.html">is
        easy as pie</ulink>. You could use <ulink url="http://aws.amazon.com/ec2/instance-types/"
        >microinstance</ulink> for which even a <ulink url="http://aws.amazon.com/free/">free 1-year
        subscription</ulink> is available. Yes, that’s right, you can have <emphasis role="italic"
        >your</emphasis> openSUSE ownCloud under <emphasis role="italic">your</emphasis> full
      control on Amazon EC2 for <emphasis role="bold">FREE</emphasis> for one year!</para>
    <para>If running your own Appliance on EC2, another provider or your own hardware is still a tad
      complicated, there is an even easier option: <ulink
        url="https://www.packagecloud.com/?au=owncloud">packagecloud.com</ulink>. They offer
      ownCloud hosting (including a free option, yup) with their convenient web interface. Yes,
      again, full control over your own data and easy to use.</para>
    <para>
      <table frame="all">
        <title>Install ownCloud</title>
        <tgroup cols="2">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
          <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
          <thead>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <ulink
                  url="http://software.opensuse.org/ymp/server:php:applications/openSUSE_11.4/owncloud.ymp">
                  <inlinemediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                      <imagedata fileref="http://files.opensuse.org/opensuse/en/f/f1/Oneclick.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                  </inlinemediaobject></ulink>
                <para>openSUSE 11.4</para></entry>
              <entry>
                <ulink
                  url="http://software.opensuse.org/ymp/server:php:applications/openSUSE_11.3/owncloud.ymp">
                  <inlinemediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                      <imagedata fileref="http://files.opensuse.org/opensuse/en/f/f1/Oneclick.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                  </inlinemediaobject></ulink><para>openSUSE 11.3</para>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry/>
              <entry/>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
    </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Helping out</emphasis></para>
    <para><inlinegraphic
        fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/owncloud_studio-300x173.png"
      /></para>
    <para>ownCloud is a Free Software project, which means you can get involved. The team is looking
      for anyone who has some skills in (or wants to learn) PHP, C++, HTML, CSS &amp; Javascript.
      Drop by #owncloud on freenode or send an email to owncloud on kde.org and get involved
      today!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Conclusion</emphasis></para>
    <para>Frank closes his blog with:</para>
    <blockquote>
      <para>I think ownCloud has the potential to become the cloud storage solution for people who
        donýt like vendor lock-ins and care about freedom and privacy</para>
    </blockquote>
    <para>We would like to go a step further and claim that the wide variety of hosting options for
      ownCloud offers not only more security and privacy but also far more flexibility and, in time,
      lower prices than what Google, Apple, Microsoft and the other ‘big boys’ bring to the table.
      Combined with the excellent integration openSUSE desktops already offer with online services,
      openSUSE has a sunny future in the cloud.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GFDL 1.2</ulink></para>
    <para><!--($ ld: 18.6.11 sm $)--></para>
  </blockquote>  
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Commandline/Script Newbies</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linux.com/learn/tutorials/458715:things-you-cant-do-with-a-gui-finding-stuff-on-linux">Linux.com/Carla Schroder: Things You Can&apos;t Do With a GUI: Finding Stuff on Linux</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>What&apos;s better, a graphical interface or the Linux command line? Both of them. They blend seamlessly on Linux so you don&apos;t have to choose. A good graphical user interface (GUI) has a logical, orderly flow, helps guide you to making the right command choices, and is reasonably fast and efficient. Since this describes a minority of all GUIs, I still live on the command line a lot. The CLI has three advantages: it&apos;s faster for many operations, it&apos;s scriptable, and it is many times more flexible. Linux&apos;s Unix heritage means you can string together commands in endless ways so they do exactly what you want. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 18.6.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Developers and Programmers</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://obsforandroid.wordpress.com/2011/06/13/11-things-ive-learned-about-git/">Justine Leng: 11 Things I’ve Learned about Git</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Now that I’ve spent a few weeks with Git, I decided to record some of the things I
        learned while moving from Subversion (a centralized version control system) to Git (a
        distributed version control system). (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 14.6.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://python4kids.wordpress.com/2011/06/14/review-formatting-silly-sentences/">Python4Kids/Brendan Scott: Review, Formatting Silly Sentences</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>We have been covering lots of new concepts very quickly. So now is the time to slow down a bit and go over some of the things we’ve already done, to have a look at them in a little more depth. In particular I want to try to give you some direction on how to make these code samples your own. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 18.6.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For System Administrators</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.marques.so/2011/06/opensuse-11-4-with-gnome2-for-the-cool-kids-a-brief-howto/">Nelson Marques: openSUSE 11.4 with GNOME2 for the ‘cool kids’… a brief howto!</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>In the past I’ve written a small howto in Portuguese to perform a openSUSE 11.4 GNOME2
        featured installation in Portuguese. Until today I still receive lots of feedback and some
        personal emails from Portuguese and Brazilian (mostly) users about it.</para>
      <para>I’ve always preached that the nice of openSUSE was the fact of allowing the users to
        install a vast number of repositories and running an updated application layer on top of a
        powerful and reliable base. This article isn’t really about ‘installing’ openSUSE, but
        instead it’s focused on the post install configuration of kinky repositories and stuff that
        by the traditional reasons isn’t provided as standard in openSUSE.</para>
      <para>This document will cover the following aspects:<orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Installation of sub-pixel font rendering (from a OBS user repository);</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Installation of latest development release of Wine (1.3.21);</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Installation of the most common multimedia codecs from Packman Essentials;</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist></para>
      <para>At the end, the user should have a working openSUSE 11.4 GNOME2 Desktop with very cool
        sub-pixel font rendering (this really kicks ass) and have an idea of the potential that
        openSUSE can deploy for customized systems. (...)</para>
<!--($ Id: 16.6.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://ostatic.com/blog/so-you-just-deleted-your-production-database-what-now">OStatic/Jon Buys: So You Just Deleted Your Production Database - What Now</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>It doesn’t matter how it happened, it doesn’t matter why, blame can (and probably will) be placed later. What matters now is that your production MySQL database was just deleted from the filesystem while the MySQL daemon was running. The good news is that the server, somehow, is still running fine, and the system is still up. The bad news is that the directory where MySQL stores the database is now empty.</para>
      <para>Take a deep breath, you are running Linux, here is what to do: (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 18.6.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
