<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 id="gsoc" role="gsoc">
  <title>Google Summer of Code</title>
  <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
      <imagedata width="20%" align="center" fileref="http://michal.hrusecky.net/wp-content/uploads/GSoC2011_300x200.png"/>
    </imageobject>
  </mediaobject>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://sysbytes.wordpress.com/2011/08/07/sax3-monitor-module-completed/">Manu
        Gupta: SaX3 – Monitor Module completed</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>As part of GSoC Project, I am working on SaX3 and I have completed the monitor
      module.</para>
    <para>You can get the latest repo from my home repository<ulink
        url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/home:/manugupt1/"
        >http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/home:/manugupt1/</ulink></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Please test it thoroughly,and let me know if common troubleshooting
        use cases for a single monitor is supported. If there is anything missing let me know.
        Xinerama is not supported</emphasis></para>
    <para>For both factory and 11.4.</para>
    <para>Next up is touchpad, which I will finish by this thursday. And will begin pencil downs the
      following week onwards.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 8.8.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://obsforandroid.wordpress.com/2011/08/01/implement-sorting-functions-for-requests/"
        >Justine Leng: Implement sorting functions for Requests</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>One of the goals for this OBS Mobile Project to make the list of requests sortable, by
      date/time, requester, target project/package, and request state.(...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 5.8.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://obsforandroid.wordpress.com/2011/08/05/new-features-added-to-requests/"
        >Justine Leng: New Features Added to Requests</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>I would like to share some exciting progress on the OBS Mobile Project:<orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Request state has been added to each request;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Sorting functions have been implemented for Requests;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>A search filter has been added to the Request page.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist></para>
    <para>Now, when the user logs into the list of requests, the user will not only be able to see
      the state of each request, but also sort requests based on 4 criteria:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>request date</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>requester’s name</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>target project/package</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>request state</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para><inlinegraphic fileref="http://obsforandroid.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/sort1.png"
        width="20%"/></para>
<!-- ($ ld: 06.08.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://redache.wordpress.com/2011/08/06/entomologist-ui-changes-weekly-report-11/"
        >David Williams: Entomologist UI Changes – Weekly report #11</ulink></title>
    <para>This week has involved trying to get the UI in place for ToDo List
      exporting/configuration. The work should now be finished and I’ve begun trying to implement
      Remember the Milk exporting which is made a bit complicated by how they accept API requests
      but I hope to have this finished as soon as possible. I don’t really have that much to talk
      about this week as nothing huge has changed but I will keep working on integrating the
      services.</para>
    <para>What I hope to achieve is Google Calendar, Remember The Milk and WebDAV server integration
      by the Soft Pencils Down Date, which I believe is the 19th of August. I think it’s perfectly
      achievable to get these features to a finished state by then and I’ll continue working on
      having them integrated. As I’ve previously mentioned I would like to use the final week as a
      time to merge and test everything to try and uncover any bugs I’ve missed whilst adding these
      features.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 06.08.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
