<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="tipsandtricks">
  <title>Tips and Tricks</title>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Desktop Users</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://thefreecountry.wordpress.com/2011/05/21/a-bit-about-fluxbox/">Linux
          Journal/Emre Sevinc: Grabbing Your Music from YouTube: Do It Your Way </ulink>
      </title>
      <para>A few months ago my father-in-law said that his company was renewing their computers.
        When I heard that some second-hand PCs were about to be available, I decided to take some of
        them, thinking that a few old PCs would not hurt when it comes to enlarging my home network
        and doing experiments with GNU/Linux. When my father-in-law asked if it would be possible to
        reformat one of those computers so that he could use it at his home, I jumped at the
        opportunity to bring another user to the world of GNU/Linux. A few days passed and he was a
        happy user of his new computer running Ubuntu, and he was enjoying his Firefox while he
        explored the web. I don’t know what other people think or usability studies say, but he said
        that he had no problem using the system and he was surprised that I did not have to install
        an anti-virus. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 24.5.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://anksos.blogspot.com/2011/05/how-to-install-enlightenment-e17-in.html">Anastasios Ksouzafeiris: How to install Enlightenment (E17) in openSUSE 11.4</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Hello folks, two days ago I installed on my netbook Enlightenment WM (window manager). A
        very lightweight WM with the minimalistic environment that i like.. After 30 minutes and
        search actually you can understand how it works, it&apos;s really easy if you understand that all
        the apps are modules and you have only to load them or unload them.. After this quick
        introduction i think we must go to the installation and see it by your self. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 18.5.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Commandline/Script Newbies</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://bashshell.net/commands/using-nl-to-number-lines/">BashShell.net/mike: Using nl to Number Lines</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The nl utility is use for numbering lines of a text file.    It’s easy to use, and there are only a few options that you need to remember.  Start by creating a file with ten consecutive lines. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 20.5.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Developers and Programmers</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://log.or.cz/?p=156">Petr Baudis: brmd: A Case for POE</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>In <ulink url="http://brmlab.cz/">brmlab</ulink>, we want to <ulink
          url="http://brmlab.cz/project/brmdoor">track</ulink> who is unlocking the space, whether
        someone is inside, have some good visual indicator that <ulink
          url="http://brmlab.cz/project/presentationcenter">live stream</ulink> is on air, and so
        on. In other words, we have an Arduino with some further hardware, and we want to show
        whatever is reported by the Arduino on IRC and <ulink url="http://nat.brmlab.cz/brmd/"
          >web</ulink>, and provide some web-based control (open/closed status override) in the
        opposite direction too.</para>
      <para>What to use for a service (we call it brmd) that will bind all these interfaces
        together? It just needs a lot of boring frontends and simple state maintenance. </para>
      <para>It turns out that Perl’s <ulink url="http://poe.perl.org/">POE</ulink> framework is
        ideal for this – most of the code for IRC, HTTP and device read/write is already there, so
        you just grab the modules, slam them together and you have exactly what you need with
        minimal effort. Right?It turns out that there are caveats – basically, the idea is correct,
        aside of getting stuck on a single stupidity of mine, I’d have the whole thing put together
        in something like half an hour. Unfortunately, the moment you want robustness too, things
        are getting a lot more complex; to handle the device disappearing, IRC disconnections, not
        having HTTP socket fds leak away, etc., you suddenly need to either magically know what
        further modules to hook up or start exeting some manual effort. Still, I like how POE is
        making it so easy to give a simple state machine many input/output interfaces and when you
        get used to the idiosyncracies, you can even make it somewhat reliable. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 26.5.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For System Administrators</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.serverwatch.com/tutorials/article.php/3933691/article.htm">ServerWatch/Joe Brockmeier: Discover Rootkits With Unhide</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>If your system has been rooted, you can&apos;t trust utilities like ps to show processes from the rootkit. For ferreting out nasties, you&apos;ll want to check out unhide and unhide.rb.</para>
      <para>If you&apos;ve ever encountered a rootkit, you know the symptoms -- suddenly a box is sluggish or sending out gobs of network traffic -- but running top and ps aux show nothing that should be the culprit. One quick and dirty way to turn up the offending processes is to use the unhide utility or its Ruby counterpart unhide.rb. It&apos;s a helpful tool to have around for Linux server management. (...)</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Editors Note</emphasis>: unhide_rb packages for openSUSE are <ulink url="http://software.opensuse.org/search?p=1&amp;baseproject=ALL&amp;q=unhide">available from OBS&apos;s security repo</ulink>.</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 20.5.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
