<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/02/13/ati-amd-flgrx-8-812-catalyst-11-1-available-also-for-11-4factory/"
        >Bruno Friedmann: ATI Amd flgrx 8.812 catalyst 11.1 available also for 11.4/factory</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>"A quick note for the week-end, I’ve build and uploaded the new fglrx drivers. </para>
    <para>The good news, they are also available for 11.4/factory,</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Unofficial-but-working repository</emphasis></para>
    <para>For openSUSE 11.4 (factory) <emphasis role="bold">NEW
      !</emphasis><screen>zypper ar -c -f -n "ATI/AMD fglrx non-official" http://linux.ioda.net/mirror/ati/openSUSE_11.4/ "ATI/AMD FGLRX"</screen></para>
    <para>I would like to have feedback about how that works for you, please comment !</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Factory specifics troubles</emphasis></para>
    <para>on a fresh auto-configuration factory install :
      libomp43<screen>Problem: fglrx64_7_6_0_SUSE114-8.812-1.x86_64 requires gcc, but this requirement cannot be provided
  uninstallable providers: gcc-4.5-16.1.i586[openSUSE-11.4-11.4-1.35]
                   gcc-4.5-16.1.x86_64[openSUSE-11.4-11.4-1.35]
 Solution 1: deinstallation of libgomp43-4.3.4_20091019-5.23.x86_64
 Solution 2: do not install fglrx64_7_6_0_SUSE114-8.812-1.x86_64
 Solution 3: break fglrx64_7_6_0_SUSE114 by ignoring some of its dependencies

Choose from above solutions by number or cancel [1/2/3/c] (c): 1
Resolving dependencies...
Resolving package dependencies...

The following NEW packages are going to be installed:
  binutils-gold fglrx64_7_6_0_SUSE114 gcc gcc45 glibc-devel
  kernel-default-devel kernel-desktop-devel kernel-devel kernel-source
  kernel-syms kernel-xen-devel libgomp45 linux-glibc-devel make patch 

The following package is going to be REMOVED:
  libgomp43 

15 new packages to install, 1 to remove.
Overall download size: 127.9 MiB. After the operation, additional 600.9 MiB
will be used.</screen></para>
    <para>Normally this bug (in M5/M6) should has been resolved in RC1.</para>
    <para>See full details on my previous dedicated post <ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/?p=4673"
      >http://lizards.opensuse.org/?p=4673</ulink>"</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 14.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://kohei.us/2011/02/14/fosdem-2011-slide-latest-updates/">Kohei Yoshida:
        FOSDEM 2011 slide &amp; latest updates</ulink></title>
    <para><quote>I’ve just uploaded the slide for my talk during FOSDEM 2011 here. It was very nice
        to be able to talk about our somewhat ambitious plan to bring LibreOffice Calc to the next
        level. Also, I regret that I haven’t been able to blog about what’s been going on lately;
        lots of time spent on writing, reviewing code, fixing bugs and integrating patches, and
        sadly little time is left on writing blogs. Having said all that, let me talk about a few
        things that are new on the master branch (since I’m already in the writing mode).</quote>
      (...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 14.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://nowwhatthe.blogspot.com/2011/02/nokia-does-right-thing.html">Jos
        Poortvliet: Nokia does the right thing!</ulink></title>
    <para>For those who've had it with the Nokia discussions - further down I have some positive
      news too... </para>
    <para>So the <ulink
        url="http://www.nokia.com/press/press-releases/showpressrelease?newsid=1488004">rumors
        turned out to be true</ulink>. Stephan Elop, the new Nokia CEO (and ex Microsoft employee),
      has decided the future of Nokia is to work with Microsoft. It will be possible to decrease
      investments in R&amp;D and Nokia won't have to build it's own platform nor focus on services
      anymore. Instead it can focus on becoming a phone hardware manufacturer, a strategy which will
      ensure high margins!</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-77DvJkCk1Ww/TVnlv4_UlsI/AAAAAAAABPA/Vb6R9VDMPYs/s200/nokia-s-qt-4-7-app-framework-goes-gold-encourages-symbian-and-meego-development-for-fun-and-profit_1.jpg"
        />
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Sarcasm aside, it seems to me that Nokia (or at least its CEO) has realized it has had its
      best time in the nineties and it is over. Better to show good profitability for the next 4-6
      years than invest in the future. Within 2-3 years Stephan will leave a company which is "going
      great" (short-term financially speaking) and receive a big bonus. Usual business of the type
      which brought us the credit crisis.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">How about us?</emphasis></para>
    <para>So what does this mean for Free Software? Hard to say yet but I think it's a fair bet that
      development on MeeGo won't increase due to these choices. Bad for the linux kernel,
      infrastructure like Telepathy, Gstreamer and top-level stuff like Qt. Qt will probably not be
      hurt that much, it is the platform of choice for Symbian for at least the next few years. And
      if they change their mind Nokia (or otherwise some volunteers, can't stop them can you?) will
      port Qt to WP7 - write one app, run on MeeGo, Symbian AND WP7. With the open governance model
      of Qt &amp; the LGPL license, the decreased investments could be compensated by community
      efforts. Still, I feel sorry for those who might get fired over this. And personally, I was
      looking for a really open mobile platform - my N900 is pretty awesome and though I'll buy the
      N9 it's sad it won't have a decent successor. </para>
    <para>Meanwhile, stock has gone down some 15% on Nokia, MS' stock went down, Apple and Google
      went up. Hmmmm, what does the stock market think... Anyhow. I guess more than enough has been
      written and said about it, let's just wait and see what happens next...</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Good News - twice!</emphasis></para>
    <para>In far more positive news, my own employer (that would be Novell) has helped the stability
      of the UK financial system by migrating the London Stock Exchange from a Microsoft .NET based
      solution to a SUSE Linux Enterprise stack. The new trading system <ulink
        url="http://www.computerworlduk.com/news/open-source/3260727/london-stock-exchange-in-historic-linux-go-live/"
        >went live last week</ulink>. The earlier Windows and .NET based software actually managed
      to get the CEO of the LSE <ulink
        url="http://blogs.computerworld.com/london_stock_exchange_to_abandon_failed_windows_platform"
        >fired after an 8 hour outage</ulink> (any idea how much money that costs?). Their new CEO,
      slightly smarter than Elop if I might say so, decided to go for Linux. This has led to better
      performance and stability - no surprise. SUSE proves to be about 15 times faster than the
      MS/.Net system which couldn't get network round trips below 2 milliseconds despite big
      investments in code and hardware improvements. Meanwhile SUSE comes in at about 126
      microseconds! I don't expect any 8-hour outages or fired CEO's, so congrats to everyone
      involved!</para>
    <para>See the Youtube Video: <ulink url="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dr7IxQeXr7g"
        >http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dr7IxQeXr7g</ulink></para>
    <para>And while at it, let me also mention an <ulink
        url="http://www.linuxplanet.com/linuxplanet/newss/7294/1/">interview with my colleague Kerry
        Kim</ulink>. Subject was IBM's supercomputer 'Watson' which took on a human in the TV show
      'Jeopardy'. Watson runs SUSE Linux - as do, Kerry mentioned, 6 out of the top-10
      supercomputers in the world. Check a video of Watson out <ulink
        url="http://www.pbs.org/newshour/bb/science/jan-june11/jeopardy_02-14.html">here</ulink> (or
      embedded above).</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 15.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://www.wafaa.eu/entry/porting-libreoffice-to-android---my-new-crazy-project-1-57.html"
        >Andrew Wafaa: Porting LibreOffice to Android - My New Crazy Project</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>"Yes, you read that correct - I am going to try and port LibreOffice to Android! :-) </para>
    <para>Why? Simples, there are no ODF compatible products on Android for reading &amp; writing.
      There is <ulink url="https://market.android.com/details?id=at.tomtasche.reader">OpenOffice
        Document Reader</ulink> which as the name suggests is just a reader, and also OOo is so 2009
      ;-) </para>
    <para>Now if I was a half decent hacker, this may not have been such a big deal. Problem is I'm
      an absolutley crap hacker, with almost no experience or knowledge of Android or LibreOffice
      development. So why on earth would I try and do such a monumentally painful task? Two reasons
      - 1. I was challenged by an engineer that I respect to do it. 2. I've got an itch that needs
      scratching (actually I'm riddled with itches, and the Doc confirms it isn't a medical
      condition ;-) ). </para>
    <para>So how to go about it? I'm still working that one out. As it stands openSUSE doesn't
      provide the necessary tools for the job - no decent ARM port :( So I'm going to have a play
      with Debian - after all 6.0 Squeeze is just out the oven so now's as good a time as any. If
      that doesn't work out I'll give Ubuntu a whirl. Never fear oh mighty Geeko lovers - these
      alien installations will be going on my test machine. My primary machine is still running
      openSUSE, with GNOME3. </para>
    <para>I'll try and document my trip through pain and fun, if for nothing else humour for those
      more seasoned than me at doing cooky stuff like this. </para>
    <para>Just as a little side note - my primary machine, a Dell D820 decided to die just before
      FOSDEM. This has left me using my Netbook as my main machine. It took me ~15.5hrs to build
      LibreOffice on it. " (...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 15.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
