<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
  %myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="kernel">
  <title>Kernel Review</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/Kernel-Log-updated-Radeon-drivers-mdadm-and-ALSA-1185791.html"
        >h-online/Thorsten Lemmhuis: Kernel Log: Consistent names for network interfaces</ulink>
    </title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">A new version of the AMD driver from X.org improves support for
        modern Radeon graphics chips. An updated mdadm, initially only designed for developers,
        allows the RAID functions of modern Intel motherboard chip-sets to be used. After nine
        months, the ALSA project has published a new version. </emphasis></para>
    <para>AMD’s kernel and X.org developer Alex Deucher has <ulink
        url="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.comp.freedesktop.xorg/45671">published</ulink> version
      6.14.0 of driver package xf86-video-ati. It contains the X.org driver for Radeon graphics
      hardware, which provides much better support for the latest version of Radeon graphics chips.
      For example, it now not only controls the graphics kernel of the Fusion processors developed
      under codename <quote>Ontario</quote>, but also the Northern Islands GPUs based on Radeon HD
      models 62xx to 68xx. With both of them, 2D acceleration via EXA now works, as does video
      acceleration with the antiquated Xv (Xvideo), but in both cases the driver remains dependant
      on <ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/Kernel-Log-Coming-in-2-6-38-Part-1-Graphics-1176900.html"
        >Linux kernel 2.6.38</ulink>, which is still under development and is expected to be
      released at the end of March or beginning of April. Its DRM driver with functions for KMS
      (kernel-based mode-setting) is required anyway for Northern Islands GPUs because the driver
      does not support UMS (user mode-setting) on these chips. </para>
    <para>In combination with KMS in kernel 2.6.36 and later, the driver also supports EXA and Xv on
      Evergreen GPUs on Radeon HD 5,000 series models. The developers have considerably upgraded the
      man page in the new version. Along with kernel 2.6.38, the driver offers page-flipping support
      so that image updates are more precisely synchronised with the start of frame re-draw. For
      further information on this new technology in Linux 2.6.38, see the <ulink url="">first
        part</ulink> of the series <quote>Coming in 2.6.38</quote>. </para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 10.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://ifup.org/2011/02/03/reverse-path-filter-rp_filter-by-example/">Brandon
        Philips: reverse path filter (rp_filter) by example</ulink></title>
    <para>Recently, I ran into an rp_filter change for all Kernels after 2.6.31. So read along for
      an explanation of both the sysctl change and a practical example of rp_filter usage. </para>
    <para>Lets say you had the following entry in your
      /etc/sysctl.conf<screen>net.ipv4.conf.all.rp_filter = 1</screen></para>
    <para>with the intention of turning on <ulink
        url="http://git.kernel.org/?p=linux/kernel/git/torvalds/linux-2.6.git;a=blob;f=Documentation/networking/ip-sysctl.txt;hb=HEAD#l844"
        >reverse path filtering</ulink> for all interfaces. Well you didn't get your wish- rp_filter
      remained disabled if you are running a Kernel older than 2.6.31. </para>
    <para>This could come as a suprise if you upgrade your Kernel and have a system relying on
      rp_filter being disabled or enabled (e.g. multicast routing, multi-homed servers). If you have
      a single-homed unicast server setups this change will probably go unnoticed however. </para>
    <para>The fix was implemented upstream in <ulink
        url="http://git.kernel.org/?p=linux/kernel/git/torvalds/linux-2.6.git;a=commit;h=27fed4175acf81ddd91d9a4ee2fd298981f60295"
        >v2.6.31</ulink> and the basic issue was that each individual interface has an rp_filter
      setting which defaulted to 0 and the interface setting overrides the "all interface setting"
      since they were AND'd together.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 4.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>Rares Aioanei: kernel weekly news 05.02.2011</title>
    <para>Rares gives us this week a great Kernel Review. Thanks Rares :-)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 4.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
