<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="belection">
  <title>Board Election 2011</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/10/05/opensuse-board-election-committee-formed/">openSUSE
        Board Election Committee Formed</ulink></title>
    <para>The 2011 openSUSE Board term is soon coming to an end. In the last few project meetings as
      well as at the conference, the board has called for people to step up for the Election
      Committee. Five openSUSE contributors have offered their help and we’d like to introduce them
      to you.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">The Team</emphasis></para>
    <para>The openSUSE Board is proud to welcome the following members of our openSUSE Community as
      this year’s Election Committee:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Izabel Valverde</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Kai-Uwe Behrmann</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>James Mason</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Kostas Koudaras</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Thomas Schmidt</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist><emphasis role="bold">The Job</emphasis></para>
    <para>In the coming days and weeks, this committee will act independently to implement a formal
      plan for the oversight and election of a new Board for the 2012 term. Currently, three board
      seats will be up for election. These seats are currently held by Rupert Horstkotter, Pavol
      Rusnak, and Bryen Yunashko (whose seat is vacated due to term limits.)</para>
    <para>The Election Committee will announce the nomination process and election period as part of
      the election plan. Please stay tuned for further news from the Committee itself.</para>
    <para>We are sure this team will perform its duties to the best benefit of the openSUSE Project
      and we look forward to an exciting election term and seeing many openSUSE Community members
      stepping up as candidates in the upcoming election.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 06.10.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
