<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://omgsuse.com/content/ten-days-opensuse-day-one-kernel">OMG!
        SUSE!/rtyler: Ten Days of openSUSE, Day One: The Kernel</ulink>
    </title>
    <note>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is licensed under the <ulink
            url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">Creatice Commons
            Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License</ulink></emphasis>.</para>
    </note>
    <para>In the lead up to the upcoming openSUSE release 11.4, I figured we could highlight some
      major new developments that are coming in this release.</para>
    <para>At the core of every Linux distribution lies the Linux Kernel, the heart of it all. The
      kernel the most fundamental part of the operating system, allowing programs to interact with
      your processor, hard disks, keyboard, etc. The kernel coming in 11.4 contains quite a number
      of great improvements.</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>"Kernel activity patch," which we had previously talked about makes the openSUSE
          desktop feel faster and more responsive than ever.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink
            url="http://kernelnewbies.org/Linux_2_6_37-DriversArch#head-c3d9fded6c4cb322c878028ff6af0bd9b491d86a"
            >Hoardes of new drivers</ulink> adding better hardware support than ever, including a
          number of new input devices (including some new Wacom hardware, which I'm particularly
          pleased about).</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Multi-processor support for Ext4, the default filesystem openSUSE uses. If you have a
          dual-core notebook or desktop, openSUSE 11.4 will give you faster data access than
          before</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Plenty more that I cannot properly enumerate.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>For all the gritty technical details, the folks over at <ulink
        url="http://kernelnewbies.org/">kernelnewbies.org</ulink> put up <ulink
        url="http://kernelnewbies.org/LinuxChanges">this handy summary</ulink> of changes.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 1.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://omgsuse.com/content/ten-days-opensuse-day-two-libreoffice">OMG!
        SUSE!/rtyler: Ten Days of openSUSE, Day Two: LibreOffice</ulink></title>
    <note>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is licensed under the <ulink
            url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">Creatice Commons
            Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License</ulink></emphasis>.</para>
    </note>
    <para>With 8 days to go until the release of openSUSE 11.4, why not highlight: <emphasis
        role="bold">LibreOffice</emphasis>! (since <ulink url="http://identi.ca/jospoortvliet"
        >Jos</ulink> already <ulink
        url="http://nowwhatthe.blogspot.com/2011/03/libreoffice-and-opensuse-114.html">spilled the
        beans</ulink>)</para>
    <para>As far as I know, openSUSE 11.4 will be <emphasis role="italic">the first</emphasis> major
      distribution to bundle LibreOffice with a release, something the folks in the underground SUSE
      ice cave seem pretty happy about.</para>
    <para>What's the big deal about LibreOffice? Remember OpenOffice and how it was pretty good but
      occasionally had some annoying quirks that seemed to take forever to get fixed. Lots of things
      have changed for the better with LibreOffice.</para>
    <para>For starters LibreOffice is developed under the umbrella of <ulink
        url="http://www.documentfoundation.org/">The Document Foundation</ulink> which strives to
      foster development and partipation in the LibreOffice community.</para>
    <para>This focus on open development and a merit-based leadership means end-users like us get to
      see <emphasis role="bold">more bug fixes</emphasis> and <emphasis role="bold">newer
        features</emphasis> faster! Already the LibreOffice guys have incorporated a number of
      outstanding improvements that were not yet incorporated into OpenOffice (such as the <ulink
        url="http://go-oo.org/">go-oo.org</ulink> changes)).</para>
    <para>The version of LibreOffice shipping with openSUSE 11.4 is faster, less buggy and will
      continue to improve at an incredible pace compared to the old OpenOffice, this is a <emphasis
        role="bold">good thing</emphasis>!</para>
    <para>If you're upgrading to, or installing openSUSE 11.4 on March 10th, you should get the
      latest LibreOffice but if you can't wait until then, click the shiny button and grab
      LibreOffice for 11.3!</para>
    <para><ulink url="http://bit.ly/hML0Pd">Install LibreOffice 3.3.1 for 11.3</ulink></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 3.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://nowwhatthe.blogspot.com/2011/03/libreoffice-and-opensuse-114.html">Jos
        Poortvliet: LibreOffice and openSUSE 11.4</ulink></title>
    <note>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is licensed under the <ulink
            url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">Creatice Commons
            Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License</ulink></emphasis>.</para>
    </note>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-zsh13s7cR7s/TW2Nw8AhS7I/AAAAAAAABQ0/w1dRRxtlsJE/s200/LibreOffice-logo.jpg"
        />
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Happy to see LibreOffice going strong... <ulink
        url="http://www.linuxjournal.com/content/who-contributes-most-libreoffice">This
        article</ulink> analyzes the contributions to LibreOffice. Some impressive numbers - 133 new
      contributors already!!! Even Canonical has send in a patch to fix something... Meanwhile
      Michael Meeks' team (Novell) is leading the 'corporate contributors' pack. And yes, openSUSE
      will be the first major linux distribution to ship LibreOffice - and it'll be good, thanks to
      that involvement in LibreOffice development.</para>
    <para>Sean Michael Kerner mentions this fact and our upcoming release in his <ulink
        url="http://blog.internetnews.com/skerner/2011/02/novell-opensuse-114-nears-comp.html">blog
        on internetnews.com</ulink> where he also quotes our AJ on several infrastructural
      improvements. We do need to educate him and explain openSUSE isn't exclusively a Novell
      product - with so many volunteers involved and the work going on to set up a Foundation you
      simply can't claim that anymore... We're leading the pack in that area as well and we need to
      be vocal about that!</para>
    <para>PS will blog on the Marketing Meeting we had last week soonish, need to catch up to some
      urgent things first... Especially sleep!</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 3.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://gburt.blogspot.com/2011/03/pdf-mod-update.html">Gabriel Burt: PDF Mod
        Update</ulink></title>
    <note>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is licensed under the <ulink
            url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">Creatice Commons
            Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License</ulink></emphasis>.</para>
    </note>
    <para>I haven't blogged about <ulink url="http://live.gnome.org/PdfMod"><emphasis role="bold"
          >PDF Mod</emphasis></ulink> since Nov, 2009. We've had five releases in the meantime,
      including 0.9.1 just released today!</para>
    <para>We have had tons of improvements and fixes, and one major new feature: <emphasis
        role="bold">bookmark editing</emphasis>!</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-zHw5vftltXI/TW_tSb6kUrI/AAAAAAAABBg/eqzmdYLWr9c/s800/pdfmod2.png"
          width="30%"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>We're up to <ulink url="http://l10n.gnome.org/module/pdfmod/"><emphasis role="bold">26
          translations</emphasis></ulink> now, including 11 of <ulink
        url="http://library.gnome.org/users/pdfmod/"><emphasis role="bold">our user
          manual</emphasis></ulink>!</para>
    <para>As a reminder, PDF Mod can:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>pull out (extract) pages from a document into a new PDF</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>combine two documents, or parts thereof</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>reorder and rotate pages</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>extract embedded images</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>edit basic metadata (title, author, keywords)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>edit a document's bookmarks (aka outlines)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>and that's it!</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <!-- ($ ld: 4.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://fridrich.blogspot.com/2011/03/opensuse-mingw-mailing-list.html"
        >Fridrich Strba: opensuse-mingw mailing list</ulink></title>
    <para>The <ulink url="https://build.opensuse.org/project/show?project=windows%3Amingw"
        >windows::mingw</ulink> project and its sub-project quickly gain a true community around
      themselves. This week, the number of source packages that we build for Windows in <ulink
        url="https://build.opensuse.org/">openSUSE Build Service</ulink> reached 200 for both the
        <ulink url="https://build.opensuse.org/project/show?project=windows%3Amingw%3Awin32"
        >32-bit</ulink> as well as <ulink
        url="https://build.opensuse.org/project/show?project=windows%3Amingw%3Awin64">64-bit</ulink>
      Windows versions.</para>
    <para>In order to make the communication between contributors, developers and users easier, we
      got a sparkling new mailing list at <ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/"
        >lists.opensuse.org</ulink>. You can subscribe it by sending a mail to
        <email>opensuse-mingw+subscribe@opensuse.org</email> and enjoy all the intelligent and
      edifying talk we are having there.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 4.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/omgsuse/~3/EF0zvH9M9wg/ten-days-opensuse-day-four-grub2"
        >OMG! SUSE!/rtyler: Ten Days of openSUSE, Day Four: GRUB2</ulink></title>
    <note>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is licensed under the <ulink
            url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">Creatice Commons
            Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License</ulink></emphasis>.</para>
    </note>
    <para>Day four of the count down to openSUSE 11.4, I've covered the kernel, some higher level
      apps and today I wanted to jump all the way back down to the beginning. The beginning of
        <emphasis role="bold">every</emphasis> experience with Linux, Windows and Mac OS X starts
      with the bootloader.</para>
    <para>The bootloader is responsible for getting your computer from "POST" (power-on self-test)
      to the operating system. Think of it like the ignition switch in your car, something has to
      get things going and for computers the bootloader is it.</para>
    <para>Historically, openSUSE has shipped with <ulink
        url="https://secure.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/wiki/GNU_GRUB">GRUB</ulink>. GRUB has long
      been the bootloader of choice for Linux users running on PCs, and has now been supplanted by
        <emphasis role="bold">GRUB2</emphasis>.</para>
    <para>In order to preserve stability for users, the openSUSE project has actually incorporated
      GRUB2 later than some other distributions who have put the system "through its paces," working
      out all the kinks in the system. The team is pretty confident that GRUB2 is now ready for
      primetime, and is making it the default bootloader for 11.4.</para>
    <para>So what's so special about GRUB2 compared to the original GRUB? The folks who maintain
      Ubuntu's "community documentation" <ulink url="https://help.ubuntu.com/community/Grub2">wrote
        up a nice comparision</ulink> that you can take a look at if you're interested, but here's
      the highlights:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>With GRUB2 you can boot LiveCD ISO images straight from your hard drive</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Better graphical boot menu support</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Themes!</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Rescue mode</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Improved speed and reliability</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Auto-detect other operating systems like Windows, etc.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>Personally, I run openSUSE on my laptop, so I rarely see the bootloader but I'm glad the
      openSUSE team's attention to detail encompasses the entirety of the computing experience from
      start to finish.</para>
    <para>If you're a dual-booter, be sure to grab openSUSE 11.4 on <emphasis role="bold">March
        10th</emphasis> and enjoy the fanciful new GRUB :)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 4.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://ugansert.blogspot.com/2011/03/suse-manager-autoinstall-screenshots.html">Uwe
        Gansert: SUSE Manager Autoinstall Screenshots</ulink></title>
    <para>as you might know, we published the <ulink
        url="http://www.novell.com/de-de/products/suse-manager">SUSE Manager</ulink> yesterday. It
      was fun to work on that project and I learned really a lot. Anyway, I read many announcement
      texts in the press and from Novell but I did not see any pictures. People love pictures. So
      here they come (most screenshots about autoinstallation - I guess you know why ;)
      ).(...)</para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://www.wafaa.eu/entry/bug-tracking-with-the-help-of-an-entomologist-1-58.html"
        >Andrew Wafaa: Bug Tracking With The Help Of An Entomologist</ulink></title>
    <para>I like to think of myself as being fairly consistent, and I've had one request for a long
      time, a desktop bug tracker client. I even <ulink
        url="http://www.wafaa.eu/entry/bugging-bugs---a-call-for-help-1-20.html">asked</ulink> if
      someone more adept in the ways of The Code could help. Unfortunately my call for help wasn't
      heard :-(</para>
    <para>That was until <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/01/19/hackweek-vi/">HackWeek
        VI</ulink> came along! Luckily <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/User:Mbarringer">Matt
        Barringer</ulink> (from those crazy cooks in the <ulink url="http://susestudio.com/">SUSE
        Studio</ulink> team) heard my call. He picked up his code machine gun and blasted away \o/ </para>
    <para>A few days after HackWeek VI ended he enlightened me to his new masterpiece – <ulink
        url="http://entomologist.sourceforge.net/">Entomologist</ulink>. So what is it? As you may
      have guessed, it is a desktop bug tracker client. It's cutely written in Qt, isn't final yet
      (is any software?) but works fairly well. Why only fairly well? Simples, it only supports
      Bugzilla at the minute, but there are plans afoot to add others (please see the <ulink
        url="http://entomologist.sourceforge.net/#todo">ToDo</ulink> list). Once more bug backends
      are added it will be great (yes, this is a subtle hint for you to contribute code ;-) ). It is
      being put forward as one of the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:GSOC_2011_Ideas#Cross_Platform_Bug_Tracker_Client"
        >GSOC</ulink> projects so fingers crossed ;-)</para>
    <para>Of course you need some obligatory screenshots, so feast your eyes :-)</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/_ObpIMjebLDY/TXC_A6xeQLI/AAAAAAAAAOY/FDjKJM3lPV8/s912/entomologist-desktop.png"
          width="30%"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Seeing your bugs on the desktop</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/_ObpIMjebLDY/TXC_Aq_GPaI/AAAAAAAAAOU/qEmmPWywluo/s640/entomologist-android1.png"
          width="20%"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Seeing your bugs on the move.</para>
    <para>Yes that's right, entomologist works on Android!! Sure the UI is a bit butt ugly on the
      platform, but the app works ;-)</para>
    <para>I'll do a post on how I ported entomologist to Android shortly, it wasn't too
      difficult.</para>
    <para>So if you want to give it a whirl, then head over to the homepage and choose your flavour
      of openSUSE, Fedora, Mandriva, Ubuntu or Debian (thanks <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Build_Service">OBS</ulink>) (...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 4.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://nowwhatthe.blogspot.com/2011/03/criticism-towards-gnome-shell.html"
        >Jos Poortvliet: criticism towards GNOME Shell</ulink></title>
    <note>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is licensed under the <ulink
            url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">Creatice Commons
            Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License</ulink></emphasis>.</para>
    </note>
    <para>Reading all the controversy around the decision by the GNOME Shell designers to remove the
      minimize and maximize buttons from GNOME shell reminds me quite a bit of the discussions
      around Plasma. Especially for stuff like the brilliant yet controversial Folderview
      widget.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">criticism</emphasis></para>
    <para>It also makes me wonder if those complaining have ever tried GNOME Shell... As is
      adequately explained in <ulink
        url="http://mail.gnome.org/archives/gnome-shell-list/2011-February/msg00192.html">this
        rationale</ulink>, minimizing simply has no place in the concepts behind GNOME Shell.
      Period. And if you've tried GNOME Shell you would realize that.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/_WMsbUl3phhU/TXD1Sqz8HyI/AAAAAAAABSc/dSs852B3rTY/s288/gnome3_windows.png"
        />
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Yes, Shell takes getting used to, it does enforce certain habits. If you want to customize
      your environment for maximum 'getting-work-done' then <ulink
        url="http://www.linux.com/learn/tutorials/415694-an-early-look-at-gnome-30">maybe GNOME
        Shell is (currently) not for you</ulink>. But that's the crowd KDE has always appeased to
      anyway. There is after all a trade-off between efficiency and ease of use (or rather,
      discoverability) - it is why most seasoned sysadmins use a command line.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Newbies!</emphasis></para>
    <para>But the power of GNOME Shell lies somewhere else. Put a newbie in front of it. Observe -
      in 5 minutes they've figured out how to use it, really. It is very simple and intuitive. I
      find that very impressive. Especially on a touch screen, it all makes a lot of sense. And it
      also works on very small screens. And yes, you'll see, the minimize button DOES NOT make sense
      in GNOME Shell. Really.</para>
    <para>If you want to criticize GNOME Shell, talk about technology. I would've advocated to not
      build a new tech platform but build Shell on something like Plasma which is designed to make
      interfaces like GNOME Shell, or do like <ulink url="https://launchpad.net/unity-2d">Ubuntu did
        with Unity 2D</ulink>). But I kind'a get why they didn't, it's software 'from the other
      camp'. A more harmful thing is that they didn't get involved with the fd.o
      systray/notification rework done by KDE and Ubuntu, I see it as a big miss for GNOME Shell,
      and I'll consider it narrow-minded until I see or hear a good rationale somewhere ;-)</para>
    <para>But don't balk at the design until you've tried it with your grandmother... And in the
      end, Shell is innovative and new and will need maturing. I always have a soft spot for
      innovative and new things, it's why I like Plasma despite the issues it still has. So I do
      look forward to the final release of GNOME 3 and I'm happy that we (openSUSE/Novell) decided
      to press GNOME 3/Shell LiveDVDs as soon as the release of GNOME 3 is out. Yes, we'll also make
      KDE ones, 4.6 on openSUSE 11.4 really rocks and deserves it ;-)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 4.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
