<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="community">
  <title>In the Community</title>
  <!--Put here things relevant to the openSUSE community maybe from * People of openSUSE or elections, votings 1 - 2 posts-->
  <sect2>
    <title>Postings from the Community</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
        url="http://suseware.com/blog/2010/12/29/foss-in-day-2-3-and-during-the-holidays/"
        >Manu Gupta: FOSS.in Day 2</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>FOSS.in day 2 continued.. yes I know after a long ten big days but I was too lazy to write a blog post, so  I will summarize things quite fast over here. The second 
        day was quite good as compared to the previous days and I attended a few workshops and was able to attend and somewhat understand a few of them like MariaDB and I 
        specially liked the talk by security in mobile devices by Tobias Mueller. Yes, and I was able to get all the openSUSE DVDs given to the Delegate Kids provided by 
        FOSS.in guys and so the DVDs were too less for us :-( . The 3rd day was the worst in terms of talks for me as I could not get into a lot of talks and missed a few 
        interesting talks. Also the mediawiki miniconf turned out to be more of a waste of time rather than fun, at least for me. An Hacker’s apology by tuxmaniac was just 
        awesome and the Raghu Dixit Project totally rocked :D . I immediately boarded the train to my home after FOSS.in</para>
      <para>As I reached my home, I was again anxiously waiting for the for the next openSUSE Collab Event – Social Media and PR which was quite successful and I enjoyed it 
        thoroughly.  In the last few days I also played with the flickr api, and came up with a bunch of php based libraries. The best flickr api wrapper which I found was 
        <ulink url="http://phpflickr.com/">phpflickr</ulink>. The reasons being this guy has wonderfully wrapped all the functions of the flickr api. I played it around and used Robert Lihm’s bento theme to make a 
        photo gallery for openSUSE at my site.</para>
      <para>You can find a view of my tinkerings at <ulink url="http:// suseware.com/flick">http:// suseware.com/flick</ulink>. Man I am such a copy cat. Please give put in your comments, improvements or anything, I will really 
      appreciate it.</para>
      <para>Also, if you may notice I have come up with a new blog design, this looks much cleaner imo and finally I inserted Google ads into my blog. Also removed a host of 
      plugins that were actually not required and I had added them for fun. Finally the title shows up in the blog pages.</para>
      <para>In the past ten days I rather cleaned things up…  and yes lazed quite a bit but then I am at home :) Enjoy Guys.. A happy new year</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>People of openSUSE</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>This Week: xyz</title>
      <para>Good Guy. Glows in the night.</para>
    </blockquote>
    </sect2> -->
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Welcome new openSUSE Members</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/Izabelvalverde">Izabel Valverde
          (Izabelvalverde)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>He is involved in some Ambassadoring Projects in Project.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/teegee-tg">Thomas Gross
        (teegee-tg)</ulink></title>
      <para>He works in the Wiki, Bugzilla and OBS.</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Events &amp; Meetings</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Past</title>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink
            url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/16/openfate-screening-day-in-opensuse-project/"
            >December 20, 2010 : openFATE screening day in #opensuse-project</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/02/pr-social-media-review/">December 21,
            2010 : Marketing Collaboration Day - PR and Social Media Review</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/05/30/german-wiki-team-meeting-2/">December
            22, 2010 : German Wiki Team Meeting</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/05/13/%ef%bb%bfopensuse-kde-team-meeting/"
            >December 23, 2010 : ﻿openSUSE KDE Team meeting</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <!-- ($ ld: 23.12.10 th $) -->
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Upcoming</title>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink
            url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/13/opensuse-testing-core-team-irc-meeting-2/"
            >December 27, 2010 : openSUSE Testing Core Team IRC Meeting</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/05/30/german-wiki-team-meeting-2/">December
            29, 2010 : German Wiki Team Meeting</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <!-- ($ ld: 23.12.10 th $) -->
    <para>You can find more informations on other events at: <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/category/events/">openSUSE News/Events</ulink>. - <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Ambassadors_events">Local Events</ulink></para>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>openSUSE for your Ears</title>
    <para>The openSUSE Weekly News are available as livestream or podcast in German. You can hear it
      or download it on <ulink url="http://blog.radiotux.de/podcast">Radiotux</ulink>. </para>
  </sect2>

  <sect2>
    <title>From Ambassadors</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://opensuseambassadors.blogspot.com/2010/12/report-1-openfest-open-christmas-at.html"
          >Greek openSUSE Ambassadors: Report: 1st OpenFest Open Christmas at Florina, December 24th 2010</ulink>
      </title>
      <figure id="fig.greek">
        <title>Merry Christmas to everyone</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="http://diamond.comlu.com/suse/events/florina_24_12_10/14.jpg"
              width="25%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>Yesterday a small team of the Greek openSUSE community decided to go on a Christmas roadtrip. We traveled about 2 and a half hours to go to the beautiful border 
        town of Florina. We were invited by teachers of The Educational Computer Association of Florina to help them promote FOSS. In the central square of the city they 
        hard wooden houses with different themes (you can see the pictures). openSUSE Greek team with KLUG and a very active elementary teacher, Mr Ioannis Kaskamanidis, 
        were informing people who was interested in what we do. Mr Kaskamanidis, brought his students with their XO laptops. Kids were showing their laptops with pride 
        and giving away info packs (PromoDVDs, stickers, brochures). We also met with a local doctor, Dr Evangelos Tsoukas. He translated and supports the Electronic 
        Medical Records program called openEMR.</para>
      <para>openSUSE team was pretty happy about promoting our distro to citizens of Florina. We didn't mind that we drove 200km to reach the city or the soft rain that made 
      us to put all our equipment inside the wooden house. What is left from this event was:</para>
      <para>We did our job and we had fun!!!<xref linkend="fig.greek"/></para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 27.12.10 th $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/12/31/kokoa-and-friends-meeting-kya2010/">José Oramas M.: Kokoa and Friends Meeting (KyA2010)</ulink></title>
      <para>The first Kokoa and Friends meeting took place the 20th of December at the Computing and Electrical Department of ESPOL.</para>
      <para>This meeting supported by the openSUSE community, gathered people from different levels of the Kokoa community and the ESPOL university. From students that are just 
        getting interested in using FLOSS (a.k.a. newbies), students who are “candidates” to join the Kokoa community, the current “active” members and the experienced “senior” 
        members.</para>
      <para>In this event different topics were discussed covering FLOSS usage in the academia and the industry. Stories of success and guidelines were shared with people 
      interested in going forward in the world of FLOSS.</para>
      <para>Special thanks to Cristina Guerrero, Nervo Verdezoto, Marisol Villacrés, and from Jarflex, Adonis Figueroa and Jessica Zuñiga the speakers of this meeting and 
      specially to Arturo Tumbaco, who helped me with the logistics to make this event possible.</para>
      <para><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/12/31/kokoa-and-friends-meeting-kya2010/">Here some pictures about the meeting.</ulink></para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 31.12.10 th $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://opensuseambassadors.blogspot.com/2010/12/xarisetogr-bazaar-december-28-29-30.html"
        >Greek openSUSE Ambassadors: Xariseto.gr Bazaar, December 28-29-30, 2010 - report</ulink></title>
      <figure id="fig.greek2">
        <title>Merry Christmas to everyone</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="http://diamond.comlu.com/suse/events/florina_24_12_10/14.jpg"
              width="25%"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>On December 28-29-30, 2010, we joined the calling from our friends from the web page xariseto.gr. They had a bazaar in Hortiatis, Thessaloniki (Greece). The place 
      was far from our city but it was near for some people that live there.</para>
      <para>Many people were bringing items they didn't need, but can be used by someone else that need them. You can see on the last picture <xref linkend="fig.greek2"/> what 
        it was all about. We were there to inform people about FOSS and openSUSE. We had a lot of people asking questions about it. Mostly they didn't know that there's 
        something different than windows. We hope we made a difference even to 1 person.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 31.12.10 th $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Communication</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/">The Mailinglists</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org">The openSUSE Forums</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Contributors</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://users.opensuse.org">The User Directory</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
