<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="tipsandtricks">
  <title>Tips and Tricks</title>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Desktop Users</title>    
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxjournal.com/content/linux-fingernail">LinuxJournal/Joey Bernard:
          Linux on a Fingernail</ulink>
      </title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://www.linuxjournal.com/files/linuxjournal.com/ufiles/imagecache/node-page/nodeimage/story/10969pocketf1.inline_2.jpg"/>
        </imageobject>        
      </mediaobject>
      <para>This issue of <emphasis role="italic">Linux Journal</emphasis> is all about how to get
        Linux in your pocket. In this article, I go one better and tell you how to get Linux on your
        fingernail. Now, before you get too excited, I won't be discussing some new nano-computer
        being used by James Bond, unfortunately. Instead, I discuss how to put Linux on a micro-SD
        card (or any other USB drive, for that matter). Using this, you can run Linux on any machine
        that can boot off a USB device. </para>
      <para>One of the first utilities to receive widespread attention and use is UNetbootin (<ulink
          url="http://unetbootin.sourceforge.net">http://unetbootin.sourceforge.net</ulink>). This
        application is available under both Linux and Windows. It has built-in support for
        downloading and installing several Linux distributions, including Ubuntu, Fedora, Debian,
        PCLinuxOS, Linux Mint, Sabayon Linux, openSUSE, Gentoo, Arch Linux, MEPIS and many others.
        (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 1.5.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxjournal.com/content/using-styles-scribus">LinuxJournal/Bruce Byfield: Using Styles in Scribus</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>If you don&apos;t include master pages (which are really styles under another name), then
        Scribus supports three types of hierarchial styles: lines, character, and paragraph. As in
        any other self-respecting word processor or layout application, these styles allow you to
        apply detailed sets of formatting options quickly, without having to change each instance of
        a formatting option individually. However, styles are implemented idiosyncratically in
        Scribus, so they can take time to learn, even if you are familiar with the basic concept
        from other applications.</para>
      <para>One of the conceptual problems you may have is that styles are defined and applied in
        different places in the editing window. To define and manage styles, you open the Style
        Manager, by selecting Edit -&gt; Styles or pressing the F3 key. However, to apply styles,
        you either select Properties from the right-click menu of a selected object or press the F2
        key. For paragraph styles, you also have the option of selecting Edit Text from the
        right-click menu of a selected text frame, or selecting Ctrl+T to open the Story
        Editor.</para>
<!--($ ld: 27.4.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.unixmen.com/linux-tutorials/1659-31-best-tutorials-of-inkscape">Unixmen/ayesha ahmed: 31 Great Tutorials for Inkscape! </ulink>
      </title>
      <para><ulink url="http://www.inkscape.org/">Inkscape</ulink> is an open source vector graphics editor. Inkscape is cross-platform and runs on Unix based OS, Windows and Mac (typically under X11). In this post we have inkscape_logoattempted to gather some best tutorials around the web, categorizing them into various groups, organized from novice users to advance level. If you have not installed inkscape then you can follow the following tutorial. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 30.4.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Commandline/Script Newbies</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxaria.com/howto/check-your-disk-usage-with-df-and-du?lang=en">Linuxaria: Check your disk usage with df and du</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>As system administrator , but also as common user on my PC, one of the more common problem is the fill up at 100% of a filesystem.
So, in this article we’ll see 2 commands that can help us in keeping under control or check the space used in every filesystem and in his directory.

</para>
      <para>df : report file system disk space usage

</para>
      <para>du: estimate file space usage (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
<!-- ($ Id: 30.4.11 sat $)-->  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Developers and Programmers</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://net.tutsplus.com/tutorials/other/a-deeper-look-at-mod_rewrite-for-apache/">net tuts+/Joseph Pecoraro: An In Depth Guide to mod_rewrite for Apache</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>When people think of .htaccess configuration, the first thing that might pop into their minds is URL manipulation with mod_rewrite. But they’re often frustrated by mod_rewrite’s complexity. This tutorial will walk you through everything you need to know for the most common mod_rewrite tasks. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 30.4.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For System Administrators</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.novell.com/communities/node/12811/ssh-keygen-password-less-ssh-login-script"
          >Novell Cool Solutions/jmeldrum: ssh-keygen: password-less SSH login script</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">license</emphasis>: 
GPLv2

</para>
      <para>This utility uses ssh-keygen and ssh_copy_id to create RSA private/public key pairs for use by SSH protocol version 1 and RSA or DSA keys for use by SSH protocol version 2. The public key is then copied onto a remote system. You can now SSH to the remote system without the use of a password from the specified machine.

</para>
      <para>If the file /etc/root/.ssh/authorized_keys exists on the destination system, you probably already have it setup.

</para>
      <para>For more information see the man pages for ssh-keygen and ssh_copy_id. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 30.4.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
