<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="status-updates">
  <title>Status Updates</title>
<!--
  <sect2 role="board">
    <title>Board</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>openSUSE Weekly News searches for contributors</title>
      <para></para>
    </blockquote>
    </sect2> --><!--
  <sect2 role="board">
    <title>openSUSE Project</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>Meeting Minutes: Projectmeeting 4.5.2011</title>
      <para>Meeting started by henne at 18:09:00 UTC</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://community.opensuse.org/meetings/opensuse-project/2011/opensuse-project.2011-05-04-18.09.txt">Summary</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://community.opensuse.org/meetings/opensuse-project/2011/opensuse-project.2011-05-04-18.09.log.html">Full Log</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </blockquote>
    </sect2> -->  <sect2 role="distribution">
    <title>Distribution</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/07/01/factory-progress-2011-07-01/">Andreas
          Jaeger: Factory Progress 2011-07-01</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Here’s with some delay the next incarnation of Factory Progress. I’ve noticed the
        following changes that might interest people using and developing openSUSE Factory:</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Package changes</emphasis></para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Linux 3.0</emphasis></para>
      <para>Linux kernel 3.0 rc5 is currently on its way to factory and the header files (in package
        linux-glibc-devel) have already been updated for it. If your software reads the Linux kernel
        version, please check that it can cope with the two digits instead of the three of the new
        version. Best would be to not read the version at all.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">systemd</emphasis></para>
      <para>Frederic has proposed a “<ulink
          url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-factory/2011-06/msg00210.html">Road to systemd for
          openSUSE 12.1″</ulink>. Systemd is a replacement of the SysVinit scripts that we have been
        using and improving in the past with many new – including some controversial – ideas. Check
        his blog post for additional references about systemd. The majority of the distributions are
        moving to systemd as well and standarizing on it, will allow to share some more code and
        development in this area.</para>
      <para>We’re now in phase 1 – which means: Get systemd running as an option. Once this is
        working satisfactory, we can switch the default (phase 2) and decide what to do with
        SysVinit support.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">No static glibc libraries</emphasis></para>
      <para>The C library glibc now does not come anymore with static libraries, those are in the
        new glibc-devel-static subpackage.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Python 3.2</emphasis></para>
      <para>The python3 package is now at version 3.2, the most important change in Python 3.2 is
        the implementation of “PEP 384, a stable ABI for extension modules” which means that with
        3.2 and upwards there won’t be any API breakages for modules which is really important
        developer wise.</para>
      <para>Another big improvement is the new GIL (Global Interpreter Lock) implementation which
        will speed up threaded Python code. Python 3.2 also introduces “futures” library which is
        used for concurrent programming, this will be useful more multi-core Python
        development.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Tomoyo</emphasis></para>
      <para>Tomoyo is a MAC (Mandatory Access Control) implementation for Linux – so an alternative
        to AppArmor and SELinux. openSUSE’s Linux kernel does now come with the module and also the
        tools were updated to support this.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Policy and tool changes</emphasis></para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">New Source Service mode activated and recompression of tar
          balls</emphasis></para>
      <para>The<ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-packaging/2011-06/msg00028.html"> new
          source service mode has been activated</ulink>, it is recommended to update to osc 0.132
        version as available in the openSUSE:Tools project to work with source services. Now the
        download URL given in source link is checked, so it has to be accurate. If you downloaded
        and recompressed a tarball, read Coolo’s <ulink
          url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-packaging/2011-06/msg00182.html">policy
          change</ulink>: “please don’t recompress tarballs unless it saves &gt;1MB for
        download.”.</para>
      <para>He also mentions:</para>
      <blockquote>
        <para>What will become policy sooner or later is that you should not have incorrect source
          URLs behind Source*, so _if_ you have to recompress, don’t lie in the</para>
        <para> Source line, but put the original tar as comment and use local file names in
          Source:</para>
      </blockquote>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Dropping a package from Factory</emphasis></para>
      <para>Vincent explained  <ulink
          url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-factory/2011-06/msg00177.html">How/why/when to
          drop a package from Factory</ulink>.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Release notes in FATE</emphasis></para>
      <para>To make it easier to write release notes, it helps a lot, if you (= the so-called
        stakeholders) would provide a release notes snippet in the future using openFATE. We can
        then collect all those release notes and edit them.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Other interesting bits</emphasis></para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">openSUSE Conference</emphasis></para>
      <para>The call for papers is continuing to run, please submit session proposals at the <ulink
          url="http://conference.opensuse.org/indico/">conference site</ulink>. If you like to learn
        what a BoF is, read this <ulink
          url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/14/opensuse-conference-and-rw-sessions-the-bof/"
          >article</ulink>.</para>
      <!--($ ld: 2.7.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blog.crozat.net/2011/07/status-update-on-systemd-for-opensuse.html"
          >Frédéric Crozat: Status update on systemd for openSUSE Factory</ulink></title>
      <para>here is a update on the work done on systemd for Factory :</para>
      <para><itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>basic support for systemctl in chkconfig and insserv is done : it is pending
              review by maintainer before integration</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>support for --root in systemctl was merged upstream and will be used by
              chkconfig/insserv patches above.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>a patch has been submitted to upstream systemd to parse insserv.conf : this patch
              only handles the "system facility" part of insserv.conf and automatically adds
              depencies specified in the file</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>quick investigation on Yast2 to adapt runlevel editor for systemctl support : we
              really need help from other people, as I don't have any knowledge of Yast internal and
              it seems the yast dbus client part might be missing some parts, needed for runlevel
              editor to talk with systemd.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>no work done on /usr as separate partition : it is not a systemd issue in itself
              but from other programs which might be using data from /usr before /usr is available.
              The best solution would be to mount /usr from initrd =&gt; help needed !!</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>(open)SUSE is using unofficial LSB target named $ALL which is supposed to put
              services requiring it at the end of the boot sequence (or at the beginning of shutdown
              sequence); After discussing with upstream : on a static boot system (sysvinit), it is
              easy to resolve such dependencies, but it isn't on a dynamic system (systemd). There
              is a ugly hack to handle that (creating a ALL.target file which is starting after
              default.target is done) but it would be probably better to just fix the 4 initscripts
              which are still using $ALL ( amazon-late, stoppreload, Susefirewall2_setup and
              vboxes). I'll open bug for them.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>X-Interactive support in systemd is not working properly : it will only work
              before getty is started and is broken if you try to start a service after boot. We
              need to transition packages which are still using X-Interactive to
              systemd-ask-password (which takes care of the async conversation). Only two packages
              need to be ported :<itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>apache2, when querying password for SSL certificate : apache allows to start
                    a script to handle the password request. We only need to plug the script and
                    configuration part in our package</para>
                  <para> and get it used when booting with systemd.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>openvpn : this one is a bit complex because we can either write a daemon
                    which would do the interface between systemd and openvpn management interface or
                    we can try to patch openvpn to have a similar feature as apache and get this
                    patch upstreamed. The latter has the preference of systemd upstream.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>For both packages, help is welcome.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>For compability with sysvinit, support for from /etc/insserv.conf in systemd
                    was not added, so we could remove X-Interactive from openvpn/httpd sysvinit
                    scripts but still have the function when booting from /sbin/init, thanks to
                    /etc/insserv.conf list.</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist></para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>/etc/init.d/kbd was not handled properly : this should be fixed inFactory today or
              tomorrow, with systemd taking care of setting up keyboard properly. However, we might
              need to improve /etc/sysconfig/keyboard parsing in systemd. More tests are needed (and
              of course, help is welcome).</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>discussion in progress on opensuse-packaging mailing list and upstream on a set of
              cross distribution RPM macros to handle systemd unit files. </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>As you can see, we still have some work to do, but we need everybody help :
        either on the issues I mentioned (feel free to say "I want to help on this" here) or to do
        more tests or even to start creating .service files (but we still need to fix the issues
        listed above). </para>
      <para> Thanks everybody for your attention.</para>
      <para> I would be great if we could get the ball moving and maybe get one of the next Factory
        milestone be a "systemd" test release but to reach this point, we need YOU !</para>
      <!--($ ld: 2.7.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Important Links</title>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://tinyurl.com/392jnb">Detailed Bugzilla Report</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Submitting_bug_reports">Submitting Bug Reports</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Bug_reporting_FAQ">Bug Reporting FAQ</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
  <sect2 role="susestudio">
    <title>SUSE Studio</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/2011/06/29/smbta-stresstest-0-0-4-appliance-features-smb-traffic-analyzer-1-2-5-and-runs-websmbta-out-of-the-box/">Holger Hetterich: SMBTA Stresstest 0.0.4 appliance features SMB Traffic Analyzer 1.2.5 and runs webSMBTA out of the box</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>
        <figure>
          <title>A browser showing webSMBTA, connected to a SMBTA Stresstest 0.0.4 virtual machine.</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata width="30%" fileref="http://holger123.files.wordpress.com/2011/06/smbta-websmbta-vm1.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </para>
      <para>Ever wanted to just try <ulink url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/smb-traffic-analyzer/">SMB Traffic Analyzer</ulink>
          to<emphasis role="bold"> see what it can do for you</emphasis>, but have been hindered
          by<emphasis role="italic">
          <emphasis role="bold">the hassle of setup and configuration?</emphasis>
        </emphasis> Today the SMBTA team released<ulink url="http://susegallery.com/a/tLEB1d/smbta-stresstest-smbtad"> SMBTA Stresstest 0.0.4</ulink>, a complete self containing appliance to be run by your virtualization
        software, such as <ulink url="http://www.vmware.com/">vmware</ulink> or <ulink url="http://www.virtualbox.org/">VirtualBox</ulink>.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="italic">
          <emphasis role="bold">It has never been easier to give SMBTA a try.</emphasis>
        </emphasis></para>
      <figure id="smbtamonitor">
        <title>An instance of the smbtamonitor real time program running against SMBTA Stresstest 0.0.4 in VirtualBox.</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata width="30%" fileref="http://holger123.files.wordpress.com/2011/06/smbta-monitor-vm.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>Just <ulink url="http://susegallery.com/a/tLEB1d/smbta-stresstest-smbtad">download the OVF image</ulink> we provide via <ulink url="http://susegallery.com/browse">SUSE Gallery</ulink>, setup your virtual machine to have network access, and point your web
        browser to the hostname or IP adress of your virtual machine. Also, you can run all real
        time clients such as the <xref linkend="smbtamonitor"/>smbtamonitor program, or our
        interface to rrdtool, rrddriver, against SMBTA Stresstest 0.0.4. It has an open port for
        real time clients on port number 3491.</para>
      <para>At the very first connect to webSMBTA, a configuration dialog will appear, asking the
        user to which database the connection has to be made. To run with SMBTA Stresstest 0.0.4,
        just fill out the form exactly like given in the screenshot.</para>
      <para>
        <figure id="websmbta">
          <title>At the very first connection to webSMBTA, use these parameters to connect to the database in SMBTA Stresstest.</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="http://holger123.files.wordpress.com/2011/06/websmbta-config.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </para>
      <para>SMBTA Stresstest 0.0.4 comes with a preinstalled<ulink url="http://www.samba.org"> Samba</ulink> server, is configured to host three shares on that server, and generates
        constant data traffic by six users that are running <ulink url="http://morelias.org/smbta/smbta-guide.html#_smbtatorture">smbtatorture</ulink>
        instances, a program we developed to test SMBTA. Thanks to the hard work of <emphasis role="bold">Benjamin Brunner</emphasis> on this release, the <ulink url="http://morelias.org/smbta/smbta-guide.html#_websmbta">webSMBTA component</ulink><xref linkend="websmbta"/> is running out of the box in this release, hosted by an Apache
        webserver.</para>
      <para>This release is based on our latest and greatest <ulink url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/2011/05/28/smb-traffic-analyzer-1-2-5-released/">stable release of SMB Traffic Analyzer, version 1.2.5</ulink>, and the rest of the
        software stack based on <ulink url="http://www.opensuse.org">openSUSE 11.4</ulink>. Needless
        to say: This release of SMBTA Stresstest was created with the fabulous <ulink url="http://susestudio.com/">SUSE Studio</ulink>!</para>
      <para>You can <ulink url="http://susegallery.com/a/tLEB1d/smbta-stresstest-smbtad">download the SMBTA Stresstest appliance</ulink> from <ulink url="http://susestudio.com/">SUSE Studio</ulink>, more information on the <ulink url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/smb-traffic-analyzer/">SMB Traffic Analyzer project</ulink> is <ulink url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/smb-traffic-analyzer/">available here</ulink>.</para>
<!--($ ld: 30.6.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://blog.susestudio.com/2011/06/using-autoyast-for-customizing-your.html">SUSE Studio: Using AutoYaST for customizing your appliance on first boot</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>When building appliances with SUSE Studio, I was often challenged with finding a way to
        configuring an appliance on first boot. The most common use cases like locale, time zone and
        network configuration are being offered by Studio already.</para>
      <para><inlinegraphic fileref="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-jAoJzRg6ZIA/TgxR_1f9qJI/AAAAAAAAAkg/fXPg4KzhxaU/s320/ask-on-firstboot.png"/></para>
      <para>Selecting these options will make Studio include the required packages and configuration
        to guide the user through a YaST workflow on first boot.</para>
      <para>But is there an easy way for further customizing your application on first boot? Yes,
        there is! Enter&#160;<emphasis role="bold">AutoYaST</emphasis>&#160;and it&apos;s powerful &quot;Ask the user
        for values during installation&quot; feature.</para>
      <para>Switch to the Configuration tab, select Scripts and check the &quot;Run AutoYaST profile on
        appliance&apos;s first boot&quot; option.</para>
      <para><inlinegraphic fileref="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-UOJTJl54NU8/TgxVJQ42_nI/AAAAAAAAAko/tfjYTaxSLkk/s320/autoyast-firstboot.png"/></para>
      <para>Next we need to create the AutoYaST profile, which will be run on first boot. The
        profile format is an ASCII XML file.</para>
      <para>Here is a simple example, that will create a simple ask dialoge &quot;Enter the user for this
        machine&quot; and promt for input. The result will be writen to /tmp/answer_user. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 1.7.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2 role="teamreports">
    <title>Team Reports</title>
<!--
    <sect3 role="artteam">
      <title>Art Team</title>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/01/13/wallpaper-community-pack-1/">Nelson
            Marques: Wallpaper Community Pack #1</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>I’ve received some emails and some positive feedback about one wallpaper I used for a
          couple of screenshot’s I’ve used in the past, including also information requests about
          where that very same wallpaper could be found. I’m happy people liked my choice. </para>
      </blockquote>
    </sect3> --><!--
    <sect3 role="boosters">
      <title>Boosters Team</title>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/29/opensuse-boosters-year-2010/">openSUSE
            Boosters Year 2010</ulink>
        </title>
        <figure id="fig.boosters">
          <title>The elusive Thirsty Thirteen</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata width="50%" align="center"
                fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/Opensuse-boosters-300x200.jpg"
              />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>At the end of the year it is the time for reviews and the openSUSE Booster <xref
            linkend="fig.boosters"/> team did not want to let that opportunity slip. So what was
          important in 2010 from an openSUSE Boosters perspective? What happened, what progress was
          made, how did the boosters help openSUSE? A report from Klaas Freitag.</para>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Who are the Boosters</emphasis></para>
        <para>For those who do not know who <ulink
            url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Boosters_team">the Boosters</ulink> are: We’re not
          Tuxies favorite boy group, but a bunch of people dedicated to help the openSUSE Project in
          any way we can. The team consists of 13 people (BTW: widely known as the thirsty thirteen)
          with skills ranging from low level C hackery over Ruby on Rails mastering to Graphical
          Design or Project Management. Our team picks milestones and works on them in a agile
          fashion while always following our mantra: Grow community by enabling community. You can
          meet us at the usual places like IRC, the mailinglists or events were we show up and
          spread the word about openSUSE. We’re there to make contributors life easier and more fun,
          so if you have anything do not hesitate to talk to us. We’re here for you.</para>
        <para role="bold"><emphasis role="bold">Events in 2010</emphasis></para>
        <para>So let’s quickly fly over the year of 2010 and see what was nice and important.</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>FOSDEM</para>
            <para>Lets start with a very important event, FOSDEM in Brussels in February. We
              traveled there by coach the first time. That was remarkable because there were some
              push back against before (long journey) but we did it because it is cheaper, which
              means more people can go. The result was that we all were quite pleased by the coach
              trip as it was comfortable and fun, and finally not so much longer than the flight.
              And yes, consider how much carbon dioxide was saved? Since that trip I am constantly
              nagging for budget for an openSUSE Coach…</para>
            <para>I held a talk about Hermes at FOSDEM which was, well, not a great success, that
              thing seems hard to market. That happens, others were more succesfull, like
              Christopher with his talk about image building with Kiwi. Michal had a meeting with
              MySQL packagers from all over the world at FOSDEM, which was probably the first real
              initiative to collaborate on cross distro topics. I also bought a GNOME T-Shirt, met
              tons of old friends, had cherry beer and got a cold as usual on FOSDEM.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Dev meeting</para>
            <para>Also in February, we hosted a dev meeting of 25 KDE hackers here in the Nuremberg
              office. They worked on the highly rated plasma workspace for KDE 4.5. I still wonder
              how Will managed to get around with definitely no sleep for days.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Bento and wiki work</para>
            <para>At home, at the beginning of the year we worked on projects called
                <quote>Integrate all Infrastructure under one Umbrella</quote> which resulted in the
              Bento web theme nowadays at all openSUSE sites use. It provides short ways from one
              site to another by thought through and pretty menus. Robert did a real great job with
              that and we got a lot of external recognition for it. At the same time the Wiki
              project started which was a huge project the Wiki community was pulling together with
              Henne and Tom. The decision was to create a new Wiki from scratch, implement reviewing
              features and transfer all relevant content into the new one while making sure to not
              transfer stuff nobody needs and maintains any more. That was a big thing and caused a
              lot of discussion. Today we can look back and say that we now have a well structured
              Wiki with valuable content. Fortune favors the bold :-)</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>OBS</para>
            <para>In parallel to that, Coolo and Tom were contributing to the new BuildService
                <ulink url="http://build.opensuse.org">web interface</ulink>. After long working
              hours we finally came out with a great web interface for OBS which was a big bum for
              the whole project, as it makes working in OBS much more fun. I remember that whole
              thing being started as a sprint called “Factory status”, aiming to provide a good
                <ulink url="https://build.opensuse.org/projectstatus?project=openSUSE%3AFactory"
                >overview page</ulink> for the Factory project in OBS. It grew a bit more ambitions,
              but, well, that’s how it goes if things are in movement ;-)</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>LinuxTag</para>
            <para>In June, there was LinuxTag in Berlin where most of us participated with talks in
              the free program or workshops on our booth. We educated a lot of people how to
              contribute to openSUSE in various ways. From submitting code fixes through the Build
              Service to creating great Geeko graphics with Inkscape to how to twist their own Geeko
              out of pipe cleaners.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>openSUSE 11.3</para>
            <para>In July, openSUSE 11.3 was released. That was lots of work beforehand with quite
              some boosters involvement, as Mr. Distro Coolo is part of the team. However not only
              he is contributing to the distribution, we all have our shares in it. 11.3 was a good
              one, it got good press and showed that we as a community are doing great. All over the
              world release parties were organized, some Boosters took over the one here in
              Nürnberg. <ulink
                url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/07/16/opensuse-11-3-launch-party-in-nurnberg/"
                >Nice party</ulink> with some talks, along with BBQ and beer. The latter ran out at
              7pm, because many community members showed up. Cool, I love that kind of stress to
              organize food and beer quickly to let the party go on :-)</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>GNOME and KDE conferences</para>
            <para>Also in Summer, GUADEC as well as Akademy took place for our desktop Boosters.
              Vincent rocked GUADEC and gave away Geekos and stuff and advertised openSUSE as a good
              platform for the upcoming GNOME3. Will could not go to Akademy this year for a very
              good reason called Anna :-)</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>openSUSE conference</para>
            <para>In autumn, the for me most exciting event of the year took place, the second
                <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Conference">openSUSE Conference</ulink>.
              We were heavily involved in organizing, program committee work, giving talks and
              presentations and all what is involved with that kind of large event. It was a huge
              success, as a very active and passionate community showed up. Discussions went from a
                <quote>This is what we did</quote> in the last year to a <quote>this is what we
                could do</quote> which is so great to see as that is resulting in innovation for the
              whole project. As a result some very concrete sub projects were created such as
                <quote>Project Brezn</quote> and openSUSE Invis which slowly evolves.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>openFATE, Connect and more</para>
            <para>After the conference and the release of 11.3 we started to dig into milestones
              again with <ulink url="http://features.opensuse.org">openFATE</ulink> and <ulink
                url="http://connect.opensuse.org">Connect</ulink>. Since a couple of weeks we have a
              nice looking openFATE that has the features that make it possible for the feature
              screening team to work on one of our most important tasks in our project: Looking into
              the future of the distribution with feature evaluation. We also implemented the future
              of the user/group handling for all the openSUSE services with a social twist: Connect.
              Our own instance of a social network that makes it possible to connect the people that
              make this project what it is and at the same time makes it possible to centralize the
              user data.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Busy 2010</emphasis></para>
        <para>So all in all the boosters had a very busy and prosperous year 2010. All of us carried
          their individual share of work in the various areas of the openSUSE project we participate
          in, be it in the openSUSE KDE and GNOME Teams, the openSUSE Distribution, the openSUSE
          tools or the openSUSE Board. We attended a lot of events and organized a couple of our own
          with great success. And we worked together on the most pressing milestones we saw for
          contributor growth in a fun and clever way. All in all we helped a lot of contributors to
          stand up, take responsibility and do get their hands dirty for the openSUSE Project. That
          makes us proud and we will do this smarter, faster, better and stronger in 2011.
          Promised!</para>
      </blockquote>
      </sect3> -->    
    <sect3 role="buildserviceteam">
      <title>Build Service Team</title>
      <!--
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/archive/opensuse-buildservice/2011-06/msg00134.html">OBS 2.3 Beta 2</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>This OBS 2.3 release is now feature complete. We changed a bit more then expected:<itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>New source service mode handling is default now. Server side services get
                applied when listing in expand mode, like with source links.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Configuration UI to setup OBS instance name and description.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>MeeGo.com is pre-configured now.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>backend daemons have integrated runtime management</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>A large number of bugfixes</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist></para>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Current State</emphasis></para>
        <para>Open tasks for next weeks are:<itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Get documentation in a better shape so that we can switch openSUSE maintenance
                using the new mechanisms.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>There are absolute zero known regressions known atm. So really everything should
                be at least as good as in OBS 2.1.x :) Feel free to run it on your production
                system, we do it also on build.opensuse.org :)</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist></para>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">The call for help</emphasis></para>
        <para>There are still a number of areas where some clean up is needed. For example we have<itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>20 FIXME2.2 lines in the code (means that read access handling code needs
                checking)</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>10 FIXME2.3 lines in the code (maintenance code needs a revisit here)</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Unknown state of Cross architecture builds. It would be nice if someone can help
                so that the OBS Appliance can build for arm architectures out of the box.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist></para>
        <para>You can stop here when you read already Beta 1 announcement ,)</para>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">OBS 2.3 main features</emphasis></para>
        <para>The main features of this release are <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Full distribution maintenance support. This includes support for the workflow in
                OBS and also the patch channel generation. This functionality can be used at full
                glance with coordination and review teams or just in parts.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Read access protection for projects (as planned for OBS 2.2)</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist></para>
        <para>Apart from that we have many smaller improvements, esp. in the area of request
          handling and the webui integration.</para>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Download it</emphasis></para>
        <para>As usual, you find current packages or an appliance in openSUSE:Tools:Unstable
          project. OBS 2.3 Beta 2 is tagged as version 2.2.84. </para>
        <para>Please read here for usage details for the appliance:<ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Build_Service_Appliance">http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Build_Service_Appliance</ulink> (...)</para>
      </blockquote>
      -->
      <formalpara>
        <title>Build Service Statistics</title>
        <para>Statistics can found at <ulink url="http://build.opensuse.org">Buildservice</ulink></para>
      </formalpara>
    </sect3>
<!--
    <sect3 role="evergreen">
      <title>Evergreen</title>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="http://www.rosenauer.org/blog/2011/04/17/evergreen-status-after-some-months/">Wolfgang Rosenauer: Evergreen status after some months</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>I’ve just noticed that I haven’t written about <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Evergreen">Evergreen</ulink> here since the
          beginning. I actually did post at least one status update on our list but I think it would
          be good to give some information to a wider audience (hoping that this blog is read by
          more people).</para>
        <para>In general we are in good shape. Up to now we have released around 55 source updates.
          You can find the list <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Evergreen_11.1">here</ulink>. So looking back that means that we were able to update almost everything
          including desktop applications which was not clear in the beginning how that would work
          out. Also the Packman team decided to support Evergreen by keeping the Essentials
          repository available. Unfortunately it is not quite usable at the moment since it contains
          RPM packages signed with keys not supported by the RPM version in 11.1 which means zypper
          refuses to install those.</para>
        <para>Another milestone is that it seems we will also support 11.2 when it runs out of
          Novell’s maintenance on May 12th, 2011. Another community member agreed to lead the
          effort. More details on that to come soon.</para>
        <para>But not everything is working perfectly fine though. Besides some rare cases where
          community members submitted packages to Evergreen/11.1 all the backporting/packaging work
          up to now was done by myself. At some points in time I was quite on the limit of my time
          for the project and there is no redundancy if something bad happens to me. We really need
          more people contributing to Evergreen. That said it would be really nice if maintainers
          (especially community maintainers) would prepare updates for 11.1 as well. Obviously there
          is no obligation in doing so but I somehow think that in some cases they are just missing
          the fact that Evergreen exists at all.</para>
        <para>So if anyone out there has interest in helping maintaining 11.1 and/or 11.2 please
          contact us through our <ulink url="http://lists.rosenauer.org/mailman/listinfo/evergreen">mailinglist</ulink> or contact me directly.</para>
    </blockquote>
    </sect3> --><!--
    <sect3 role="education">
      <title>Education Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3>

    <sect3 role="forums">
      <title>Forums Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
      </sect3> -->    <sect3 role="gnometeam">
      <title>GNOME Team</title>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="http://www.marques.so/2011/06/banshee-2-1-0-for-opensuse/">Nelson Marques: Banshee 2.1.0 for openSUSE</ulink>
        </title>
        <para><inlinegraphic fileref="http://www.marques.so/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/Screenshot-Banshee-Media-Player.png"/></para>
        <para>I’ve finally updated Banshee to 2.1.0 on Banshee:Unstable. Unfortunatly this took longer
          than I expected because of the changes involved on this package. From this version on the
          package was renamed to ‘<emphasis role="bold">banshee</emphasis>‘ (previously banshee-1), and
          there’s also a few changes in the sub-packages which should be transparent to most
          users.</para>
        <para>My advice for the users who are subscribed to this repository is to remove current
          installed packages, which can be done through: </para>
        <programlisting>rpm -e `rpm -qa | grep banshee-1`</programlisting>
        <para>and then install again the repository through the 1-Click installer (make sure the mirror
          you’re downloading from is already updated).</para>
        <para>For users who want to subscribe for the repository to check out this nice version of
          Banshee, you can do it through the following steps (using openSUSE 11.4 example):</para>
        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Install the repository:
            <programlisting>zypper ar http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/Banshee:/Unstable/Banshee_openSUSE_11.4/Banshee:Unstable.repo</programlisting></para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Install Banshee 2.1.0:
            <programlisting>zypper install banshee banshee-core</programlisting></para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
        <para>Banshee 2.1.0 won’t be available for SLE11 and SLE11SP1 due to dependencies (ex:
          gstreamer). This version is also being submitted to Factory on the next days. This version
          introduces:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>eMusic Store;</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>ArtworkManager enhancements;</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>51 notable bug fixes.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
<!--($ ld: 26.6.11 sm $)-->      </blockquote>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="http://www.marques.so/2011/06/new-package-submitted-to-gnomeapps-synapse/">Nelson Marques: New package submitted to GNOME:Apps – Synapse</ulink>
        </title>
        <para><inlinegraphic fileref="http://www.marques.so/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/Screenshot-synapse.png"/></para>
        <para>I’ve written about <ulink url="http://launchpad.net/synapse-project">synapse</ulink> in
          the past and it was one of the applications I wanted to add to GNOME:Ayatana. With the awesome
          work from several people from the openSUSE GNOME Team, most of the dependencies are now
          provided in Factory, so it’s really a nice time to submit this application to GNOME:Apps and
          hope it ends up in openSUSE Factory/openSUSE 11.2.</para>
        <para>Synapse is a semantic launcher that allows to search for applications, locations, files,
          etc. It is written in Vala and uses the Zeitgeist engine. It’s really a cool application and
          it’s battle tested with GNOME 3. The only less positive part is the fact it’s not yet ported
          to GTK3. It can provide an awesome alternative to the “ALT+F2″ macro.</para>
        <para>Hope everyone enjoys… and I know that a few people were already waiting for an opportunity
          to give it a test ride… Let’s see how the review goes (unless something strange happens, it
          should get green light).</para>
        <para><inlinegraphic fileref="http://www.marques.so/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/Screenshot1.png"/></para>
        <para>Anyone who gives it a test ride and wants to deploy some feedback, it will be gladly
          accepted! My test package is available on my <ulink url="http://bit.ly/lIE0OZ">home project</ulink> in OBS (and hopefully available soon in GNOME:Apps).</para>
<!--($ ld: 26.6.11 sm $)-->      </blockquote>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="http://www.marques.so/2011/06/gnomeayatana-indicators-for-opensuse-11-4/">Nelson Marques: GNOME:Ayatana indicators for openSUSE 11.4</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>Over a year ago when I initially joined the openSUSE Marketing Team I wanted to write
          an article about OBS (back then <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Build_Service">openSUSE Build Service</ulink>, now <ulink url="http://open-build-service.org/">Open Build Service</ulink>) and my biggest problem was to realize what OBS was and what it
          really did… My first package was a ZX Spectrum emulator (fuse) and libspectrum, which I
          still have on my repo due to emotional reasons. But that wasn’t actually good enough to
          get my stuff done and the article was postponed many times until I had no interest in
          performing such article.</para>
        <para>The whole thing about GNOME:Ayatana came during my pursue to knowledge around OBS and
          get some experience, and to be honest it became very addictive as things were going on.
          During this entire time, I’ve learned a lot about <ulink url="http://www.gnome.org">GNOME</ulink>, the technology behind GNOME and how a Linux Desktop works at low level.
          It was one of the most enriching experience I’ve had as a hobby. Above all, as it’s <ulink url="http://www.opensuse.org">openSUSE</ulink> tradition, it was fun, though it had also
          some moments of frustration, many of them softened out members of the openSUSE GNOME Team
          help and availability to help. My gratitude lies with them all, some months after, I
          reached a point I never believed I would in knowledge about the stuff I like,
          GNOME.</para>
        <para>If I was to label this experience, I would claim it has been a ‘one man inglorious
          rush’ from my side and a challenge to Dimstar’s patience, my reviewer and at some point my
          mentor (that’s how I see him), I am sure it wouldn’t happen without his encouragement,
          patience and availability to help (which is why I admire him, because I know he’s a really
          busy person).(...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 29.6.11 sm $)-->      </blockquote>
<!--
      <blockquote>
        <title>GNOME Team Meeting</title>
        <para>Meeting started by vuntz at 15:34:39 UTC.<itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para><ulink url="http://community.opensuse.org/meetings/opensuse-gnome/2011/opensuse-gnome.2011-05-05-15.34.txt">Summary</ulink></para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para><ulink url="http://community.opensuse.org/meetings/opensuse-gnome/2011/opensuse-gnome.2011-05-05-15.34.log.html">Full Log</ulink></para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist></para>
          </blockquote>-->    </sect3>
    <sect3 role="kdeteam">
      <title>KDE Team</title>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="http://vizzzion.org/blog/2011/06/new-plasma-active-window-switcher/">Sebastian Kügler: New Plasma Active Window Switcher</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>Last week, Marco and I have integrated a new window switcher into Plasma Active. We
          had designed and started to implement this rather central component of the shell during
          the Tokamak sprint a couple of weeks ago, now it finally made its way into Active, so you
          can update your system to the latest packages and enjoy it. (In order for it to work
          correctly, you’ll have to delete your plasma-tablet-appletsrc file, as we do not update
          these automatically at this stage of development). The new window switcher works very
          well, and is quite snazzy on top of that. It also contains an application launcher! I’ve
          recorded a small <ulink url="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IgdnuxcUcWg">demo video</ulink> showing these new features. Look at: <ulink url="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IgdnuxcUcWg">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IgdnuxcUcWg</ulink></para>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Window Strip</emphasis></para>
        <para>The idea is to have a non-modal interface, which means that the window switcher does
          not block, but allows to interact with other applications that are currently in focus. For
          this, we use a panel which can be dragged down partly or completely from the top,
          revealing a strip of windows that is horizontally flickable with the finger. This way, it
          works for only a few windows, but also scales quite well for those that want to have more
          apps open at the same time.</para>
        <para>The implementation is a bit hacky, but only in the background. It is in fact a
          combination of QML and KWin’s compositing effects. We are basically catching move events,
          &quot;polishing&quot; these into a more straight stream of events which we then pass to KWin, asking
          the window manager to paint thumbnails of the windows at a given position. While we didn’t
          know if it would work at all when we came up with this design, luckily it turned out to be
          nice and very usable.</para>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">App Launcher</emphasis></para>
        <para>The new panel also has an app launcher, which allows you to launch an app. As the user
          might potentially have lots of apps installed, there’s a &quot;tag cloud&quot; which lists
          categories of apps (you tap on one and it shows only apps in the category), and a search
          field you can use to find apps. (There’s a theming problem which affects readability in
          the tag cloud, we’ll fix that shortly.) As the number of apps available might not fit into
          the available screen space, you can flick the apps grid horizontally to reveal more
          apps.</para>
        <para>These features have already been merged into the KDE:Active packages on the Open Build
          Service, and you’ll be able to try them on your device with the next <ulink url="http://open-slx.com/?Downloads">Balsam Professional Live image</ulink>. </para>
        <para>What do you think about these new pieces in the UI?</para>
<!--($ ld: 30.6.11 sm $)-->      </blockquote>
    </sect3>
<!--
    <sect3 role="marketingteam">
      <title>Marketing Team</title>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="http://dev-loki.blogspot.com/2011/01/review-of-opensuse-trademark-guidelines.html">Pascal Bleser: Review of openSUSE Trademark Guidelines</ulink>
        </title>
        <para><ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/User:Byunashko">Bryen</ulink> just opened an <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311039">interesting feature request about a review of the current openSUSE trademark guidelines (#311039).</ulink>
        </para>
        <para>The current state of things is that Novell owns the openSUSE and openSUSE related
          trademarks (which include things like the openSUSE name and the openSUSE branding). While
          at some point I would love to see those trademarks go into the ownership of the openSUSE
          foundation (but let&apos;s first actually have that foundation ;)), it is better to keep
          them with Novell until we have a properly working and funded foundation, because owning
          trademarks is also an obligation to enforce them. And that potentially means legal
          enforcement as well. </para>
        <para>As the trademarks are owned and enforced by Novell, permissions to use trademarked
          material must be sent to Novell (<email>permission@novell.com</email>, actually), but in
          practice, Novell&apos;s legal team has been delegating the responsibility of evaluating
          such requests to the openSUSE board. </para>
        <para>Nevertheless, the board has to take decisions within a certain framework. Part of that
          framework, obviously, are a few legal aspects, but more prominently, it is what is
          currently defined in the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Trademark_guidelines">openSUSE Trademark Guidelines</ulink> document. </para>
        <para>Bryen&apos;s feature request (which is essentially filed as such because <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Openfate">openFATE</ulink> gives us a good tool for
          transparency and collecting feedback) is precisely about that point: let&apos;s take a
          step back and rethink our trademark guidelines. </para>
        <para>The task isn&apos;t as simple as it might sound, of course, as we have to find a good
          balance between a few, most probably contradictory things:<itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>make the rules short and simple: the simpler they are, the easier to grasp and
                the less daunting to approach</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>enable derivatives of openSUSE: yes, we&apos;d love to see more and more
                derivative works based on openSUSE (but the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Trademark_guidelines">current guidelines</ulink>, which the board has to abide by, do not really reflect
                that)</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>prevent abuse</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist></para>
        <para>Which is why we&apos;d love to hear from YOU what you believe are genuinely good use
          cases that we want to enable and support and what you believe would be cases of abuse,
          especially if you have been involved or have been pondering about making a derivative of
          openSUSE or, more generally, use the openSUSE trademarks in one way or another. </para>
        <para>To do so, <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/311039">just click here</ulink>,
          log in with your openSUSE account, and give us constructive feedback. Thanks !</para>
    </blockquote>
    </sect3> --><!--
    <sect3 role="medical">
      <title>Medical Team</title>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="hhttp://zoumpis.wordpress.com/2011/06/06/announcement-of-opensuse-medical-11-4-no2/">Rousinopoulos Athanasios-Ilias: Announcement of openSUSE Medical 11.4- No2</ulink>
        </title>
        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>What is openSUSE Medical Project?</para>
            <para>The openSUSE Medical project supports the use of openSUSE in doctor&apos;s practices
              and other clinical environments. We try to collect and update software. As base for
              packaging we use: List of Open Source Healthcare Software List. After we have packaged
              enough software we will try to create an openSUSE based Distribution out of it.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Where can i find more info about the project?</para>
            <para><ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Medical">http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Medical</ulink></para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>What&apos;s new in this release?</para>
            <para>openSUSE 11.4 Repositories :<itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>openSUSE 11.4 Updates remove</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>openSUSE 11.4 OSS,</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>education 11.4,</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Nvidia 11.4,</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Libre Office Stable 11.4,</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>11.4 Wireless,</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Medical 11.4,</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>non-ossd</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist></para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>New features that will impress you!</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Where can i download it ?</para>
            <para><ulink url="http://susegallery.com/a/UbPYJM/opensuse-medical-114">http://susegallery.com/a/UbPYJM/opensuse-medical-114</ulink></para>
            <para>Also available at : OVF image , VMware Image , Live CD/DVD</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Ok , i would like to make some comments or contribute in the project , what do i
              have to do?</para>
            <para>Comments are great, you can sent us with an Email to:<ulink url="mailto:opensuse-medical@opensuse.org">opensuse-medical@opensuse.org</ulink>. </para>
            <para>If this don’t run directly, then you must subscribe the List (mail to <ulink url="mailto:opensuse-medical+subscribe@opensuse.org">opensuse-medical+subscribe@opensuse.org</ulink>). </para>
            <para>Feel free to express your opinion!</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </blockquote>
    </sect3> --><!--
    <sect3 role="monoteam">
      <title>Mono Team</title>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="http://foodformonkeys.blogspot.com/2011/03/first-beta-of-monodevelop-26.html">Lluis Sanchez Gual: First beta of MonoDevelop 2.6</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>MonoDevelop 2.6 beta 1 was released yesterday. Like every major release, it has many
          new features. Here is a summary of what have we done.</para>
        <para>The first new big feature is <emphasis role="bold">support for GIT</emphasis>. This
          was long time due, especially since Mono and MonoDevelop itself moved to GIT. I already
            <ulink url="http://foodformonkeys.blogspot.com/2010/10/ngit.html">blogged about it</ulink> a few months ago, but basically we are using NGit, a C# port of JGit, as the
          core for the GIT add-in. It hasn&apos;t been easy to make this port fully operational, but we
          now have a GIT core that can be easily updated and which is fully portable.(...)</para>
      </blockquote>
      </sect3> -->    <sect3 role="openfateteam">
      <title>openFATE Team</title>
      <sect4>
        <title>Top voted Features</title>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/120340">decouple download and installation (Score: 356)</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>Network installation could be improved by running package download and package
            installation in parallel.</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/305493">Look at plymouth for splash during boot (Score: 187)</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>I wanted to open a fate feature about this when I first heard of plymouth, but
            reading
            http://fedoramagazine.wordpress.com/2008/10/21/interview-fedora-10s-better-startup/
            really makes me think we should go this way.</para>
          <para>Ray&apos;s comment starting with &quot;Every flicker and mode change in the boot
            process takes away from the whole experience.&quot; is especially interesting. Is it
            okay to track the &quot;don&apos;t show grub by default&quot; here?</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/305305">1-click uninstall (Score: 154)</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>An easy way to remove Software! For example: you installed an application with &quot;1-click install&quot; (which will install all the packages that you need), there should be an easy way (also with 1 click) to remove what you have installed with that 1-click operation... in another words: an &quot;1-click Uninstall&quot; to remove installed software (dependencies and packages included).</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/308497">Update to GRUB v2 (Score: 135)</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>Every single bug or feature that anyone has developed for GRUB 0.97 has been
            rejected by the upstream project in favor of using GRUB 2. There has been resisitence in
            the distribution community to switching boot loaders, but this stalemate isn&apos;t
            going to go away. The code itself isn&apos;t well written or well maintained. Adding a
            new feature involves jumping through a lot of hoops that may or may not work even if you
            manage to work around all the runtime limitations. For example, a fs implementation has
            a static buffer it can use for memory management. It&apos;s only 32k. For complex file
            systems, or even a simple journaled file system, we run into problems (like the reiserfs
            taking forever to load bug) because we don&apos;t have enough memory to do block mapping
            for the journal so it needs to scan it for every metadata read. (Yeah, really.)
            (...)</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/305877">Popularity contest (Score: 103)</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>We need a feedback about packages that are preferred by users and actively used. Debian already has a tool named Popularity contest (popcon)

    </para>
          <para>* reusing popcon will give us results that are directly comparable with Debian and Ubuntu
    </para>
          <para>* packagers team can take care of the package
    </para>
          <para>* we need a configuration dialog in YaST that is visible enough
    </para>
          <para>* we need a server infrastructure on opensuse.org. (There are certain privacy issues, see Debian FAQ for details)</para>
        </blockquote>
<!-- ($ ld: 2.7.11 sat *updated* $) -->      </sect4>
      <sect4>
        <title>Recently requested features</title>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Features newly requested last week. Please vote and/or comment if you get interested.</emphasis></para>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/312585">Iceweasel instead of Firefox</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>With the new scheme of version numbers at Mozilla (called by myself &quot;the idiot scheme&quot;) and the result, that the add-on-developers need to do a major-port every 3-6 months, I think it&apos;s necessary to drop Firefox and set Iceweasel instead as default.</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/312586">Add locales support for groff papersize</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>Groff&apos;s papersize definition in font description don&apos;t allow usage of locale variables, even if it will benefit from that. So let&apos;s extend the definition for a new keyword &apos;locale&apos;, which will query the setting from existing locale variables (LC_PAPER, LANG or LC_ALL).</para>
        </blockquote>
        <blockquote>
          <title>
            <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/312589">Continuous button look Oxygen in hole KDE also Yast and KPackageKit</ulink>
          </title>
          <para>The buttons of the KPackageKit and the buttons of Yast are in the standard installation not in the Oxygen look like the rest of KDE.</para>
          <para>This can bee solved: type in a console kdesu qtconfig under Select GUI Style: choose the option Oxygen to change the look of Yast The same for KPackageKit: type qtconfig and select the Oxygen style.</para>
          <para>But it would be very easy to have this setting in the standad installation? The Oxygen look is set by default at the hole KDE, why not in the KPackageKit and Yast? Make the look auf Suse homogen and deliver in the standard installation the Oxygen look.</para>
        </blockquote>
<!-- ($ ld: 2.7.11 sat *replaced with newer ones* $) -->      </sect4>
      <sect4>
        <title>Feature Statistics</title>
        <para>Statistics for openSUSE distribution <ulink url="https://features.opensuse.org/statistic/product/opensuse_dist">in openFATE</ulink></para>
      </sect4>
    </sect3>
    <!--
    <sect3 role="oooteam">
      <title>OpenOffice/LibreOffice Team</title>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/06/21/libreoffice-3-3-3-bugfix-release-available-for-opensuse/">Petr Mladek: LibreOffice 3.3.3 bugfix release available for openSUSE</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>I’m happy to announce LibreOffice <emphasis role="italic">3.3.3 bugfix release</emphasis>
          for <emphasis role="italic">openSUSE</emphasis>. The packages are available in the Build
          Service <ulink url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/LibreOffice:/Stable/">LibreOffice:Stable</ulink> project. They fix various crashers, usability and translation
          problems, see the <ulink url="http://cgit.freedesktop.org/libreoffice/build/plain/NEWS?id=libreoffice-3.3.3.1">libreoffice-3.3.3.1 release news</ulink> for more details. See also some notes about <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/LibreOffice">openSUSE LibreOffice build</ulink>.</para>
        <para>The openSUSE LO team hopes that you will be happy with this release. Though, any software
          contains bugs and we kindly ask you to <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Bugreport_LO">report bugs</ulink>. It will help us to
          fix them in the future releases.</para>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Other information and plans:</emphasis></para>
        <para>The bugfix release 3.3.4 is planed two months from now. Though, I would rather provide
          LO-3.4.2 packages instead.</para>
        <para>I am already working on the LO-3.4 packages. They are more complicated because there were
          significant changes in the build stuff. You might expect something within the next few weeks
          in the <ulink url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/LibreOffice:/Unstable/">LibreOffice:Unstable</ulink> project.</para>
      </blockquote>      
    </sect3> -->
    <sect3 role="testing">
      <title>Testing Team</title>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-testing/2011-07/msg00000.html">Larry
            Finger: Weekly News for July 2</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>The Testing Core Team held an IRC meeting at 17:00 UTC, June 27 on our usual
          channel. </para>
        <para>We discussed our experiences with openSUSE 12.1 MS2. The main problems that were
          encountered was the failure of the KDE NetworkManager applet to detect any network devices
          (Bug # 702461), and the inability to shut down the system from the GUI (Bug #702220). The
          workaround for the network applet problem is to install nmk-applet, the Gnome version,
          which works perfectly. The workaround for the shutdown problem is to bring up an alternate
          terminal using CTRL-ALT-F1 and shutdown or reboot from there. </para>
        <para>We also discussed the draft text of our request to rename MS6 to Beta in hopes of
          increasing the number of testers in the critical late stages of testing.</para>
      </blockquote>
    </sect3>
    <sect3 role="translationteam">
      <title>Translation Team</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Daily updated translation statistics are available on the <ulink url="http://i18n.opensuse.org/">openSUSE Localization Portal</ulink>.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://i18n.opensuse.org/stats/trunk/toplist.php">Trunk Top-List</ulink>
            – <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/OpenSUSE_Localization_Guide">Localization Guide</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </sect3>
<!--
    <sect3 role="tumbleweed">
      <title>Tumbleweed Team</title>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="http://www.kroah.com/log/suse/tumbleweed-status-04-22-2011.html">Greg Kroah-Hartman: openSUSE Tumbleweed status for the week of April 22, 2011</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>Here&apos;s a short note as to the status of some recent activity in the
          openSUSE:Tumbleweed repo:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>the kernel is at the 2.6.38 release level tracking the upstream stable 2.6.38
              releases.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>lxde (and its sub-packages) was added</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>calibre was added</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>other smaller packages were added</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>KDE update seems stable and working. It&apos;s in the openSUSE:Tumbleweed:KDE repo if
              anyone wants to test it out now. I&apos;ll be working next few weeks to merge this into the
              main openSUSE:Tumbleweed repo as my bandwidth allows.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>There is a GNOME 3.0 Tumbleweed repo at openSUSE:Tumbleweed:GNOME. It&apos;s properly
              building right now, but the same caveats remain for the main GNOME 3.0 repo (i.e.
              network manager issues with KDE, and other minor stuff), so I can&apos;t merge it to the
              main openSUSE:Tumbleweed repo just yet. I&apos;ll wait for these changes to settle down,
              but if you want, feel free to try out the repo for your GNOME 3.0 systems running
              Tumbleweed. I&apos;ll keep it up to date as the changes merge into the main GNOME 3.0
              repo.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>artwork questions were raised with one proposed logo already sent in. More to come
              in this area hopefully soon.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>There were a few &quot;version downgrades&quot; that happened as the upstream project
              release number was changed to reflect the basesystem release number correctly. This
              will probably continue to happen as this change is propagated throughout the openSUSE
              build system to fix up these errors by the various developers. You can safely ignore
              them when they happen.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>As always, if anyone knows of any packages they wish to see added to Tumbleweed,
          please let me know.</para>
        <para>Please read the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Tumbleweed">wiki page for Tumbleweed</ulink> if you have any basic questions about what it is or how to use it.
          Any other questions, please ask them on the <ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-factory/">opensuse-factory mailing list</ulink>.</para>
      </blockquote>
    </sect3> --><!--
    <sect3 role="weeklynews">
      <title>Weekly News Team</title>
      <blockquote>
        <title>
          <ulink url="http://saigkill.homelinux.net/2011/04/new-available-german-opensuse-podcast/">Sascha Manns: New available: german openSUSE Podcast</ulink>
        </title>
        <para>I’m pleased to announce my new german openSUSE Podcast. For listening this Podcast,
          you have two options.</para>
        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Download it <ulink url="http://saigkill.homelinux.net/podcasts/file/13-saigkills-opensuse-podcast-170">there</ulink>, or</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Add the Feed: <ulink url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/SaigkillsOpensuseWeeklyPodcast">http://feeds.feedburner.com/SaigkillsOpensuseWeeklyPodcast</ulink></para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
        <para>Have a lot of fun <inlinemediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="http://saigkill.homelinux.net/components/com_wordpress/wp/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif"/>
            </imageobject>
          </inlinemediaobject></para>
     </blockquote>
    </sect3> --><!--
    <sect3 role="wiki">
      <title>Wiki Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </sect3> --><!--
    <sect3 role="yast">
      <title>YaST Team</title>

      <para>...</para>
      </sect3> -->  </sect2>
</sect1>
