<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="belection">
  <title>Board Election 2011</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/12/02/opensuse-board-election-2011-started/"
        >openSUSE Board election 2011 started</ulink></title>
    <para><inlinegraphic
        fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/elections2011.jpeg" width="15%"
        align="right"/></para>
    <para>The openSUSE board election just started! Please go to:</para>
    <para><ulink
        url="https://connect.opensuse.org/pg/polls/read/digitaltomm/15228/opensuse-board-election-2011"
        >https://connect.opensuse.org/pg/polls/read/digitaltomm/15228/opensuse-board-election-2011</ulink>
      and cast your vote for this election. All <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Members">openSUSE
        members</ulink> are eligible to vote.</para>
    <para>The board consists of 6 members and one chairperson. As the election period of Bryen
      Yunashko, Pavol Rusnak and Rupert Horstkotter ends, this election will appoint 3 new board
      members.</para>
    <para>The election period ends at December the 16th.</para>
    <para> All candidates have put their agenda on the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board_election_2011">wiki</ulink>, linked as “Platform”
      after the candidates’ name.</para>
    <para>If you have any questions, please contact the election officials
      (<email>election-officials@opensuse.org</email>).</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 03.12.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://dev-loki.blogspot.com/2011/12/opensuse-election-platform-2011.html"
        >Pascal Bleser: openSUSE election platform 2011</ulink></title>
    <para>Yep, I'm running for the privilege of being on the openSUSE board again. Lots of fine
      candidates this time, which is pretty cool in its own right.</para>
    <para>I finally managed to fill out the remaining bits of <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board_election_2011_platform_template_yaloki">my
        election platform page</ulink>, so if you're interested, please have a read -- yes, I know,
      it's long ;)</para>
    <para>The short summary:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>I care about the contributors, their environment, it must be a fun place where
            people feel comfortable, with friends</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>I care a lot about the people aspects of the project, probably even more so than for
            the technical bits</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>I believe that I have a few ideas on concrete things we (and specifically, but not
            only, the board) should get involved in</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>All that "I, I, I" comes quite tedious, to be honest, and I'm under the impression that
      I'm bragging around, which is something my inner beast is spanking me for, endlessly. But
      well, the whole purpose is specifically to explain what each candidate proposes so I guess
      it's fine.</para>
    <para>So if you adhere to <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board_election_2011_platform_template_yaloki">what I
        wrote there</ulink> and/or if you trust me to do the right things, do vote for me -- don't
      think that oh well, I'll be elected anyway, if everybody thinks like that, I won't ;D</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 03.12.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.sysrich.co.uk/?p=3">Richard Brown: Running for the openSUSE
        board</ulink></title>
    <para>openSUSE, the FOSS project near and dear to my heart is electing 3 new members to sit on
      its <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board">Board</ulink>, the group that has the
      responsibility to help guide the great ship Geeko forward.</para>
    <para>I’m standing alongside a number of great candidates in the hope of being one of the 3
      elected this year.</para>
    <para>My full platform can be read on <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board_election_2011_platform_template_rbrownccb">my
        election page here</ulink></para>
    <para>I’m excited at the idea of trying something new, taking on a new challenge, and having an
      opportunity to get my hands dirty helping out the best (and greenest) FOSS project out
      there.</para>
    <para>If you’re an <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Members">openSUSE Member</ulink>
      please consider me for one of your 3 votes, which you can place on our <ulink
        url="https://connect.opensuse.org//pg/polls/read/digitaltomm/15228/opensuse-board-election-2011"
        >openSUSE Connect Election Poll</ulink></para>
    <para>Thanks to everyone who’s supporting me and wish me luck for the results when the poll
      closes in two weeks.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 03.12.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
