<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="tipsandtricks">
  <title>Tips and Tricks</title>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Desktop Users</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.unixmen.com/linux-tutorials/documentations-a-howto/1578-upgrade-opensuse-to-114"
          >Unixmen: Howto upgrade Opensuse to 11.4</ulink>
      </title>
      <para> How to upgrade Opensuse 11.x to 11.4 ? Unixmen gives the answer... (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 28.3.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://masterpatricko.blogspot.com/2011/03/opensuse-114-first-steps.html">Tejas
          Guruswamy: openSUSE 11.4 - first steps</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Finally term is over and I'm on my Easter break, which means I can step up my
        contributions again. First step was to install the new release on my desktop - openSUSE 11.4
        looks really, really good! No hassles during installation at all, took about 20mins from
        DVD. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 28.3.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Commandline/Script Newbies</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.unixmen.com/linux-commands/1602-watch-al-jazeera-live-with-one-command"
          >Unixmen/M. Zinoune (Zinovsky): Watch Al Jazeera Live in Linux with one command</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>If you are a fun of Aljazeera News channel, this is a nice command that allow you to
        watch Al Jazeera live in your Linux desktop. I tested the command and is working like a
        charm.</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://cdn.unixmen.com/images/stories/thumbnails/images-stories-videos-aljazeera1-400x225.png"/>
        </imageobject>        
      </mediaobject>
      <para>First check if you have rtmpdump installed, if not install it using the command
        :<screen>sudo apt-get install rtmpdump</screen></para>
      <para>Now to start watching Aljazeera live, open terminal and enter the following
        command</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">To use Mplayer
        :</emphasis><programlisting><emphasis role="bold">$ rtmpdump -v -r rtmp://livestfslivefs.fplive.net/livestfslive-live/ -y "aljazeera_en_veryhigh" -a "aljazeeraflashlive-live" -o -| mplayer -</emphasis></programlisting></para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">To use VLC
        player:</emphasis><screen>$<emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="bold"> rtmpdump -v -r  rtmp://livestfslivefs.fplive.net/livestfslive-live/ -y "aljazeera_en_veryhigh" -a "aljazeeraflashlive-live" -o -| vlc -</emphasis></emphasis></screen></para>
      <para>Enjoy :)</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Editors Note:</emphasis> For openSUSE you should install via:
          <emphasis role="italic">zypper in rtmpdump</emphasis> instead of sudo apt-get</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 30.3.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Developers and Programmers</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://dominique.leuenberger.net/blog/?p=178">Dominique Leuenberger: how to fix
          brp and rpmlint warnings – today:I: Program causes undefined operation(likely same
          variable used twice and post/pre incremented in the same expression)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>It seems the planned series sort of finds an audience, which in turn of course is
        motivational to keep on writing it. Today, we’ll have a look at this Informational message
        in BRP
        checks:<screen>I: Program causes undefined operation
 (likely same variable used twice and post/pre incremented in the same expression).
 e.g. x = x++; Split it in two operations.</screen></para>
      <para>This is currently informational only and is not failing the build, but you might want to
        address them together with upstream. </para>
      <para>I assume you do know what “a++” means in C (otherwise, you should start reading
        C-books), so we just try to reproduce this error in a simple c test
        case:<screen>#include &lt;stdio.h>
 
int main() {
 int i=5;
 i = i++ * ++i;
 printf("The current value of i is %d\n", i);
 return 0;
 }</screen></para>
      <para>When building this using gcc -Wall test.c, we get this compiler warning (which in turn
        is what brp translates to the information we’re discussing
        here)<screen>> gcc -Wall test2.c
 test.c: In function ‘main’:
 test.c:5:5: warning: operation on ‘i’ may be undefined</screen></para>
      <para>So, let’s first see for ourselves what we would expect this to be? Hmm.. already for us,
        this looks not logic (and I surely hope nobody would write this code). Let’s just see what
        starting this executable gives shall we?<screen>The current value of i is 37</screen></para>
      <para>Now, is this surprising? We multiplied, assigned it to i and as a result we get a prime
        number? By closely analyzing the line you will likely understand what the compiler did. But
        was this expected? If this is actually what the programmer intended, the code should just be
        rewritten to be more logical, like:<screen>i = (i+1) ^2 + 1;</screen></para>
      <para>This is understandable for all of us and does not yield the surprise of what is going
        on.</para>
      <para>And that is actually all this warning is about: it requests the programmer to write code
        that can be understood and does not depend on what the compiler interprets. It might even
        very well be that the different optimization levels or the usage of different compilers
        might end up in different results.</para>
      <para>If you want to read some more about this topic, I suggest to have a look at:<itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sequence_point">Wikipedia</ulink></para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink
                url="http://publications.gbdirect.co.uk/c_book/chapter8/sequence_points.html"
                >http://publications.gbdirect.co.uk/c_book/chapter8/sequence_points.html</ulink></para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
<!-- ($ Id: 28.3.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://azouhr.wordpress.com/2011/03/22/itunes-on-opensuse-11-4/">Berthold Gunreben: iTunes on openSUSE 11.4</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>In order to use iTunes University, I had to install iTunes on my notebook that is
        running openSUSE 11.4. It is quite easy to get some old version of iTunes from <ulink url="http://www.oldapps.com/itunes.php">http://www.oldapps.com/itunes.php</ulink> but
        trying to install it on a 64bit machine with wine always failed.</para>
      <para>In the end, I could install a 32bit version by doing the following:</para>
      <programlisting>rm -rf ~/.wine #(don&apos;t do this if you have other wine applications installed, it basically kills any previous wine installation)
export WINEARCH=win32
wine ~/Downloads/iTunesSetup1021.exe</programlisting>
      <para>To start iTunes later on, it is sufficient to run the following
        command:<screen>wine c:/Program\ Files/iTunes/iTunes.exe</screen></para>
      <para>Unfortunately, with most of the available courses on iTunes University, I get conversion
        errors. To circumvent this, I just download the respective courses and view them with
        mplayer:<screen>cd ~/Music/iTunes/iTunes Media/iTunes U/
mplayer -vo xv &lt;course file&gt;</screen></para>
      <para>This is not too nice, but at least it allows me to view iTunes U courses without the
        need for an operating system I do not own.</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 22.3.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://python4kids.wordpress.com/2011/03/22/increasingly-trivial-questions/">Python4Kids: New Tutorial - Increasingly Trivial Questions</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><ulink url="http://www.ibras.dk/montypython/episode08.htm#5">
          <emphasis role="italic">First Hermit Hello, are you a hermit by any chance?</emphasis>
        </ulink></para>
      <para><ulink url="http://www.ibras.dk/montypython/episode08.htm#5">
          <emphasis role="italic">Second Hermit Yes that’s right. Are you a hermit?</emphasis>
        </ulink></para>
      <para><ulink url="http://www.ibras.dk/montypython/episode08.htm#5">
          <emphasis role="italic">First Hermit Yes, I certainly am.</emphasis>
        </ulink></para>
      <para><ulink url="http://www.ibras.dk/montypython/episode08.htm#5">
          <emphasis role="italic">Second Hermit Well I never. What are you getting away from?</emphasis>
        </ulink></para>
      <para><ulink url="http://www.ibras.dk/montypython/episode08.htm#5">
          <emphasis role="italic">First Hermit Oh you know, the usual – people, chat, gossip, you know.</emphasis>
        </ulink></para>
      <para><ulink url="http://www.ibras.dk/montypython/episode08.htm#5">
          <emphasis role="italic">Second Hermit Oh I certainly do – it was the same with me. I mean there comes a time when you realize there’s no good frittering your life away in idleness and trivial chit-chat.</emphasis>
        </ulink></para>
      <para>If you remember back a few tutorials ago, we learnt how to <emphasis role="italic">pickle</emphasis> objects so that we could get them back later. To <emphasis role="italic">pickle</emphasis> the object <emphasis role="italic">triviaQuestions</emphasis> (which was a <emphasis role="italic">list</emphasis> object)
        we first imported the <emphasis role="italic">pickle</emphasis> module, then opened a file
        and <emphasis role="italic">dump</emphasis>ed the object into the file, then <emphasis role="italic">close()</emphasis>d the
        file:<screen>-&gt;code snippet removed to note [1] because I don&apos;t want you typ</screen></para>
      <para>(...)</para>
<!--($ Id: 23.3.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://dominique.leuenberger.net/blog/?p=151">Dominique Leuenberger: how to
          fix brp and rpmlint warnings – today: Expression compares a char* pointer with a string
          literal</ulink></title>
      <para>After having seen this kind of question several times, I think it could be interesting
        to start creating a small ‘series of rpmlint errors and their typical fixes”.</para>
      <para>Interested in it? So welcome to part #1 (this issue). The “series” is not really fledged
        out, but I will try to write post for various errors / topics, as they come along. Just drop
        me a note with an error you have seen / experienced in OBS while building a package.</para>
      <para>So what does it mean, if OBS tells you this:</para>
      <para> Expression compares a char* pointer with a string literal. Usually a strcmp() was
        intended by the programmer</para>
      <para>Let’s have a look at a very simple C program, to show the
        issue:<screen>#include &lt;stdio.h>
int main() {   
char *mytext;   
mytext = "Help";   
if (mytext == "Help") {     
printf("This should raise a warning");   
}   
return 0; 
}</screen></para>
      <para>Trying to compile this very simple C program, which on first sight many would probably
        say this is correct, will result in
        this:<screen>$ gcc test1.c -Wall 
test1.c: In function ‘main’: 
test1.c:6:14: warning: comparison with string literal results in unspecified behavior </screen></para>
      <para>So, even though we had such an easy program, line 6 seems to be an issue for
        us:<screen>if (mytext == “Help”) {</screen></para>
      <para>The issue, as simple as it may sound, is the comparison of a pointer (char *) with a
        literal (“Help”).</para>
      <para>So how do we fix it? It involves changing the code, thus writing a patch (there are many
        good helps around for this… I won’t dive into patching here).. Of course, after having
        written a patch, be a good downstream, send it upstream! What you want to do here is to
        replace this comparison with strcmp (just as OBS’ error message implied).</para>
      <para>Look at this code
        now:<screen>#include &lt;stdio.h> 
#include &lt;string.h>
int main() {   
char *mytext;   
mytext = "Help";   
if (strcmp(mytext,"Help")==0) {     
printf("No warning here\n");   
}
return 0; 
}</screen></para>
      <para>I changed <emphasis role="italic">“mytext == “Help”</emphasis> to <emphasis
          role="italic">strcmp(mtext,”Help”)==0</emphasis> (<ulink
          url="http://linux.die.net/man/3/strcmp">man 3 strcmp</ulink> will explain you why… 0 means
        the texts are equal, or ’0 difference detected’ can help you remember that). As the code was
        too simple and strcmp was not yet defined (this of course can also happen in packages you
        patch), I had to add an additional <emphasis role="italic">#include
          &lt;string.h&gt;</emphasis>.</para>
      <para>Not too hard, is it?</para>
      <para>So what do you think? Such a series of “how to fix my typical brp / lint warnings”
        useful?</para>
      <!--($ Id: 26.3.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For System Administrators</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.serverwatch.com/tutorials/article.php/3929346/article.htm"
          >Serverwatch/Juliet Kemp: Use Linux and WebDAV to Facilitate Online Collaboration</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The WebDAV protocol enables users to store and share files via HTTP. This is
        particularly valuable in cases where HTTP is usually read-only, as WebDAV allows writing as
        well. In addition to accessing documents, users can (with suitable permissions) edit and
        re-upload them. Think of it as a networked file-system run over HTTP; or as a way of
        supporting long-distance collaboration on files. The protocol supports locking and
        versioning information, so once you've accessed the WebDAV folder, you can edit files
        without risking overwriting other people's edits. These days, there are more and more ways
        available to undertake online collaboration, but WebDAV remains a useful and straightforward
        way to share files, especially as it's supported by plenty of software at both server and
        client end. (...)</para>
<!--($ Id: 30.3.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.howtoforge.com/how-to-install-apache-solr-and-use-it-with-drupal-and-ispconfig-opensuse-debian">HowtoForge/luisfreitas: How To Install Apache-Solr And Use It With Drupal And ISPConfig (OpenSUSE/Debian)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Solr is the popular, blazing fast open source enterprise search platform from the Apache Lucene project. Its major features include powerful full-text search, hit highlighting, faceted search, dynamic clustering, database integration, and rich document (e.g., Word, PDF) handling. I use this on OpenSUSE and Debian (minor tweaks on Debian, just paths to correct but it&apos;s almost the same). Packages from 4 of March 2011. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 26.3.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://blog.encodingit.ch/2011/03/backup-und-restore-mit-linux/">Bits, Bytes and my 5 cents: Backup und Restore mit Linux</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Von den bisher vorgestellten Themen in LPIC 201 ist das folgende eines der
        interessanteren: Backup und Archivierung! Wie in den Artikeln vorher schon erwýhnt, ersetzt
        RAID nicht wirklich ein Backup und LVM schon gar nicht! Es muss also trotzdem noch eine
        Lösung her – und um die kýmmern wir uns jetzt! </para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
