<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="forums">
  <title>openSUSE Forums</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/other-forums/news-announcements/announcements/452191-new-forum-home-page-layout.html">
	New Forum Home Page layout
	</ulink></title>
    <para>
      This has kept the Forums Team busy for a bit. With the new forums template effective, we've looked for further improvement of the accessibility of the forums. We hope help, info and the community have come a couple of clicks closer for our members and guests. Another aspect is the improved visibility of the non-english forums. This thread gets a lot of reponse. Don't forget to check the new home page layout.
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/other-forums/development/programming-scripting/451959-proper-way-obtain-source-code-packages.html">
      Proper way to obtain source code packages
      </ulink></title>
    <para>
      We use an open source OS, open source programs, now what if we actually want to take a look at the source of a program to see, like in this thread, where it takes it's icons from. The replies point to the ins and outs of this.
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/applications/452176-permissions-make-files-cd-writable-when-copying-hard-disk.html">
      Permissions: make files from CD writable when copying to hard disk
      </ulink></title>
    <para>
      When files, like photos get copied from a CD they keep their read-only permissions. This member supports his parents in using linux, he knows how to change the permissions himself, but he does not want his parents to have to do that. Yet they would need write permissions to their photos to do some basic photo editing, like rotation and removing red eyes. Read how it can be done.
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>This week's subforum: <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/other-forums/forums-feedback/">
      Forums Feedback
      </ulink></title>
    <para>
      This is our place where members give feed back on the forums themselves, i.e. the layout, accessibility, translation issues, suggested features and improvements. There are no stats available on this, but a lot of the things we see today were born in these regions.
      </para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 07.12.10 gl $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
