<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
  %myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="kernel">
  <title>Kernel Review</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://www.linuxuser.co.uk/opinion/the-kernel-column-96-with-jon-masters-2010-in-review/">Linux User and Developer/Jon Masters: The kernel column #96 with Jon Masters – 2010 in review </ulink>
    </title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">2010 was another exciting year for the Linux kernel and its community. Over the course of four kernel releases and many tens of thousands of mailing list messages, over one thousand individual developers (some working alone, some working for corporations) contributed two new architectures, several new file systems, and drivers for key hardware in the form of the Nouveau Nvidia driver (produced independently of Nvidia) and an open source Broadcom driver for its recent Wi-Fi chips. Of course, many more features were added, too… </emphasis></para>
    <para>Along the way, we also had two huge flame wars, several major security holes (one of which
      had been around for many years) were fixed, and many regressions were tracked and squashed.
      But if the year had to be summarised in a word, that word would be scalability. 2010 saw work
      on almost every aspect of the kernel – from Nick Piggin’s VFS (virtual file system)
      scalability patches to Arnd Bergmann’s BKL (Big Kernel Lock) removal work, and countless other
      efforts in between. You will see that recurring theme in the following month-by-month summary.
      If you’d like to see some more figures to accompany this timeline, visit the Linux Foundation
      website (linuxfoundation.org). Their annual kernel report focuses on overall numbers, not on
      individual features as we do here.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="italic">This article is due to appear in issue 96 of <ulink url="http://www.linuxuser.co.uk/">Linux User &amp; Developer</ulink> magazine.The kernel column #96 with Jon Masters - 2010 in review Subscribe and save more than 30% and receive our exclusive money back guarantee – click <ulink url="http://bit.ly/dTo0l9">here</ulink> to find out more.</emphasis></para>
<!-- ($ ld: 5.1.11 sm $) -->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/What-s-new-in-Linux-2-6-37-1163376.html">h-online/Thorsten Leemhuis: What&apos;s new in Linux 2.6.37 </ulink>
    </title>
    <para>After about eleven weeks of development, Linus Torvalds has released the Linux kernel
      2.6.37. The new version of the main development line has many improvements. Advances in the
      Ext4 file system mean it should be able to compete with XFS on larger systems and new discard
      functions can inform slow SSDs of vacant areas, without negatively affecting performance. </para>
    <para>This kernel also sees the first parts of the support for operation as a Xen host (Dom0).
      LZO compression will speed the transition into and out of hibernation and after years of work,
      almost all areas of the kernel are now without the Big Kernel Lock (BKL). Hundreds of new and
      revised drivers improve hardware support. New examples are the support for fast USB 3.0 disk
      with USB Attached SCSI Protocol (UASP) and various drivers for wireless hardware from Atheros,
      Broadcom and Realtek. The new kernel also has an audio loopback driver, extensions to deal
      with the Apple Magic Trackpad and support for 4 KByte logical sectors on hard drives. </para>
    <para>The following Kernel Log offers an overview of these and many further new features of
      Linux 2.6.37. These changes will eventually impact all Linux users as Linux distributions
      adopt the 2.6.37 kernel, or subsequent point releases, and make these improvements available
      to end users. At the end of this article, the Kernel Log will also take a peek at the advances
      that might make it into 2.6.38. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 5.1.11 sm $) -->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://news.softpedia.com/news/Linux-Kernel-2-6-37-Is-Available-for-Download-176428.shtml">Softpedia/Marius Nestor: Linux Kernel 2.6.37 Is Available for Download</ulink>
    </title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Eariler today, January 5th, none other than Linus Torvalds, the father of Linux, proudly announced the release of Linux kernel 2.6.37.</emphasis></para>
    <para>Among the new features includes in Linux kernel 2.6.37 we can mention support for PPP over the IPv4 protocol, lots of enhancements to various important file systems, such as EXT4, XFS and Btrfs, support for I/O throttling, Perf probe improvements, and a Ceph-based network block device. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 8.1.11 sat $) -->  </blockquote>
</sect1>
