<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/05/03/vintage/">Nelson Marques:
        Vintage…</ulink></title>
    <para>Yesterday I’ve seen in facebook a few photos by Chuck Payne from the Marketing team
      showing his collection of SuSE materials… I do have a few ‘vintage’ items as well… Back in 98
      when I tried SuSE Linux 5.3 for the first time, it was somehow expensive to burn DVD’s and I
      was hanging around on a 56K line back then, so pulling them over the internet was not really
      an option. (...)</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/DSCN0004.jpg"
          width="20%"/>
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <!--($ ld: 4.5.11 sm $)-->    
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://kdeatopensuse.wordpress.com/2011/05/05/let-the-user-decide-if-in-doubt/">KDE at
        openSUSE: Let the user decide if in doubt</ulink></title>
    <para>If it comes to decisions there is always the aim to just do the right thing. In a lot of
      cases there is the one right thing. In quite a few cases there is no right thing but the
      consequences are small enough that it does not really matter which decision one takes. And
      then there are those use-cases where the only right thing to do is to ask the user because any
      other decision would just be guessing and lead to RAM and CPU wasting.</para>
    <para>Yet even in the latter situations some apps are too lazy to ask the user or even claim
      that not asking the user – not even once – is the best solution – and even more astonishing:
      for the user’s good. So basically they claim to be smarter than the user or just do not care
      about the user’s resources or opinion. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 6.5.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://duncan.mac-vicar.com/opensuse-clients-with-spacewalk">Duncan Mac-Vicar
        Prett: openSUSE clients with Spacewalk</ulink></title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2011-05-06/IpveccbwojlttHFagxHiffEhaJqnqGgIxkwisopffGvdrvmeFniECIhEhpja/40_system_groups.png.scaled500.png"
          width="20%"/>
      </imageobject>      
    </mediaobject>
    <para>My team has been busy the last months with the release of SUSE Manager, which was received
      with very good reviews. There is lot of room for improvements, some of them specific to SUSE
      products/integration but others in Spacewalk itself.</para>
    <para>There is lot of work to do and lot of patches being reviewed. Lot of them are already
      upstream.</para>
    <para>One common question is: if I already have a Spacewalk server, how do I setup openSUSE
      clients?</para>
    <para>Thanks to Michael Calmer, we submitted the required packages to a repository in the
      openSUSE Build Service. You can find the instructions looking for the SUSE section in the
        <quote>Registering Clients</quote> page of the official Spacewalk wiki.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 7.5.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote> 
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/05/05/gpick-an-advanced-color-picker/">Nelson Marques: Gpick – An advanced color picker…</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>It was brought to my attention through I <ulink url="http://karl-tux-stadt.de/ktuxs/?p=3176">article</ulink> (german) the existence of
      <ulink url="http://code.google.com/p/gpick/">gpick</ulink>, an advanced and high featured
      color picker. I’ve taken a quick look at it to make it available for openSUSE as it seems an
      interesting tool for artists and web designers (maybe GTK3+ themers) and others.</para>
    <para>To build this package a few files are generated with the <ulink url="http://www.hwaci.com/sw/lemon/">Lemon Parser Generator</ulink> which isn’t really
      available. I’m contacting upstream regarding the possibility of including the generated
      files in the tarball, or eventually if that fails, I’ll probably need to include lemon.c,
      hand compile it and hack scons build to use the local binary to generate those files.
      (...)</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata width="15%" fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/Screenshot-New-palette-Gpick.png"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <!--($ ld: 6.5.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
</sect1>
