<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="tipsandtricks">
  <title>Tips and Tricks</title>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Desktop Users</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.brighthub.com/hubfolio/matthew-casperson/blog/archive/2011/08/18/positioning-windows-automatically-in-gnome-3.aspx">Hubfolio/Matthew Casperson: Positioning windows automatically in Gnome 3</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>One of the best features of Gnome 3 are the dynamic workspaces. Using some simple <ulink url="http://www.brighthub.com/hubfolio/matthew-casperson/blog/archive/2011/05/25/efficient-application-switching-with-gnome-3.aspx">keyboard shortcuts</ulink>, it is possible to assign an application to a workspace and quickly switch between them. If you run a standard set of applications, this process makes switching between them very efficient.</para>
      <para>The problem with running applications in their own workspace is that you have to spend some time once Gnome 3 has booted moving the applications to their proper workspaces. However, using a tool called <ulink url="http://www.foosel.org/linux/devilspie">devilspie</ulink>, it is possible to setup a script that will automatically rearrange your windows for you. (...)</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Editors Note</emphasis>: openSUSE users can install devilspie <ulink url="http://software.opensuse.org/search?p=1&amp;baseproject=ALL&amp;q=devilspie">via OBS</ulink>.</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 26.8.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.techdrivein.com/2011/08/10-good-inkscape-tutorials-for-vector.html">Tech Drive-in/Manuel Jose: 10 Good Inkscape Tutorials for Vector Graphic Designers</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Inkscape is the premier open source vector graphics editor for Linux. Inkscape is cross platform and is available for Windows and Mac OS X for free download. We have dealt with a bunch of really good <ulink url="http://www.techdrivein.com/2010/10/13-beautiful-inkscape-tutorials-for.html">Inskcape tutorials</ulink> before, here are even more of those. Following is a collection of 10 of the very best and descriptive Inkscape tutorials from around the web. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 26.8.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Commandline/Script Newbies</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://elevenislouder.blogspot.com/2011/08/introduction-to-find.html">Eleven is Louder: An Introduction to Find</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Learning find can seem daunting at first, but it is worth learning. There is no single more useful search tool for UNIX like systems. You could almost consider find a very primitive scripting language in itself as find can find the files you request and then perform tasks. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 26.8.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Developers and Programmers</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://python4kids.wordpress.com/2011/08/22/really-gui-more-on-buttons-images-and-handlers/">Python4Kids/Brendan Scott: Really GUI (more on Buttons, images and handlers)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>In the last few tutorials we have been looking at various parts of what make up a graphical user interface.   We’ve created labels and buttons and have attached images to a label (and a button if you did the homework).  We have also associated an action with pressing a button.   In this tutorial we’re going to put these together to make a simple image viewer application.  As with the previous tutorials, this will only work with images which are saved as a “gif” format.  Also, a word of warning – you need to do pretty much all of the code before any of it will work.</para>
      <para>Here are some images for you to use.  As with the earlier tutorial, you can either use ‘save as’ to download a copy, or you can use the Python code in the note below to download them (if you use Python you should be in your python4kids directory when you do the download otherwise the files will get saved somewhere else).  A gold star if you use Python for the download. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 26.8.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For System Administrators</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.ibm.com/developerworks/linux/library/l-lpic1-v3-102-3/index.html?ca=drs-"
          >ibm-developerworks/Ian Shields: Learn Linux, 101: Manage shared libraries</ulink>
      </title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Overview</emphasis></para>
      <para>In this article, learn to find and load the shared libraries that your Linux programs
        need. Learn to: </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Determine which libraries a program needs</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Know how the system finds shared libraries</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Load shared libraries</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>This article helps you prepare for Objective 102.3 in Topic 102 of the Linux
        Professional Institute's Junior Level Administration (LPIC-1) exam 101. The objective has a
        weight of 1. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 01.09.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://beginlinux.com/desktop/opensuse/configuring-the-dhcp-server">BeginLinux: Configuring the DHCP Server</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>What we will look at

</para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Installing the DHCP Server on openSUSE</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Configuring the Server with YaST</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Configuring the Server from the command line (...)</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
<!-- ($ Id: 26.8.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
