<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
  <!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://lwn.net/Articles/420487/">The Document Foundation joins Open Invention
          Network</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The Document Foundation has joined the Open Invention Network (OIN), to further extend
        the free software ecosystems. By becoming a licensee, The Document Foundation - developer of
        LibreOffice, a free office suite for personal and corporate productivity - has joined the
        growing list of organizations that recognize the importance of participating in the Open
        Invention Network, in order to protect the free software ecosystem from the risks associated
        to software patents.</para>
      <para><quote>The Document Foundation is a major free software project, and LibreOffice a key
          office suite for creating, managing and sharing documents. By becoming a licensee of the
          Open Invention Network, we fight software patents - which stifle innovation and encourage
          predatory business practices - and at the same time we improve the protection of our
          software projects,</quote> said Charles Schulz, Member of TDF Steering Committee.</para>
      <para>Patents owned by Open Invention Network are available royalty-free to whichever company,
        institution or individual that agrees not to assert its patents against free software.
        Through this network of developers, distributors, sellers, resellers and end-users that
        license its patent portfolio, Open Invention Network is creating a supportive and shielded
        ecosystem to ensure the growth and adoption of free and open source software. This enables
        OIN licensees like The Document Foundation to make significant investments, helping to fuel
        economic growth. </para>
      <para>OIN has amassed a broad portfolio of patents, including patents held by nominees on its
        behalf. These patents are available to all licensees as part of the patent portfolio that
        OIN is creating in support of free software. The license agreement is at <ulink
          url="http://www.openinventionnetwork.com/pat_license_agreement.php"
          >http://www.openinventionnetwork.com/pat_license_agreement.php</ulink></para>
      <para>The home of The Document Foundation is at <ulink url="http://www.documentfoundation.org"
          >http://www.documentfoundation.org.</ulink></para>
      <para>The Document Foundation has the mission to facilitate the evolution of the OOo Community
        into a new open, independent, and meritocratic organization within the next few months. An
        independent Foundation is a better match to the values of contributors, users and
        supporters, and will enable a more effective, efficient, transparent, and inclusive
        Community. TDF will protect past investments by building on the achievements of the first
        decade, will encourage wide participation in the Community, and will co-ordinate activity
        across the Community.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 20.12.10 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://dot.kde.org/2010/12/21/kde-ev-joins-open-invention-network">dot.kde.org:
          KDE e.V. Joins Open Invention Network</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>KDE e.V. is <ulink url="http://www.openinventionnetwork.com/press_release12_21_10.php"
          >pleased to announce</ulink> that we have joined the Open Invention Network community as a
        licensee. </para>
      <para>Open Invention Network was founded as a way to help defend the Linux ecosystem, and by
        extension much of the Free and Open Source software world, from the risks associated with
        software patents. Patents owned by Open Invention Network are available royalty-free to any
        company, institution or individual that agrees not to assert its patents against the Linux
        System, creating an umbrella of protection for its members.</para>
      <para><quote>We view an OIN license as one of the key methods through which open source
          innovators can deter patent aggression,” said Adriaan de Groot, vice president of KDE. “We
          are committed to freedom of action in Linux, and in taking a license we help to address
          the threat from companies that support proprietary platforms to the exclusion of open
          source initiatives, and whose behaviors reflect a disdain for inventiveness and
          collaboration.</quote></para>
      <para><quote>Given its leadership in creating a user-friendly computing experience, including
          its advanced graphical desktop for the Linux community, we are pleased to have KDE become
          a licensee,” said Keith Bergelt, CEO of Open Invention Network. “By doing so, KDE affirms
          its continued support for open source. We applaud their foresight in taking this step to
          support both itself and the open source community broadly.</quote></para>
      <para>While KDE maintains our position against software patents, this development provides an
        additional safety net for KDE when it comes to the risks Free Software is facing from such
        patents today.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 22.12.10 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://kde.org/announcements/announce-4.6-rc1.php">KDE Software Compilation 4.6
          RC1 Released: Codename Chanukkah</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>December 23rd, 2010. Right before christmas, KDE has published the first candidate for
        the upcoming release of KDE 4.6.0. The focus at this stage is on fixing bugs and completing
        translations and artwork. As such, the rework of the Oxygen icon set is nearing completion,
        many bugs reported by testers in the past weeks have been fixed and stabilization is still
        in full swing. KDE&apos;s release team has decided to not include the new release of
        KDE-PIM, containing the Kontact groupware client and the new KMail2 which is based on the
        Akonadi groupware cache in this release due to open issue with migration of large sets of
        data from the traditional client. These bugs are being worked on as we speak, but the risk
        at this point is too high to include the new Kontact in the 4.6.0 release. Therefore, it has
        been decided to release KMail2 and its companions together with one of the subsequent 4.6
        releases, likely 4.6.1 one month later. A 3rd beta version of the kdepim module is available
        already. As the other components of the frameworks, workspaces and applications are nearing
        release date, KDE encourages testers to give their favorite software some final thorough
        testing. The last chance for feedback will be the second release candidate, planned for
        January, 5th 2011. The final release of 4.6.0 will be <ulink
          url="http://www.kdedevelopers.org/node/4365">available</ulink> on January, 26th 2011. </para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata width="45%" fileref="http://kde.org/announcements/announce-4.6-beta2_thumb.png"
          />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>To find out more about the KDE Plasma desktop and applications, please also refer to the
          <ulink url="http://www.kde.org/announcements/4.5/">4.5.0</ulink>, <ulink
          url="http://www.kde.org/announcements/4.4/">4.4.0</ulink>, <ulink
          url="http://www.kde.org/announcements/4.3/">4.3.0</ulink>, <ulink
          url="http://www.kde.org/announcements/4.2/">4.2.0</ulink>, <ulink
          url="http://www.kde.org/announcements/4.1/">4.1.0</ulink> and <ulink
          url="http://www.kde.org/announcements/4.0/">4.0.0</ulink> release notes. </para>
      <para>KDE, including all its libraries and its applications, is available for free under Open
        Source licenses. KDE can be obtained in source and various binary formats from <ulink
          url="http://download.kde.org/unstable/4.5.90/">http://download.kde.org</ulink> and can
        also be obtained on CD-ROM or with any of the major GNU/Linux and UNIX systems shipping
        today. </para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Editors Note</emphasis>: The openSUSE Packages of KDE SC 4.6 RC1
        are placed in <ulink url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/KDE:/Distro:/Factory/"
          >KDE:Distro:Factory</ulink> Repository.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 23.12.10 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://wine-reviews.net/wine-reviews/winetricks/winetricks-20101222-released.html"
          >winetricks 20101222 released</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Another month, another Winetricks.</para>
      <para>Dan Kegel released winetricks 20101008 today. new verbs icodecs, msnasn1, opensymbol,
        wmi, xmllite; removed obsolete verbs audioio, dcom98, eadm, urlmon </para>
      <para>wsh57 now works with vb scripts, the code has undergone some spring cleaning, so watch
        out for regressions. (We've fixed a few already.) In particular, the audioio, dcom98, eadm,
        and urlmon verbs are gone, let me know if you really need those! </para>
      <para>There's a new --optin commandline option that will tells winetricks to phone home after
        each run with info about which verbs really get used. Please consider using this, it will
        help future winetricks development. (You only have to give that option once, it sticks. You
        can turn it off with the --optout option, or by removing ~/.cache/winetricks.) (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 25.12.10 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://qt-apps.org/news/?id=340">QT Apps: Win 10.000,- EUR at the &quot;Qtest
          Mobile App Port&quot;</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Welcome to the Qtest Mobile App Port! As developers of applications using Qt, you
        already know how great it is to work with - but how about on mobile platforms, such as
        Symbian and MeeGo? How would you like to take that step you have been wanting to take, but
        not been able to justify: Take your application from the desktop and bring it into the
        hand-held world via the Ovi store. Let this contest be the justification, with the
        possibility of a new phone or even 10,000 euros waiting at the end. </para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Dates</emphasis>: The contest starts on 20th of December, 2010,
        and runs till 28th of February. The 31st of December is important for you if you wish to
        take part in the Early Bird competition. If you do no win, you will still take part in the
        main competition, and will be allowed to continue your work and submit new versions to the
        Ovi Store. The 28th of February is the deadline for taking part in the main
        competition.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Developer Sprint</emphasis>: There will be a sponsored developer
        sprint organized together with the KDE e.V. during the competition. The travel and stay can
        be paid for if you do not have the budget yourself. Further details will be made public at a
        later time, and all participants will be notified of this information via email. </para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Judging and prizes</emphasis>: The Qtest Mobile App Port is
        evaluated by a panel of judges which will be announced in the next few days. The jury will
        pic 5 winners at 31th of December as the early bird winners. Every winner gets a free N900
        phone. The main competition first prize is EUR 10,000, which will be awarded to the
        application which the judges find to be the best ported application. The second to sixth
        price will be another 5 N900 phones.</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata width="25%" fileref="http://qt-apps.org/CONTENT/news-pics/340-pic4.jpg"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>And, finally: Everybody who takes part in the competition will be awarded a gift bag,
        with a T-shirt and other merchandise.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Eligibility</emphasis>: To be able to take part in the contest,
        the ported application must be submitted for Ovi Store signing by one of the two deadlines:
        - Early bird entries must be submitted by December 31st - Standard entries must be submitted
        by February 28th.</para>
      <para>You also have to submit your application to the &quot;Mobile Contest&quot; category on
        Qt-Apps.org or MeeGo-Central.org </para>
      <para>You can submit your application to the Ovi Store as many times as you wish during the
        competition. This allows you to get feedback from the public on your software. It´s possible
        to submit new or existing KDE/Qt applications.</para>
      <para>So have fun and good luck everybody!</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 23.12.10 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxlinks.com/article/2010121106112994/NotableGamesPart2.html">21
          More Notable Free Linux Games (Part 2 of 3)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>We have always been strong advocates of computer games. Rather than rotting the brain,
        computer games are interactive, teach essential life skills, and can stimulate learning.
        They also have been proven to enhance skills such as creativity, cooperation, teamplay, as
        well as encouraging innovative and strategic thinking and improving hand-eye coordination. </para>
      <para>Linux is not championed as a viable gaming platform in many communities, in part because
        of its smaller user base and the relatively low number of commercially supported native
        Linux games that are released each year. However, there are a number of encouraging
        developments on this front. For example, the Unigine engine should enable developers to
        produce high-quality 3D games with up-to-date visuals and advanced rendering. One title to
        be released using this engine is OilRush. This eagerly awaited title fuses a classical real
        time strategy with a Tower Wars genre. </para>
      <para>Notwithstanding these developments, Linux has an ever-expanding library of tens of
        thousands of free games, many of which are released under an open source license. A good
        proportion of these titles are entertaining, highly addictive, offer captivating gameplay,
        and are challenging. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 20.12.10 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://ostatic.com/blog/my-top-five-favorite-distributions-for-2010"
          >Ostatic/Susan Linton: My Top Five Favorite Distributions for 2010</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Ms. Carla Schroder shared a list of her <quote>bestest distros</quote> recently, so I
        thought I might follow suit. She called hers <quote>not-usual</quote> and looking at her
        list, I&apos;d say my choices are probably a little more usual. In any case, here are my top
        five favorite Linux distributions for 2010, in no real order.</para>
      <para>
        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink url="http://www.mepis.org/">MEPIS</ulink></para>
            <para>SimplyMEPIS has always been one of my favorite distributions for several reasons.
              SimplyMEPIS was one of the first to understand that looks do matter and so does out of
              the box functionality. It includes proprietary drivers, codecs, and browser plugins
              that make using Linux enjoyable. It leans toward the conservative side concerning new
              version of its components, but that makes for an extremely stable operating system. In
              all its years I only ran into one release that gave me any trouble, and that was about
              three or four years ago - possibly when it went through its Ubuntu phase. It is truly
              one of the best.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink url="http://www.opensuse.org/">openSUSE</ulink></para>
            <para>openSUSE has been one of my favorites since it first opened up to community
              involvement in 2005. Novell&apos;s agreement with Microsoft did damper my enthusiasm a
              bit, but the distro itself remains one of the most polished and professional offerings
              we have. It just has a commercial feel to it. Like SimplyMEPIS, I only encountered one
              release that gave me any trouble. Otherwise, its been a slick and attractive distro. I
              don&apos;t run it full time mainly because I&apos;d have to hunt up some one-clicks
              (that are available for openSUSE) or install codecs and stuff myself to get going and
              then worry about those updates. But it always remains high on my radar. I follow its
              development very closely. I&apos;m a little worried about what will become of it
              despite assurances. But as long as it lives, so will my admiration. (...)</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 20.12.10 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.h-online.com/open/news/item/X-org-7-6-supports-udev-and-modularized-configuration-1157824.html"
          >h-online: X.org 7.6 supports udev and modularized configuration</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The X.org developers have released version X11R7.6 of their graphics system, which
        contains the X Server version 1.9.3. One of the innovations in 7.6 is that it uses udev for
        hardware detection and hot-plug notification; a HAL (Hardware Abstraction Layer) is no
        longer required. </para>
      <para>Xorg configuration directories now allow the X Server configuration to be saved as
        individual module files. For instance, the input device driver matching rules previously
        provided in HAL .fdi files are now provided as InputClass sections in .conf files in
        /etc/X11/xorg.conf.d.</para>
      <para>The <ulink url="http://www.x.org/releases/X11R7.6/src/">sources</ulink> for the current
        release, the <ulink url="http://www.x.org/releases/X11R7.6/doc/xorg-docs/ReleaseNotes.txt"
          >release notes</ulink>, the detailed <ulink
          url="http://www.x.org/releases/X11R7.6/changelog.txt">Change Log</ulink> and the <ulink
          url="http://www.x.org/wiki/">project wiki</ulink> are all available from the X.org project
        web site. X11R7.8 is released under the <ulink
          url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/X11_License">MIT licence.</ulink></para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 22.12.10 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.h-online.com/open/news/item/Google-launches-open-source-YouTube-channel-1157267.html"
          >Google launches open source YouTube channel</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Google has launched an<ulink url="http://www.youtube.com/user/googleOSPO"> official
          YouTube channel</ulink> for its<ulink url="http://code.google.com/opensource/"> Open
          Source Programs Office</ulink> (OSPO). According to Google Open Source Team member Ellen
        Ko, the new channel is aimed at organizing videos related to Google and other open source
        projects in a single place.</para>
      <para>A number of playlists with videos of, for example, <ulink
          url="http://www.youtube.com/googletechtalks">Google Tech Talks</ulink> that feature open
        source projects have already been added. Other videos from Jeremy Allison’s <ulink
          url="http://www.youtube.com/view_play_list?p=7FC162E0B1E7C602">Geek Time</ulink> series,
        as well as of Googlers speaking at open source conferences are also available. The Google
        OSPO YouTube channel currently has 14 videos, with links to a variety of other videos from
        other channels and users.</para>
      <para>Google&apos;s current open source projects include the <ulink
          url="http://www.h-online.com/news/item/Google-releases-Chrome-8-0-stable-1147222.html"
          >Chrome</ulink> web browser, which is based on <ulink url="http://www.chromium.org/"
          >Chromium</ulink> , the Android mobile operating system, <ulink
          url="http://www.h-online.com/news/item/Google-previews-Chrome-OS-Cloud-computing-but-without-touch-1149420.html"
          >Chrome OS</ulink> and many others.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 22.12.10 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.2indya.com/2010/12/23/advantages-of-opensuse%E2%80%99s-yast-software-management/"
          >2indiya.com/Nilanka: Advantages of OpenSUSE’s YaST Software Management</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Different Linux distributions use their own tools for software, or more precisely,
        package management. As an example, Ubuntu uses its Synaptic, Fedora uses Yum, Gentoo uses
        Portage, and OpenSUSE uses YaST.</para>
      <para>YaST stands for ‘Yet another Setup Tool’. YaST is an easy to use package management
        system for Linux distributions that support rpm based packages. Although YaST features in
        many commercial Linux distributions, it is free and open source software released under GPL.
        Therefore, it is free to be used by any party interested. </para>
      <para>YaST features many functionality the advanced package management tools offer. Let’s take
        the appearance as an example. YaST offers the end users both a GUI front-end as well as CLI
        front-end. The CLI front-end is especially useful for the installation done through networks
        where everything is performed through a terminal or a command line interface. Due to this
        support, the installation of OpenSUSE systems can be done over slow Internet connections and
        while the X server is not present in the system (such as a server installation).
        (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 23.12.10 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.consortiuminfo.org/standardsblog/article.php?story=20101221084910541"
          >ConsortiumInfo.org/Andy Updegrove: EC Takes One Step Forward, Two Steps Back in
          Openness</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Last Thursday the European Commission took a major step forward on the “openness” scale.
        The occasion was the release of a new version of the European Interoperability Framework
        (EIF) which definitively endorsed the use of open source friendly standards when providing
        “public services” within the EU. This result was rightly hailed by open source advocates
        like <ulink
          url="http://www.openforumeurope.org/press-room/press-releases/EIF%20PR3%2016.12.10.pdf"
          >Open Forum Europe</ulink>. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 23.12.10 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://www.linux.com/learn/tutorials/392855:weekend-project-replace-delicious-with-an-open-source-bookmark-service"
          >Linux.com/Nathan Willis: Weekend Project - Replace Delicious with an Open Source Bookmark
          Service</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The past two weeks have been rough for users of the Yahoo-owned "social bookmarking"
        service, <ulink url="http://www.delicious.com/">Delicious</ulink>. First, reports leaked out
        that Yahoo was shutting the site down. Then the Delicious team <ulink
          url="http://blog.delicious.com/">fired back</ulink> saying essentially don't worry, all is
        well — we're simply getting sold off. That's cold comfort if you use the service to manage
        and tag a large collection of links, though. If you're not comfortable with the uncertainty,
        what better solution is there than installing your own open source replacement?</para>
      <para>Running your own Web bookmarking application has two key advantages over a proprietary
        commercial service. First, you can change and adapt the system to fit your way of working.
        Don't care about sharing your collection with the world at large? You can run a single-user
        instance and keep your bookmarks private. Second, you can host it on your own server,
        whether a small box in your closet at home, or on a co-located hosting plan — either way,
        you're in control.</para>
      <para>There are several Web-based bookmarking applications suitable for running on a LAMP
        server setup, but the option that most closely matches the Delicious service is <ulink
          url="http://sourceforge.net/projects/scuttle/">Scuttle</ulink>. It implements the
        Delicious API, supports multiple user accounts, and even allows you to import your bookmark
        collection from Delicious. Scuttle requires MySQL and PHP, and the most recent release is
        version 0.8.0, from December 21st of 2010. That is recent enough that although some Linux
        distributions provide builds through their package management systems, most will not have
        caught up yet.</para>
      <para>That means you'll have to grab a <ulink
          url="http://sourceforge.net/projects/scuttle/files/">source package</ulink> from the
        project's Web site if you want to run the latest and greatest, but don't let it frighten you
        away. As a pure LAMP app, you don't have to worry about compilation — the setup process is
        straightforward. We'll take a look at installing and configuring the basic Scuttle
        application, then talk about some alternatives, including an interesting Scuttle derivative.
        (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 25.12.10 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linuxjournal.com/content/ubuntu-indicators-opensuse">Linux
          Journal/Susan Linton: Ubuntu Indicators in openSUSE?</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Ubuntu takes a lot of punches from time to time for its marketing and even its
        interface. Some feel Ubuntu is dumbed down and oversimplified, while many others think
        it&apos;s innovative and user-friendly. Where ever you fall in the debate, one developer
        thinks some elements of Ubuntu should land into openSUSE. In fact, he has packaged up and
        pushed them to openSUSE:Contrib.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Nelson Marques</emphasis>, Fedora and openSUSE contributor, thinks
        Ubuntu indicators are the bee&apos;s knees. Actually, since Ubuntu is the dominant
        distribution in his corner of the world he thinks using some of its more familiar elements
        might help users migrate to openSUSE. He said, &quot;We don’t want to make of openSUSE a
        ‘clone’ of Ubuntu, instead we want to make the openSUSE experience more close to what people
        already use.&quot; (...) Other Sources: <ulink
          url="http://ostatic.com/blog/unity-coming-to-opensuse-too">ostatic</ulink></para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 25.12.10 sat $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.h-online.com/security/news/item/Phrack-hole-closed-in-ProFTPD-1156782.html"
          >h-online: Phrack hole closed in ProFTPD </ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The development team behind <ulink url="http://www.proftpd.org/">ProFTPD</ulink> has
        released version <ulink url="http://www.proftpd.org/docs/RELEASE_NOTES-1.3.3d"
          >1.3.3d</ulink>, which closes a critical security hole in the SQL module of all previous
        versions. The flaw was <ulink url="http://www.phrack.org/issues.html">reported</ulink>
        roughly a month ago in Phrack, the hacker magazine. A buffer overflow in the function
        sql_prepare_where() allows attackers to remotely execute arbitrary code on the server. The
        developers themselves suffered when this vulnerability was exploited by still unknown
        parties, who entered the project server and <ulink
          url="http://www.h-online.com/news/item/Back-door-in-ProFTPD-FTP-server-1146592.html"
          >installed</ulink> a back door in the source code.</para>
      <para>The new version also fixes a number of additional <ulink
          url="http://www.proftpd.org/docs/NEWS-1.3.3d">bugs</ulink>; as a result, the GPL-licensed
        server is reportedly now more stable. At the same time, the developers have also published
        the first release candidate for version <ulink
          url="http://www.proftpd.org/docs/RELEASE_NOTES-1.3.4rc1">1.3.4</ulink>. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 22.12.10 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>LOL</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://xkcd.com/838/">XKCD: Incident</ulink>
      </title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata width="50%" fileref="http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/incident.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.pcworld.com/article/214710/15_crazy_japanese_tech_gizmos.html"
          >PCWorld/Jeff Bertolucci: 15 Crazy Japanese Tech Gizmos</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The Japanese have proven their techie prowess over the decades. Where would we be
        without the transistor radio, the camcorder, or the Sony Walkman? But sometimes they jump
        the technological shark with whimsical and weird gear, some of which is downright loopy.
        Here are our favorite examples of oddball tech that could be made only in Japan.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <!-- ($ ld: 25.12.10 sat $) -->
  </sect2>
</sect1>
