<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
  <!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
  %myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="kernel">
  <title>Kernel Review</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/Kernel-Log-coming-in-2-6-37-Part-4-Architecture-and-infrastructure-code-1156965.html"
        >h-online/Thorsten Leemhuis: Kernel Log: coming in 2.6.37 (Part 4) – Architecture and
        infrastructure code</ulink>
    </title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">The kernel now includes some components for supporting operation as
        a Xen host (Dom0). Switching into and out of sleep mode should be accelerated by the use of
        LZO compression. Following years of work, almost all parts of the kernel are now able to run
        without using the big kernel lock (BKL). </emphasis></para>
    <para>On releasing 2.6.37-rc6 last week, Linus Torvalds<ulink
        url="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.kernel/1077573"> reiterated</ulink> that he hoped
      to release Linux kernel 2.6.37 after the holiday period, around the turn of the year. However
      things have not been running quite as smoothly as he might like – something which probably
      also applies to the seventh pre-release version, due for release shortly, since a change aimed
      at improving hardware resource allocation has now been reverted. </para>
    <para>This, Part 4 of our "What's coming in 2.6.37" Kernel Log series, provides an overview of
      these and other changes in platform-specific and infrastructure-related kernel code. <ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/Kernel-Log-Coming-in-2-6-37-Part-1-Graphics-1144218.html"
        >Part 1</ulink> of the series dealt with graphics hardware-related changes, <ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/Kernel-Log-Coming-in-2-6-37-Part-2-File-systems-1148305.html"
        >Part 2</ulink> with file system changes and the <ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/Kernel-Log-Coming-in-2-6-37-Part-3-Network-and-storage-hardware-1153025.html"
        >Part 3</ulink> with changes to network and storage code. The fifth and final part will be
      published around the turn of the year and will deal with other drivers and the kernel
      subsystems in which they are found. (...)</para>
  </blockquote>
  <!-- ($ ld: 16.12.10 sm $) -->
</sect1>
