<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/20/attachmate-acquisition-what-does-it-mean-for-suse-opensuse-open-source/"
        >Attachmate Acquisition: What does it mean for SUSE, openSUSE &amp; open source?</ulink>
    </title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">A Q &amp; A with Jeff Hawn, chairman and CEO of Attachmate by Jos
        Poortvliet, openSUSE Community Manager at Novell</emphasis></para>
    <para><emphasis role="italic">I had a chance to speak with Jeff Hawn, chairman and CEO of
        Attachmate Corporation about his views and intentions around SUSE and openSUSE. Jeff has
        commented that SUSE is an important brand and business that he wants to strengthen. What are
        his thoughts about the community and what does he see for SUSE and openSUSE? Here below are
        the questions I put forward and Jeff’s current thoughts. –Jos</emphasis></para>
    <para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Open Source</emphasis></para>
          <para><emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="underline">What is Attachmate’s history with
                open source projects? </emphasis></emphasis></para>
          <para>Attachmate does not have a corporate track record in the open source business.
            However, we recognize the importance of open source technology, particularly Linux, and
            the growing value it brings to enterprises globally. We also recognize and value the
            openSUSE project, the contribution that the community makes to the SUSE business and
            most importantly, the many ways in which the community benefits SUSE customers.</para>
          <para>At the end of the day, we are a technology company that is customer-driven, made up
            of engineers and technology enthusiasts. We have a lot of individuals that are long-time
            users of open source and participants in the open source movement. We recognize and
            understand what the community has developed, particularly over the last decade, and we
            are excited to be part of its future.</para>
          <para><emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="underline">What is Attachmate’s view of open
                source software?</emphasis></emphasis></para>
          <para>Attachmate recognizes that enterprises all over the world are utilizing more open
            source technology in their infrastructures, data centers and desktops every year. We
            believe this is a trend that will continue and that’s why we are excited about the Open
            Platform Solutions business and in particular, the SUSE Linux community.</para>
          <para>It is easy for people to assume that because we are not currently in the open source
            business, we don’t value or understand it. This is far from the case. We are in the
            business of meeting customer needs and they see great value in utilizing open source
            technology solutions. Because of its open nature, open source is being adopted by
            enterprises in all industries around the world. Our intent is to keep it that way and
            continue to foster what has made it so successful for the Open Platforms Solutions
            business.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">SUSE</emphasis></para>
          <para><emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="underline">Ok, then what is the plan for
                SUSE?</emphasis></emphasis></para>
          <para>We cannot speak to specifics until after close, but what we can communicate now is
            our intention to establish a SUSE business unit on par with the existing Attachmate and
            NetIQ business units. We believe that establishing SUSE as its own business unit will
            give greater focus and flexibility to grow within a competitive market. We view SUSE as
            a well regarded and proven technology in the open source and enterprise Linux community
            and we want to further build upon that. We intend for SUSE to continue to provide the
            same high quality open source technology solutions, such as SUSE Linux Enterprise
            Server, needed to meet users’ demands for scalability, interoperability and cost
            effectiveness.</para>
          <para><emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="underline">What will the SUSE business unit
                be – what do you mean by “business unit”?</emphasis></emphasis></para>
          <para>A business unit brings together all the resources, IP, people and infrastructure
            needed to operate – to build product, deliver solutions and support customers. So, what
            is known today as Open Platform Solutions will now be centralized within the SUSE
            business unit. In most respects SUSE will continue to operate as it did as OPS, but will
            benefit from being a dedicated and more visible brand with a focused business unit
            behind it.</para>
          <para><emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="underline">Does Attachmate intend to
                immediately sell the SUSE business?</emphasis></emphasis></para>
          <para>I want to be clear here: all of our efforts will be focused on doing the things
            necessary to make SUSE the highest performing business with the strongest openSUSE
            community that we can. This is a healthy, growing dynamic business. We want to continue
            to nurture this business and grow it. This is why we want to elevate the SUSE brand and
            operate that part of the business as a distinct unit where it will receive greater
            visibility and focus.</para>
          <para><emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="underline">How do you plan to compete in the
                Linux market? </emphasis></emphasis></para>
          <para>We’re excited about SUSE because of the great competitive advantages it already has.
            With thousands of certified ISV applications, the best interoperability and unsurpassed
            scalability, it provides the best value and the lowest cost of ownership on the market.
            Attachmate intends to continue that commitment to high quality and cost-effective
            solutions.</para>
          <para><emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="underline">What are your intentions for open
                source initiatives sponsored by Novell today?</emphasis></emphasis>
          </para>
          <para>No decisions have been made regarding any specific projects or sponsorships. Much
            more integration work needs to happen before discussions of changing the status of
            individual projects can occur. But we can say that the new SUSE business unit will stay
            committed to participating in the projects and initiatives that are most important to
            the SUSE business and its customers.</para>
          <para><emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="underline">Will Attachmate continue to
                support Linux kernel development by employees as Novell has
              done?</emphasis></emphasis></para>
          <para>Yes, we will. Key contributions to the Linux kernel are a benefit to everyone in the
            community. This sort of contribution is a key element of what makes the synergy between
            business and open source so successful and we intend to continue support it.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">openSUSE</emphasis></para>
          <para><emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="underline">Will Attachmate increase or
                decrease the investments in development and marketing for
              openSUSE?</emphasis></emphasis></para>
          <para>There is a lot of integration work to do before those decisions are made and some of
            that work cannot be done until after the transaction has closed. Our intent is to
            continue to sponsor and participate in the openSUSE project. </para>
          <para><emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="underline">Will this impact the initiative
                to create an independent foundation for openSUSE?</emphasis></emphasis></para>
          <para>No decisions on this initiative have been made. This is a complex topic that has
            been actively debated in the community for some time. We look forward to continuing that
            discussion with the community after the close of the transaction.</para>
          <para><emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="underline">Will Attachmate continue to
                support the openSUSE conference?</emphasis></emphasis></para>
          <para>No decisions have been made about the ongoing sponsorship of openSUSE conference. It
            is simply too early to reach conclusions on specific areas such as this – more
            integration work and collaboration with the SUSE team is needed. Our overall intent is
            to maintain the continuity of success we see within the SUSE business and that includes
            continuing to work closely with the openSUSE community.</para>
          <para><emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="underline">Will the acquisition have any
                other effects on the openSUSE project or community?</emphasis></emphasis></para>
          <para>We look forward to learning more about the project and working together with the
            community to figure out what’s working well, what could be done differently or improved.
            This will be a highly collaborative relationship.</para>
          <para><emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="underline">Does Attachmate intend to shut
                down the openSUSE community project?</emphasis></emphasis></para>
          <para>No, we don’t. Attachmate intends to continue the sponsorship and collaboration with
            the openSUSE project. We view the openSUSE project and its extended community as an
            important part of the overall SUSE business and we value its contributions to the
            technology that forms the heart of the SUSE offerings (see related statement on the
            Attachmate website here).</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Intellectual Property</emphasis></para>
          <para><emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="underline">What IP assets are being
                purchased by CPTN Holdings LLC?</emphasis></emphasis></para>
          <para>Attachmate cannot provide details on the IP assets being purchased, but we can
            clarify that CPTN is NOT purchasing products. They are purchasing 882 patents and patent
            applications as described in the initial 8-K filed by Novell.</para>
          <para>The purchase does not include the Novell UNIX copyrights (see related statement on
            the Novell website here). It does not include the product source code or product
            implementations.</para>
          <para>Attachmate would not buy a company and not preserve what is working nor hamper our
            ability to operate this business. So, SUSE will retain all the technology, rights and IP
            needed to continue and grow.</para>
          <para><emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="underline">Does the purchase by CPTN
                Holdings impact the openSUSE project or the SUSE enterprise
              business?</emphasis></emphasis></para>
          <para>After the merger is complete, the SUSE business unit will retain all the IP and
            technology rights needed to operate, continue its sponsorship of the openSUSE project
            and supporting SUSE customers.</para>
          <para><emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="underline">What happens to the Novell UNIX
                copyrights after the sale of IP assets to CPTN
            Holdings?</emphasis></emphasis></para>
          <para>No change. The purchase of IP assets by CPTN Holdings does not include the UNIX
            copyrights and the copyrights will continue to be owned by Novell (see related statement
            on the Novell website here).</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </para>
    <para>FORWARD-LOOKING STATEMENTS</para>
    <para>This communication contains statements that constitute forward-looking statements within
      the meaning of the Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. These statements are
      based on current expectations and beliefs and are subject to a number of risks, uncertainties
      and assumptions that could cause actual results to differ materially from those described in
      the forward-looking statements. Any statements that are not statements of historical fact
      (such as statements containing the words <quote>believes,</quote>
      <quote>plans,</quote>
      <quote>anticipates,</quote>
      <quote>expects,</quote>
      <quote>estimates</quote> and similar expressions) should be considered forward-looking
      statements. Among others, the following risks, uncertainties and other factors could cause
      actual results to differ from those set forth in the forward-looking statements: (i) the risk
      that the merger may be delayed or may not be consummated; (ii) the risk that the definitive
      merger agreement may be terminated in circumstances that require Novell to pay Attachmate a
      termination fee of $60 million; (iii) risks related to the diversion of management’s attention
      from Novell’s ongoing business operations; (iv) risks regarding the failure of Attachmate to
      obtain the necessary financing to complete the merger; (v) the effect of the announcement of
      the patent sale or the merger on Novell’s business relationships (including, without
      limitation, partners and customers), operating results and business generally; and (vi) risks
      related to obtaining the requisite consents to the patent sale and the merger, including,
      without limitation, the timing (including possible delays) and receipt of regulatory approvals
      from various governmental entities (including any conditions, limitations or restrictions
      placed on these approvals) and the risk that one or more governmental entities may deny
      approval. Additional risk factors that may affect future results are contained in Novell’s
      filings with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (the <quote>SEC</quote>), including
      Novell’s Annual Report on Form 10-K for the fiscal year ended October 31, 2010, which are
      available at the SEC’s website http://www.sec.gov. Because forward-looking statements involve
      risks and uncertainties, actual results and events may differ materially from results and
      events currently expected. Novell expressly disclaims any obligation or undertaking to update
      or revise any forward-looking statements contained herein to reflect any change of
      expectations with regard thereto or to reflect any change in events, conditions or
      circumstances.</para>
    <para>ADDITIONAL INFORMATION ABOUT THE MERGER AND WHERE TO FIND IT</para>
    <para>In connection with the merger, Novell filed a preliminary proxy statement regarding the
      merger with the SEC on December 14, 2010 and intends to file a definitive proxy statement
      regarding the merger and other relevant documents with the SEC in the future. Investors and
      security holders of Novell are urged to read these documents, including the definitive proxy
      statement, if and when they become available, as well as any amendments or supplements to
      those documents, because they contain or will contain important information about Novell, the
      merger and the other parties to the merger. Investors and security holders may obtain these
      documents (and any other documents filed by Novell and Attachmate with the SEC) free of charge
      at the SEC’s website at http://www.sec.gov. In addition, the documents filed with the SEC by
      Novell may be obtained free of charge by directing such request to: Novell Investor Relations
      at 1-800-317-3195 or from the investor relations portion of Novell’s website at
      http://www.novell.com/company/ir/. <emphasis role="bold">Investors and security holders are
        urged to read the definitive proxy statement and the other relevant materials when they
        become available before making any voting or investment decision with respect to the
        merger.</emphasis> Novell and its directors and executive officers may be deemed to be
      participants in the solicitation of proxies from Novell’s stockholders in respect of the
      merger. Information regarding Novell’s directors and executive officers is contained in
      Novell’s proxy statement for its 2010 Annual Meeting of Stockholders, dated February 26, 2010,
      and subsequent filings which Novell has made with the SEC, including its Annual Report on Form
      10-K for the fiscal year ended October 31, 2010. Stockholders may obtain additional
      information about the directors and executive officers of Novell and their respective
      interests with respect to the merger by security holdings or otherwise, which may be different
      than those of Novell’s stockholders generally, by reading the preliminary proxy statement and
      the definitive proxy statement and other relevant documents regarding the merger, when filed
      with the SEC. Each of these documents is, or will be, available as described above. Other
      Sources: <ulink url="http://bit.ly/own1551">phoronix</ulink>
      <ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/open/news/item/Attachmate-says-future-of-SUSE-Linux-is-secure-1157083.html"
        >h-online</ulink></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 20.12.10 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/21/board-meeting-summary-15-december-2010/">Board
        Meeting Summary 15 December 2010</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>For the full transcript of the last openSUSE Board meeting, see our <ulink
        url="http://community.opensuse.org/meetings/opensuse-project/2010/opensuse-project.2010-12-15-19.01.log.html"
        >logs</ulink>. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Introduction of new openSUSE Board Chairman – Alan Clark
      </emphasis></para>
    <para>We opened with an introduction to new Board Chairman, Alan Clark who answered general
      questions from the community about his role and goals. To the question of what Clark’s goals
      are he answered:<orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>The top goal is as a Board to get the Foundation up and operational. As we continue
            to work towards this, I’m sure that we will uncover other issues that we will need to
            address</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Grow the Community</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Is a personal goal: Tune up my decoder ring for all these alias cloaking and get to
            know as many people as possible -simply because that is the fun part of being in a
            community.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Let people get their work done; er <quote>have a lot of fun</quote></para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist></para>
    <para>Alan also provided his background experience with open source projects, both within Novell
      and outside Novell. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Foundation Creation</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>Several board members expressed a desire to develop a more open and transparent process in
      communicating the development of the openSUSE Foundation than what currently exists. Some
      believe there has been a disconnect in how we become aware of what everyone is doing and
      keeping the momentum of the process going forward, as well as ensuring that all those with a
      vested interest are able to participate in the process.</para>
    <para>We all agreed that we must begin to identify who are the stakeholders and take steps
      immediately to open up the process. To that end, a new open mailing list will be created and
      Alan will create a wiki page where we will collect all the relevant information for the
      foundation creation. Relevant points and concerns of the stakeholders will be listed and the
      progress of the creation will be documented.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Membership Approval Concerns</emphasis></para>
    <para>Membership approval team members expressed concern about the clarity of the rules for
      consideration and eligibility.</para>
    <para>In the current rules, it states that a membership application is processed after receiving
      four votes. It was unclear whether that meant four votes in sum or four votes of either
      positive or negative. With a minor edit of the rules, we stated that an application is
      considered processed once it has received either four positive votes or four negative
      votes.</para>
    <para>Additionally, there was concern about a recent email request to process a particular
      application expeditiously. Team members felt this was an inappropriate breach of protocol and
      that all applications are equal and that no single application should be placed ahead of
      existing applications. We agreed and declared that henceforth, such requests should not be
      honored.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Where do we fail?</emphasis></para>
    <para>Our regular topic to identify areas where we fail and can quickly remedy brought up a
      topic of concern regarding communication. To this, we agreed that the Board will begin
      regularly posting summaries of meetings (which is what you are reading now.)</para>
    <para>We also took a general board action item to review <ulink
        url="https://features.opensuse.org/statistic/product/opensuse.org">opensuse.org product
        category in openFATE</ulink> to ensure we stay on top of “Where do we fail?” concerns that
      are not brought up during board meetings.</para>
    <para>Read here for the <ulink
        url="http://community.opensuse.org/meetings/opensuse-project/2010/opensuse-project.2010-12-15-19.01.log.html"
        >full meeting transcript</ulink>.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Next Meeting</emphasis></para>
    <para>With the holidays coming up, we will have our next Board meeting on 12 January,
      2011.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 22.12.10 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/12/23/opensuse-announces-fifth-development-milestone-with-kernel-interactivity-patch/"
        >openSUSE Announces Fifth Development Milestone with Kernel Interactivity Patch</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>The openSUSE project released the fifth of six milestones in the development of openSUSE
      11.4 some days ago. <emphasis role="bold">Milestone 5 (M5)</emphasis> brings a wide range of
      updates, both major and minor. As usual, you can get it <ulink
        url="http://software.opensuse.org/developer/en">here</ulink>.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Major Features</emphasis>:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Kernel 2.6.37rc5-12 is the basis of M5, including the famous “200 line” per tty task
          groups patch to improve desktop interactivity, and featuring the almost-complete removal
          of the so-called ‘Big Kernel Lock’, which should improve scalability. This kernel supports
          new drivers, including Broadcom wireless and updated open-source graphics drivers, and a
          host of the usual other improvements.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Libzypp 8.10.2 adds improved support and fixes for metalinks, the multiple download
          URL specification.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>On the desktop, the KDE Platform makes the leap to version 4.6 beta with many
          improvements in the UI and underlying infrastructure. This includes a complete rewrite of
          Kontact and is undergoing heavy testing. There is a serious chance KDE PIM 4.6 will not
          make it into the final openSUSE 11.4 release, testing and development is needed!</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>KOffice is updated to 2.3 RC superseding beta1, including the exciting Krita natural
          media painting app. Meanwhile OpenOffice.org is removed, having been succeeded by
          LibreOffice which is updated to 3.3.0.1.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>GNOME 2.32.1 is now available as the 2.32.2 is the final version planned for openSUSE
          11.4, which is notable for being the last stable release before GNOME 3 in March.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>GNUCash 2.4 RC comes with a new complete dress-up.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Pidgin updates fixes several MSN and ICQ issues.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>In the Virtualization area, available now are kernel-xen 2.5.37 features and
          kernel-ec2 2.6.37 with improvements for cloud sync services and Virtual Box 4 Beta
          including USB devices support and more than 2GB RAM support on 32 bit guest, Intel HD
          Audio, asynchronous I/O for iSCSI, VMDK, VHD and Parallels image support.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>systemd 15 provides aggressive parallelization capabilities to start multiple daemons
          at the same time with dependencies which offers improvements to the boot times on some
          systems. More testing (and porting of init scripts) is still needed for systemd, which
          will most likely make it into 11.4 as experimental and optional feature.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Get it!</emphasis></para>
    <para>A list of most annoying bugs is being compiled; please check it before installing. We look
      forward to your bug reports and test experiences! Automated testing and the openSUSE Factory
      team have been very active to ensure that your download of M5 will be at least minimally
      functional, thanks for that! now go and <ulink url="http://software.opensuse.org/developer/en"
        >download it!</ulink></para>
    <para>The next milestone is scheduled for Thursday, Jan 20 2011, and will be the openSUSE 11.4
      Milestone 6 release. The final openSUSE 11.4 is planned to be released in March 2011.</para>
    <para>Other Souces: <ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/open/news/item/openSUSE-11-4-Milestone-5-released-1158848.html"
        > h-online</ulink>
      <ulink
        url="http://www.linux.com/news/enterprise/biz-enterprise/392669:opensuse-114-milestone-5-released"
        >Linux.com</ulink></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 23.12.10 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>openSUSE Weekly News searches for contributors</title>
    <figure>
      <title>Merry Christmas (c) Péronne vd Ham / pixelio.de</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://images.pixelio.de/data/media/51/sterre_22_wr_Large.jpg"
            width="45%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>Hello Mates. The last year was a great year. We had seen many funny things. The Relaunch
      of the openSUSE BuildService now provides many Features for packager. Then the
      kde-obs-generator makes the life easier for cross packaging. The openSUSE Conference was
      another interesting Highlight, and last but not least the sell of Novell. </para>
    <para>The openSUSE Weekly News Team searches the whole week for new things. Now we searching one
      or two new Contributors who are collecting news with us. In the past we have given one part
      of the news to one person, and that person was responsible for this part of the Weekly News.
      As Example you provide the Section "Tips and Tricks" so you can add and remove that Section
      what do you think is the best.</para>
    <para>ATM we can give the following Sections to a good Hand:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Tips and Tricks</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>In the Community</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>On the Web.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>What do you need for working in the english newsletter? If you can read and a little bit
      write XML, and you know how to svn up, then you're the perfect Candidate. If you can't this
      things, and would like to learn it, you are a perfect Candidate.</para>
    <para>If you're interested in helping us, just send a Mail to: <ulink
      url="mailto:saigkill@opensuse.org">saigkill@opensuse.org</ulink></para>
    <para>Last but not least the openSUSE Weekly News team with the translations into hungarian,
    greek and japanese wishes merry cristmas to all people across the world.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 25.12.10 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
