<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="community">
  <title>In the Community</title>
  <!--Put here things relevant to the openSUSE community maybe from * People of openSUSE or elections, votings 1 - 2 posts-->
  <sect2>
    <title>Postings from the Community</title>    
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blip.tv/file/4729446">openSUSE TV: Example of cross-distro
          collaboration: Application Installer (Vincent Untz)</ulink></title>
      <para>Nearly all distributions are slowly moving towards making it easier to deal with
        applications, and get information about those. However, many of us are working in our own
        corners: unfortunately, this is often what happens with many topics that would move faster
        if they were looked from a cross-distro perspective.A small team of people from various
        distributions will meet in January to discuss what can be done in a cross-distro way. This
        talk will present the conclusions from this meeting, and will come back on the experience of
        organizing work in a cross-distro way.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 7.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blip.tv/file/4729504">openSUSE TV: Distribution collaboration
          manifesto (Stefano Zacchiroli, Jared K. Smith, Jos Poortvliet)</ulink></title>
      <para>The FOSS distribution communities work toward very similar goals: each distribution aims
        at providing a coherent set of (Free) softwares to their users.A good deal of work (and
        patches!) can be shared across distributions and in part already is. The more we
        collaborate, among us and with our (common!) upstreams, the more we can improve Free
        Software as a whole. Sometimes, however, social obstacles get in the way of collaboration:
        volunteers don't like each other or each other distro; they might also easily get
        "religious" about the everlasting question "which is the best distro out
        there?".Understanding why we should collaborate across distros is the first needed step in
        improving how we collaborate.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 7.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>    
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://opensuse.blip.tv/file/4747393/">openSUSE TV: Downstream packaging
          collaboration (Hans de Goede, Michal Hrušecký)</ulink></title>
      <para>patch sharing or start a new upstream?Most distributions contain packages where upstream
        is completely dead or very close to it, yet there still is a significant user group for the
        packages in question, be it directly or through other packages depending on them. But even
        when upstream is alive, packages often needs some additional patching.All distributions seem
        to end up carrying some custom distro grown patchset, with some patches being shared and
        other patches being unique per distro. Clearly not an ideal situation and one which most
        distributions try to avoid by feeding all necessary changes upstream and aiming for having
        packages which use the upstream provided code as is.Clearly the usual model of sharing code
        fixes / integration work done at the distribution level between distributions by pushing it
        upstream does not work for projects where there is no upstream. And even with upstream
        around, distributions sometimes needs to fix bugs in versions that upstream no longer care
        about or fix bugs that are not important/considered feature upstream and it may take a long
        time to get them fixed there. In the end we can't avoid all patching. But we can try to
        avoid duplicating the work by better sharing the results.The plan for this sessions is to
        give a short presentation sketching the problem, show two possible approaches to help
        solving this problem together with few generally helpful ideas. After presenting these
        hopefully somewhat structured discussion with the audience about this topic is
        planned.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 7.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://blip.tv/file/4729654">openSUSE TV: ZYpp your distro (Dominik Heidler
          Duncan Mac-Vicar P.)</ulink></title>
      <para>ZYpp is an opensource project originated in the openSUSE distribution which groups the
        most advanced and fast dependency solver (satsolver), a package management library and a
        command line package management tool (zypper). Over the years ZYpp has matured to become one
        of openSUSE most appreciated features.This talk will show ZYpp's main features and work
        being done to have it running on other rpm-based distributions.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 7.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://hedgehogpainter.livejournal.com/11599.html">Katarina Machalkova: I
          survived FOSDEM 2011</ulink></title>
      <para>After some reports from other LibreOffice crowd members (<ulink
          url="http://luxate.blogspot.com/2011/02/fosdem-2011-summary.html">here</ulink> and <ulink
          url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/ItalosOOoBlog/~3/pJrk3wbKI9g/">here</ulink>), I'm
        adding mine to the heap: </para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Friday</emphasis>
      </para>
      <para>The fun has started at Prague airport already. Due to (to put it mildly) incompetence of
        the printing shop I'm not gonna name, Kendy and me had exactly 10 minutes to dispatch 45
        kilos of swag through the check-in -- that meant distributing the load into our luggage and
        shipping the remaining boxes as overweight ( including paying criminal surcharge for it). I
        hereby apologize to Czech Airways check-in clerk for spoiling her shift with it ;-) Getting
        the material from Brussels luggage claim to the train station was rather challenging as
        well, but fortunately there were some helping hands waiting for us at Brussels Nord (thanks
        Thorsten, Rene and Kohei). In Kendy's words: "T<emphasis role="italic">he experience doesn't
          necessarily have to be positive, but it definitely has to be remarkable. We would have
          nothing to talk about otherwise</emphasis>." Friday's beer event (my first ever) was also
        an enchanting experience. Met Caolan and Florian 'flr' Reuter for the first time (who, in
        slightly boozed state, asked me "Hey, so you are my successor at Novell?"). It was amazing
        to see LibreOffice crew almost having blocked the street in front of Delirium Cafe :)
        (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 10.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://florianreuter.blogspot.com/2011/02/just-came-back-from-fosdem.html"
        >Florian Reuter: FOSDEM</ulink></title>
      <para>Just came back from FOSDEM. Felt really good to meet the “usual suspects” again. Thanks
        for the great weekend! </para>
      <para>I also had a chance to talk with Jos about ODF Web and ODF Collaboration. Jos gave a great
        talk about his ODF Web Javascript Framework which emerged from his ODFKit efforts. </para>
      <para>Jos had a very important slide in his talk which echoed my own believe: NO CONVERSION!
        This principle guided the design of his ODF Web Framework. NO CONVERSION simply means that Jos
        does not try to heuristically (aka lossy) map ODF to HTML and then map HTML heuristically (aka
        lossy) back to ODF. Instead Jos decided to have a clean 2-tier architecture which cleanly
        separates the content- and the view layer: ODF is content and HTML is the view. I think that’s
        the right approach. Even more: I think if you start adding “smart conversions”/”heuristics”
        and other “intelligent mappings” things will get ugly sooner or later. [And from my experience
        on OpenOffice.org filter hacking things will get messy sooner than you like. Always keep
        Murphy’s law in mind: What can go wrong will go wrong!]. </para>
      <para>We also had a chance to talk about Operational Transformation (OT) in the context of ODF.
        I tried to argue that what is really missing in ODF is a list of “atomic changes” a user can
        make to an ODF document. If we had this list of “atomic changes” we could build a
        transformation on top of it. For OT it is very important that you have “atomic” operations,
        since you need operation transformations for every pair of operation. E.g. if you have |OPS|
        operations you need |OPS x OPS| transformations. So keeping |OPS| small is quite important! </para>
      <para>Assembling the list of atomic operations is a lot of work --- admitted. However it is work
        that every designer of an API needs to do anyway. I really believe that some input from the
        ODF API projects like Oracles’ ODFDOM, IBM’s Simple API for ODF, ANR’s LPOD and Jos’ ODFKit
        could really help. </para>
      <para>Let me finish my post by a classification of change to an ODF document:</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_k9bd8YQpZ7Y/TVARD-e1z0I/AAAAAAAAAIQ/aejOhYvKRZg/s400/changeclasses.jpg"
            width="30%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para> I believe that for change tracking we only need “atomic operations” and a way to combine
        them to “compound operations”. I don’t think we need to be able to track changes to the XML
        tree or the XML text. In fact I think it does more harm than good. </para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 8.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://dev-loki.blogspot.com/2011/02/fosdem-2011-eol.html">Pascal Bleser:
        FOSDEM 2011 EOL</ulink></title>
      <para>So <ulink url="http://fosdem.org/2011">FOSDEM 2011</ulink> is over, at last, and it was a
        huge success, as always (mind you, I'm one of the organizers, my opinions might be just a
        little subjective here ;)). </para>
      <para>From the organizational point of view, I was less active this year compared the the 7
        previous ones (yes, it's already the 8th time for me, and I noticed how annoying it is to say
        "8th" in English quite a few times during the weekend): lots of procastrination and my "spare
        time" being vampirized by other activities, most prominently work on the <ulink
          url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board">openSUSE Board</ulink> (which I am now <ulink
            url="http://dev-loki.blogspot.com/2011/01/why-i-am-not-running-for-opensuse-board.html">no
            longer part of</ulink>). Definitely something to fix for next year, and a big mea culpa to
        my mates on the FOSDEM organization team. </para>
      <para>That being said, it was still a lot of work, as it is for every edition, and while I
        suppose that most if not all the visitors are sorry that the event is already over, we're
        pretty happy it is, I'm sure you can understand why :). </para>
      <para>All in all, it was very successful. There were more visitors, as each year, and I believe
        that we've really reached the limits of the infrastructure we're using at the moment. That
        means we'll have a few "interesting" challenges ahead of us for the next edition (no, we won't
        move away from the ULB nor from the Solbosch campus, we'll just have to stretch the space used
        by FOSDEM a bit more to use more and larger rooms). But more about that in a few months' time. </para>
      <para>It was also very smooth for everything else. Having so many volunteers to help us out
        during the weekend, including for the very tedious task of setting things up, was really
        ${deity}-send. Thanks to the support of the ULB networking team, Belnet as well as Cisco made
        FOSDEM provide what must be the best possible wifi infrastructure at an event of such size.
        Our usual <ulink url="http://bit.ly/ewcvgx">collaboration with LPI</ulink> went great as well
        (was awesome to meet my good friend <ulink url="http://twitter.com/fabricemous">Fabrice
          Mous</ulink> again) as it provided the opportunity for ~130 exams to be taken by FOSDEM
        visitors. </para>
      <para>We even managed to fill up our largest room, <ulink
        url="http://fosdem.org/2011/schedule/room/janson">Janson</ulink>, which is one of the
        largest auditoriums in Belgium with 1400 seats, up to the limit and even a bit more for the
        keynotes. That was impressive, to say the least. </para>
      <para>It was a great pleasure to meet so many fine people and friends again (including, but not
        exclusively, Henne Vogelsang, Peter Linnell, Andrew Wafaa, Jürgen Weigert, Will Stephenson,
        Bruno Friedmann, Pavol Rusnak, Michal Hrusecky, Vincent Untz, Michael Meeks, Daniel Seuffert,
        Frank Karlitschek, Delphine Lebedel, Tristan Nitot, William Quiviger, Tom Marble, etc etc
        etc... -- sorry if I forgot you, I'm just too lazy and tired to keep pulling names out of my
        brain at this point, too many to list :)), even if it was usually only for a short chat as I
        have to keep running around all over the venue to get things done. </para>
      <para>That's usually the point where one realizes again that it is so much about the people,
        more than anything else (you are fine to disagree here, dear reader, it is just my very humble
        opinion). So many FOSS projects are driven by so many great people, I'd just love it to last
        for a couple of weeks to have the time to have beers (or coffee) with every single one of
        them, at the very least the ones I already know. I'm really happy and thankful -- to FOSDEM, I
        guess -- to be so lucky to have been in touch with so many interesting people, and obviously
        hope to still be in the future. </para>
      <para>And FOSDEM is also a very inclusive event, where projects and initiatives covering the
        whole spectrum in terms of technologies, domains and (OSI compatible) licenses get together to
        have a great deal of fun. I believe that every single visitor would agree that it is the most
        effective way to get our motivation batteries loaded to spend our spare time, energy, love,
        sweat and blood into doing such great things. </para>
      <para>On the cross-pollination front, which is more and more of a priority for us, I'm happy to
        see the <ulink url="http://fosdem.org/2011/schedule/track/crossdistro_devroom">Crossdistro
          developer room</ulink> clearly evolve into the right direction (thanks to <ulink
            url="http://grep.be/">Wouter Verhelst</ulink> (of Debian fame) to take care of that); where
        not quite there yet, as intentions need to be followed by much more action, but it is a step
        forward already, and such things do take a good deal of time, as much as many of us would like
        to see it happening as soon as possible, especially at openSUSE. FOSDEM is such a great
        opportunity to get together with other projects and people, as so many of them are on the
        spot. </para>
      <para>For a couple of final words, my big "thank you" goes out, in no particular order, to the
        volunteers who helped us during the weekend, to the sponsors that support the event, to the
        visitors who have donated money in order to keep giving us the chance of remaining
        independent, to the people and projects who were there at the stands, devrooms, lightning
        talks, to the speakers who accepted our invitations, obviously to the other members of the
        FOSDEM organization team (we did it again! :D), to the ULB and CI for providing us with their
        infrastructure, and, of course, to the people who attended. </para>
      <para>On a side note, if you were at FOSDEM 2011, please take a minute to fill out our <ulink
        url="http://fosdem.org/2011/census">census </ulink>as well as our <ulink
          url="http://fosdem.org/2011/feedback">feedback form</ulink>.</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 8.2.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>People of openSUSE</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>This Week: xyz</title>
      <para>Good Guy. Glows in the night.</para>
    </blockquote>
    </sect2> -->
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Welcome new openSUSE Members</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/fcrozat">Frederic Crozat (fcrozat)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Very active in the openSUSE GNOME Team and Bugzilla.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/helen-au">Helen South
        (helen-au)</ulink></title>
      <para>Helen works inside Marketing and the Editor Team of news.opensuse.org.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/dominian">Matt Hayes
        (dominian)</ulink></title>
      <para>Active in Bugzilla, Wiki and Mailinglists.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/tsotsos">Angelos Tzotsos
        (tsotsos)</ulink></title>
      <para>Active inside the Greek Community and Marketing.</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="https://users.opensuse.org/show/bekun">Kai-Uwe Behrmann
        (bekun)</ulink></title>
      <para>Kai-Uwe serves as Speaker, Boothman and Developer for the openSUSE Project.</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Events &amp; Meetings</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Past</title>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/03/24/opensuse-board-meeting/">February 09, 2011 : openSUSE Board Meeting</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/05/13/%ef%bb%bfopensuse-kde-team-meeting/">February 10, 2011 : openSUSE KDE Team meeting</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Upcoming</title>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/03/24/opensuse-board-meeting/">February 23, 2011 : openSUSE Board Meeting</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <!-- ($ ld: 12.02.11 sm $) -->
    <para>You can find more informations on other events at: <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/category/events/">openSUSE News/Events</ulink>. - <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Ambassadors_events">Local Events</ulink></para>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>openSUSE for your Ears</title>
    <para>The openSUSE Weekly News are available as livestream or podcast in German. You can hear it
      or download it on <ulink url="http://blog.radiotux.de/podcast">Radiotux</ulink>. </para>
  </sect2>
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>From Ambassadors</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://stick.gk2.sk/blog/2011/01/gnome-python-hackfest-appinstaller-meeting-and-bretzn-hackfest/"
          >Pavol Rusnak: GNOME Python Hackfest, AppInstaller Meeting and Bretzn Hackfest</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>What a cool and productive week! But let me start from the beginning … </para>
      <para>A couple of months ago we decided to start a <ulink
          url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hackerspace">hackerspace</ulink> in Prague called <ulink
          url="http://brmlab.cz/">brmlab</ulink>. Most of the members deal with hardware, but there
        are also couple of software guys like me. At the end of November we were contacted by <ulink
          url="http://blog.tomeuvizoso.net/">Tomeu</ulink> and he asked if they can organize <ulink
          url="http://live.gnome.org/Hackfests/Python2011">GNOME Python Hackfest</ulink> in our
        hackerspace. I was more than delighted about the idea, so we agreed and started to plan
        things. In the end we had 9 FOSS hackers working on GNOME and Python and I think they
        enjoyed their time in Prague. Hackerspace is a great concept, because these folks didn’t
        have to spend extra money on renting some place and our members had opportunity to meet
        foreign FOSS developers and try exotic hardware like <ulink
          url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OLPC_XO-1">OLPC XO-1</ulink>.</para>
      <figure id="fig.blogpost">
        <title>Blogposts from <ulink
            url="http://blog.tomeuvizoso.net/2010/12/python-gnome-hackfest-2011.html">Tomeu</ulink>
          and <ulink url="http://www.j5live.com/2011/01/19/pygi-in-prague/">J5</ulink> about the
          event</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://stick.gk2.sk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/gnome-python-1.jpg"
              width="25%" align="center"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>I had to leave the guys on Tuesday evening, because I spent the rest of the week in SUSE
        office in Nuernberg. The first three days were dedicated to <ulink
          url="http://distributions.freedesktop.org/wiki/Meetings/AppInstaller2011"
          >Cross-distribution meeting</ulink> about application installer organized by <ulink
          url="http://www.vuntz.net/journal/">Vincent</ulink>. It went more than well, we discussed
        and agreed on many things, which is great and in the end we were able to give a <ulink
          url="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BHeP2ZBwS_U">presentation</ulink> + we also created a
          <ulink url="http://distributions.freedesktop.org/wiki/AppStream">nice AppStream
          wikipage</ulink> as a starting point for any future work.</para>
      <figure id="fig.summary">
        <title>Vincent wrote a nice summary for <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/">openSUSE
            News</ulink>. (It is not yet there, but should appear soon.)</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="http://stick.gk2.sk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/appstream_meeting.jpg"
              width="25%" align="center"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>This meeting was immediately followed by <ulink
          url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:2011_Bretzn_Meeting">Bretzn hackfest</ulink>
        organized by <ulink url="http://blog.karlitschek.de/">Frank</ulink>. The main focus of it
        was implementing some of the things we agreed on previous meeting from the KDE/Qt
        perspective and porting MeeGo Garage to openSUSE. During it I was mainly dealing with
        appdata.xml format we described in the AppStream meeting – I created an XML schema so we can
        validate it and also developed a proof-of-concept generator of this piece of metadata in
        Python. (<ulink url="http://gitorious.org/appstream">git repo</ulink>) Hope we can get it in
        createrepo and dpkg-scan* utilities soon.</para>
      <figure id="fig.planetsuse">
        <title>Frank’s summary about the hackfest will appear on <ulink
            url="http://planet.opensuse.org/">Planet openSUSE</ulink> soon</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="http://stick.gk2.sk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/DSC_1674.jpg"
              width="25%" align="center"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>I would like to thank GNOME Foundation and Collabora for sponsoring the GNOME Python
        Hackfest, Novell for sponsoring the Bretzn Hackfest and Canonical, Debian, Mageia, Novell
        and Red Hat for sending their people to AppInstaller Meeting! It’s really nice and
        encouraging to see folks from various companies working on one common goal.</para>
      <para>And yeah,</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://stick.gk2.sk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/going-to.png"
            width="10%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>so see you there!</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Communication</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/">The Mailinglists</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org">The openSUSE Forums</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Contributors</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://users.opensuse.org">The User Directory</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
