<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
  %myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="kernel">
  <title>Kernel Review</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/Kernel-Log-updated-Radeon-drivers-mdadm-and-ALSA-1185791.html"
        >h-online/Thorsten Lemmhuis: Kernel Log: Consistent names for network interfaces</ulink>
    </title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">A new version of the AMD driver from X.org improves support for
        modern Radeon graphics chips. An updated mdadm, initially only designed for developers,
        allows the RAID functions of modern Intel motherboard chip-sets to be used. After nine
        months, the ALSA project has published a new version. </emphasis></para>
    <para>AMD’s kernel and X.org developer Alex Deucher has <ulink
        url="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.comp.freedesktop.xorg/45671">published</ulink> version
      6.14.0 of driver package xf86-video-ati. It contains the X.org driver for Radeon graphics
      hardware, which provides much better support for the latest version of Radeon graphics chips.
      For example, it now not only controls the graphics kernel of the Fusion processors developed
      under codename <quote>Ontario</quote>, but also the Northern Islands GPUs based on Radeon HD
      models 62xx to 68xx. With both of them, 2D acceleration via EXA now works, as does video
      acceleration with the antiquated Xv (Xvideo), but in both cases the driver remains dependant
      on <ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/Kernel-Log-Coming-in-2-6-38-Part-1-Graphics-1176900.html"
        >Linux kernel 2.6.38</ulink>, which is still under development and is expected to be
      released at the end of March or beginning of April. Its DRM driver with functions for KMS
      (kernel-based mode-setting) is required anyway for Northern Islands GPUs because the driver
      does not support UMS (user mode-setting) on these chips. </para>
    <para>In combination with KMS in kernel 2.6.36 and later, the driver also supports EXA and Xv on
      Evergreen GPUs on Radeon HD 5,000 series models. The developers have considerably upgraded the
      man page in the new version. Along with kernel 2.6.38, the driver offers page-flipping support
      so that image updates are more precisely synchronised with the start of frame re-draw. For
      further information on this new technology in Linux 2.6.38, see the <ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/Kernel-Log-Coming-in-2-6-38-Part-1-Graphics-1176900.html">first
        part</ulink> of the series <quote>Coming in 2.6.38</quote>. </para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 10.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://schaiba.wordpress.com/2011/02/11/kernel-weekly-news-12-02-2011/">Rares
        Aioanei: kernel weekly news 12.02.2011</ulink></title>
    <para>Rares gives us this week a great Kernel Review. Thanks Rares :-)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 12.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.kroah.com/log/linux/maintainer-05.html">Greg
        Kroah-Hartman: How not to piss off a kernel subsystem maintainer - part 5</ulink></title>
    <para>Fifth in a long series of complaints... See <ulink
        url="http://www.kroah.com/log/linux/maintainer.html">part 1</ulink> and <ulink
        url="http://www.kroah.com/log/linux/maintainer-02.html">part 2</ulink> and <ulink
        url="http://www.kroah.com/log/linux/maintainer-03.html">part 3</ulink> and <ulink
        url="http://www.kroah.com/log/linux/maintainer-04.html">part4</ulink> for previous
      atrocities. </para>
    <para>Heck, It's not like I haven't said all of this before, but it sure seems like no one
      learns from the past, or reads the documentation that we write for how to actually submit a
      patch for the kernel. Linux has one of the best documented procedures for how to do this, it's
      not like it's a secret or something... </para>
    <para>Anyway, here's a list of patches that people have sent me in this week alone that have
      caused me major problems:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>patch was never even build tested, and of course, it breaks when you do build
            it.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>patch does build, but it was never tested because the patch does the opposite of
            what the submitter wanted to do.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>patch sent with no authorship </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>patch sent with no signed-off-by line</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>patch sent with no description of what the patch did</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>patch sent with a description, yet it was not the description of the patch
            itself</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>patch sent with a description that the patch only did one thing, yet the patch did 4
            different things</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>patch sent with a description that made no sense at all</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>patch sent in a series of 13 patches, all with the same exact subject, and no
            description of what the patch did</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>a one line patch that if applied, would instantly break the build</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>patch that asked for reviews, yet gets angry when you ask why something was done a
            certain way</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>patch that asked for reviews, and when asked, can't explain why code was done a
            certain way, blaming a non-existent person for that portion</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>patch that said it fixed a bug, yet added a new feature without fixing the original
            bug</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>patch for cleaning up coding style issues</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>yet adds different coding issues patches asked for review, yet had obviously never
            been even run through our automatic "test this patch for sanity" tools.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>Yeah, it's been a fun week... </para>
    <para>And if anyone ever wonders why code reviewers are grumpy, just look at the above list and
      understand.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 12.2.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
