<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1>
  <title>Board Election 2010</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/12/14/board-elections/">Nelson Marques: Board elections…</ulink></title>
    <para>I’ve decided to remain a spectator during this Board elections to understand the process
      and I like the applies for the board. I can say I’m happy to see ‘mrdocs’ applying for the
      board, as he was one of the persons which helped me a lot with openSUSE Build Service in my
      early days. He always had a cool advice or a couple of minutes to make my life easier. </para>
    <para>Except for ‘mrdocs’ I really don’t know much about the other candidates, so I’ve decided
      to take a small note and expose my frustration for not seeing Sirko Kemter running for the
      Board. I would support Sirko on running to the board for several reasons: </para>
    <para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>He’s the face of openSUSE Artwork team. He’s been doing awesome screencasts and
            tutorials… I guess in a way, related to Artwork, which I find to be an area which is
            underdeveloped in openSUSE, he can bring lots of new synergies… and a new visual
            identity to openSUSE. </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>His degree of commitment to the local German Community. I’ve seen some posts of him
            and some of the initiatives he does. I loved the openMovie night at KommKino in Nürnberg
            during openSUSE Conference for which he was the mastermind behind it. So he’s really a
            community guy. </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para> His a vertical and direct person, which speaks his mind. This is something I love
            on people. I don’t know Sirko from talking on the back of people, I know him from being
            straight to point and direct. This is a very positive thing… </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Gnokii plays well the role of ‘bad cop’. That’s always good to have around.
            Sometimes people need to ear more harsh things to get back into reality. Gnokii does
            this role good. </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>He’s one of the most objective people I’ve seen around… many times bringing people
            to reality, thus speeding up people on taking actions and drop the philosophical
            issues</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </para>
    <para>I really see him as a community guy, always around, helping whenever he cans… He’s doing a
      great job and he should be empowered to run to the Board. </para>
    <para>For all the other candidates, which many I don’t know… good luck… with so much cool people
      running for the Board, I can only see a smiling future ahead. I won’t vote for the Board
      elections for some reasons, being the major… I won’t to split votes amongst so many cool
      people, therefore, I’m remaining on neutral grounds wishing all the best of luck. Whatever is
      the outcome, I’m sure openSUSE will win! </para>
    <para>Have a lot of fun! </para>
    <para>PS: I hope to see a public debate with all candidates on IRC opened to questions and
      doubts from the openSUSE community members and users! Please make it happen!</para>
  </blockquote>
  <!-- ($ ld: 16.12.10 sm $) -->
</sect1>
