<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="forums">
  <title>openSUSE Forums</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/news/announcements/450971-greek-language-forums-now-open.html"
        >Greek subforums now open</ulink></title>
    <para>
      The <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org">openSUSE Forums</ulink> have a growing number of language specific subforums. Until the 7th of december we only had German, Hungarian, French, Japanese, Dutch and Russian subforums, and provided external links to forums in Spanish and Hebrew. Now we're proud to let you know, that a Greek Language subforum has been added. So if you're Greek, become part of the openSUSE Community, using your native language in the Greek subforums.
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
      url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-help-here/install-boot-login/450978-open-suse-asking-cd-number-1-all-time.html"
      >openSUSE asking CD number 1 all the time</ulink></title>
    <para>This is a thread about problems with the install media, or with the CD/DVD devices used to run the install media. Like many times, it seems that "a problem" is not just "a problem"; there's more going on. Sometimes it's the install medium itself, sometimes it's the drive it's in, sometimes the machine to install to has it's part in the trouble. All these aspects are addressed.
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
      url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/community/general-chit-chat/450914-where-do-forum-members-come.html"
      >Where do forum members come from?</ulink></title>
    <para>
      Here's a user posted poll, to see where the forums members come from. View the results, read the comments.
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
      url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/news/announcements/451115-staff-appoinment-jonathan_r-global-moderator.html"
      >Staff appointment - New Global Moderator</ulink></title>
    <para>
      Another thing to let you know: the staff of the <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org">openSUSE Forums</ulink> is glad to announce the appointment of member Jonathan_R as a Global Moderator, who already was a Moderator for the english forums. Welcome Jonathan_R !!
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>This week's subforum: 
      <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-help-here/install-boot-login/"
      ></ulink></title>
    <para>
      This forum of the <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org">openSUSE Forums</ulink>is a subforum of <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-help-here/">Get Help Here</ulink>. It's one of the most active subforums, where people post for/to help during the install of openSUSE, where useful info is provided for starters in the linux field. The subjects vary from partitioning to graphic card issues, from the penguins we see in the GRUB menu around Christmas to login methods.    
    </para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 07.12.10 gl $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
