<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
  <!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->
  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://www.osor.eu/news/eu-european-parliamentarians-participate-in-document-freedom-day">EU: European Parliamentarians participate in Document Freedom Day</ulink></title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Members of the European Parliament and their assistants are
          participating in this year's Document Freedom Day, a 'grassroots effort to educate the
          public about the importance of Free Document Formats and Open Standards in general',
          according to an announcement on the organisation's website. The three are hosting several
          presentations, in the Paul-Henri Spaak building of the European Parliament in Brussels, on
          Wednesday. </emphasis></para>
      <para>MEPs Malika Benarab-Attou, Indrek Tarand and Karima Delli are taking part “to emphasize
        the opportunities offered by digital technologies to broaden access to culture in Europe and
        in the world”, writes MEP Malika Benarab-Attou on her website. The MEPs say all documents
        formats and document applications should be readably by any machine and for any person. “The
        public domain needs to be protected from erosion and on the contrary nourished and
        extended.”</para>
      <para>The MEPs have organised three presentations on open documents, by Stefan Gradmann,
        Professor of Library and Information Science at Humboldt-University in Berlin, by Hýkon Wium
        Lie, Chief Technology Officer of Opera Software and Kaido Kikkas, Associate Professor at the
        Estonian Information Technology College and Associate Professor of Social and Free Software
        at Tallinn University, in Estonia. (...)</para>
      <!--($ ld: 26.3.11 sm $)-->   
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://www.opennetworkingfoundation.org/?p=7">Open Networking Foundation Formed to Speed Network Innovation</ulink></title>
      <para>PORTLAND, Ore. — March 21, 2011 — Six companies that own and operate some of the largest networks in the world — Deutsche Telekom, Facebook, Google, Microsoft, Verizon, and Yahoo! — announced today the formation of the Open Networking Foundation (ONF), a nonprofit organization dedicated to promoting a new approach to networking called Software-Defined Networking (SDN). Joining these six founding companies in creating ONF are 17 member companies, including major equipment vendors, networking and virtualization software suppliers, and chip technology providers.</para>
      <para>In the past two decades, enormous innovation has taken place on top of the Internet architecture. Email, e-commerce, search, social networks, cloud computing, and the web as we know it are all good examples. While networking technologies have also evolved in this time, the ONF believes that more rapid innovation is needed. SDN fulfills this need by enabling innovation in all kinds of networks — including data centers, wide area telecommunication networks, wireless networks, enterprises and in homes — through relatively simple software changes. SDN thus gives owners and operators of networks better control over their networks, allowing them to optimize network behavior to best serve their and their customers’ needs. For instance, in data centers SDN can be used to reduce energy usage by allowing some routers to be powered down during off-peak periods. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 26.3.11 sat $) -->    
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Call for participation</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://www.linuxjournal.com/content/wanted-passionate-geeks">LinuxJournal/Katherine Druckman: Wanted: Passionate Geeks</ulink></title>
      <para>If you love tinkering with your Linux machine, have ninja sysadmin skills, or are an
        avid user of open source software in general, <emphasis role="italic">and</emphasis> you
        love to share your knowledge with others, I'd really like to hear from you.</para>
      <para>We're looking for a few more passionate techies to join our ranks as contributing
        LinuxJournal.com authors. We're particularly interested in articles about System
        Administration, Linux on the desktop, high-performance computing, embedded Linux, web and
        mobile development, security, and virtualization. If you have an interest in any of these
        areas, and useful knowledge to share, <ulink url="mailto:webmistress@linuxjournal.com">drop
          me a line</ulink>. We're always looking for great technical content as well as opinion
        pieces about the world of open-source software. (...)</para>
      <!--($ ld: 23.3.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://www.techrepublic.com/blog/opensource/will-new-opensuse-with-kde-46-bring-distro-back-from-obscurity/2347">techrepublic/Jack Wallen: Will new openSUSE with KDE 4.6 bring distro back from obscurity?</ulink></title>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Takeaway</emphasis>: <emphasis role="italic">The openSUSE
          distribution nearly faded away into obscurity. But 11.4 brings this distribution back to
          serious relevancy. See what Jack Wallen thinks about the latest from the openSUSE
          developers.</emphasis></para>
      <para>Remember when SuSE Linux was a real powerhouse? YaST was one of the finest
        administration tools available and SuSE was one of the few distributions featuring the KDE
        desktop as the default. But then Novell purchased SuSE and things changed. Ubuntu came to be
        and new users flocked to a distribution that promised Nirvana for Linux users. And with all
        of the changes happening on the Linux landscape, <ulink url="http://www.opensuse.org/en/"
          >openSUSE</ulink> continued moving ever forward, not swaying from its path, not causing
        rifts in the Linux community, and eating their own dog food.</para>
      <para>The only problem? openSUSE seemed to be slowly disappearing. With Ubuntu taking up the
        majority of the media’s attention and end users looking for something more compatible and
        easier to use, only the faithful few remained with openSUSE.</para>
      <para>But now a new release for the distribution, the project that is controlled by the
        community, is poised to bring it back out of obscurity…and with good reason. Actually, I
        will give you two good reasons: KDE 4.6 and Tumbleweed/Factory. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 21.3.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://www.h-online.com/open/news/item/Linux-Foundation-switches-MeeGo-TV-on-1213423.html">h-online/Linux Foundation switches MeeGo TV on</ulink></title>
      <para>The <ulink url="http://www.linuxfoundation.org/">Linux Foundation</ulink> has <ulink
          url="http://www.linuxfoundation.org/news-media/announcements/2011/03/linux-foundation-announces-meego-tv-working-group"
          >announced</ulink> the creation of the MeeGo Smart TV Working Group. The working group is
        to be tasked with looking at how to use MeeGo in the new "Smart TV" market of internet
        connected TVs and set top boxes. Among the participants in the group are Intel, Nokia, MIPS,
        Telecom Italia and <ulink url="http://www.aminocom.com/">Amino Communications</ulink>. The
        working group will expand MeeGo's reach from it's current target devices: netbooks, tablets
        and automotive systems.</para>
      <para>The group will have its first meeting in April and will be submitting code to produce
        twice yearly releases (in the first and third quarters of the year) as it establishes how to
        make use of the MeeGo Linux platform and it's Qt based user interface. The working group
        will also have to working out how to create a <ulink
          url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/10-foot_user_interface">10 foot user interface</ulink>
        for MeeGo devices which have, to date, been focussed on touch or handheld interfaces.
        (...)</para>
      <!--($ ld: 23.3.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://standardsandfreedom.net/index.php/2011/03/17/what-does-community-mean-part-2/">Networkworld/Jon Brodkin: Linus Torvalds: Android copyright violation claim is bogus</ulink></title>
      <para>Linux kernel creator Linus Torvalds has said new claims that <ulink
          url="http://www.networkworld.com/news/2011/031711-android-linux-gpl.html">Android violates
          the Linux license</ulink> are <quote>totally bogus</quote>.</para>
      <para>Intellectual property attorney Edward Naughton <ulink
          url="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/edward-j-naughton/googles-android-contains-_b_836697.html"
          >argued last week</ulink> that with Android, Google improperly took Linux code and passed
        it on in a derivative work without using the GPLv2 license. But it seems that no lawsuits
        have been filed on the issue and several open source observers have disputed Naughton's
        argument. (...)</para>
      <!--($ ld: 23.3.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://www.unixmen.com/news-today/1579-open-source-kimono-lanterns-to-the-rescue">Unixmen/Anuradha Shukl: Open source Kimono Lanterns to the rescue</ulink></title>
      <para>The devastation in Japan is heart rending and compels each of one of us to contribute to help improve the situation. Similar thoughts have been running through developers at <ulink url="http://freaklabs.org/">Freaklabs</ulink> . At the <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hackerspace">hackerspace</ulink> they are involved with, a solar rechargeable lantern was designed for garden and patio use. Called the Kimono Lantern, today they are able to put it to better use. Donating the complete design to the open source hardware community, they are indeed standing true to the commitments of the Open Source community.</para>
      <para>(...)</para>
      <para><ulink url="http://www.pcworld.com/article/222160/opensource_kimono_lantern_could_help_tsunami_victims.html">Kimono lanterns</ulink> are basically designed for small output but with long battery life. Running on solar cells that are recharged due to exposure to sunlight will glow for 8 hours providing the quake victims much needed night light. As flashlights, and the other standard and regular artificial light sources area premium and essential for critical situations as in makeshift hospital rooms, a Kimono lantern should do the desired needful. Light the pathway and generally offer a comforting glow amid all the darkness. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 26.3.11 sat $) -->    
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://www.brighthub.com/hubfolio/matthew-casperson/articles/110077.aspx">Hubfolio/Matthew Casperson: Five things to do in your new OpenSuse 11.4 Installation</ulink></title>
      <para>OpenSuse 11.4 is out, and it includes some of the latest and best software available for Linux. But there are still a few things you can do to spruce things up.</para>
      <para>With KDE 4.6, Libre Office, the latest Linux kernel, a preview of what is to come with Gnome 3 and so much more, OpenSuse 11.4 is ready to take your <ulink url="http://www.brighthub.com/guides/linux-desktop.aspx">Linux desktop</ulink> to the next level.</para>
      <para>But while OpenSuse 11.4 does provide a rich ecosystem of Linux applications, there are still a few things every Linux user needs to make their desktop shine, and to make it functional.</para>
      <para>Here are five steps to take after you install OpenSuse 11.4 to put the icing on the cake. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 26.3.11 sat $) -->   
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://www.itworld.com/operating-systems/140885/opensuse-114-blast-linux-past">ITworld/Steven J. Vaughan-Nichols: OpenSUSE 11.4: A blast from Linux past</ulink></title>
      <para>I&apos;ve liked openSUSE since before it was named openSUSE and went by the unlikely name S.u.S.E Linux 4.2 back in 1996. It&apos;s come a long, long way since then. Today, this Novell-supported community Linux distribution makes both a strong, server and desktop. For all that, though I&apos;ve found in this go-around some fit and polish issues.</para>
      <para>To test it out, I put openSUSE 11.4, on two computers. The first was a Gateway SX2802-07 desktop. This PC uses a 2.6GHZ Intel Pentium Dual-Core E5300 processor and has 6GBs of RAM and a 640GB hard-drive and was being wasted doing nothing but serving as a full-time Windows PC. The other was VirtualBox 4.04 VM (virtual machine) running on my Mint 10 desktop. Behind the VM was a Dell Inspiron 530S powered by a 2.2-GHz Intel Pentium E2200 dual-core processor with an 800-MHz front-side bus. This box has 4GBs of RAM, a 500GB SATA (Serial ATA) drive, and an Integrated Intel 3100 GMA (Graphics Media Accelerator) chip set. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 26.3.11 sat $) -->    
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://dasublogbyprashanth.blogspot.com/2011/03/review-opensuse-114-kde.html">Das U-Blog/Prashanth Venkataram: Review: openSUSE 11.4 KDE</ulink></title>
      <para>This review you are about to read was originally going to be about Scientific Linux 6. However, two things changed that: one, openSUSE 11.4 got released yesterday, though I did think about doing Scientific Linux today and openSUSE in a few days, and two, Scientific Linux didn&apos;t play well with either UnetBootin or MultiSystem. In any case, that review will have to wait a bit. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 26.3.11 sat $) This article is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. -->   
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://www.linuxjournal.com/content/mingle-opensuse-ites-connect">Linux Journal/Susan Linton: Mingle with openSUSE-ites on connect</ulink></title>
      <para>The ever-inventive openSUSE gang have come up with another cool service to enhance user experience and promote good will. This time it is a little less technical and a little more social. Connect with other openSUSE users, developers, and groups. You can make friends, find out the latest news, and get involved.</para>
      <para>Henne Vogelsang introduced the new service a few days ago and he said connect was the answer to &quot;What are we really doing when we develop a new tool to handle openSUSE users and groups?&quot; The purpose is to connect people to projects, groups and with each other; connect faces to names, nicknames and to email addresses; and, ultimately, connect all our other tools to this one so we can share the data, as Vogelsang explained. In other words, it&apos;s openSUSE&apos;s very own little social network. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 26.3.11 sat $) -->    
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://www.petur.eu/blog/?p=349">Petur.eu: Linux can be hacked with an USB
          device</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>I have to admit, over the years I haven’t given openSUSE enough love or credit for being
        the outstanding Linux distribution is it. With that said, I wanted to give some attention to
        the latest release coming out of the openSUSE project. And, since the default desktop for
        openSUSE 11.4 is KDE, I will be giving a little extra attention to the KDE desktop. Since
        both might well gain some serious ground, when Ubuntu 11.04 is released, it will be nice for
        users to not only know of its existence, but to also know that openSUSE 11.4 is, in fact, a
        solid distribution worth giving a look. (...)</para>      
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>LOL</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://xkcd.com/874/">XKCD: Time Management</ulink></title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/time_management.png" width="50%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
          url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.5/">CC-BY-NC</ulink></para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
</sect1>
