<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 id="gsoc" role="gsoc">
  <title>Google Summer of Code</title>
  <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
      <imagedata fileref="http://michal.hrusecky.net/wp-content/uploads/GSoC2011_300x200.png"
        width="20%" align="center"/>
    </imageobject>
  </mediaobject>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/03/24/gsoc-idea-improve-clic-filesystem/">Stephan Kulow: GSOC Idea: Improve Clic Filesystem</ulink></title>
    <para>I really look for the perfect gsoc student: someone who has a brilliant idea, noone else
      thought of how to improve linux in general or openSUSE in specific and just needs my
      guidance.</para>
    <para>But for those that need some ideas, my best bet is really to rewrite clicfs to make it
      even better. Right now clicfs is a FUSE filesystem hosting a loop image. So a page read goes
      from ext4-&gt;loop-&gt;fuse-&gt;clicfs-&gt;CD-&gt;clicfs-&gt;fuse-&gt;loop-&gt;ext4.</para>
    <para>If it lived in the kernel, it could offer a block device you mount your ext4 on, leaving
      aside loop and
      fuse:<screen>modprobe clicfs packfile=/read-only/openSUSE-kde.i586 cowfile=/read-write/.COWfile cowlog=/dev/ttyS0 
mount /dev/clicfs/0 /mnt 
chroot /mnt /bin/init</screen></para>
    <para>Great idea, no? For someone who wants to become famous, it would be the perfect
      target!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GFDL 1.2</ulink></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 26.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.digitalflow.de/blog/2011/03/summer-of-code-2011/">Thomas Schmidt: Summer of Code 2011</ulink></title>
    <para>Google’s <ulink url="http://www.google-melange.com/site/home/site">summer of code
        2011</ulink> is approaching, and openSUSE.org got <ulink
        url="http://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/mentor/request/google/gsoc2011/opensuse"
        >accepted</ulink> as mentoring organization.</para>
    <para>So now we are searching for students that would like to hack on one of our <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:GSOC_2011_Ideas">proposed projects</ulink> from May
      23rd – August 22nd (fulltime, 40h/week) being payed by Google (5000$ on success). Sounds like
      a fair deal, doesn’t it? <inlinemediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="http://www.digitalflow.de/blog/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif"/>
        </imageobject>
      </inlinemediaobject></para>
    <para>There are even some days left to propose a new project to hack on! In that case we would
      try to find a suitable mentor from our community to get you started.</para>
    <para>There are quite some interesting project proposals on our gsoc2011 wiki page, reaching
      from build service projects to SUSE Studio tools and distribution specific tools, as well as
      cross-distribution efforts.</para>
    <para>I would like to mentor a student in the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:GSOC2011_OBS_Mobile">OBS Mobile</ulink> project which
      will create a nice interface to use the buildservice from your handheld. So if you are skilled
      in web technologies (jquery-mobile, rails) please apply and get the chance to hack this summer
      of code on this exciting project!</para>
    <para>To get in contact with the openSUSE community please join channel <emphasis role="bold"
        >#opensuse-project</emphasis> on freenode, or our project mailinglist at
        <email>opensuse-project@opensuse.org</email> and we will help you to get started.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 26.3.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/03/24/gsoc-idea-build-service-plasma-widget-suite/">Will Stephenson: GSoC Idea: Build Service Plasma Widget Suite</ulink></title>
    <para>I’m blatantly abusing GSoC for a project that I would like to see in openSUSE but that
      I’ve never had time to work on. But really it’s a worthwhile thing to have: a set of Plasma
      widgets that users and developers can add to their workspace to make it easy to see what’s
      going on in OBS in the projects that matter to them. If you want to work on a fun project with
      cutting edge technologies such as Qt, QML, Plasma then head on over to the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:GSOC_2011_Ideas#Build_Service_Plasma_Widgets">GSoC 2011
        Ideas Page</ulink>.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GFDL 1.2</ulink></para>
    <!--($ ld: 26.3.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://thefreecountry.wordpress.com/2011/03/25/gsoc-2011/">Alexander Naumov: GSoC 2011</ulink></title>
    <para><ulink url="http://www.google-melange.com/site/home/site">Google Summer of Code</ulink>
      (GSoC) is a program for students across the world to hack on interesting Free Software
      projects and get paid for their work. Historically, the program has brought together over 4500
      students with over 300 Open Source projects, to create millions of lines of code!</para>
    <para>Of cource openSUSE hopes to participate in <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:GSOC_2011">GSoC</ulink>, while being mentored by
      experienced members of the community they are working in. We have many different <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:GSOC_2011_Ideas">ideas</ulink> and looking for
      stundens. This is a good opportunity not only to help openSUSE and have a lot of fun working
      on interesting project, but also get 5000 $ if your project will be finished successful <inlinemediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="http://s1.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif?m=1235253118g"/>
        </imageobject>
      </inlinemediaobject><ulink
        url="http://www.google-melange.com/document/show/gsoc_program/google/gsoc2011/faqs#timeline"
        > Time for hacking</ulink> is from May 23rd to August 22nd.</para>
    <para>In my opinion one of the most interesting projects is the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:GSOC_2011_Ideas#Build_Service_Plasma_Widgets">Build
        Service Plasma Widgets</ulink>. It will be very useful, I guess.</para>
    <para>To get in contact with us please join IRC channel <emphasis role="bold"
        >#opensuse-project</emphasis> on freenode, or our project’s ML at
        <email>opensuse-project@opensuse.org</email> and don’t forget – we’re going to help you to
      start.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 26.3.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
