<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="updates">
  <title>New/Updated Applications @ openSUSE</title>
  <!--* Gnome
* KDE
* XYZ 

Version should be available at packman or software.opensuse.org/search max. 4 posts. -->
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/2011/03/23/smb-traffic-analyzer-1-2-3-released/">Holger Hetterich: SMB Traffic Analyzer 1.2.3 released</ulink></title>
    <para>Should you read this in a blogroll, and <emphasis role="italic"><emphasis role="bold"
          >think what you read is from outer space</emphasis></emphasis>: This article is about the
        <emphasis role="bold">SMB Traffic Analyzer project</emphasis>, more information is <ulink
        url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/smb-traffic-analyzer/">here</ulink>.</para>
    <para>The team is happy to announce the release of <emphasis role="bold">SMB Traffic Analyzer
        1.2.3</emphasis>. It is loaded with new features and lots of bug fixes, driving SMBTA
      forward in terms of scalability, performance, and functionality. Let’s dive into and begin
      with the most important news on <emphasis role="bold">smbtad</emphasis>, the daemon program
      collecting data. A problem identified by several users was the fact that the created database
      grows too large after a short time. Well, at this level <emphasis role="bold">smbtad
      </emphasis>was doing real data mining and stores any single VFS function in it’s database. A
      copy of a single file that is larger than a megabyte could create more than a hundred entries
      in the database. <emphasis role="bold">smbtad</emphasis> now solves this issue with a reworked
      cache subsystem that is implemented as a bi-tree algorithm adding up similar VFS entries for
      up to 5 seconds, and thus creating an interpolation of the data to be stored. The result is a
      much smaller database and should make <emphasis role="bold">smbtad</emphasis> much faster. The
      user can change the time period while smbtad is summing up similar entries, and also force
      smbtad to do full data mining if wanted. (<emphasis role="bold">bnc#669679</emphasis>).</para>
    <para>If your main target for using SMB Traffic Analyzer is to generate graphics with <emphasis
        role="bold">rrddriver</emphasis> or to run <emphasis role="bold">smbtamonitor</emphasis>,
      there are good news. <emphasis role="bold">The database handling in smbtad can be completely
        shut down.</emphasis> In this mode, smbtad only acts as a repeater, sending the data to the
      real-time clients, without the overhead of maintaining the database. The client programs have
      been adapted for this (<emphasis role="bold">bnc#668193</emphasis>).We have implemented a way
      to parse data from the VFS module without re-allocating the data in the systems memory. This
      makes smbtad much faster, reduces memory handling a lot, and much of the underlying code has
      been simplified (<emphasis role="bold">bnc#671346</emphasis>). The real time monitor code had
      problems when several smbtamonitor instances where connected, and the throughput display did
      not work in 1.2.2. As a consequence, we reworked the monitor code, simplified the code a lot,
      and removed throughput calculation from smbtad, reimplementing it in the <emphasis role="bold"
        >smbtamonitor</emphasis> client (<emphasis role="bold">bnc#669809</emphasis>).</para>
    <figure>
      <title>This picture is showing the HTML output of a fuzzy search done on a SMBTA Stresstest appliance.</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://holger123.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/fuzzy-search.png"
            width="30%" align="right"/>
        </imageobject>        
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>    
    <para>Due to a bug in the CmakeFile of 1.2.2. both smbtad and smbtatools where unable to install
      anywhere else than /usr; the installation prefix can now be given with the
      CMAKE_INSTALL_PREFIX variable (<emphasis role="bold">bnc#673767</emphasis>). The <emphasis
        role="bold">smbtatorturesrv</emphasis> program, distributing unique filenames and supporting
      smbtatorture when running networked and in parallel, sometimes crashed on 32bit architectures,
      fixed in <emphasis role="bold">bnc#667101</emphasis>.</para>
    <para>Two new functions have been added to smbtatools. First off, there’s now a fuzzy search
      function in <emphasis role="bold">smbtaquery</emphasis>, allowing to do searches over the
      whole data set and supports unix wildcards. If the given search pattern is found, the function
      is identifying the object (<emphasis role="bold">bnc#599145</emphasis>). </para>
    <figure>
      <title>SMBTA Stresstest</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://holger123.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/smbtamonitor-1-2-31.png"
            width="20%" align="left"/>
        </imageobject>        
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>Also, <emphasis role="bold">smbtaquery</emphasis>, now includes a throughput calculation
      function, to let the<ulink
        url="http://holger123.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/smbtamonitor-1-2-31.png"> </ulink> user
      quickly view the data throughput of an object over the last minutes, hours or even days
        (<emphasis role="bold">bnc#668190</emphasis>). As mentioned before, throughput display in
        <emphasis role="bold">smbtamonitor</emphasis> did not work in 1.2.2. <emphasis role="bold"
        >smbtamonitor</emphasis> now does this on it’s own, no longer requesting this calculation
      work from smbtad, and the interface has been slighty reworked. And finally, it now has
      keyboard handling.</para>
    <para>The “top” function of smbtaquery has been reworked to display more information on the
      entries in the produced list. With every user and share, the domain is listed, and with any
      file, the corresponding share and domain is shown additionally (<emphasis role="bold"
        >bnc#668172</emphasis>).</para>
    <para>The SMBTA documentation has of course been updated to reflect the current state and is
      already uploaded <ulink url="http://morelias.org/smbta/smbta-guide.html">here</ulink>. <ulink
        url="http://build.opensuse.org">openSUSE’s Buildservice</ulink> already consumed SMB Traffic
      Analyzer 1.2.3, and <ulink
        url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/smb-traffic-analyzer/smb-traffic-analyzer-download/"
        >downloads are available</ulink>. Furthermore, with version 1.2.3, <emphasis role="bold">SMB
        Traffic Analyzer</emphasis> debuts on <ulink url="http://www.gentoo.org">Gentoo
        Linux</ulink>, and shall be available in the Gentoo Software directory soon. Of course, SMB
      Traffic Analyzer should appear in <emphasis role="bold">openSUSE Tumbleweed</emphasis> very
      soon.</para>
    <figure>
      <title>The german ADMIN magazine released an extensive article about SMB Traffic Analyzer</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="http://holger123.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/admin_02_11_300x407_rgb.jpg"
            width="10%" align="right"/>
        </imageobject>        
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>In other news, SMB Traffic Analyzer recently got <emphasis role="italic"><emphasis
          role="bold">print media attention with a six page long, workshop-like
        article</emphasis></emphasis> about it in the German <ulink
        url="http://www.admin-magazin.de/">ADMIN Magazine</ulink>. The article is very detailed and
      really good in showing what SMB Traffic Analyzer can do and how to configure it, and even
      describes the SMBTA Stresstest appliance! Good stuff, the SMBTA Development team is happy
      about this work and suggests to buy the magazine if you read German and are interested in SMB
      Traffic Analyzer. Moreover, we added a new page “<ulink
        url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/smb-traffic-analyzer/contribute/"
        >Develop/Contact/Contribute</ulink>” to the homepage, to make it easier for people to get
      into SMB Traffic Analyzer development, or for users to talk about SMBTA. A new release of the
      SMBTA Stresstest appliance is ahead, including SMBTA 1.2.3, making it easy to give it a quick
      test. Stay tuned. </para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 26.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>

</sect1>
