<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 id="sneak-peeks" role="sneak-peeks">
  <title>Sneak Peeks</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://blip.tv/file/4845672">openSUSE TV: opensuse-11.4-e3</ulink></title>
    <para>third and last part of the tutorial about openSUSE 11.4 install. The end of the install: automatic hardware configuration.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 6.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://nowwhatthe.blogspot.com/2011/03/114-almost-there.html">Jos Poortvliet: 11.4 - almost there</ulink></title>
    <note><para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is licensed under the <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">Creatice CommonsAttribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License</ulink></emphasis>.</para></note>
    <para>Warning: huge blog ahead. To butcher Mark Twain:</para>
    <para><quote>I didn't have time to write a short blog, so I wrote a long one instead.</quote></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Excitement</emphasis>. Lack of sleep. More excitement. Many things not finished. Yep, a major release. Despite a crashing laptop (every 30 min it hangs, I'm afraid it is the heath) I'm having fun preparing for the biggest event since I joined the openSUSE community: the release of openSUSE 11.4!</para>
    <para>The marketing team had a <ulink url="http://nowwhatthe.blogspot.com/2011/03/opensuse-marketing-meeting-in-los.html">meeting 2 weeks</ulink> ago to prepare for 11.4. But we weren't the only ones working hard. And this week, our release dude, Coolo, got sick and AJ had to replace him. Well, the GoldMaster was in time, so AJ, great work. And Coolo: <emphasis role="bold">if a doctor tells you to stop working it probably makes sense to listen.</emphasis></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">New features</emphasis></para>
    <para>11.4 will be exciting. I mean really, really exciting! There is a huge number of new features and improvements. I just finished an <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Presentations#openSUSE_11.4">11.4 feature overview</ulink> presentation. It's not perfectly complete (how could it be with so much new stuff?) but a good start if you want to have a <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/07/live-code-party/">launch party</ulink>. Speaking of, if you're Dutch, there will be a <ulink url="http://nl.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Launch_party_11.4">Launch Party in NL</ulink>!</para>
    <para>Anyone who wants to visit or organize a launch party, there is still time. Go to the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Launch_parties_11.4">Launch Party Wiki</ulink> Page and see if there is something close by. If not, organize it! Seriously, it's not hard: just put a page up there, point to a cafe where you can get beer &amp; coke and you're already pretty far. Sure, you can do fancy presentations in a conference room, but isn't beer what brings people together? And isn't a party nothing without a well-equipped bar?</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Posters - but where is the source?</emphasis></para>
    <para>By the way, there is a bunch of awesome-looking Launch Party Posters on the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Launch_parties_11.4">Launch Party Wiki Page</ulink>, where are the sources? I bet you can ask in the #opensuse-marketing channel on Freenode for them but having them up there is easier, ladies and gents!</para>
    <para>I want the sources because I'd love to have a release party here, in <emphasis role="bold">Porto Alegre</emphasis>, Brazil. Anyone else close by? Any suggestions for a decent pub? Please mail me at my first name on opensuse.org! KDE and GNOME, XFCE &amp; LXDE fans - you're all welcome, we're YOUR best distribution after all!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Shout out</emphasis></para>
    <para>As I said, I'm pretty tired, so I surely will skip people in this list but I just HAVE to thank some people for what they did: First of all the <emphasis role="bold">whole marketing team</emphasis> for their work on the amazing Product Highlights (I keep calling it feature guide, hehe). I shout out to Bruno, Tony and James for their technical knowledge, Izabel for her TIRELESS work in adding all the relevant information and Helen for helping to clean things up and write proper text. Sascha, Holger, Christian, Carlos, Frank, Greg, Chuck, Andres, Andreas, Bryen, Kostas, Dominique, Guido and all others - thank you too, every line of text helped tremendously!!! If you helped out and weren't credited, add your name to the list at the bottom of the Product Highlights. You deserve it, don't be shy! Those not on the marketing team, you'll see the end results when the announcement is live ;-)</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Chuck</emphasis>, I have to mention you especially. Your mail on social media made my day. I was worried nothing was being organized - and I didn't have time. You took it on yourself and made a difference. Love you.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="italic">rtyler</emphasis>, you're another hero. Your writing for <ulink url="http://omgsuse.com/">OMGSUSE.com</ulink> in the last 10 days has been awesome. I know it was exhausting - yet you still helped out reviewing and writing. AWESOME! Oh, and add your name to the list on the Product Highlights!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="italic">Manu</emphasis>, manu, manu. You've been all over again. Despite busy with school and other obligations, you worked until deep in the night. Feature guide, website, social media, everywhere. You deserve a thousand hugs!</para>
    <para>The work our <emphasis role="italic">Tiger Bruno</emphasis> has been doing, working with Chuck, Carlos and Javier - invaluable. Thanks to you guys we'll have an amazing openSUSE 11.4 poster shipped with the next Linux Magazine!!! And Bruno, give a hug to your girlfriend for organizing <ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/02/03/join-us-for-the-first-virtual-launch-party-opensuse-11-4/">our Virtual Launch Party on Second Life</ulink>!!!</para>
    <para>A full round of hugs and Doritos (sorry sshaw)!</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 10.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://blip.tv/file/4866763">openSUSE TV: openSUSE 11.4 Installation using a DVD</ulink></title>
    <note><para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is licensed under the <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">Creatice CommonsAttribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License</ulink></emphasis>.</para></note>
    <para>Installation of openSUSE 11.4 using a DVD.</para>
    <para>Music: Bach - Toccata and Fugue in D minor ; interpreted by <ulink url="http://www.youtube.com/user/smalin">Stephen Malinowski</ulink>.</para>
    <para>Video: openSUSE-11.4-DVD</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 11.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://psankar.blogspot.com/2011/03/gnome-vs-canonical-freedesktoporg.html">Sankar P: GNOME vs Canonical, Freedesktop.org - A Neutral Observation</ulink></title>
    <para>Few sensational things happened last week in one of the oldest debates of the Linux community, GNOME vs KDE, touching on the topic of freedesktop.org and joined this time by the new hot topic, "<emphasis role="bold">GNOME vs Canonical</emphasis>". The bulk of the actions happened in the comments section of two blog posts, one by <ulink url="http://blogs.gnome.org/bolsh/2011/03/07/has-gnome-rejected-canonical-help/">Dave Neary</ulink>, well-known GNOME advocate and another post by <ulink url="http://aseigo.blogspot.com/2011/03/collaborations-demise.html">Aaron Seigo</ulink>, well-known KDE Developer. I want to improve my writing skills and the ability to get information from a community discussion. So, below is a step in that direction.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Disclaimer</emphasis>: All opinions are personal and none of the views expressed represent my employer, NASA, WHO or anyone else for that matter. The following is the <emphasis role="bold">juice</emphasis> of the events of last week written from a (as honest as possible) neutral perspective. Read through this post if you don't want to read through all the comments in the mentioned blog posts.</para>
    <para role="bold">GNOME 3 release is just days away. Canonical and the GNOME community have taken different routes with <emphasis role="bold">Unity</emphasis> and gnome-shell respectively. Dave Neary <ulink url="http://blogs.gnome.org/bolsh/2011/03/07/has-gnome-rejected-canonical-help/">wrote</ulink> a blog post with an analytic title "<emphasis role="bold">Has GNOME rejected Canonical's Help ?</emphasis> " . Neary cited instances of Canonical exhibiting behavior that shows discomfort in the Canonical-GNOME relationship. (...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 11.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
