<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="tipsandtricks">
  <title>Tips and Tricks</title>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Desktop Users</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.makeuseof.com/tag/manage-twitter-identica-accounts-choqok-linux/">MakeUseOf/Danny Stieben: Manage Your Twitter &amp; Identi.ca Accounts With Choqok</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>For people who are really tweet-o-holics, constant access to <ulink url="http://www.makeuseof.com/tags/twitter">Twitter</ulink> (or <ulink url="http://www.identi.ca">Identi.ca</ulink>, an open source clone of Twitter) is as much
        a necessity as food and water. At varying levels, this may also be true for those who are
        fans of Twitter but not necessarily tweet-o-holics.</para>
      <para>One possible choice is to have Twitter up and running in the browser most of the time.
        While this is a feasible solution, you’ll start missing out when the browser is minimized.
        Also, a browser isn’t exactly lightweight on system resources. Therefore, your best bet
        would be to use a well-built Twitter desktop client.</para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">About Chokoq</emphasis></para>
      <para><ulink url="http://choqok.gnufolks.org">Choqok</ulink> is a slim Twitter and Identi.ca
        client made to integrate well with the <ulink url="http://www.makeuseof.com/tags/kde">KDE</ulink> desktop environment. As far as social media clients go, <ulink url="http://www.makeuseof.com/tag/gwibber-the-everything-client/">Gwibber</ulink> may be a
        more well known piece of software, but it’s best suited to run under a <ulink url="http://www.makeuseof.com/tags/gnome">GNOME</ulink> desktop. You’re always welcome to
        try Gwibber with KDE, but I’ve always preferred software native to the desktop environment
        you’re using. With Choqok, you can quickly and easily reach your Twitter stream at any time
        and get notifications that appear right on your desktop. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 14.8.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.linux.com/learn/tutorials/482178:weekend-project-turn-thunderbird-into-a-groupware-client-with-sogo-connector">Linux.com/Nathan Willis: Weekend Project: Turn Thunderbird into a Groupware Client with SOGo Connector</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Mozilla <ulink url="http://www.mozilla.org/thunderbird/">Thunderbird</ulink> has earned its place as an email app on Linux desktops, and its cross-platform nature makes it a popular choice for Windows and OS X machines as well — particularly when you include the calendaring and task management power of the <ulink url="http://www.mozilla.org/projects/calendar/lightning/">Lightning</ulink> add-on. But uptake in corporate environments has never been its strong suit, largely because it does not include groupware features such as event invitations and shared address books. The <ulink url="http://www.sogo.nu/downloads/frontends.html#c1304">SOGo Connector</ulink> extension adds those features and more, turning Thunderbird into a proper groupware client suitable for business use. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 19.8.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://lamarque-lvs.blogspot.com/2011/08/wireless-sharing-with-plasma-nm-09.html">Lamarque: Wireless sharing with Plasma NM 0.9</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>During <ulink url="https://www.desktopsummit.org/welcome-second-desktop-summit">Desktop Summit</ulink> in Berlin some people asked me how to make wireless sharing work. Connection sharing allows to use a computer as gateway for other computers, NM does that by routing all IP packages from one network interface to the default route of your computer (yes, that is a Masquerate configuration). For example, you can configure your notebook to access Internet through ethernet cable and create a wifi shared connection to allow other computers to access Internet using your notebook&apos;s default route. Your notebook will act like an access point. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 19.8.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://maketecheasier.com/three-great-mindmapping-tools-for-the-linux-desktop/2011/08/19"
          >MakeTechEasier/scottnesbitt: Three Great Mindmapping Tools for the Linux
        Desktop</ulink></title>
      <para>Sometimes, you run into a problem that you just can’t work through with mental brute
        force alone. Brainstorming with others works, but that’s not always an option.</para>
      <para>One popular and effective way of beating a problem or releasing your creativity is
        mindmapping. While you can go old school and use pen and paper, there is quite a bit of
        mindmapping software out there for the desktop and on the web.</para>
      <para>There are a number of really solid mindmapping tools for the Linux desktop. Let’s take a
        closer look at three of them. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ Id: 20.8.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Commandline/Script Newbies</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.anchor.com.au/blog/2011/08/awesome-but-often-unknown-linux-commands-and-tools/">Anchor/Keiran Holloway: Awesome but often unknown Linux commands and tools</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>I’ve been working in this industry for a while now and naturally spend a lot of time using Linux on a daily basis. This gives lots of exposure to various Linux commands and tools. That said, I am sometimes surprised when I see, often very experienced system administrators, using somewhat convoluted commands to do something relatively simple using a different tool. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 19.8.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Developers and Programmers</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://olex.openlogic.com/wazi/2011/build-web-apps-like-a-pro-with-these-php-frameworks/">Wazi/Anatoliy A. Dimitrov: Build Web Apps Like a Pro with These PHP Frameworks</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Nowadays, few enterprise websites run without <ulink url="http://olex.openlogic.com/packages/php">PHP</ulink>, the dynamic scripting language that serves as the “P” in the <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LAMP_%28software_bundle%29">LAMP</ulink> stack. Coding PHP applications is relatively easy thanks to the abundance of high-quality PHP frameworks available. Here’s a high-level overview of several of these open source frameworks, noting their scalability, maturity, licenses, and commercial support. While they may differ in many ways, they have one thing in common: they cost nothing to try and to use.</para>
      <para>PHP frameworks not only make web development fast and easy but also standardize and streamline the whole development process. They are much more than just snippets of code or libraries you can reuse. They guide you through the whole development process, from laying out file structures to building data connectors and performing unit tests. All of these popular frameworks are object-oriented and follow the Model-View-Controller (<ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Model%E2%80%93view%E2%80%93controller">MVC</ulink>) design philosophy. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 19.8.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://psankar.blogspot.com/2011/08/introducing-find-many-strings-chrome.html">Sankar
          P: Introducing Find Many Strings - A chrome extension</ulink></title>
      <para>Of late, I have been reading a lot of code via browser. Sometimes, when evaluating a
        patch or when reading through open source project sources, I find it very hard to track how
        variables move across functions/loops. </para>
      <para>If I am using VIM, I can happily use CTAGS for this. Chrome highlights all the
        occurrences of the text that you searched for in yellow color. However when you search for
        another string, the old highlights disappear. It would have been nicer if any new string
        search starts highlighting in a different color. I could not find any plugin for achieving
        this, So, I wrote my own Chrome extension for this. (...)</para>
      <!--($ Id: 20.8.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For System Administrators</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://obsforandroid.wordpress.com/2011/08/16/install-broadcom-sta-wireless-driver-in-opensuse-11-4-and-other-linux-distros/">Justine Leng: Install Broadcom STA wireless driver in openSUSE 11.4 (and other Linux distros)</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Broadcom is a real nag. Buying a laptop with Broadcom wireless network card never
        bothered me until I installed several Linux distros and things started to go less smoothly…
        especially when you do not have wired ethernet nearby and wireless is all you get.</para>
      <para>On the other hand, installing the Broadcom wireless driver for different Linux distros
        is a great learning experience.</para>
      <para>Previously, I talked about<ulink url="http://developify.wordpress.com/2011/08/12/activate-broadcom-sta-wireless-driver-in-fedora-14/">how to activate the Broadcom STA wireless driver in Fedora 14</ulink>. It turns out the
        activation is slightly different in openSUSE.</para>
      <para>The following works on openSUSE 11.3, 11.4, Mint 10 Julia, Ubuntu 10.x, Kubuntu 10.x,
        and LMDE. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 18.8.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://obsforandroid.wordpress.com/2011/08/16/live-upgrade-opensuse-11-3-to-11-4/">Justine Leng: Live Upgrade openSUSE 11.3 to 11.4 </ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Doing a live upgrade in openSUSE to the latest version has certain advantages:<itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>You only download the packages that need to be upgraded, saving a lot of
              bandwidth.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>During the upgrade you can still use your system (although this is not
              recommended); the only downtime will be the reboot after the upgrade.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>You do not have to write an ISO image to a DVD. You could also boot from 1) the
              Internet; or 2) a USB key, and install the rest from the Internet (...)</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
<!-- ($ Id: 18.8.11 sm $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.ibm.com/developerworks/linux/library/l-lpic3-312-4/index.html">IBM developerWorks/Roderick W. Smith: Learn Linux, 302 (Mixed environments): Domain control</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>In SMB/CIFS parlance, a domain is similar to a workgroup: It&apos;s a collection of related computers, typically existing on a single local network. A domain, however, features a special computer known as a domain controller that manages logons for all the servers in the domain. It also provides a few additional services. Samba can function as a domain controller, but you need to set several Samba options for it to do so. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ Id: 19.8.11 sat $)-->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://dkukawka.blogspot.com/2011/08/how-to-get-your-full-disc-space-back-on.html"
          >Danny Kukawka: How to get your full disc space back on ext filesystems</ulink></title>
      <para>You may have already wondered why you can't use the full disc space on an ext2/3/4
        partition? You already seen something like this, where the used and available blocks don't
        fit the number of blocks on the
        device/partition:<screen>Filesystem                 1K-blocks   Used    Available Use%
Mounted on /dev/sdc1       15391664    38184   14571608  1%
/mnt</screen></para>
      <para>The reason is: if you create an ext filesystem (no matter if with mkfs or YaST), 5 % of
        the filesystem get reserved for the super-user to allow e.g. root daemons to continue to
        write to the partition after unprivileged processes stopped because the partition is
        full.While this perfectly make sense on system partitions as '/', it makes no sense on data
        partitions or external media (in the most cases). By this you get e.g. on an external
        2TB/1.8TiB drive 100GByte/~92GiB, which you can't use as normal user. But you can get this
        space back. Either you set the number of reserved blocks to zero when you create the file
        system: (...)</para>
      <!--($ Id: 20.8.11 sm $)-->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
