<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="ontheweb">
  <title>On the Web</title>
<!-- Announcements, Call for participation, Reports, Reviews and Essays, Warning! -->  <sect2>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://dot.kde.org/2011/07/19/intel-collabora-and-suse-be-main-sponsors-desktop-summit"
          >Intel, Collabora and SUSE to be main sponsors of the Desktop Summit</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>We are pleased to announce that the Desktop Summit 2011 in Berlin will be supported by
        Intel as the Platinum sponsor. The event organizers also welcome Collabora and SUSE as Gold
        partners, and are delighted with the community spirit of these generous corporate partners.
        Mirko Boehm, lead organizer of the Desktop Summit, said: "Their support is essential for the
        Desktop Summit's efforts to bring together Free Software developers from all around the
        world to work in a collaborative spirit on the next generation desktop technology."
        (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 23.7.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
<!--<sect2>
  <title>Call for participation</title>
  <blockquote><title>
      <ulink url="http://blog.worldlabel.com/2011/tux-paint-kids-summer-drawing-contest.html">Tux Paint Kids Summer Drawing Contest</ulink>
    </title><para><emphasis role="bold">Grab <ulink url="http://www.tuxpaint.org/">Tux Paint</ulink>, make a cool drawing, win one of 3 <ulink url="http://one.laptop.org/">OLPC laptops</ulink>, one of 10 <ulink url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Sugar_on_a_Stick">Sugar-on-a-stick</ulink> and other awesome prizes!</emphasis></para><para>The 2011 <ulink url="http://www.tuxpaint.org/">Tux Paint</ulink> Summer Drawing Contest is sponsored by Worldlabel.com and is open to all children aged 3 to 12 who live anywhere in the World!

Here’s a chance to show off your talent using a great drawing program made especially for kids. Tux Paint is an award-winning drawing program you can download to your computer. Tux Paint was recently awarded <ulink url="http://sourceforge.net/blog/potm-201106/">SourceForge.net Project of the Month</ulink>. It will run on all versions of Windows (including Tablet PC), Mac OS X 10.4 and up, Linux, FreeBSD and NetBSD. And it’s FREE! (...)</para> ($ ld: 2.7.11 sat $) </blockquote>
</sect2>-->  <sect2>
    <title>Reports</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.datamation.com/open-source/choosing-the-best-linux-desktop-kde-unity-gnome-1.html"
          >Michael Gapczynski (MTGap): Testers needed for sharing files with ownCloud</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>I have good news this week. First, I’m still here because I passed the mid-term
        evaluation for Google Summer of Code. Thanks for passing me Robin. Second, I was successful
        in completing my goal last week and now have everything setup so others can start
        experimenting with sharing files.</para>
      <para>Besides general bug fixing this past week I’ve also refactored OC_SHARE, which is the
        class that handles the database records of all shared files in ownCloud. It started to get a
        little messy and I was unhappy with the quality of code so I rewrote many of the functions
        and moved some of the error handling into OC_FILESTORAGE_SHARED where it should belong. I
        also commented all of the functions so other developers can use OC_SHARE in their own apps
        and understand what it is doing. I’ve also added two hooks to OC_SHARE: post_delete and
        post_rename. These are triggered by OC_FILESYSTEM when files are deleted, renamed, or moved.
        The database gets updated when these actions occur in order to avoid any missing shared
        items.</para>
      <para>The backend for sharing is pretty much complete so I can now focus on the user interface
        for the rest of the summer. The only part that needs updating is the permissions system. I
        was having a difficult time deciding on what to do with permissions and ended up going with
        only read and write, without the ability to permanently delete files. I’ve changed my mind
        now and will expand the options to more specific permissions that you can assign users. I
        was worried before that this would make the user interface too complex, but I now believe I
        can still achieve simplicity with the user experience. (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 22.7.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/suse-studio-12-ships-suse-linux-chief-to-roll-out-full-cloud-strategy-soon/9260"
          >ZDNet/Paula Rooney: SUSE Studio 1.2 ships, SUSE Linux chief to roll out full cloud
          strategy soon</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>The newly independent SUSE Linux unit unveiled the first leg of its cloud platform
        today: SUSE Studio Version 1.2.</para>
      <para>The development platform, which has been on the market for two years, helps SUSE Linux
        customers build, update and manage applications. Version 1.2 allows customers to better
        build, update and manage applications across physical, virtual and cloud environments
        including public clouds as well as x86 and System Z mainframe systems.</para>
      <para>In a recent interview, SUSE’s new chief, a 20-year Attachmate and Novell vet, said he is
        preparing to roll out a full-fledged cloud strategy for the No 2 Linux distribution, even as
        his on-the-job training continues. Top Linux distributor Red Hat has unveiled a
        comprehensive cloud strategy in recent months. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 23.7.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.datamation.com/open-source/suse-joins-xamarin-for-mono.html"
          >Datamation/Sean Michael Kerner: SUSE Joins Xamarin for Mono</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Mono isn't dead, and SUSE isn't giving up on it entirely either. Attachmate's SUSE Linux
        division today officially announced a deal with startup Xamarin for support and ongoing
        development of Mono.</para>
      <para>Xamarin is a company founded by former Novell employees including Nat Friedman and Mono
        founder Miguel de Icaza. The pair founded the company afterAttachmate laid off an
        undisclosed number of Mono developers in May, following their acquisition of Novell.</para>
      <para>"What we're announcing is that SUSE and Xamarin have entered into a partnering
        agreement, which will make sure that we are able to effectively support customers using
        Mono-based products," Holger Dyroff VP Product Management at SUSE told InternetNews.com. "As
        part of the partnership we are granting Xamarin a broad intellectual property license."
        (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 23.7.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/top-five-linux-contributor-microsoft/9254"
          >ZDNet/Steven J. Vaughan-Nichols: Top Five Linux Contributor: Microsoft</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Cats and dogs; apples and oranges; Linux and Microsoft. Two of these three things do not
        go together. Would you believe that Microsoft—yes Microsoft—was the fifth largest
        contributor to the soon to be released <ulink
          url="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/new-name-same-linux/9016">Linux 3.0
          kernel</ulink>? Believe it.</para>
      <para>In a Linux Weekly News story, currently only available to subscribers, an analysis of
        Linux 3.0 contributors reveals that Microsoft was the fifth largest corporate contributer to
        Linux 3.0. While only 15h overall, that still puts Microsoft behind only Red Hat, Intel,
        Novell, and IBM in contributing new code to this version of Linux. (...)</para>
      <!-- ($ ld: 23.7.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink url="http://digitizor.com/2011/07/20/microsoft-video-linuxs-20th-birthday/"
          >digitizor.com/Ricky: Microsoft Makes A Video For Linux’s 20th Birthday</ulink></title>
      <para>The Linux Foundation is celebrating 20 years of Linux and as a part of the celebration,
        they are accepting videos as part of a video contest. One of the video submission came form
        none other than Microsoft itself.</para>
      <!--($ ld: 23.7.11 sm $) -->
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>Reviews and Essays</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://www.zdnet.co.uk/blogs/mapping-babel-10017967/how-linux-saved-my-computer-from-windows-update-10023470/"
          >ZDNet UK/Jack Clark: How Linux saved my computer from Windows Update</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>If it wasn't for Linux, a Windows Update crash would have forced me to format my drive
        and reinstall everything. On Friday I got home from work, powered up my HP Pavilion DV6
        6055ea laptop and watched as it promptly shut down to churn through Windows Update. It got
        30 percent of the way through then the blue screen of death (BSOD) appeared.</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 23.7.11 sm $) -->    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
<!--
  <sect2>
    <title>Warning!</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink url="http://omgsuse.com/content/yet-another-flash-player-security-update">OMG!SUSE! team: Yet another Flash Player security update</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>Security Team member <ulink url="http://www.suse.de/~thomas/">Thomas Biege</ulink>
        published an advisory this morning more critical security updates in..you guessed it:
        <emphasis role="bold">flash-player</emphasis>.</para>
      <para>According to the security announcement this package update affects openSUSE 11.3, 11.4
        as well as SUSE Enterprise Linux Desktop 10 SP4 and 11 SP1. This announcement also mentions
        that this is a <emphasis role="bold">remote code execution</emphasis> vulnerability, which
        means not updating to the latest flash-player package will leave you open to attackers
        running programs and exploits on your machine!</para>
      <para>Adobe has posted more <ulink url="http://www.adobe.com/support/security/bulletins/apsb11-12.html">details on this bulletin on their site</ulink> if you&apos;re <emphasis role="italic">that</emphasis>
        interested in the different issues this fix addresses.</para>
      <para>For most users, you&apos;ll just need to follow these steps:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Open up <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/YaST2-GTK">Yast2</ulink><emphasis role="bold">or</emphasis> click on the &quot;Online Update&quot; applet running in your GNOME or
            KDE panels</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Select the flash-player update and install it</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Make sure you restart <emphasis role="bold">
            <emphasis role="italic">all</emphasis>
          </emphasis> of your browsers, this will ensure that no program is
            running the older vulnerable flash-player package</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Relax with a Long Island Ice Tea</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
          </blockquote>
  </sect2> --><!--<sect2>
  <title>LOL</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://xkcd.com/874/">XKCD: Time Management</ulink>
    </title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/time_management.png" width="50%"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.5/">CC-BY-NC</ulink></para>
  </blockquote>
</sect2>--></sect1>
