<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/08/15/opensuse-edu-li-f-e-11-4-update-release-announcement/"
        >openSUSE Edu Li-f-e 11.4 update release announcement</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>The <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Education">openSUSE Education</ulink> team
      is proud to announce the release of updated <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Education-Li-f-e">openSUSE Edu Li-f-e</ulink> – Linux
      for Education. A Linux distribution that provides parents, students, teachers as well as IT
      admins running labs at educational institutes with education and development resources for
      their needs. Edu Li-f-e is based on openSUSE 11.4.</para>
    <para><inlinegraphic
        fileref="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/hTh2MdJW0YcGRU-G4Au1tTfewcAgZj-sY0D-k-EdIL23MAKjdwRZw_4KhEf_R_weY2ISsIKhWt58fzW5AK87h-vzNQ1B0BZWcSl-gbSVg3yrUMtOPYg"
        width="40%"/></para>
    <para>This new version has all packages available from the official update repository which
      contains many bug and security fixes. There are also some packages with version updates from
      the Open Build Service and a few new feature additions as well. New features include, but are
      not limited to: KDE version 4.7, GeoGebra, a geometry package providing for both graphical and
      algebraic input. The chromium browser from the open-source project behind the Google Chrome
      browser. And Blender, the cross platform suite for 3D creation with ffmpeg and luxrender
      support.</para>
    <para><!-- ($ ld: 16.8.11 sm $)--></para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/08/20/open-bugs-day-on-august-21/">Open Bugs
        Day on August 21</ulink></title>
    <para>The Testing Core Team has decided to hold our third <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Open-Bugs-Day">Open Bugs Day </ulink>(OBD) on Sunday
      August 21 from 0:00 to 23:59 UTC.</para>
    <para>To ensure that all the testers are using the same code base, we are making Virtual
      Machines available on our server. For those people that wish to test on their own hardware,
      there will be KDE and Gnome virtual images available at <ulink url="http://www5.zq1.de/img/"
        >http://www5.zq1.de/img/</ulink>, and distribution snapshots available at <ulink
        url="http://mirror.zq1.de/opensuse/factory/iso/"
        >http://mirror.zq1.de/opensuse/factory/iso/</ulink>. The virtual images have been prepared
      with KVM and tested with VirtualBox, and are compressed to a little over 900 MB. Instructions
      for using them in a VirtualBox VM are posted at the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Open-Bugs-Day">Open Bugs Day wiki page</ulink>.</para>
    <para>The purpose of this OBD is to test the open bugs reported for openSUSE 11.4 to see which
      of them are still affecting 12.1. As there are over 1300 open bugs for 11.4, we have a major
      job to do. If you have any time available on August 21,ý please join us. Use Channel
      #opensuse-testing on the Freenode IRC Network to get started.</para>
    <para>Larry Finger for the openSUSE Testing Core Team</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 20.08.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
