<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
  <!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
  %myentities;
]>
<sect1 role="forums">
  <title>openSUSE Forums</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/news/tech-news/450348-re-kde4-6-beta-1-released-new-post.html"
        >KDE4 4.6 beta 1 Released</ulink></title>
    <para>On the 25th of december <ulink url="http://kde.org">the KDE Team</ulink> released beta 1 for KDE4 4.6. Read how users discuss the news, their first experiences with this beta release. </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
      url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-help-here/install-boot-login/450335-cant-log-file-system-full.html"
      >Can't login, file-system is full </ulink></title>
    <para>Here's a user having trouble to logon to his system, because his root file system is full. Going through this thread will present you with a lot of info on how this could happen, and lots and lots of methods to solve the problems related to it.</para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
      url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-help-here/hardware/450339-best-driver-intel-core-i3-integrated-graphics.html"
      >Best driver for Intel Core i3 integrated graphics</ulink></title>
    <para>Some video cards can be real troublemakers for linux users. Lots of times there's no problem at all, sometimes one has to go through quite a lot to get things working as they should. This user has an Intel i3 CPU with 
      integrated graphics chip. </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>This week's subforum: <ulink
      url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/development/programming-scripting/"
      >Programming and Scripting</ulink></title>
    <para>Many users of the <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org">openSUSE Forums</ulink> are also involved in programming and scripting, in various kinds of projects. This subforum provides a place where they can discuss, 
    help eachother. If one reads or searches the threads, tons of shared knowledge become available. Help is provided, approaches and techniques discussed. A very useful subforum for starters in the world of programming and scripting too.</para>
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
