<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document licensed under CC-BY-SA by Sascha Manns -->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
  %myentities;
]>
<sect1 role="tipsandtricks">
  <title>Tips and Tricks</title>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Desktop Users</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>
        <ulink
          url="http://jared.ottleys.net/alfresco/alfresco-alfresco-pdf-tool-kit-insert-pdf-action"
          >Jared Ottley: Alfresco: Alfresco PDF Tool Kit – Insert PDF Action</ulink>
      </title>
      <para>I’ve taken a bit of Holiday time to update the Alfresco PDF Toolkit. <ulink
          url="http://www.unorganizedmachines.com/">Nate</ulink> has been doing an outstanding job
        adding <ulink
          url="http://www.unorganizedmachines.com/site/software-and-technology/34-software-development/99-watermarking-pdf-documents-with-alfresco"
          >Watermarking</ulink>, <ulink
          url="http://www.unorganizedmachines.com/site/software-and-technology/34-software-development/106-alfresco-pdf-toolkit-digital-signatures"
          >Digital Signatures</ulink>, <ulink
          url="http://www.unorganizedmachines.com/site/software-and-technology/34-software-development/101-encrypting-pdf-documents-with-alfresco"
          >Encryption</ulink> and cleaning up my messy code. But it was time to add a little bit
        myself. So I took sometime this evening to add in one of my planned actions: Insert PDF.
        This action allows you to insert a PDF into another PDF at a specific page. This is a pretty
        straight forward action to test: From the Document Details page of the PDF you want to
        insert content into, select Run Action (This action can also be run through the rules engine
        or scripted). (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/12/01/googleearth-6-0-running-in-opensuse-11-4-factory-64bits/"
          >Bruno Friedmann: GoogleEarth 6.0 running in opensuse 11.4 factory 64Bits</ulink></title>
      <para>Sometimes we need some of those applications running under our favorite OS. If you can
        stick with <ulink url="http://kde.org/applications/education/marble/">marble</ulink>. So the
        new googleearth 6.0 version hit the street. And if like me you want to give it a try,
        there’s some tricks to make it installing under your 64bits opensuse factory. My first
        attempt just result in a nice crash … (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://www.unixmen.com/linux-tutorials/1300-install-and-configure-wine-to-play-latest-windows-games-in-linux-ubuntu-linuxmint-fedora"
          >Unixmen/zinovsky: Install and configure wine to Play latest windows games in
          Linux</ulink></title>
      <para>In this post i will show you how to install latest windows applications and games using
        wine in Linux. When you install wine the first time, wine will work but not all windows
        application and games will work properly because most of them need a special configuration,
        some installed dlls and libraries. There are severals opensource software based on wine like
        for example <ulink url="http://www.unixmen.com/tag/playonlinux">PlayOnLinux</ulink>, a great
        software that can install and use windows games and applications. (...) </para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  
  <!--
  <sect2>
    <title>For Commandline/Script Newbies</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>Full hack</title>
      <para>do this...</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
    <title>For Developers and Programmers</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title>super article</title>
      <para>bin/sh</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2> -->
  <sect2>
    <title>For System Administrators</title>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://suseware.com/blog/2010/11/28/installing-broadcom-wireless-bcm43225-opensuse-113/"
          >Manu Gupta: Installing Broadcom Wireless – BCM43225 on openSUSE 11.3</ulink></title>
      <para>Again I am with a blog post, this time I am troubleshooting the Broadcom driver, BCM
        43225. Ok, to start with we need to do the following (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <title><ulink
          url="http://feeds.ottleys.net/~r/jaredottley/~3/FvOzTp4RrCY/alfresco-simple-file-diff"
          >Jared Ottley: Alfresco: Simple File Diff</ulink></title>
      <para>I’ve heard asked many times by customers and community members if there was a way to
        diff files in Alfresco and alas there isn’t an OTB way to do this. A month ago the
        discussion came up again internally. And I thought it might be fun to tackle this as side
        project just to see if/what was possible. So I took an evening and hammered out a simple
        Java class that did a comparison between two text files. Once I saw that I had at least the
        basics (annotate the differences between two files) and had gotten the question of basic
        possibility/difficulty out of the way I moved on to other projects. Today almost the entire
        family is sick so I thought I’d pick up the project again, moving the Java class to a Java
        Backed web script. The web script is a simple GET that takes the nodeRef of two files, or
        two versions of the same file and outputs a simple HTML page that highlights the differences
        between the two. There are no complex algorithms that take into account shifts in blocks or
        identifies just the text in a line that has changed. It is a simple line by line comparison
        of two pieces of content. It is not integrated in to Share or Explorer at this time. I might
        take that as a separate sick day project (or accept any code contributions to add that).
        (...)</para>
    </blockquote>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
