<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
  <!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
  %myentities;
]>
<sect1 role="kernel">
  <!--  This document licensed under CC-BY-SA by Sascha Manns -->
  <title>Kernel Review</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/Kernel-Log-Coming-in-2-6-37-Part-1-Graphics-1144218.html"
        >h-online/Thorsten Leemhuis: Kernel Log: Coming in 2.6.37 (Part 1) -
      Graphics</ulink></title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">The Nouveau driver now supports power management and can address the
        GeForce 320M, and the code for Intel graphics cores now supports the video units on Sandy
        Bridge processors, which are due to be released shortly. A number of changes to the Radeon
        KMS driver should improve its performance. </emphasis></para>
    <para>Linus Torvalds <ulink url="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.kernel/1066261"
        >released</ulink> the third pre-release version of Linux 2.6.37 ten days ago and then
      despite Thanksgiving and a <ulink
        url="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.kernel.pci/9946/focus%3D9947">trip to
      Tokyo</ulink>, he kept to his usual tempo and the fourth pre-release version was released two
      days ago. </para>
    <para>The final release of 2.6.37 will probably be in late December or early January next year.
      The current developer version already resembles the final version pretty closely, since kernel
      hackers have, as ever, used the merge window which opens the development cycle, to merge all
      major changes into the main development tree. The current stabilisation phase is reserved
      primarily for bug-fixes rather than major changes, to avoid introducing further bugs.
      (...)</para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://www.linux.com/news/featured-blogs/amanda-mcpherson/386194:our-annual-kernel-development-report-new-and-old-faces"
        >Linux.com/Amanda McPherson: Our Annual Kernel Development Report: New (and Old) Faces
      </ulink></title>
    <para>Today we are pleased to publish <ulink
        url="http://www.linuxfoundation.org/docs/lf_linux_kernel_development_2010.pdf">annual report
        on Linux kernel development</ulink>, detailing who does the work, who sponsors it and how
      fast the Linux kernel is growing. </para>
    <para>The paper documents how hard at work the Linux community has been. There have been 1.5
      million lines of code added to the kernel since the 2009 update. Since that last paper,
      additions and changes translate to an amazing 9,058 lines added, 4,495 lines removed, and
      1,978 lines changed every day, ­ weekends and holidays included. </para>
    <para>The other good news is that in the list of sponsoring entities we see more mobile and
      embedded companies participating in Linux kernel development. We see companies such as Nokia,
      Texas Instruments and Renasas moving up the list of companies who sponsor Linux development.
      This certainly should not be a surprise given the rise of Linux usage in devices over the last
      few years. This is great to see, even though the traditional Linux supporters are still at the
      top of the list: Red Hat, Intel, Novell and IBM. </para>
    <para>This paper documents a bit less frenzied development than the last one, which was expected
      given all the new features of 2.6.30 (ext4, ftrace, btrfs, perf etc) as well as the peak of
      merged drivers from Linux stable tree. Regardless, this report continues to paint a picture of
      a very strong and vibrant development community. </para>
    <para>I’d like to congratulate Paul Mundt who had the most individual contributions to the
      kernel, equally 1.3%, since our paper last year, and give my heartfelt thanks to Jon Corbet
      and Greg Kroah-Hartman, kernel developers and members of our Technical Advisory Board, who
      really do all the work on this paper. This publication is an important one as it gives a rare
      glimpse into the world of kernel development. Without their knowledge of the participants and
      their technical tools to analyze the code, this analysis would not be possible. If you’re
      interested in kernel development and want to support the work of Jon, please consider buying a
      subscription at <ulink url="http://www.lwn.net/">lwn.net</ulink>. </para>
    <para>Read more at <ulink
        url="http://www.linux-foundation.org/weblogs/amanda/2010/12/01/our-annual-kernel-development-report-new-and-old-faces/"
        >News and Thoughts from Inside the Linux Foundation</ulink>.</para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://arstechnica.com/open-source/news/2010/12/linux-kernel-13-million-lines-over-5-patches-per-hour.ars"
        >Arstechnika/Ryan Paul: Linux kernel: 13 million lines, over 5 patches per
      hour</ulink></title>
    <para>The Linux Foundation has published its third annual report about Linux kernel authorship.
      The statistics included in the paper illustrate growth trends in the kernel development
      process and provide insight into how the labor is distributed among individual contributors
      and corporate sponsors. The kernel has seen modest growth in its base of contributors over the
      past year, though the rate of development has seen a marginal decline. </para>
    <para>The latest version of the Linux kernel currently consists of approximately 13 million
      lines of code across over 33,000 files. The rate of development peaked with version 2.6.30
      last year, which saw an average of 6.40 patches per hour. The rate declined to an average of
      5.30 patches per hour in version 2.6.35.</para>
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
