<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="updates">
  <title>New/Updated Applications @ openSUSE</title>
  <!--* Gnome
* KDE
* XYZ 

Version should be available at packman or software.opensuse.org/search max. 4 posts. -->
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.wafaa.eu/entry/the-board---packaged-for-your-pleasure-1-50.html"
        >Andrew Wafaa: Blogged about: The Board - packaged for your pleasure</ulink></title>
    <para>No, I'm not talking about this <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Board">board</ulink> -
      I'm talking about the cool project by GNOME afficianado <ulink url="http://lucasr.org/">Lucas
        Rocha</ulink> - <ulink url="http://live.gnome.org/TheBoardProject">The Board</ulink>. There
      is a little gotcha with the packages - it is for openSUSE Factory/11.4 only at the moment. I
      need to work on backporting some of the shiny dependencies to 11.3. </para>
    <para>Things aren't 100%, as I need to do a tiny bit of cleaning up with the packages, but it
      works pretty well for a 0.1.0 release ;-) (...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 19.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://packman.links2linux.org/package/cclive">Packman: cclive
        0.7.1-1.pm</ulink></title>
    <para><quote>cclive is a command line video extraction utility similar to clive but focuses on
        low requirements. Its features are few and essential. cclive is intended for users who
        prefer lightweight and <quote>snappy</quote> programs. It was written in C and depends on
        libcurl. cclive sports much of the same features but some compromises were made along the
        way to keep the prerequisites low.</quote></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 20.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/2011/01/20/smb-traffic-analyzer-1-2-2-released/">Holger
        Hetterich: SMB Traffic Analyzer 1.2.2 released</ulink></title>
    <para>After some delay which wasn’t on our plan, we’re happy to announce <ulink
        url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/smb-traffic-analyzer/">SMB Traffic Analyzer</ulink>
      (called SMBTA in the following) version 1.2.2, bringing a whole bunch of new features and
      bugfixes to the table. First off, you might not believe it but SMBTA actually received some
      artwork, as we already reported here. :) <emphasis role="bold">Version 1.2.2</emphasis>
      includes those graphics as well as the SVG source. Thank you Sirko!</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://holger123.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/smbta1281.png" width="10%"
        />
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>SMBTA was installed on completely different systems than Linux during the past months. In
      some cases, things could have been much easier if required libraries could have come included
      with SMBTA. So we did for sqlite. If shared sqlite objects are found, and are of version 3.7.0
      or newer, those will be used, otherwise SMBTA will compile the 3.7.4 <ulink
        url="http://www.sqlite.org/amalgamation.html">Amalgamation build of sqlite</ulink>, that is
      included with both smbtad and smbtatools (<emphasis role="bold">bnc#662186</emphasis>). By
      specifying an environment variable, the user can also force an amalgamation build, even if
      shared libraries are available. Since the amalgamation build of sqlite is basically sqlite in
      a single c file, most compilers can employ optimization much better compared to a usual sqlite
      build.</para>
    <para>We are in the process of addressing possibilities to make SMBTA more than just output it’s
      results to a text mode terminal.</para>
    <figure id="fig.smbt">
      <title>A run of 'global, top 10 files rw', and it's HTML output</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://holger123.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/html-demo2.png"
            width="30%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>The decision was taken to drive the output of smbtaquery – the main program used to query
      the database of SMBTA – with XML, a move that allows us maximum flexibility. The smbtaquery
      program therefore produces XML by default and employs the XSLT processor <ulink
        url="http://xmlsoft.org/XSLT/"><emphasis role="bold">xsltproc</emphasis> of the libxslt
        library</ulink> to convert the output to HTML or ASCII text automatically.<xref
        linkend="fig.smbt"/></para>
    <para>Snipped of the "usage" function output in HTML All functions of smbtaquery are supported
      in both formats. SMBTA includes style sheets to produce the output and the user can choose the
      prefered output format on the command line. HTML support in smbtaquery forms the core of our
      plans to create a web based user interface for SMBTA (<emphasis role="bold"
        >bnc#659326</emphasis>). </para>
    <figure id="fig.smbt1">
      <title>Snipped of the "usage" function output in HTML</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://holger123.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/html-demo1.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>SMBTA 1.2.2 extends 128Bit AES encryption for the whole software suite. All tools, smbtad,
      and the module are now able to talk encrypted to each other. With former versions this has
      only been possible from the VFS module to smbtad. To support the end user, smbtaquery has been
      extended to generate 128 bit keys for usage with smbtad. The smbtad daemon supports two
      different keys, to allow a different group of users running the smbtatools (<emphasis
        role="bold">bnc#599644</emphasis>). A long standing issue finally resolved. <xref
        linkend="fig.smbt1"/></para>
    <para>A lot of effort moved into our test suite – smbtatorture -, in order to enhance the <ulink
        url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/2010/12/23/smbta-stresstest-0-0-1-released/">SMBTA
        Stresstest appliance</ulink>. First off, a smbtatorture process now creates directories, and
      filenames that make some more sense then the ones used before (which were just generated out
      of the user name and a number), to produce much more realistic looking results (<emphasis
        role="bold">bnc#653618</emphasis>). Furthermore, we worked on having support for multiple
      instances of smbtatorture on the same shares. A small control server has been created,
        “<emphasis role="italic">smbtatorturesrv</emphasis>“, distributing unique filenames to make
      sure that no smbtatorture process chooses the same file name than one of the others running on
      the network. smbtatorturesrv is internet socket networked, therefore smbtatorture processes
      can connect from anywhere to it.</para>
    <figure id="fig.smbt2">
      <title>Snipped of the SMBTA-Guide. We will work on getting more illustrations into where it
        makes sense.</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://holger123.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/docu.png" width="30%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>This program will be extended to make up a controlling instance for the connecting
      smbtatorture processes, showing statistics and healthiness information. We will implement the
      features introduced with 1.2.2 in the upcoming version of the <ulink
        url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/2010/12/23/smbta-stresstest-0-0-1-released/">SMBTA
        Stresstest</ulink>. <xref linkend="fig.smbt2"/></para>
    <para>On the documentation, <emphasis role="bold">probably the most irrelevant part of
        SMBTA</emphasis> :) , it has been completely reviewed and many design changes have been
      made. Everything about encryption has been taken out, and formed into a separate new chapter,
      addressing how encryption works in all parts of the software suite. All new features of
      smbtatorture and smbtatorturesrv have been documented. We have added descriptive illustration
      and diagrams to the documentation. (<emphasis role="bold">bnc#664823</emphasis>). And of
      course we updated <ulink url="http://morelias.org/smbta/smbta-guide.html">the online version
        of this document</ulink>. </para>
    <para>Oh wait, the <ulink url="http://build.opensuse.org/">openSUSE’s BuildService</ulink>
      already consumed SMB Traffic Analyzer 1.2.2. We will submit packages to openSUSE Factory and
      Tumbleweed in the next days. </para>
    <para>You can download SMB Traffic Analyzer on the <ulink
        url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/smb-traffic-analyzer/smb-traffic-analyzer-download/"
        >Download Page</ulink>. To get more info about SMB Traffic Analyzer, <ulink
        url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/smb-traffic-analyzer/">visit it’s home
      page</ulink>.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 21.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/01/21/libreoffice-3-3-rc4-available-for-opensuse/"
        >Petr Mladek: LibreOffice 3.3 rc4 available for openSUSE</ulink></title>
    <para>I’m happy to announce that LibreOffice 3.3 rc4 packages are available for <emphasis
        role="italic">openSUSE</emphasis> in the Build Service <emphasis role="italic"><ulink
          url="http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/LibreOffice:/Unstable/"
          >LibreOffice:Unstable project</ulink></emphasis>. They are based on the <ulink
        url="http://cgit.freedesktop.org/libreoffice/build/plain/NEWS?id=libreoffice-3.3.0.4"
        >libreoffice-3.3.0.4</ulink> release. Please, look for more details about the openSUSE
      LibreOffice build on the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/OpenOffice.org">wiki page</ulink>. </para>
    <para>The packages are based on LibreOffice release candidate sources. Though, they include some
      addons from the old <emphasis role="italic">Go-oo</emphasis> project. They have not passed
      full QA round yet and might include even serious bugs. Therefore they are not intended for
        <emphasis role="italic">data-critical</emphasis> usage. A good practice is to archive any
      important data before an use, … </para>
    <para>As usual, we kindly ask any interested beta testers to try the package and <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Bugreport_OOo">report bugs</ulink> against the product
        <emphasis role="italic">LibreOffice</emphasis> .</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Known Bugs</emphasis>:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>some packages were not renamed, .e.g. <emphasis role="italic"
              >OpenOffice_org-thesaurus</emphasis>, …; they are not built from the main LibO
            sources; I will do soon.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>SLED10 build is not available; need more love</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">More known Bugs</emphasis>:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://alturl.com/dmqve">Free Desktop bugzilla</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://alturl.com/qaq5">Novell bugzilla</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Other information and plans</emphasis>: </para>
    <para>First, I am sorry that I did not announce two older builds. I published rc2 build just
      before Christmas and the announce was forgot in the hurry. There were problems with building
      rc3. It was ready only one day before rc4, so it did not make sense to announce it. </para>
    <para>There still might be some <emphasis role="italic">openSUSE-specific</emphasis> bugs that
      would need to be fixed. I hope that they do not break the base function but… I will continue
      with producing newer builds with more fixes from the stable libreoffice-3-3 branch. I will
      move the packages to a stable project once we finish testing of all the SUSE-specific addons.
      It should happen within the next few weeks. </para>
    <para>Please be patient and thanks for understanding.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 21.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
