<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/01/11/reviewing-the-trademark-guidelines/">Reviewing
        the Trademark Guidelines</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>In 2009, a set of <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Trademark_guidelines"
        >trademark guidelines</ulink> were created to help define how the community and beyond could
      use the openSUSE logo and related trademarks in their own products and services. Along with
      this, Novell granted powers to the openSUSE Board to be the guardians of the openSUSE
      trademarks. This included ensuring that proper usage followed the guidelines as well as giving
      the Board the ability to review special use cases.</para>
    <para>It also helped those who wanted written permission from the Board authorizing the use of
      trademarks on their products and services. Formal requests for such permissions were sent to
        <email>permission@novell.com</email>, and Novell would forward the request to the Board for
      review. </para>
    <para>As you know, trademark protection is important because it represents the identity of an
      organization. Trademark usage also provides an important tool for the community that wishes to
      promote openSUSE. The use of the trademarks makes it easier to share and spread openSUSE
      works. Of course, regulating the appropriate usage of the trademarks is also a necessary evil
      to prevent abuse. </para>
    <para>As with anything in life, time gives perspective. There has been sufficient time since the
      implementation of the first guidelines to observe real use cases where the guidelines were
      either effective or ineffective. And for the Board, this includes identifying a more
      responsive workflow to addressing requests for authorization of usage, as we, and others,
      recognize the current process as being perfectible. </para>
    <para>The Board, along with others in the community, would like to begin a review of the current
      state of our trademark guidelines and identify where it can be strengthened and be more
      effective. To this end, our first step is to open an <ulink
        url="https://features.opensuse.org/311039">openFATE Feature request</ulink> for comments. We
      invite the community and beyond to review the current guidelines and offer their input on
      language and past use case experiences. </para>
    <para>While we would like comments submitted on openFATE, if you prefer, you can post your
      comments here or send your thoughts directly to <email>board@opensuse.org</email>. A specific
      timeline for completion of this process has not been determined yet, but it is the intention
      of the Board to move forward on this topic in order to help the community at large move
      forward on their own projects.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 11.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/01/12/the-opensuse-board-election-2010/">The
        openSUSE Board election 2010</ulink></title>
    <para>The openSUSE Board Election process, started in December 2010, is heading full-speed for
      the planned announcement of the results on January 26, 2011. Today the voting begins and it’s
      time to take a closer look at the candidates and <ulink
        url="https://connect.opensuse.org/pg/polls/read/digitaltomm/10769/opensuse-board-election-2011"
        >make up our minds</ulink>!</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata width="25%"
          fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/vote.jpeg" align="center"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>In this election we will have 2 seats to be voted upon as the board periods of Pascal
      Bleser and Henne Vogelsang expire. With the existing company affiliations in the board (Pavol
      Prusnak- Novell, Bryen Yunashko – none, Rupert Horstkötter – openSLX) the restraint is that at
      most one of the to be elected members can be affiliated with Novell and at most one with
      openSLX. According to the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board_election#Company_affiliation">election
        rules</ulink>, no single organization or company can control more than 40 percent of the
      electable Board seats. That means, in this election, that if two candidates from either Novell
      or openSLX score a first and second place, only the one with most votes will have a seat. The
      other seat will to go to the third candidate in line (provided of course that person is not
      also affiliated with the same company). This time we have seven candidates, all contributors
      with different experiences and backgrounds. </para>
    <para>You can check their user pages, blogs and the platform page explaining their vision and
      plans for openSUSE:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/User:Terrorpup">Chuck “PUP” Payne</ulink>,
            ambassador from the US (<ulink url="http://opensuse.terrorpup.net/">blog</ulink>) <ulink
              url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board_election_2010_platform_terrorpup"
              >Platform</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/User:Vizzzion">sebas</ulink>, open-slx user
            experience expert (<ulink
              url="http://vizzzion.org/blog/2010/12/running-for-the-opensuse-board/">blog</ulink>)
            <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board_election_2010_platform_sebas">Platform</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/User:Warlordfff">Kostas Koudaras</ulink>,
            ambassador from greece (<ulink url="http://warlordfff.tk/">blog</ulink>) <ulink
              url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board_election_2010_platform_warlordfff"
              >Platform</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/User:Mrdocs">Peter Linnell aka mrdocs</ulink>,
            OSS It consultant <ulink
              url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board_election_2010_platform_mrdocs"
              >Platform</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/User:Hennevogel">Henne Vogelsang</ulink>,
            Booster, currently Board Member, Novell (<ulink url="http://blog.hennevogel.de/"
              >blog</ulink>) <ulink
              url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board_election_2010_platform_hennevogel"
              >Platform</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/User:Psankar">Sankar P</ulink>, Programmer,
            Hacker, FOSS Enthusiast, Novell <ulink url="http://psankar.blogspot.com/">(blog</ulink>)
              <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board_election_2010_platform_psankar"
              >Platform</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/User:Ketheriel">Nelson Marques</ulink>,
            Contributor (<ulink url="http://nmarques.digitalwhores.net/">blog</ulink>) <ulink
              url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board_election_2010_platform_ketheriel"
              >Platform</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>The openSUSE board was set up to lead the overall project. The main tasks for members of
      the board are:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Act as a central point of contact</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Help resolve conflicts</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Communicate community interests to Novell</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Facilitate communication with all areas of the community</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Facilitate decision making processes where needed</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>The board should provide guidance to and support for existing governance structures, but
      shouldn’t direct or control development, since community mechanisms exist to accomplish the
      goals of the project. The board does however document decisions and policies, as well as
      mediate when issues arise. The board decides on usage of the trademarks of openSUSE, deals
      with conflicts, works with the Novell openSUSE community manager on funding decisions, works
      with the community on the organization of events and in general does a lot of ‘small things’
      often only visible when they are not handled. The board members are elected according to
        <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board_election">Board Election rules</ulink> by
      the members of the community who’ve been accepted as official ‘openSUSE Members’ and the chair
      person is appointed by Novell. Current chair is Alan Clark. </para>
    <para>Our current Board has had a busy time in the last year, setting up the foundations for a
      great 2011 for openSUSE. And the new Board members will need to put in some hard work to bring
      openSUSE to this new level. This includes the work on setting up the Foundation and the new
      responsibilities waiting for the board once that work has completed. Moreover challenges that
      might come up related to the Attachmate takeover of Novell have to be handled but also the
      usual day to day work in the community must continue. </para>
    <para>Ballots have just been opened and all openSUSE members whose membership is in good
      standing are eligible to vote. Please verify if your email address is valid and that you are
      able to read emails sent to your openSUSE address! The ballots are being done via the web on
        <ulink
        url="https://connect.opensuse.org/pg/polls/read/digitaltomm/10769/opensuse-board-election-2011"
        >connect.opensuse.org</ulink> and have been announced on <ulink
        url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-project/2011-01/msg00048.html">opensuse-project IRC
        channel and Mailing Lists</ulink>. Once a vote has been submitted it may not be changed
      afterwards. Finally, voting will end on <ulink url="http://bit.ly/gkQypN">January 26th,
        2011</ulink> when the ballots close. Shortly thereafter, you can expect the announcement of
      our two new board members! </para>
    <para>More detailed information can be found on the generic <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board_election">Board Election</ulink> and <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board_election_2010">board election 2010</ulink> wiki
      pages. Have a good vote!</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 13.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
