<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://omgsuse.com/content/zombie-lizards-evergreen-brings-111-back-dead">OMG!
        SUSE!-Team: Zombie Lizards! Evergreen brings 11.1 back from the dead</ulink>
    </title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata width="15%" fileref="http://cdn.omgsuse.com/omg/images/evergreen.jpg"
          align="center"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>In mid-October we wrote about <ulink url="http://omgsuse.com/content/adios-opensuse-111"
        >openSUSE 11.1 being put out to pasture</ulink> and the openSUSE team's decision to rapidly
      end-of-life the release. In the world of open source, what does "end of life" actually mean
      for users? As resident security expert <ulink url="http://twitter.com/msmeissn">Marcus
        Meissner</ulink> stated in the original announcement: </para>
    <para><quote><emphasis role="italic">SUSE Security announces that the SUSE Security Team will
          stop releasing updates for openSUSE 11.1 soon. Having provided security-relevant fixes for
          the last two years, we will stop releasing updates after December 31st
        2010.</emphasis></quote>
    </para>
    <para>Before the deadline of December 31st came, there <ulink
        url="http://www.rosenauer.org/blog/2010/11/30/community-powered-long-term-support-for-opensuse/"
        >was already talk</ulink> about extending support for openSUSE 11.1 by the openSUSE
      community. Shortly after the new year, openSUSE <ulink
        url="http://www.rosenauer.org/blog/2011/01/03/opensuse-project-evergreen/">project Evergreen
        was born</ulink>, a community-powered attempt at extending long-term support for 11.1. </para>
    <para>Currently Evergreen is still very much an experiment but community member <ulink
        url="http://www.rosenauer.org/blog/">Wolfgang Rosenauer</ulink>, who originally proposed the
      project, is actively working with a few other contributors to get all the infrastructural and
      technical issues worked out so the Evergreen project can start pushing out updates. If you're
      interested in joining the project, Wolfgang has created a <ulink
        url="http://lists.rosenauer.org/mailman/listinfo/evergreen">mailing list</ulink> you can
      subscribe to in order to get started.</para>
    <para>(...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 11.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://masterpatricko.blogspot.com/2011/01/winter-updates.html">Tejas
        Guruswamy: Winter updates</ulink></title>
    <para>Phew. long time no news! It's been a busy start of winter ... on that topic a happy new
      year to everyone! Welcome if you're reading this for the first time on PlanetSUSE, have a look
      at my <ulink url="http://masterpatricko.blogspot.com/2010/09/introduction.html">intro</ulink>
      if you're curious who I am. A few updates on what I've been working on this month at
      least.</para>
    <para><ulink url="http://kde-apps.org/content/show.php/opensync-plugin-akonadi?content=132900"
        >libopensync-plugin-akonadi 0.22.1</ulink> released Released an update to try and make it
      work better with the Google Akonadi resource (thanks ares).</para>
    <para>Package updates on the OBS:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Packaged <emphasis role="bold">krazy2</emphasis>, the KDE code quality checker,
            straight from git in <emphasis role="italic">KDE:Unstable:Playground</emphasis></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Updated <ulink url="http://www.infradead.org/get_iplayer/html/get_iplayer.html"
              >get_iplayer</ulink>, the BBC iPlayer download tool, in <emphasis role="italic"
              >home:MasterPatricko</emphasis>. It now works!</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Packaged <ulink url="http://blog.fenrus.org/">powertop2 beta</ulink>, the power
            consumption monitor, in <emphasis role="italic">home:MasterPatricko</emphasis>;
            interesting improvements compared to powertop. Needs kernel 2.6.37 (i.e. Factory or
            Kernel:HEAD) to show off its full power, but still works in 11.3.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Update <ulink url="http://www.gnu.org/software/liquidwar6/">liquidwar6</ulink>, the
            particle simulation game, to 0.0.9beta in <emphasis role="italic"
            >games</emphasis></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Update <ulink url="http://maxima.sourceforge.net/">maxima</ulink>, the Computer
            Algebra system, in <emphasis role="italic">science</emphasis> to 5.23.0</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Update <ulink url="http://www.synce.org">unshield</ulink>, the .CAB file extractor
            from the SynCE project, in <emphasis role="italic">Archiving</emphasis> (and eventually
            Factory) to 0.6</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fix build of <ulink url="http://denyhosts.sourceforge.net/">denyhosts</ulink>, the
            SSH brute-force protection tool, on x86_64</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Update <ulink url="http://jonls.dk/redshift/">redshift</ulink>, the auto
            screen-brightness adjuster in <emphasis role="italic">Factory:Contrib</emphasis> to
            0.6</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Created a package <emphasis role="bold">vncserver-autostart</emphasis> in
            home:MasterPatricko which adds an init script to start a tightvnc vncserver on bootup.
            Complete with sysconfig-style configuration. Completely insecure of course but perfect
            for a local network.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>Started using my hard-earned openSUSE member benefits; tejas.guruswamy AT and
      masterpatricko AT opensuse.org are operational; got the blog syndicated on <ulink
        url="http://planet.opensuse.org">planet.opensuse.org</ulink>.</para>
    <para>Plus, as always, I have a couple of new project ideas I'd like to get started on ... more
      on that soon. Comments welcome as always.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 11.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://www.linux.com/distrocentral/distroblogs/395853:opensuse-weekly-news-available-for-ebook-reader"
        >Sascha Manns: openSUSE Weekly News available for EBook Reader</ulink></title>
    <para>Some years, the openSUSE Weekly News, only was edited and published in the Wiki. </para>
    <para>Now, after some time the team is looking forward to break new ground. The new ground are
      new formats. editing for . Also, translations are well done. The disadvantage, however, that
      an interested reader must surf again and again to a particular website, and these must be read
      online. </para>
    <para>To extend our offer, we have already started in the middle of last year to convert the
      wikicode in HTML code, and published it in full on openSUSE's News platform news.opensuse.org.
      This is now offered readers the opportunity to subscribe to the RSS feed, and thus any time if
      the reader wishes it to be available. (...)</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 11.1.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
