<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://www.marques.so/2011/10/opensuse-12-1-delivers-gtk-3-2-with-broadway-backend/"
        >Nelson Marques: openSUSE 12.1 delivers GTK+ 3.2 with Broadway backend!</ulink></title>
    <para>On the 25th of September 2001, <ulink url="http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/User:Mclasen"
        >Mathias Clasen</ulink> announces the <ulink
        url="http://mail.gnome.org/archives/gtk-devel-list/2011-September/msg00175.html">release of
        GTK+ 3.2.0</ulink>. This release includes delivers:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Many improvements to the CSS theming support;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Width-for-height support in many more widgets (ex: GtkPanel, GtkMenuBar,
            GtkNotebook, etc);</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>New experimental Wayland and <emphasis role="bold">HTML5 ‘Broadway’
              backeds</emphasis>;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>GtkFileChooser and GtkAssistant received face-lifts;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>New widgets (ex: GtkLockButton and GtkOverlay, etc);</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <!--($ ld: 03.10.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://www.wafaa.eu/entry/hardware-needed-for-opensuse-on-arm-1-71.html"
        >Andrew Wafaa: Hardware needed for openSUSE on ARM</ulink></title>
    <para>As I <ulink url="http://www.wafaa.eu/entry/target-arm-hardware-1-70.html"
        >mentioned</ulink> before, we have an initial target platform identified for testing the
      work of all those involved in the openSUSE ARM port. The problem is we need to obtain the
      hardware.</para>
    <para>I am in discussions trying to get some corporate sponsorship of hardware, but we can not
      rely soley on those kind companies that would like to see us succeed. We as a community need
      to help ourselves succeed, as such I've set up a <ulink
        url="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/16098">campaign</ulink> on Pledgie to enable us the
      community to contribute to the effort for obtaining hardware. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 05.10.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://openleadership.blogspot.com/2011/10/looking-back-at-opensuse-conferece-osc.html"
        >Gregory M. Zysk: Looking back at the openSUSE Conference 2011 (oSC)</ulink></title>
    <para>Well, once again, I had a chance to meet a community, one of which, I have never met
      before ;-) </para>
    <para>I arrived at <ulink url="http://www.zentrifuge-nuernberg.de/">Zentrifuge</ulink> on the
      10th of September for the warmup to the <ulink url="http://conference.opensuse.org/"
        >oSC</ulink>. Immediately after arrival, I was greeted with warm smiles, open discussions,
      and cold beer ;-) No one knew who I was, but they all welcomed me. As the evening continued, I
      was witness to how the community also made sure that they welcomed everyone, once they
      arrived. This is pure class and I would like to say is very important to a newbie who is
      entering the community. This is one aspect where openSUSE makes the difference, since it is
      not practiced to this extent in many other communities. </para>
    <!--($ ld: 05.10.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://openleadership.blogspot.com/2011/10/opensuse-marketing-hackfest-2011.html"
        >Gregory M. Zysk: openSUSE Marketing Hackfest 2011</ulink></title>
    <para>On the 15th and 16 of September 2011, following the oSC, the marketing team held a
      Marketing Hackfest at the SUSE headquarters in Nuremberg, Germany. </para>
    <para>I was asked to attend this event for several reasons aside from the normal Marketing
      related things, two of which were the most important to me being new to this event. One, was
      to observe how the marketing team functions as a unit. And second, to hold meetings with
      different people to discuss certain issues with an outlook of solving them for the benefit of
      the openSUSE community. Moreover, many of us had a chance to further discuss (in person)
      initiatives started at the oSC, since we had a chance to digest them and come with some
      valuable input that was used to move things forward ;-)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 05.10.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://saigkill.homelinux.net/entry/2011/10/07/balsam-professional-121-boxdesign-based-on-opensuse"
        >Sascha Manns: Balsam Professional 12.1 Boxdesign (based on openSUSE)</ulink></title>
    <para>Now it is out, our new Boxdesign:</para>
    <para><inlinegraphic fileref="http://saigkill.homelinux.net/images/121_boxtitel_gb_v2.jpg"
        width="30%"/></para>
    <!--($ ld: 08.10.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
