<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://vizzzion.org/blog/2011/08/desktop-summit-thoughts/">Sebastian Kügler:
        Desktop Summit Thoughts</ulink></title>
    <para>I’ve been to the <ulink url="http://desktopsummit.org/">Desktop Summit</ulink> in Berlin
      for the past few days, we’re now around the middle of the event, after the conference, before
      the workshop and BoF sessions, so I thought I might share some thoughts I’ve gathered in idle
      moments in the past few days.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">boredom and diversity</emphasis></para>
    <para>Last night, the build system BoF was planned, a team session where we look at the way how
      we develop our software. I have to admit that to me, this is quite a boring (but nevertheless
      very important topic). As it also affects the way we release software, I’ve put my release
      team hat on and joined the session. I was a bit afraid that since it’s not the most sexy topic
      in the world, that little people would show and we end up with incomplete or broken ways to
      release the KDE SC, and KDE Frameworks in the future. My worries were ungrounded as quite some
      people showed up and we made good progress on all the topic we talked about. (If you’re
      interested what we talked about, keep an eye on the kde-core-devel and kde-buildsystem
      mailinglists.) What struck me is that in KDE, there’s enough people who feel responsible, even
      for boring topics. When I shared my (ungrounded) concerns with Stephen Kelly, he looked at me
      with this empty expression on his face and told me “but that’s exciting, it’s the way we build
      our software!”, and given his enthusiasm, I believe him (even if I don’t exactly personally
      share his excitement). Diversity makes us strong. (...)</para>
    <!--($ ld: 10.08.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://emmes.livejournal.com/9967.html">Matthias Hopf: SUSE graphical
        benchmark test</ulink></title>
    <para>We at SUSE needed to know whether we had some severe regressions regarding graphics
      performance during enablement of intel SandyBridge graphics - and it turned out that it was
      not commonly understood <emphasis role="italic">what</emphasis> graphics performance is
      actually composed of. Some were only interested in core X commands (xterm users :-) , some
      only in render performance (office users :-) , some in low-core 3D graphics (compiz users :-)
      , some in hardcore 3D graphics (gamers :-) .</para>
    <para>So finally I put together a standardized graphical benchmark with aspects for all users.
      And no, it won't output a single number, because that would be meaningless for everybody. But
      it makes it easy to compare different aspects between different graphics cards and drivers,
      and there are some surprising results. But more about the results later.</para>
    <para>The sources for the benchmark are now on gitorious, and the <ulink
        url="https://gitorious.org/performance-frameworks/pages/GraphicalBenchmark">Wiki
        entry</ulink> describes its usage. It's currently somewhat tailored to SLE11SP1, so you
      might run into minor issues when running it on a different OS version. And of course, it's not
      very polished yet .</para>
    <!--($ ld: 12.08.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/2011/08/11/smb-traffic-analyzer-opensuse-conference/"
        >Holger Hetterich: SMB Traffic Analyzer @ openSUSE conference</ulink></title>
    <para>Should you read this article in a blog roll, here is a clue what it is about: a) the
        <ulink url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/smb-traffic-analyzer/">SMB Traffic Analyzer
        project (SMBTA)</ulink>, b) <ulink url="http://conference.opensuse.org/">the openSUSE
        conference</ulink>, and c) <ulink
        url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/2011/08/11/smb-traffic-analyzer-opensuse-conference/www.samba.org"
        >Samba</ulink>.</para>
    <para>You guess it, we finally got a slot for a presentation at the wonderful <ulink
        url="http://conference.opensuse.org/">openSUSE conference</ulink> for <ulink
        url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/smb-traffic-analyzer/">SMBTA</ulink>. To me, it is
      remarkable to see a project like SMBTA being presented at OSC because it is not really
      something related to openSUSE. It’s not that SMBTA improves your boot time, or discusses
      details of the <ulink url="https://build.opensuse.org/">buildservice</ulink>, or makes your
      life with the openSUSE distribution better in any way. SMBTA is very likely not even
      interesting to the casual user, except for some administrators.</para>
    <para>That said, SMBTA was born inside of the openSUSE infrastructure, growing to a project used
      on different distributions and operating systems, such as Solaris. And the one thing we can
      really say is that we exploited all the services that make up openSUSE to the core. We used
      the openSUSE Buildservice from the beginning, and we use appliances created by <ulink
        url="http://susestudio.com/">SUSE Studio</ulink> for both demoing and developing
      SMBTA.</para>
    <para>With the recent release of <ulink
        url="http://www.samba.org/samba/news/releases/3.6.0.html">Samba 3.6.0, among it’s top
        changes like full SMB2 support and other major features</ulink>, it is also prime time for
      SMBTA. The<emphasis role="bold"> Virtual File System layer</emphasis> module that supports our
      current infrastructure is included in this release of the Samba CIFS server and that marks
        <emphasis role="bold">a milestone</emphasis> for our project. SMBTA is already used in
      production at some sites, and the release of Samba 3.6.0 will hopefully forward this
      trend.</para>
    <para>Benjamin Brunner and me will give an introduction talk to SMB Traffic Analyzer at the
      openSUSE conference and most likely <emphasis role="bold">live-demo</emphasis> the software
      chain. We’ll welcome anyone interested to join our presentation at OSC!</para>
    <!--$ ld: 12.08.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://vizzzion.org/blog/2011/08/board-business/">Sebastian Kügler: Board
        Business</ulink></title>
    <para> Tonight, the new board of directors of KDE e.V. went out for dinner, generously (!)
      treated by our constituency. </para>
    <para>It was a nice and relaxed dinner, gave us some good opportunity to brief Lydia (our newest
      board member) on how we work, boring stuff like where we store our documents, what to expect
      from our bi-weekly conference calls, what granularity of emailing we found to be productive,
      and so on. One official thing we always have to do (according to German foundation
      regulations, so-called “Vereinsrecht”) is appointing roles. Cornelius was volunteered as
      president, Frank as treasurer, both accepted their new and old responsibilities. I promoted
      from regular board member to vice president (which really only has a a theoretical meaning).
      The vote was, as usual a formal thing and we got it done between dumpling 2 and 3 on my plate,
      it took all of 3 minutes. Serious, effective, yet duely diligent. :P </para>
    <para>We also used the opportunity to talk about non-board stuff, about our other projects in
      KDE (we’re also pretty active in the community outside of the board chores), private going
      ons, random fun things. I came back happy about our team, and looking forward to our work in
      the coming year. Just right. </para>
    <para>Earlier this afternoon, we met with the GNOME board. There were also some personal changes
      in the new GNOME board, I especially enjoyed Ryan Lortie (desrt) having joined the board of
      directors of the GNOME foundation. I’ve met Ryan at several occasions in the past, and always
      found that we got a good click, enough differences to keep conversations interesting, but very
      much one the same line of communication. One of the topics was communications across the
      boards, and we thought that having some kind of ‘open communication channel’ for situtations
      which might turn unproductive would be good. Ryan and me volunteered, and we took immediate
      opportunity and went out for an afternoon drink, which I very much enjoyed. </para>
    <para>While going to our dinner appointment, I had really two things in mind, love and hate. Not
      sure why those two words sprang to my mind, but I really <emphasis role="italic"
        >hate</emphasis> saying goodbye to the people I <emphasis role="italic">love</emphasis>.
      Even if it’s very much a temporary thing (our meetings in the Plasma team have become pretty
      frequent, especially with Plasma Active One being on the horizon), having people leave after
      an intensive week of excellent collaboration always makes me kind of sad. That’s of course
      just an indication of how much I enjoy working in this excellent team, or maybe just a sign of
      exhaustion after a week of pushing the Free desktop to the next level with peers who are as
      passionate about this as I am. Tomorrow in the afternoon, I’ll take a train back home to the
      Netherlands, and will commence putting our plans (and continuation, tweaks thereof) to action.
      Exhausted after week of frantic Free software conferencing, but just as energized as if it
      were my first Akademy.</para>
    <para>The coming weekend will be used for catching up on sleep, then next weekend, I’ll be at
        <ulink url="http://froscon.de">Froscon</ulink>, where I’ll be presenting Plasma Active. Be
      there if you want to touch it yourself. :) </para>
    <!--($ ld: 12.08.11 sm $-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
