<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 id="gsoc" role="gsoc">
  <title>Google Summer of Code</title>
  <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
      <imagedata width="20%" align="center" fileref="http://michal.hrusecky.net/wp-content/uploads/GSoC2011_300x200.png"/>
    </imageobject>
  </mediaobject>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://rxvl.in/post/7967401920/gsoc-2011-ssc-week-9">Ratan Sebastian: GSOC 2011:
        ssc Week 9</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>Tasks completed this week:<orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Replacing of ArgumentParser with Thor. I’d given a mid-week update about <ulink
              url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-project/2011-07/msg00098.html">this</ulink> on
            the mailing list. Please check there for complete details.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Implementing the general commands (checkout, commit and status). As a direct
            consequence of using thor for the command line parsing, we get to use the invoke method
            to call other actions. This made writing these commands quite easy.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Started on refactoring the DirectoryManager module. The NewDirectoryManager is
            currently in use in the general commands and will gradually replace the older version
            which is a mess of helper functions right now. There will be separate classes for
            handling each of the local storage files (for software, repositories and files) deriving
            from a parent LocalStorageFile class which implements the
            generic #read and#save methods.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>The gem is now hosted on rubygems.org . So, you can install it with gem install ssc.
            Use the fantastic thor generated usage instructions to help you use the app.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist></para>
    <para>The tasks for next week are:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Write integration tests</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Implement a command to get information about installed packages from the currently
            run system.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Commands for Appliance building and build status reporting.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>If you have any suggestions for features. Please do write in on the studio-users mailing
      list.</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 24.7.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://nbprashanth.wordpress.com/2011/07/26/gsoc-progress/">N.B.Prashanth: GSoC
        Progress (libYI)</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>Last week has been quite dull after the mid term evaluations. The week started off with me
      trying to improve the documentation and a home page for it. While the latter went pretty
      smooth, the documentation is quite baffling. Most of the source code was quite well documented
      and small hacks with the Doxyfile seemed to produce the proper results. Nevertheless, there
      were cases (quite a few) where the results seemed out of place. While struggling with the
      docs, I also started working on the libyui-gtk-pkg package. This package provides the libzypp
      plugin for the libyui-gtk module. This has been separated from libyui-gtk package so as to
      make it platform independent. I am nearly there on getting this package to compile. A day or
      two should be sufficient, I guess.</para>
    <para>By the end of last week, I switched over to writing examples for YUI in the hope that it
      would give me further insight into what a developer might expect from the docs. After a few
      not-so-great ideas, I settled on an IRC client written with YUI. The library to manage the IRC
      protocol is self-implemented and is complete. At this point in time, it handles only
      conversations and a single channel. This is very small compared to the span of the IRC
      protocol. But since the main aspect of the example is to showcase YUI as a UI library, I guess
      the features are sufficient.</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 26.7.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://cbounta.wordpress.com/2011/07/29/a-utility-for-merging-configuration-sysconfig-files-–-week-10-report/"
        >Christos Bountalis: A utility for merging configuration / sysconfig files – Week 10
        Report</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>Hello again, this is my report for the 10th week of GSoC. Unfortunately i wasn’t able to
      create the beta packages i was hoping. There are still some issues to be resolved within the
      aug_process_tree that hopefully will be solved this weekend.  (...)</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 29.7.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink
        url="http://alex.eftimie.ro/2011/07/29/packagekit-backend-for-software-center-short-week-9-report/"
        >Alex Eftimie: PackageKit backend for Software Center: short week 9 report</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>It’s nice to write to you again. I’ve been having a 10 days vacation (that’s why there was
      no week 8 report), enjoyed it and now I’m back with fresh forces.</para>
    <para>This short (started slowly on Tuesday) week’s activity regards:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>almost fixing a bug that prevents my PackageKit software-center from prime time:
            package information isn’t correctly refreshed after an installation/removal</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>starting work on the openSUSE integration (the corresponding Distro class, removal
            of forgotten apt related imports, dependency identification and testing).</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>I will continue work on this side and <emphasis role="italic">hope</emphasis> that by the
      end of the next week, will have everything working and up for testing in openSUSE.</para>
    <para>NB: I will have to provide for testing a trunk version of pygobject since a release is
      delayed by another awaited merge;</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 30.7.11 sm $)-->  </blockquote>
</sect1>
