<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"[
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="updates">
  <title>New/Updated Applications @ openSUSE</title>
  <!--* Gnome
* KDE
* XYZ http://oyranos-cms.blogspot.com/2011/05/openicc-and-basiccolor-profile-packages.html

Version should be available at packman or software.opensuse.org/search max. 4 posts. -->
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://oyranos-cms.blogspot.com/2011/05/openicc-and-basiccolor-profile-packages.html"
        >Kai-Uwe Behrmann: OpenICC and basICColor profile packages</ulink></title>
    <para>Originally I wanted to have most packages ready for Montreal. But it was good to not
      announce them. Now they are slowly rolling out. </para>
    <para>Today came the <ulink
        url="http://lists.freedesktop.org/archives/openicc/2011q2/004133.html"
        >basICColor_Offset_2009 package 1.1.1</ulink> shortly after <ulink
        url="http://lists.freedesktop.org/archives/openicc/2011q2/004130.html">OpenICC Data package
        1.2.0</ulink>. Both form now a fairly distributable and stable usable set of ICC profiles
      with completely free licenses. </para>
    <para>ICC Examin had some issues in the CinePaint plugin. So I decided to first fix that and as
      well finish the started ICC v4 support in ICC Examin. Most of that should work already in
        <ulink url="http://www.oyranos.org/scm">git</ulink>. </para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 30.5.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/2011/05/28/smb-traffic-analyzer-1-2-5-released/">Holger
        Hetterich: SMB Traffic Analyzer 1.2.5 released</ulink></title>
    <para><emphasis role="italic">Just in case you’re wondering what this article is about, check
        out the <ulink url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/smb-traffic-analyzer/">SMB Traffic
          Analyzer project</ulink> to get more information.</emphasis></para>
    <para>The team is proud to release <emphasis role="bold">SMB Traffic Analyzer version
        1.2.5</emphasis>. Among numerous changes and enhancements, this release brings <ulink
        url="http://morelias.org/smbta/smbta-guide.html#_websmbta">a huge documentation update on
        webSMBTA</ulink>, thanks to Benjamin of the SMBTA team. In <emphasis role="bold"
        >smbtaquery</emphasis>, we had a bug that caused the “from..to” and “since” time modifiers
      on functions not to work (bso#8169). Furthermore, this release fixes an error condition on
      smbtad which we encountered during the SambaXP conference, when a directory was created that
      already existed. Packages for Gentoo Linux and openSUSE should be available very soon, and
      with release 1.2.5, we’ve sub-packaged webSMBTA. The “one click install” optioný for openSUSE
      will install all required repositories such as rails3 to run webSMBTA from the apache
      webserver. We have added installation instructions to the source tarball.</para>
    <para>SMB Traffic Analyzer 1.2.5<emphasis role="bold"> makes changes to the database being used
        by SMBTA</emphasis>. We provide an <emphasis role="bold">upgrade path</emphasis> from
      whichever version of SMBTA you are coming from. Just run “smbtaquery -C” and follow the
      instructions.</para>
    <para>Checkout the <ulink url="http://holger123.wordpress.com/smb-traffic-analyzer/">SMB Traffic
        Analyzer homepage</ulink> to get more information and download options. </para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 30.5.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
