<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 id="hackweek" role="hackweek">
  <title>Hackweek VII</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/09/22/suse-hackweek-7-next-week/">SUSE Hackweek 7 – Next Week</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>One of the ways SUSE and its developers contribute to openSUSE is through <ulink url="http://hackweek.opensuse.org">Hackweek</ulink>: – a week long sprint permitting
      developers to work on something entirely of their own design or wishes as long as it is
      FOSS-related. Started in 2007, it has become a regular part of SUSE’s development. This is in
      keeping in line with the openSUSE Project’s goal of being more than just an organization that
      benefits itself. We believe in a project that benefits the greater good of free and open
      software.</para>
    <para>Some 150+ developers will have free reign to work on new applications or make improvements
      to other software projects. Hackweek also permits developers to push away from the grind of
      deadlines and “must fix” bug fixing (unless it’s a critical customer situation) which can be
      at times stressful and tedious. (...)</para>
<!--($ ld: 23.9.11 sm $) -->  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://michal.hrusecky.net/2011/09/hack-week/">Michal Hrušecký: Hack Week</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>Next week is a Hack Week. Do you know, what Hack Week is? It’s week during which we at
      SUSE come to work and work on anything we want. Anything? Well anything open source related.
      So if you normally work as a designer, you can sit down and spend a whole week hacking Linux
      kernel. Or on the other hand, as kernel developer, you can try to improve design of our web.
      What are my plans for next week? I’m not sure yet. I still have some requests regarding <ulink url="http://michal.hrusecky.net/2011/02/opensuse-paste-after-the-sixth-hackweek/">openSUSE Paste</ulink>. But as week is a long time, I would like to try something else, requiring
      more time.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">libguestfs</emphasis></para>
    <para><ulink url="http://libguestfs.org/">libguestfs</ulink> is a set of tools for accessing and
      modifying virtual machine disk images. And I would like to have it available somehow in
      openSUSE as I use virtualization quite a lot. That can be interesting and useful project for
      the next week and I think it may be useful not just for me.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Karma in Connect</emphasis></para>
    <para>Yes, here I go again. I already  <ulink url="http://michal.hrusecky.net/2010/08/ideas-about-karma-in-opensuse-connect/">wrote about it</ulink> <ulink url="http://michal.hrusecky.net/2011/03/gsoc-2011-ideas-karma-plugin-for-opensuse-connect/">several times</ulink> and it is still not implemented and although I think full
      implementation would take quite some time, I could try to take a look at some simple way how
      to provide something to start with.</para>
    <para>So these are my two ideas what I may try to do next week. Not decided yet, so maybe I will
      end up with something completely different. But in the meantime, this can serve as an
      inspiration for others and if somebody would like to join me on either of these, don’t
      hesitate to leave a comment</para>
<!-- ($ ld: 21.9.11 sm $) -->  </blockquote>
</sect1>
