<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="forums">
  <title>openSUSE Forums</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/other-forums/news-announcements/tech-news/465508-microsoft-requires-windows-8-certified-machines-use-uef.html">Microsoft requires that Windows 8-certified machines use UEF</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>
      A link to this thread in the Tech News subforum about Microsoft's new policy. Various sources report that this could be the end of linux and other small OS-es, since dual booting was said to become impossible. Important to the community since a lot of our openSUSE users dual boot their openSUSE with some flavor of Windows. Personally I don't believe this is going to be the end of linux, I'm pretty sure we'll overcome this, as I'm sure this new policy will make Microsoft a regular visitor in the courts of law, at least in the EU, which is a big market for Microsoft. Read the thread to find out more about the subject, and ....that linux may already be fit to deal with this.
    </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
    <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/pre-release-beta/464419-sax3-testers-needed.html">sax3 testers needed</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>
      This year GOSC -Google's Summer Of Code- accepted an application for the development of a new sax2, sax3. Sax2 used to be the tool to configure the X-server concerning our keyboard, mouse, our display driver and monitor. It was depracated some releases ago in favor of autodetection and -configuration. Still quite some users appeared to be needing a tool to configure the X-server. This thread called out for testers, to report their experiences using the new tool. 
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
    <ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/get-technical-help-here/network-internet/465315-cannot-write-samba-shares.html">Cannot write to Samba shares</ulink>
    </title>
    <para>
      In a network environment with windows machines, Samba is the server software to share almost anything for windows clients. It can behave as a windows domain controller, control printer queues, do user management etc. Here's a user having trouble to write to those shares, a thing one could describe as a minimum requirement. A must-read for anyone using Samba, or looking for a replacement for expensive windows servers. 
      </para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title>
      openSUSE Language specific subforums:
    </title>
    <para>We now host the following language specific subforums under the umbrella of the openSUSE Forums:
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/english/">Main forums, english</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/ae-ae-chinese/">中文(Chinese)</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/nederlands-dutch/">Nederlands (Dutch)</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/frana-ais-french/">Français (French)</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/deutsch-german/">Deutsch (German)</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/greek/">Ελληνικό (Greek)</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/magyar-hungarian/">Magyar (Hungarian)</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/japanese/">日本語 (Japanese)</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/portuguese/">Portuguese</ulink>
	<ulink url="http://forums.opensuse.org/p-russian/">Pусский (Russian)</ulink>
      </para>
<!-- ($ ld: 22.09.2011 gl $) -->  </blockquote>
</sect1>
