<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/15/mingle-today/">Mingle Today!</ulink></title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/about_connect-300x128.png"
          align="left"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>It all started out with a simple question Pavol Rusnak asked on the openSUSE Conference
      ’09 </para>
    <para><emphasis role="italic">What are we really doing when we develop a new tool to handle
        openSUSE users and groups?</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>The answer was simple: Connecting people to projects, groups and with each other.
      Connecting faces to names, nicknames and to email addresses. In the end connecting all our
      other tools to this one so we can share the data. These are the fundamental ideas behind our
      newest openSUSE tool: <ulink url="http://connect.opensuse.org/">connect</ulink>. In the
      following months the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Boosters_team">openSUSE
        Boosters</ulink> and friends started to work on this tool based on <ulink
        url="http://elgg.org/">Elgg</ulink>. An open source social networking engine, that delivers
      the building blocks that enable us to create our own fully-featured social network. And today
      we release it to you, the openSUSE Community.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">What is connect?</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>First and foremost connect is a user database. The openSUSE project operates a lot of
      tools and most of them require users to authenticate to operate them, have some kind of access
      level for different user types (groups) and possibly other attributes stored for the user like
      contact information, an avatar or a description of the person. Instead of having to enter and
      maintain this information over and over again in each tool, connect is the first step in
      centralizing this.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/connect_userprofile-e1300199288617-300x146.jpg"
          align="center"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Secondly connect introduces the nowadays mandatory social features. Instead of rather
      boring collection of user attributes, connect reflects the social relations among the openSUSE
      community. It allows the users to share activities, places, events and interests within their
      network. It truly helps you to connect with other lizards.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">And what can I do with it?</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>Make friends and tell them about yourself. See what they are up to in the Build Service,
      openFATE or Bugzilla. Find out who your friends, friends are or get your openSUSE business
      cards. Or how about you gang up in groups and collaborate in discussions, run your own polls
      and create your groups events? You can also apply to be an <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Members">openSUSE Member</ulink> and vote in project
      wide polls like the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Board">openSUSE Board</ulink>
      election. And more!</para>
    <para>
      <informaltable frame="void">
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                  <imagedata
                    fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/connect_followers-150x150.jpg"
                    width=""/>
                </imageobject>
              </mediaobject>
            </td>
            <td>
              <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                  <imagedata
                    fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/connect_group-150x150.jpg"
                    width=""/>
                </imageobject>
              </mediaobject>
            </td>
            <td>
              <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                  <imagedata
                    fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/connect_polls-150x150.jpg"
                  />
                </imageobject>
              </mediaobject>
            </td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </informaltable>
    </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Can I improve it? </emphasis></para>
    <para>connect is far from done and is constantly under development, so please help out! Are you
      able to explain complicated IT coherences so your grandma can understand them? Help us to
      document the various tools and processes in connect. Is web-development your thing and you
      master any HTML/CSS? Then improve the whole user experience. Or is PHP coding your thing? Get
      your editor out then and extend this tool to your needs. As mentioned in the beginning of this
      article, connect is based on an open source social networking platform called Elgg. They have
        <ulink url="http://docs.elgg.org/">fantastic documentation</ulink> on how to <ulink
        url="http://docs.elgg.org/wiki/Themes">theme it</ulink>, <ulink
        url="http://docs.elgg.org/wiki/Getting_Started_With_Development">getting started with Elgg
        development</ulink> or how to extend it with <ulink
        url="http://docs.elgg.org/wiki/Plugin_development">plugins</ulink>. They also run their own
        <ulink url="http://community.elgg.org/">community</ulink> where you can talk to other Elgg
      developers and users.</para>
    <para>You can read, check out and alter the code that is running on connect.opensuse.org in our
      gitorious repository <ulink url="http://gitorious.org/opensuse/connect"
        >http://gitorious.org/opensuse/connect </ulink>and communicate with us about your changes on
      our mailing list <ulink url="mailto:opensuse-web@opensuse.org">opensuse-web</ulink>, so get
      going. Happy Hacking!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Enjoy this new addition to the family of openSUSE tools …and don’t
        forget to mingle today!</emphasis></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">License</emphasis>: <ulink
        url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">FDL 1.2</ulink></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 15.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
