<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/07/opensuse-11-4-will-be-first-to-roll-out-with-libreoffice/">openSUSE 11.4 Will Be First To Roll Out With LibreOffice</ulink>
    </title>
    <note><para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is Licensed under the <ulink url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GNU Free Documentation License version 1.2.</ulink></emphasis></para>
    </note>
    <para>openSUSE 11.4 is set to release on 10th March 2010. A highlight among many exciting
      features is the debut of <ulink url="bold">LibreOffice</ulink>, successor project of the
      popular cross-platform desktop office suite by OpenOffice.org.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/LibreOffice-splash-150x150.jpg"
        />
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">LibreOffice features</emphasis></para>
    <para>LibreOffice comes with many improvements over its predecessor, OpenOffice.Org-3.2.1. The
      new Search Bar, Title Page, and Print Dialogs are impressive additions. Petr Mladek, long
      standing LibreOffice and openSUSE contributor, comments:</para>
    <para><quote>I think that users will appreciate the new hierarchical axis labels for charts, RTF
        export, easier slide layout handling, and all the other features we were able to add thanks
        to our more open development model.</quote></para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/11.4-screenshot-libreoffice-calc-on-xfce-300x225.jpg"
          align="right"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>LibreOffice provides some unique benefits over other Office solutions beyond simply being
      free, like Online Help, as well as a host of usability improvements. Different Formula
      Syntaxes are implemented, including Calc A1, Excel A1 and Excel R1C1. Inline form editing is a
      lot easier to use. Another useful feature is the ability to use a split view on a sheet, while
      in multi-lingual documents we now have the ability to change language for a particular
      sentence. Presentations with LibreOffice will sparkle with the new 3D slide transitions in
      Impress.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">LibreOffice in openSUSE</emphasis></para>
    <para>Mladek notes several advantages of LibreOffice in openSUSE; one of them being a huge group
      of LibreOffice Developers inside openSUSE benefiting from the suite’s faster development model
      and no need of any copyright assignment. Another advantage he mentions is the use of the
        <ulink url="https://build.opensuse.org/">openSUSE Build Service</ulink>, which helps to keep
      the packages up-to-date and compatible for older distributions. And finally, openSUSE is the
      only distribution using the split build (separate packages for each component) which makes it
      easier to hack on LibreOffice, providing a quicker development path for bug fixes and
      incremental feature improvements.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/libreoffice-300x187.png"
          align="left"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Developers and packagers at both LibreOffice and openSUSE have taken special care that the
      migration and update process from OpenOffice.org to LibreOffice moves on smoothly. Backward
      compatibility and improved import &amp; export filters were set as top priorities.</para>
    <para>LibreOffice receives major contributions from Novell and SUSE hackers, as <ulink
        url="http://cedric.bosdonnat.free.fr/wordpress/?p=758">a recent blog from Cedric Bosdonnat
        showed</ulink>. Bosdonnat also notices the growth of LibreOffice:</para>
    <para><quote>LibreOffice now counts 133 new hackers and 55 localizers (since the
      fork).</quote></para>
    <para>Michael Meeks, another prominent LibreOffice contributor and openSUSE developer,
      adds:</para>
    <para><quote>I’m really excited to have LibreOffice in openSUSE 11.4, and the converse, to have
        so many great openSUSE developers involved with LibreOffice both in testing and developing.
        It is great to work together with the wider community to get the best Free Software Office
        experience possible into users’ hands.</quote></para>
    <para><quote>openSUSE 11.4 will be the first stable distribution to ship with LibreOffice, a
        happy accident of timing. If you happen to be an enterprise user of SLED, don’t worry –
        there will also be updates to LibreOffice across our portfolio of supported
        products.</quote></para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/11.4-screenshot-libreoffice-writer-on-lxde-300x225.jpg"
          align="right"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Foundations</emphasis></para>
    <para>Meeks, who was closely involved with the decision to fork LibreOffice away from the
      control of Oracle and create the <ulink url="http://www.documentfoundation.org/">Document
        Foundation</ulink>, sees similarities between the Document Foundation and the work going on
      to set up an openSUSE Foundation:</para>
    <para><quote>in some ways, openSUSE’s trajectory is close to that of LibreOffice’s with the
        creation of a truly independent foundation. Surely openSUSE is under the stewardship of a
        company which is very much open to contributions, unlike OpenOffice.org was, but for
        sustained growth and a secure future a Foundation is really important.</quote></para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/11.4-screenshot-libreoffice-start-300x225.jpg"
          align="right"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Coming soon!</emphasis></para>
    <para>Watch out for LibreOffice in the upcoming scheduled release of openSUSE 11.4 on 10th
      March, 2011 which besides being the first major distribution to ship LibreOffice in a stable
      release promises many other new and updated applications, features and extensions, as well as
      numerous improvements to and stability and performance.</para>
    <para>A recent <ulink
        url="http://sysbytes.wordpress.com/2011/03/07/an-interview-with-petr-mladek-libre-office-developer/"
        >interview with openSUSE LibreOffice developer Petr Mladek</ulink> gives additional
      information.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="italic">Article contributed by Manu Gupta</emphasis></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 7.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/07/live-code-party/">Live.Code.Party.</ulink></title>
    <note><para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is Licensed under the <ulink url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GNU FreeDocumentation License version 1.2.</ulink></emphasis></para>
    </note>
    <para><ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:11.4">openSUSE 11.4</ulink> is going to be
      released this Thursday (<emphasis role="bold">March 10th, 2011</emphasis>) and there is no
      better way to enjoy the new release than having fun with your fellow openSUSE Lizards! That’s
      why community members all over the world prepare launch parties. Launch parties are events
      around the release of a new openSUSE version, what kind of event is up to the organizers. But
      it’s usually about sharing knowledge with each other, get new people to know the distribution,
      the tools and the project and most important about <emphasis role="italic">having a lot of
        fun</emphasis>, celebrating our success! Interested? Here are a couple of parties to check
      out!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Europe/Nürnberg</emphasis></para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://en.opensuse.org/images/5/51/Release_party_poster_nuernberg.png"
          align="right"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>In the town where openSUSE was born, that still hosts the SUSE headquarters and therefor a
      large portion of the community the launch event will happen on Wednesday March 16 (19:00) in
      the <ulink url="http://artefakt-nuernberg.de/">Bar/Cafe/Gallery Artefakt</ulink>. In the
      historic district of Nürnberg the folks plan to have a blast with an introduction to 11.4 by
      the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Boosters_team">Boosters</ulink>, live music
      from <ulink url="http://www.myspace.com/ukuleleinsanity">Ukulele Insanity</ulink> and lots of
      the openSUSE brew <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Beer">Old Toad</ulink>. They
      expect a couple of high profile visitors like the man that pulled it off for the 6th time,
      Stephan Kulow (coolo), release manager of the distribution, Henne Vogelsang, long time
      openSUSE Board member and maybe even a couple of the SUSE founders!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">North America/San Diego</emphasis></para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/the-party-150x150.jpg"
          align="left"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>In the land of the free, Lizards will meet in San Diego, Americas finest city. The <ulink
        url="http://www.kernel-panic.org/">Kernel-Panic Linux User Group (KPLUG)</ulink> kindly
      hosts the openSUSE 11.4 launch party at their general meeting on March 10 (18:30) in the
        <ulink url="http://extension.ucsd.edu/">UC San Diego Extension</ulink> Mission Valley, the
      continuing education and public program branch of the University of California. Among the
      guests will be openSUSE news own Izabel Valverde and openSUSE Board, Marketing, GNOME and a11y
      team member Bryen Yunashko. Join them in celebrating and learn about the features of the new
      release!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">South America/Guatemala</emphasis></para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/frets_on_fire-300x240.jpg"
          align="right"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>openSUSE Ambassadors Fernando Mejía, founder of the <ulink
        url="http://www.opensuse.org.gt/">openSUSE LUG Guatemala</ulink> and Axel Ruiz will host a
      party in the beautiful Centro Histórico, Ciudad de Guatemala. It’s going to take place in a
      cultural center called Bakabs (15:00). On the event they will introduce the crowd to the
      principles and philosophies of free software and teach them about new developments in and
      around the distribution. An install fest, lots of giveaways, like T-shirts and DVDs, and their
      legendary Frets on Fire tournament will round off the event. We heard there is usually also a
      nice after-party!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Asia/Honk Kong</emphasis></para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3068/2824169709_859f70f4e2_m.jpg"
          align="left"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>In Hong Kong, organizers are still looking for more participants for their launch party!
      They are contemplating to have lunch together in a <ulink url="http://jojofood.com/main.htm"
        >restaurant</ulink> or to meet up at the seaside mid March. Dates and locations are still
      not set in stone and are worked out, like everything else, in a collaborative fashion. The
      launch party will not only be about food and drinks but also host an install fest where you
      can grab DVDs and community members will then help you with your installation if you bring
      your computer along. All Lizards in Hong Kong that are interested to celebrate 11.4 together,
      please get in contact with the organizers on the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:11.4_Launch_party_Hong_Kong">openSUSE
      Wiki</ulink>!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">More parties…</emphasis></para>
    <para>For more launch party locations around the globe like Paris, Prague, Thessaloniki, San
      Salvador, Utrecht, Atlanta, Neuss, Colombo or Managua and for dates, addresses and a large
      scale map check the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Launch_parties">openSUSE Wiki
        launch party</ulink> page.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">…or how about you run your own?</emphasis></para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata
          fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/party_map-e1299503361641-300x147.png"
          align="right"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>By the way if you’re interested in hosting your own launch party, see our <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Launch_party_HOWTO">Launch Party HOWTO</ulink> for
      starters. Also note that launch parties aren’t limited to the release date! Feel free to plan
      yours at any time convenient to you and your guests. Just remember one thing:</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Have a lot of fun…</emphasis></para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 8.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/10/opensuse-11-4/">openSUSE News: openSUSE 11.4 – A New Hallmark For The openSUSE Project</ulink></title>
    <note><para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is Licensed under the <ulink url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GNU FreeDocumentation License version 1.2.</ulink></emphasis></para>
    </note>
    <para>Dear openSUSE Community. Users. Contributors. Fans and friends. The time has come:
        <emphasis role="bold">openSUSE 11.4 has arrived</emphasis>!. After 8 months of hard work,
      you can <emphasis role="bold">learn what is new, download it and upgrade!</emphasis></para>
    <para>We are proud to announce the launch of 11.4 in the openSUSE tradition of delivering the
      latest technology while maintaining stability. The 11.4 release brings significant
      improvements along with the latest in Free Software applications. Combined with the appearance
      of new tools, projects and services around the release, 11.4 marks a showcase of growth and
      vitality for the openSUSE Project! Read on for more details about this release…</para>
    <para>
      <ulink url="http://software.opensuse.org"><inlinemediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/get.jpg"/>
          </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject></ulink>
    </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Base System</emphasis></para>
    <para>openSUSE always concentrates on a stable foundation that is usable for different
      workloads. The base system of 11.4 brings better scalability and performance, an enhanced boot
      processes and significantly faster repository refresh, package install and update.</para>
    <para>
      <informaltable frame="void">
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                  <imagedata
                    fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/11.4_NET_installer-boot-150x150.png"
                    width="40%"/>
                </imageobject>
              </mediaobject>
            </td>
            <td>
              <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                  <imagedata
                    fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/Startup-150x150.png"
                    width="40%"/>
                </imageobject>
              </mediaobject>
            </td>
            <td>
              <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                  <imagedata
                    fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/11.4_DVD_installer-overview1-e1299760821406.png"
                    width="40%"/>
                </imageobject>
              </mediaobject>
            </td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </informaltable>
    </para>
    <para>11.4 is based around <ulink url="http://www.kernel.org/">Kernel</ulink> 2.6.37 which
      improves the scalability of virtual memory management and separation of tasks executed by
      terminal users, leading to <emphasis role="bold">better scalability and performance</emphasis>
      and less interference between tasks. The new kernel also brings better hardware support, with
      open <ulink url="http://www.broadcom.com/products/?industry_id=2">Broadcom Wireless
        drivers</ulink>, improved <ulink url="http://www.wacom.com/">Wacom</ulink> support and many
      other new or updated drivers. It also supports the improvements to graphic drivers in the
      latest <ulink url="http://www.x.org/">Xorg</ulink> and <ulink url="http://www.mesa3d.org/"
        >Mesa</ulink> shipped, so users will enjoy better 2D and 3D acceleration.</para>
    <para>New tools for an <emphasis role="bold">enhanced boot process</emphasis>. The latest <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/SDB:Gfxboot">gfxboot</ulink> 4.3.5 supports <ulink
        url="http://www.virtualbox.org/">VirtualBox</ulink> and <ulink
        url="http://www.linux-kvm.org/">qemu-kvm</ulink> while Vixie Cron has been replaced with
        <ulink url="https://fedorahosted.org/cronie/">Cronie</ulink> 1.4.6 supporting the <ulink
        url="http://www.kernel.org/pub/linux/libs/pam/">PAM</ulink> and the <ulink
        url="http://www.nsa.gov/research/selinux/">SELinux</ulink> security frameworks. The more
      experimental software options include <ulink url="http://www.gnu.org/software/grub/"
        >GRUB2</ulink> and <ulink url="http://www.freedesktop.org/wiki/Software/systemd"
        >systemd</ulink>.</para>
    <para>The <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Libzypp">ZYpp</ulink> package management
      introduces a MultiCurl backend, support for <ulink url="http://zsync.moria.org.uk/"
        >zsync</ulink> transfers, and <ulink url="http://www.metalinker.org/">Metalink</ulink>
      download support. With simultaneous downloads from multiple servers, and fetching of only
      changed parts of files, the result is a <emphasis role="bold">significantly faster repository
        refresh, package install and update</emphasis>. The new backend gives better support for
      network proxies and allows for HTTP BASIC password-protected repositories. On the desktop,
        <ulink url="http://www.packagekit.org/">KPackageKit</ulink> replaces the KDE applet and both
        <ulink url="http://www.kde.org/">KDE</ulink> and <ulink url="http://www.gnome.org/"
        >GNOME</ulink> applets now default to installing all package updates, not just
      patches.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Desktops and Applications</emphasis></para>
    <para>openSUSE is committed to flexibility and choice, providing all major desktops and a full
      range of applications, well integrated and supported. The desktops and applications of 11.4
      take the next step with a revamped user experience, all the popular up to date Free Software
      applications and consistent functionality even in lighter desktops.</para>
    <para>
      <informaltable frame="void">
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                  <imagedata
                    fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/114_screenshots_gnome_pulse_speaker_tests-e1299761291203-150x150.jpg"
                    width="40%"/>
                </imageobject>
              </mediaobject>
            </td>
            <td>
              <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                  <imagedata
                    fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/114_screenshots_gnome_pulse_speaker_tests-e1299761291203-150x150.jpg"
                    width="40%"/>
                </imageobject>
              </mediaobject>
            </td>
            <td>
              <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                  <imagedata
                    fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/114_screenshots_gnome_pulse_speaker_tests-e1299761291203-150x150.jpg"
                    width="40%"/>
                </imageobject>
              </mediaobject>
            </td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </informaltable>
    </para>
    <para><ulink url="http://www.mozilla.com/en-US/firefox/">Firefox</ulink> 4.0, first to ship in
      11.4, introduces a major redesign of the user interface with tabs moved to the top of the
      toolbar, support for pinning of tabs and more. <ulink
        url="https://wiki.mozilla.org/Firefox_Sync">Firefox Sync</ulink> synchronizes bookmarks,
      history, passwords and tabs between all your installations. Firefox 4 also supports newer web
      standards like HTML5, WebM and CSS3. 11.4 includes even more of the <emphasis role="bold"
        >popular up to date Free Software</emphasis> applications as it’s the first major
      distribution to ship <ulink url="http://www.libreoffice.org/">LibreOffice</ulink> 3.3.1.
      Delivering it’s cleaner, faster code base and features like import and edit SVG files in Draw,
      support for up to 1 million rows in Calc and easier slide layout handling in Impress. 11.4
      also débuts the result of almost 4 years of work with the <ulink url="http://www.scribus.net/"
        >Scribus</ulink> 1.4 release based on Qt 4 and Cairo technology. Improved text rendering,
      undo-redo, image/color management and vector file import are highlights of this
      release.</para>
    <para>openSUSE offers deep integration of all these technologies. By carefully creating
      ‘patterns’ of software, openSUSE ensures <emphasis role="bold">consistent functionality even
        in lighter desktops</emphasis> like XFCE and LXDE. Keyboard shortcuts are set, menu layouts
      tweaked, user-friendly file associations chosen and branding and theming integrated. 11.4
      furthermore improves on the LibreOffice and Firefox integration in KDE Plasma, using native
      file dialogs, oxygen styling (also for GTK applications) and respecting the user’s mail client
      and browser choices.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Professional tools for administrators and
      developers</emphasis></para>
    <para>openSUSE aims to be the perfect power tool for system administrators to keep their network
      safe and their systems under control. And as developing and maintaining free software is the
      bread and butter task of the openSUSE Project the distribution naturally brings everything a
      software developer needs. 11.4 ships the latest virtualization and web server stacks and all
      the major development languages, platforms and associated IDEs.</para>
    <para>
      <informaltable frame="void">
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                  <imagedata
                    fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/11.4-VirtualBox-150x150.png"
                    width="40%"/>
                </imageobject>
              </mediaobject>
            </td>
            <td>
              <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                  <imagedata
                    fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/11.4-YaST-HTTP-Module-e1299762428373-150x150.png"
                    width="40%"/>
                </imageobject>
              </mediaobject>
            </td>
            <td>
              <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                  <imagedata
                    fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/11.4-KDevelop-150x150.png"
                    width="40%"/>
                </imageobject>
              </mediaobject>
            </td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </informaltable>
    </para>
    <para>11.4 brings <emphasis role="bold">the latest virtualization stack</emphasis> with <ulink
        url="http://www.xen.org/">Xen</ulink> 4.0.2 introducing memory overcommit and a VMware
      Workstation/player driver, <ulink url="http://www.virtualbox.org/">VirtualBox</ulink> 4.0.4
      supporting VMDK, VHD, and Parallels images, as well as resizing for VHD and VDI and <ulink
        url="http://www.linux-kvm.org/">KVM</ulink> 0.14 with support for the QEMU Enhanced Disk
      format and the SPICE protocol. As guest, 11.4 includes open-vm-tools and
      virtualbox-guest-tools, and seamlessly integrates clipboard sharing, screen resizing and
      un-trapping your mouse.</para>
    <para>openSUSE ships with <emphasis role="bold">the latest web server stack</emphasis> featuring
        <ulink url="http://www.apache.org/">Apache</ulink> 2.2.17, <ulink
        url="http://www.lighttpd.net/">lighttpd</ulink> 1.4.26 and <ulink url="http://nginx.net/"
        >ngninx</ulink> 0.8.54. As well as the main databases like version 9.0.3 of <ulink
        url="http://www.postgresql.org/">PostgreSQL</ulink>, a release that brings major features
      like easy-to-use replication, a mass permission-changing facility, and anonymous code blocks.
      And <ulink url="http://www.mysql.com/">MySQL</ulink> 5.1.53 (community edition), and its fork
        <ulink url="http://mariadb.org/">MariaDB</ulink> 5.1 that offers a drop-in replacement with
      better performance and some extra features are complemented while SQLite features a new
      transaction control mechanism using a write-ahead log.</para>
    <para>openSUSE 11.4 comes with <emphasis role="bold">all the major development languages,
        platforms and associated IDEs</emphasis>. <ulink url="http://qt.nokia.com/">Qt</ulink> 4.7.1
      and <ulink url="http://qt.nokia.com/products/developer-tools/">QtCreator</ulink> 2.1 bring a
      better and faster WebKit and support for the QML Declarative language, also supported in the
      KDE Development Platform 4.6 which in turn introduces a ‘Mobile Build Target’ for a thinner
      version of its libraries. The GNOME 2.32 platform brings <ulink
        url="http://live.gnome.org/Vala">Vala</ulink> and <ulink url="http://www.python.org/"
        >Python</ulink> support to <ulink url="http://www.anjuta.org/">Anjuta</ulink> and Glib 2.26
      supports Gsettings. 11.4 ships with <ulink url="http://www.gtk.org/">GTK+</ulink> 3 bringing
      improved device input handling, fully <ulink url="http://library.gnome.org/devel/cairo/"
        >Cairo</ulink> based drawing (with multiple backends) and much easier theming to developers
      who want to develop for the upcoming GNOME 3 release. For developers who are interested in
      working on LibreOffice, openSUSE offers the unique advantage of using a ‘split build’, making
      it easy to get involved.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Around 11.4</emphasis></para>
    <para>Additionally to the distribution the openSUSE project also provides a variety of tools,
      projects and services to its fellow Free and Open Source community members and its users.
      Supporting 11.4 are <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Tumbleweed">Tumbleweed</ulink>,
      a rolling release repository, the <ulink url="http://build.opensuse.org/">Build
        Service</ulink> to easily create and release open source software and 11.4 inside <ulink
        url="http://susestudio.com/">susestudio</ulink> for you to experiment with.</para>
    <para>
      <informaltable frame="void">
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>
              <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                  <imagedata
                    fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/appstream.png"
                    width="40%"/>
                </imageobject>
              </mediaobject>
            </td>
            <td>
              <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                  <imagedata
                    fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/11.4-studio-150x150.jpg"
                    width="40%"/>
                </imageobject>
              </mediaobject>
            </td>
            <td>
              <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                  <imagedata
                    fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/11.4-Build-Service-150x150.jpg"
                    width="40%"/>
                </imageobject>
              </mediaobject>
            </td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </informaltable>
    </para>
    <para>For this release we are particularly pleased to introduce <emphasis role="bold"
        >Tumbleweed, a rolling release repository</emphasis> containing the latest stable versions
      of projects instead of relying on a rigid, periodic release cycle. The project does this for
      users that want the newest, but stable software. Additionally the popular third-party package
      provider Packman has reorganized and optimized its repositories for the openSUSE 11.4 release.
      The <ulink url="http://packman.links2linux.org/">Packman</ulink> team, which provides a large
      number of new and updated packages for openSUSE, simultaneously introduces support for
      Tumbleweed.</para>
    <para>The Free and Open Source software developers are greatly aided in the distribution of
      their software by the innovative technologies developed or initiated by the openSUSE Project.
      Like the newly released Build Service 2.1.6 which provides the infrastructure to <emphasis
        role="bold">easily create and release open source software</emphasis> for openSUSE, Fedora,
      Debian and many other Linux distributions and projects like <ulink
        url="http://socialdesktop.org/bretzn/">Bretzn</ulink> or <ulink
        url="http://distributions.freedesktop.org/wiki/AppStream">Appstream</ulink> which support
      developers in building and distributing their applications and users in getting it.</para>
    <para>We are also happy to also announce that Novell’s SUSE Studio, building upon openSUSE
      technology like KIWI, offers 11.4 as a base to build appliances upon from its convenient
      webinterface. We invite anyone to <emphasis role="bold">visit <ulink
          url="http://susestudio.com/">susestudio.com</ulink> to experiment with 11.4</emphasis>, to
      create custom versions as Live CD, USB or VM images and to share them on <ulink
        url="http://www.susegallery.com/">susegallery.com</ulink>!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="Get 11.4 now"/></para>
    <para>openSUSE is now available for <ulink url="http://software.opensuse.org/">immediate
        download</ulink>. You can also <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Buy_openSUSE">purchase a
        retail box</ulink> with 11.4 that includes 90-day installation support, physical media, and
      a printed Getting Started guide. Read more about what is new in openSUSE 11.4 in our <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/Product_highlights">Product Highlights</ulink>!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Thanks</emphasis></para>
    <para>openSUSE 11.4 represents the combined effort of thousands of developers who participate in
      openSUSE and projects shipped in openSUSE. The contributors, inside and outside the openSUSE
      Project, should be proud of this release, and they deserve a major “thank you” for all of the
      hard work and care that have gone into 11.4. We hope that 11.4 is the best openSUSE release
      yet, and that it will help to encourage the use of Linux everywhere! We hope that you all
        <emphasis role="italic">have a lot of fun</emphasis> while you use 11.4, and we look forward
      to working with you on the next release!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="About the openSUSE Project"/></para>
    <para>The openSUSE Project is a worldwide community that promotes the use of Linux everywhere.
      It creates one of the world’s best Linux distributions, working together in an open,
      transparent and friendly manner as part of the worldwide Free and Open Source Software
      community. The project is controlled by its community and relies on the contributions of
      individuals, working as testers, writers, translators, usability experts, artists and
      ambassadors or developers. The project embraces a wide variety of technology, people with
      different levels of expertise, speaking different languages and having different cultural
      backgrounds.</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 11.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/12/opensuse-11-4-made-a-splash/">openSUSE 11.4 made a splash</ulink></title>
    <note><para><emphasis role="bold">This Article is Licensed under the <ulink url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/fdl-1.2.html">GNU FreeDocumentation License version 1.2.</ulink></emphasis></para>
    </note>
    <para>Yesterday, openSUSE 11.4 saw the light of day. This release introduced some <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/Product_highlights">awesome new features</ulink> and this was
      noticed by Linux users on social media and the press around the world. Of course we’ve got a
      huge spike in visits but also the number of downloads has been enormous, almost twice as much
      as for the openSUSE 11.3 release!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Press on openSUSE</emphasis></para>
    <figure id="fig.secondlife">
      <title>Party time on second life for openSUSE 11.4</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata
            fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/party-time-on-second-life-300x188.jpg"
          />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>While openSUSE has been released less than 36 hours ago, a large <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/In_the_press">number of reviews and articles</ulink> has already
      appeared and many journalists and writers have commented on the new features. Over at <ulink
        url="http://www.linuxplanet.com/">linuxplanet.com</ulink> Sean Michael Kerner <ulink
        url="http://www.linuxplanet.com/linuxplanet/newss/7316/1/">talks about tumbleweed and some
        other cool stuff in 11.4</ulink>, quoting Novell’s openSUSE community manager Jos
      Poortvliet. ZDnet’s J.A. Watson installs openSUSE 11.4 on his desktop and netbook and
      concludes:</para>
    <para><quote>All in all, this is an excellent release, and I am very impressed with it. Whether
        you’re new to Linux or an experienced user, it is definitely worth a try.</quote></para>
    <para>At Eye on Linux Jim Linch <ulink
        url="http://eyeonlinux.com/2011/03/10/quick-look-opensuse-11-4/">says about openSUSE
        11.4</ulink>:</para>
    <para><quote>It’s arguably one of the best desktop distros available, and I expect it to remain
        among the top choices for a long time.</quote></para>
    <para>Jay Lyman, senior analyst for enterprise software at The 451 Group, was quoted by V3.co.uk
      on openSUSE 11.4 saying:</para>
    <para><quote>It’s not only an option for early adopters, and we see a preference for these kinds
        of distributions in cloud computing</quote></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Social media</emphasis></para>
    <para>The <ulink url="http://linux.slashdot.org/story/11/03/10/2210209/OpenSUSE-114-Released"
        >announcement on Slashdot</ulink> attracted the usual comments and so did <ulink
        url="http://digg.com/news/technology/opensuse_11_4_release">digg</ulink>. On <ulink
        url="http://twitter.com/#!/search/opensuse">Twitter</ulink> and <ulink
        url="http://identi.ca/search/notice?q=%23opensuse&amp;search=Search">identi.ca</ulink>
      openSUSE was mentioned many times and quite a few tweeters found the <ulink
        url="http://twibbon.com/cause/openSUSE-Users/">twibbon for openSUSE</ulink>. Last but not
      least, the <ulink url="http://www.facebook.com/#!/pages/openSUSE/45393742283">Facebook
        page</ulink> of openSUSE got quite some attention! For all these media: if you’re not a fan,
      follower or friend, you can become one!</para>
    <para>Find links to more reviews, articles and discussions on our <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/In_the_press">In the Press page</ulink>. Feel free to add
      articles you have found.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Party time!</emphasis></para>
    <para>We have a continuous virtual party <xref linkend="fig.secondlife"/> going on on <ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/02/03/join-us-for-the-first-virtual-launch-party-opensuse-11-4/"
        >Second Life</ulink>, you can find pictures <ulink
        url="http://picasaweb.google.com/friedmann.bruno/VirtualLaunchPartyMarch10th?feat=directlink"
        >here</ulink>. Even if the virtual release party is (almost) over by now, you can still
      visit the openSUSE area in Second Life!</para>
    <para>For those preferring Real Life over Second Life, there will be <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Launch_parties_11.4">Launch Parties</ulink> around the
      world and it’s certainly not too late to organize your own!</para>
    <para><emphasis>The numbers</emphasis></para>
    <para>But the above is all talk (and party). What counts are the numbers – and they are big. To
      just talk about the number of downloads via <ulink url="http://software.opensuse.org/114/en"
        >software.opensuse.org</ulink> we’ve almost doubled the numbers of downloads in the first 24
      hours compared to our <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2010/07/16/opensuse-11-3-launch-information/">previous 11.3
        release</ulink>! Well over 90.000 downloads from our website with another 12 thousand via
      Bittorrent in one day is quite impressive.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Not perfectly accurate, but…</emphasis></para>
    <para>Since each mirror site uses different ways of measuring, we cannot give an 100% reliable
      number of total downloads of openSUSE 11.4 but we can point out some numbers and give examples
      from our more than 80 mirrors. The <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/12/opensuse-11-4-made-a-splash/roxen.integrity.hu"
        >Hungary mirror at Integrity.hu</ulink> reported 220 GB distributed using http and
      additionally 400 GB via torrents. The <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/12/opensuse-11-4-made-a-splash/mirror.cst.temple.edu"
        >American mirror at temple.edu</ulink> had 460 GB on Thursday. The <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/12/opensuse-11-4-made-a-splash/mirror.switch.ch">Swiss
        switch.ch</ulink> distributed 1329 GB of data and the <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/03/12/opensuse-11-4-made-a-splash/rwth-aachen.de">German
        mirrors from rwth-aachen</ulink> distributed at peak time 5 gbit/sec and additionally 60
      MB/sec of torrent data.</para>
    <para><ulink url="http://susestudio.com/">SUSE Studio</ulink> offers another great way of
      getting a openSUSE 11.4 image – and well over 1000 people have already used this.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">download.opensuse.org</emphasis></para>
    <para>A total of 90844 requests for ISOs were reached via our download redirector at
      download.opensuse.org during the first 24 hours, a nice bump compared to 49599 for openSUSE
      11.3! Note that we can not count who accessed a mirror directly instead of using the
      redirector on <ulink url="http://download.opensuse.org/">download.opensuse.org</ulink>, so
      there are more downloads than that. Moreover, we have been emphasizing the possibility of
        <ulink url="http://upgrade.opensuse.org/">upgrading openSUSE 11.3 over the web</ulink>
      instead of by downloading an ISO and these are not tracked either.</para>
    <para>However, you’ll be able to find openSUSE 11.4 statistics soon on the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/Statistics">Statistics</ulink> page. There we track how many
      unique IP addresses regularly update from our servers – a reasonably reliable way of knowing
      how many users we have. Of course those on a NAT or internal deployments as well as those who
      don’t upgrade via our servers are not counted and those with a dynamic IP might be counted a
      few times so take the numbers with a grain of salt as well.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Distribution and torrents</emphasis></para>
    <para>These are the number of downloads split over the different media:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>NonOss Addon CD BiArch: 3926</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>32-bit x86: 49845 (total) </para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Net 2863</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>DVD 28437</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>GNOME-LiveCD 6127</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>KDE-LiveCD 6997</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Addon-Lang 5421</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>64-bit x86-64: 37073 (total) </para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Net 2102</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>DVD 23746</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>GNOME-LiveCD 2837</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>KDE-LiveCD 5732</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Addon-Lang 2656</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>Our main distribution <ulink url="http://software.opensuse.org/">download page</ulink>
      usually gets 17000 visits a day, on the launch day we had 63000.</para>
    <para>Torrents worked really well for this release thanks to the many seeders, several folks
      reported that they could download torrents with the full capacity of their connection. The
      largest number of seeders was for the x86-64 DVD with 1076 followed by 959 for the i586 DVD.
      The tracker counted 12596 complete downloads via bittorrent during the first 24 hours,
      awesome!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Thank you</emphasis></para>
    <para>The openSUSE launch on Thursday was possible thanks to a world wide infrastructure of ftp
      mirrors that coordinated the release with us. We’d like to thank all of them. Moreover, we’d
      like to thank the sysadmin team for the hard work they did to make the changes to the websites
      so users could download their brand new openSUSE 11.4! We’d also like to thank the marketing
      team and anyone who helped for their awesome work (check out the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/Product_highlights">Product Highlights</ulink> if you haven’t
      yet!) and of course all many contributors of openSUSE who helped to make this release
      possible! Finally, a shout to <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/Sponsors">our
      sponsors</ulink> Novell, AMD, IP Exchange and B1!</para>
    <!-- ($ ld: 11.3.11 sm $) -->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
