<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
%myentities;
]>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<sect1 role="announcements">
  <title>Announcements</title>
  <!--Put a maximum of 5 announcements from the following sources here: 
    * opensuse-announce mailinglist
    * opensuse-project mailinglist
    * news.opensuse.org
    * carefully selected other sources-->
  <important>
    <para>The Articles inside this Section are in full. If you are already knowing the stuff in
      news.opensuse.org, then you can skip this section through using the TOC.</para>
  </important>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/20/opensuse-summer-camp-greece-2011/"
        >openSUSE Summer Camp Greece 2011</ulink></title>
    <para><inlinegraphic fileref="http://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/Geekocamp.jpg"
      /></para>
    <para>Summer in Greece! Is the weather too hot for you to code or contribute to your favorite
      FOSS project? Do you need some motivation and a refreshing swim? Come to our Summer
      Camp!</para>
    <para>The Greek openSUSE community is organizing its first openSUSE Summer Camp, in central
      Greece at Grand Platon Hotel at Olympiaki akti. This is is the beach of the city of Katerini.
      The doors will be open from the 15th to the 17th of July 2011, at the Heart of Summer!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Sounds awesome, I’ll book my tickets.</emphasis></para>
    <para>So, you’ll be there. What can you expect?</para>
    <para>Our goal is to bring FOSS communities closer and encourage people to contribute to their
      favorite projects.</para>
    <para>A lot of people, with little to a lot of experience can benefit from the workshops
      included in our program, during which we will work on things like translation, wiki usage,
      coding, packaging and much more, showing how to work inside a community and how to collaborate
      with others!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Hmmm. But I could go swimming…</emphasis></para>
    <para>There will be relaxing and swimming of course! But hey, we have a common passion, don’t
      we?</para>
    <para>We love what we do, we are having fun contributing to FOSS and we hate doing it alone in
      our rooms during Summer time. Besides coding, translating and all other ‘working stuff’ there
      will also be plenty of sun and beach, a large swimming pool and plenty of beers – all paid by
      you since we only sponsor the sun, the fun and all the other free stuff…</para>
    <para>We are looking forward to seeing you at the openSUSE Summer Camp Greece!</para>
    <!--($ ld: 21.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/22/opensuse-releases-milestone-2/">openSUSE
        releases milestone 2</ulink></title>
    <para><inlinegraphic
        fileref="http://lizards.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/geeko-cast-my-vote.png"
        width="20%"/></para>
    <para>About 3 weeks after the <ulink
        url="http://news.opensuse.org/2011/06/01/first-step-towards-12-1-with-milestone-1/">first
        milestone for openSUSE 12.1</ulink>, today the second milestone has been made available.
      Following the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Roadmap">Roadmap</ulink>, this is
      the second of 6 milestone until the openSUSE 12.1 release in November.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Milestones</emphasis></para>
    <para>openSUSE is developed in a repository called <ulink
        url="http://opensuse.org/Portal:Factory">Factory</ulink>. Packages flow from the <ulink
        url="http://nl.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Build_Service_Collaboration#Devel_Project_maintainer.27s_workflow"
        >devel projects</ulink> into Factory upon OK from the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Release_team">release team</ulink> following the <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Factory_development_model">Factory Development
        Model</ulink>. During the <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Roadmap">development
        cycle</ulink> (<ulink url="http://www.suse.de/%7Ecoolo/opensuse_12.1/">more detailed
        model</ulink>) periodic releases are made available for testing – these are the milestones.
      Six of them become available. After some several freezes go into effect, the component freeze
      just before the fourth milestone for instance. And about a couple of weeks after the last
      milestone the first of two Release Candidates is made ready for testing. The final openSUSE
      12.1 release is expected on November 11th.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Progress since the previous milestone</emphasis></para>
    <para>The first milestone had a huge number of changes and improvements on top of the latest
      openSUSE release. Again, many packages have been updated. You can check the latest package
      versions on <ulink url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Factory_versions">this page</ulink>.
      What are the major changes?</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Firefox 5 RC</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Horde4 packages (php5-pear-horde)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>“The Board”</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>rawstudio</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>llvm/clang 3.0 snapshot</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>many smaller updates to KDE and GNOME applications and desktops</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>Also nspluginwrapper is now updated which will allow a more stable Flash plugin on 64bit
      platforms. With this change you can now watch two flash videos at the same time. And over 100
      new packages have been added, including extensions for Banshee, some small tools like <ulink
        url="http://software.opensuse.org/search?q=dds2tar">DDS2tar</ulink> and <ulink
        url="http://brainfuck.tk/">brainfuck interpreter</ulink>, Cdecl (turns C/C++ gibberish into
      English), cint (small C/C++ interpreter) and a number of other devel and language
      tools.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">systemd</emphasis></para>
    <para>On the openSUSE <ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-project/">project</ulink>
      and <ulink url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-factory/">factory</ulink> mailing lists a
      discussion is taking place centered around the new systemd init system. After <ulink
        url="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-factory/2011-06/msg00210.html">the introduction of
        the road to systemd for openSUSE 12.1</ulink> by <ulink
        url="http://blog.crozat.net/2011/06/road-to-systemd-for-opensuse-121.html">Frederic
        Crozat</ulink>, issues, complaints and limitations of systemd are being discussed and
      dissected. Changing an init system is an invasive change and systemd has ambitions beyond just
      replacing sysV not everyone always agrees with. Work will be needed to ensure a stable and
      usable init system for 12.1 and the team welcomes help and bugreports!</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Helping out easier than ever!</emphasis></para>
    <para>As expected from a development release, there is still a lot of work to do, so your input
      at this early stage will be a huge help in making the final release into the beautifully
      polished work that we aim for. openSUSE 12.1 Milestone 2 has a <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Most_annoying_bugs_12.1_dev">list of most annoying bugs
        here</ulink>, please add issues you find and help fix them. As Will Stephenson <ulink
        url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2011/05/16/have-you-burped-yet-today/">recently
        blogged</ulink>, fixing an issue is a matter of <emphasis role="bold">BURP</emphasis>ing on
        <ulink url="http://build.opensuse.org">build.opensuse.org</ulink>! Find a how-to <ulink
        url="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Build_Service_Collaboration#Example_with_web_interface"
        >here</ulink>.</para>
    <para>So go and see for yourself what the next version of openSUSE has in store for you at our
        <ulink url="http://software.opensuse.org/developer">download center</ulink>.</para>
    <!--($ ld: 23.6.11 sm $)-->
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
