<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
  
  This work is licensed under the
  Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
  by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
  Creative Commons
  171 Second Street
  Suite 300
  San Francisco California 94105
  USA.
  
-->
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
  <!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
  %myentities;
]>
<sect1 role="planetsuse">
  <title>Planet SUSE</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink url="http://lizards.opensuse.org/2010/12/05/unity-maybe-on-fedora/">Nelson
        Marques: Unity (maybe) on Fedora</ulink></title>
    <para>According to this <ulink
        url="http://www.happyassassin.net/2010/12/03/unity-on-fedora-possibly/">post</ulink> by
        <ulink url="http://www.happyassassin.net/2010/12/03/unity-on-fedora-possibly/">Adam
        Williams</ulink> (Fedora QA), Unity might actually land on Fedora. </para>
    <para>Some time ago, I’ve dropped into openSUSE-GNOME mailing list an email regarding this
      topic, and the need that we openSUSE have regarding to protect a possible risk of having our
      users migrating to Ubuntu to check out Unity. The downside of openSUSE is the fact that we
      might be limited by manpower. </para>
    <para>To me, this sounds the most sane strategy to promote a vertical defense of our community.
      Adam Williams and Fedora seem to have acknowledged that it is important to provide users with
      software so that they do not feel the rush or need to change vendor to check out a new piece
      of software, specially when it’s something already strong in name as Unity. </para>
    <para>From my side… I’ve started to work on building a test repository for Ubuntu stuff…
      currently I’ve got most dependencies already ready for Factory, including a gtk+ version with
      the patches to enable some functionality required for the Ubuntu Indicators. </para>
    <para>If ‘openSUSE IBERIA’ happens to happen… it’s GNOME version will be very close to Ubuntu
      (and in some cases even featuring extended functionality, like GDM Configuration tool,
      Notify-OSD skinning, amongst other small goodies). Why to build something close to Ubuntu?
      EASY ANSWER! PORTUGAL AND SPAIN are dominated by Ubuntu… by providing something very close to
      the Ubuntu experience we might become more attractive to those users and establish positive
      synergies to attack their user base! YES, we, proud Portuguese and Spanish are packing out
      stuff to take the fight to the streets! Which reminds me of an old English saying: </para>
    <para>“Españoles en la mar quiero. Y si es en tierra, San Jorge nos proteja…” (The spanish we
      want on the sea. If in land we find them, Saint George protect us…”</para>
  </blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://blog.cornelius-schumacher.de/2010/12/week-in-life-of-kde-ev-board-member.html"
        >Cornelius Schumacher: A week in the life of a KDE e.V. board member</ulink></title>
    <para>Did you ever want to know how life as a KDE e.V. board member is? From the questions I get
      I know that at least some of you do. So here you go. I took some notes last week to give you a
      brief impression of what I did in my role as board member of KDE e.V. (...)</para>
  </blockquote>
  
</sect1>
