<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
  "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[
  <!ENTITY % myentities SYSTEM "entities.ent">
  %myentities;
]>
<sect1 role="kernel">
  <!--
    
    This work is licensed under the
    Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License
    by Sascha Manns. To view a copy of this license, visit
    http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/ or send a letter to
    Creative Commons
    171 Second Street
    Suite 300
    San Francisco California 94105
    USA.
    
  -->
  <title>Kernel Review</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title><ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/open/features/Kernel-Log-An-analysis-of-Linux-kernel-development-1147619.html"
        >h-online/Thorsten Leemhuis: Kernel Log: An analysis of Linux kernel development</ulink>
    </title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">A new edition of a study by the Linux Foundation explains the Linux
        kernel development process and includes various statistics that demonstrate the kernel's
        growth rate. It also analyses how much is contributed to the kernel's development by which
        developers and companies. </emphasis></para>
    <para>The Linux Foundation has released an updated edition of its "Who Writes Linux and Who
      Supports It" study which offers insights into the development of the Linux kernel. The <ulink
        url="http://www.linuxfoundation.org/docs/lf_linux_kernel_development_2010.pdf">new
        edition</ulink> is called "Linux Kernel Development – How Fast it is Going, Who is Doing It,
      What They are Doing, and Who is Sponsoring It" and, like the <ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/news/item/Linux-Foundation-study-goes-behind-the-scenes-of-kernel-development-734755.html"
        >first</ulink> and <ulink
        url="http://www.h-online.com/news/item/Linux-Foundation-updates-Kernel-Development-study-743009.html"
        >second</ulink> edition, it analyses such aspects as which companies sponsor the kernel's
      development, how many programmers contribute changes, and how fast the kernel is growing. </para>
    <para>The study was written by kernel developer and chief editor of LWN.net, Jonathan Corbet, by
      kernel developer Greg Kroah-Hartman, who works on SUSE products at Novell, and by the Linux
      Foundation's Amanda McPherson. Like the first two studies, the current edition is based on
      kernel version 2.6.11 – immediately after this version, Linus Torvalds migrated the kernel
      sources to the Git source code management system he had started at that time. In some areas,
      however, the authors of the study focused on the changes the kernel developers made between
      version 2.6.30 and version 2.6.35 – which covers the period between the study's second edition
      and the time of writing of the now released third edition. As before, the three authors used
      the "Git Data Miner" (<ulink url="git://git.lwn.net/gitdm.git%0D">gitdm</ulink>) for their
      evaluations (access to this link requires the installation of a Git handler). (...)</para>
  </blockquote>
</sect1>
